<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AD1001"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
 
<TEI.2 id="AD1001">  
<teiHeader type="migrated">  
 
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Diary of Michael Reid Hanger (1861)</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county diary of michael reid hanger 1861</title>
        <author>Hanger, Michael Reid </author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Valley Staff</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
 
      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes">ca. 132 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>  
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
 
        <idno type="VCDH">AD1001</idno>  
 
        <!--
<availability>  
<p>Publicly accessible </p>  
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
<p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>  
</availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500328</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>Valley of the Shadow</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>  
 
 
      <sourceDesc>   
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Diary of Michael Reid Hanger</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">diary of michael reid hanger</title>
            <author>Michael Reid Hanger</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>e.g. Translator</resp>
              <name>Robert Driver</name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent> pages</extent>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher> </publisher>  
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>  
            <date value=""> </date>  
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Michael Reid Hanger Diary, Augusta County Historical Society, Staunton, Virginia</idno>  
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt> 
            <note>
              <p>Unless otherwise noted, all comments are Mr. Driver's.  We are 
indebted to Ray and Cindy Ledgerwood of Pullman, Washington, for making this diary 
available.  Harold Howard of Lynchburg, realizing it would be of local interest, sent us a 
copy of this valuable manuscript.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Augusta County Historical Society, Staunton, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
 
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1861-04-18" to="1861-10-30">1861-04-18 - 1861-10-30</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>
Battle Description, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Death/Casualties, 
Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Women
</term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
 
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>  
        <item/>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
  </teiHeader>  
 
<text id="AD1001T"> 
 
<front id="d2"> 
<div1 id="AD1001bio" type="bio"> 
<head>Biography 
<!-- <ref>AD1001bio</ref> -->
</head> 

<p>Michael Reid Hanger was born in Staunton, Virginia on May 10, 
1840.  He worked as a carpenter in Lexington, Virginia, in 1860, and  
enlisted there in the "Rockbridge Rifles" on April 18, 1861, in 
response to Governor John Letcher's call for volunteers to defend 
Virginia.  During the war the Rifles became part of the 4th and 5th
Virginia Infantry.  In this diary Hanger describes in very detailed daily
entries the movement of the Rifles in the Valley and in central Virginia.
</p></div1> 
 
<div1 id="AD1001int" type="introduction"> 
<head type="main">Introduction 
<!-- <ref>AD1001int</ref> -->
</head> 


 <!-- <ref>Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment</ref> --> 
<p>The "Rifles," 103 strong, assembled in front of the courthouse in 
Lexington on April 18th to be sworn in.  The new soldiers had drawn 
their arms and equipment from the state arsenal at the V.M.I. </p> 
 
<p>A reporter for the <hi rend="italic">Lexington Gazette</hi> described the 
ceremony:</p> 
 
<p>"When all was ready, after bidding adieu to friends and relatives, 
the Rifles were formed in front of the Court House, where Rev. Mr. 
Tebbs<ref n="1" target="hanger1">[1]</ref>and the venerable Dr. 
McFarland<ref n="2" target="hanger2">[2]</ref>stood prepared to call 
upon the Lords of Hosts for his protecting care under the trying 
circumstances in which they were soon to be placed.  All heads were 
uncovered while the men of God appealed to the God of battle, to bless 
those who had left their wives and children, fathers and mothers, 
brothers and sisters, to go forth in defense of rights bestowed upon 
us by our fathers of the revolution, and to protect and defend them 
from those who instigated by folly and wickedness, would deprive us of 
our dearly prized institutions.  All hearts were softened, all eyes 
were moistened by the tear of sorrow for the necessitation of the 
case.  Every soldier was determined, if need be, to stand to the last, 
and die in a cause so just and a service so honorable."</p> 
 
<p>Another added:  "The pomp and circumstances of glorious war were 
present when on that bright spring morning [this] company, with colors 
flying and martial music, took up the line of march from Lexington to 
Harpers Ferry.  His [Elisha F. Paxton's]<ref n="3" target="hanger3">[3]</ref>young wife 
with sad forebodings, wept until her handkerchief was wet with tears.  In their last fond 
embrace he took this from her hand and as a reminder of her love carried it on 
many a bloody battlefield.</p> 
 
<p>Cadet A. C. S. Greenwood wrote: ". . . the Rifle Company 
started today at one o'clock they passed the institute and [we] 
saluted them. . . ."</p> 
 
<p>Young Hanger begins his diary: </p> 

</div1> 
</front> 
 
<body id="d5"> 

 
<div1 id="AD10011861" type="part" n="1861"> 
<head>1861
<!-- <ref>AD10011861</ref> -->
</head> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-04" id="d7"> 
<head>April 1861
 <!-- <ref>Troop Movement, Women</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-04-18" id="d8"> 
<head>the April 18 1861</head> 
<p>We left Lexingtom at 1 oclock PM in stages [sic] - hacks - Waggons 
We got to Fairfield at sunset I took supper at Mr. 
McCormicks <ref n="4" target="hanger4">[4]</ref>went on to midway &amp;  
there the whole Company got Supper at 9 PM Mr. Varner <ref n="5" target="hanger5">[5]</ref>[,] Marston 
<ref n="6" target="hanger6">[6]</ref>[,] Middleton <ref n="7" target="hanger7">[7]</ref> &amp; 
myself eat at Mr Dr Hameltons <ref n="8" target="hanger8">[8]</ref> then we preseeded to 
Greensvill got there at 2 oclock AM.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-04-19" id="d9"> 
<head>the April 19</head> 
<p>we got to Staunton this morning put up at the Va House got 
breakfast and Asbury McCluerer <ref n="9" target="hanger9">[9]</ref> &amp; my self went to see 
some ladies came back at 10 oclock AM.  Wm. Hartigan <ref n="10"
target="hanger10">[10]</ref> Samuel Charlton <ref n="11" target="hanger11">[11]</ref> &amp; 
my self went and taken dinner at 
Lieut Staffords <ref n="12" target="hanger12">[12]</ref> went 
back to the Hotel and in A few moments we started out was Escorted out 
of town with the band of musick &amp; we all got aboard of stages hacks 
and prseeded to Mt Sidney got there at dark.   Sargent 
Campbell <ref n="13" target="hanger13">[13]</ref>  John 
Middleton  Marston  Reilly <ref n="14" target="hanger14">[14]</ref> &amp;  John Edmondson 
<ref n="15" target="hanger15">[15]</ref> &amp; my self stayed at Mr. ______es the 
rest stayed in different places.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-04-20" id="d10"> 
<head>the April 20th</head> 
<p>We left Mt Sidney this morning for Harrisonburg had quite a nice 
time of it all day got to Mount Crawford at 12 AM the Rockbridge 
Cavalry<ref n="16" target="hanger16">[16]</ref> was there I saw my 
Brother John <ref n="17" target="hanger17">[17]</ref> &amp; many 
others that I knew--we went on got to Harrisonburg at 4pm marched into 
the Court House &amp; then we devided our for different places for to stay 
all night Mr. Varner  Bailey <ref n="18" target="hanger18">[18]</ref>  Burtons <ref n="19"
target="hanger19">[19]</ref> &amp; my self went to  Mr 
Effingers <ref n="20" target="hanger20">[20]</ref> A wealthey merchant 
and was treated verry kindley after supper Mr. Reilly &amp; 
myself went to call upon some ladies we got Acquainted with two 
Misses Vanpelts <ref n="21" target="hanger21">[21]</ref> and 
Misses Smith <ref n="22" target="hanger22">[22]</ref> Mr. 
Fonshill <ref n="23" target="hanger23">[23]</ref> came in and we had A 
good time generally.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-04-21" id="d11"> 
<head>April the 21st</head> 
<p>Beautifull morning this Mr. Fonshill 
Reilly &amp; myself went to take leave of our lady 
Acquaintences they were so verry Agreeable that I hated verry much to 
part with them though we bid them <hi rend="italic">Adieu</hi> and took the coach for 
Mt Jackson <ref n="24" target="hanger24">[24]</ref></p> 
 
<p>had a pleasant time all day Reached Mt Jackson at sun set 
Mr. Tanquary <ref n="25" target="hanger25">[25]</ref> had made 
arrangements for our staying all night.  We stayed in the ________ 
[Mr. Farrah's and Mr. Walters] Hotels and had verry good 
entertainment</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-04-22" id="d12"> 
<head>April 22nd</head> 
<p>At 8 o'clock this morning we took the Cars, and came on to 
Strasburg for [from] here we walked to Winchester, a distance of 18 
miles.  We here stoped at the Taylor House, and staid all night and in 
morning took the Harpers Ferry and Winchester R.R..  Passed by edge of 
Charlstown [sic], and came on to the Ferry.  We quartered in the 
Armory, amongst machinery.  We remained here for a week or so, and 
then went on the Maryland Heights, and staid 1 day and a night, and 
got a pretty good ducking.  We then came back to the Armory, staid 
there about 1 week, and then moved to Bolivar. staid there week or so, 
and then went to Va Heights, we here knocked up some old shandies and 
went to cutting down trees and cleaning up generally.  burning brush 
&amp;c.  We cleared off about 30 acres of land and built one Block house. 
We were in one of the greatest Hail storms I ever saw.  The stones 
were as large as partridge eggs the ground was covered, an inch deep. 
it cut our shanties down and left us in the storm.  We staid here 10 
days and then came back to Bolivar.  The next place we went to was 
Martinsburg on the B. &amp; O. R.R.  We had a glorious time here, though 
it was a great Union place. the ladies sent us everything we could 
wish, and presented us with thousands of Bouquets.  We spent a very 
happy time here certain.  We were here about 1 week and started back 
to Ferry, and burned a bridge (Opequon) on the B. &amp; O. R>R> about 2 
1/2 miles from Martinsburg.  We came back to Bolivar, but didn't tarry 
long.  We were in Martinsburg during election.  We were quartered in 
Grantham Hall).  We again started and went to Shepherds-town, from 
there to the Neck or (Shepherd's Bend,) about 5 miles from the town. 
We saw some of the enemy, with red caps and blue uniform.  I shot at 
one of them, and all say I certainly killed him.  We were quartered in 
an old barn all night.  The next day we moved back about 1 mile to 
Mr. Chapman's house.  I was then ordered to go on Picquet. to Dam No. 
4.  We soon got orders to move.  We all came back to Shepherd's town 
joined the Regt. [5th Va. Infantry] and that night.  came to 
Charlestown.  about 11 o'clock that night, and camped in the 
Fairgrounds.  Early the next morning we started to Wonchester, and got 
there about 9 o'clock at night and camped in the Fairgrounds.  the 2nd 
day we were ordered to march to Martinsburg, but hearing of the enemy 
crossing the [Potomac] River, and overtaking Col. 
Johnston<ref n="26" target="hanger26">[26]</ref> with 6 or 8 Regts at 
Bunker's Hill.  we halted and there formed 1 line of battle.  As we 
heard nothing of the enemy, we returned together with the other Regts 
to Winchester.  We here staid all night, and the next eveneing started 
again for Martinsburg.  We traveled that evening 14 miles, and as the 
Companies were very much fatigued &amp; c, we camped for the night at 
Bucklestown, alias, Darksville [Darkesville] 6 miles from 
Martinsburg.  We camped all night out side the town a piece.  In the 
morning came on through Martinsburg 4 miles below, on the road and 
here camped (Camp Stevens)<ref n="27" target="hanger27">[27]</ref></p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-06" id="d13"> 
<head>June 1861
 <!-- <ref>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-23" id="d14"> 
<head>Camp Stevens June 23rd Sunday 1861</head> 
<p>Was to hear Rev Dr Pendleton <ref n="28" target="hanger28">[28]</ref> preach this 
morning at his quarters, in the evening heard Rev Mr Goul <ref n="29" 
target="hanger29">[29]</ref> preach at our quarters.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-24" id="d15"> 
<head>June 24th Monday</head> 
<p>Still here at Camp 4 miles from town.  We resumed Bat" [Battalion] 
and Co" [Company] Drills this morning.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-25" id="d16"> 
<head>June 25th Tuesday</head> 
<p>Beautiful day.  Our baggage was sent to us from Winchester.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-26" id="d17"> 
<head>June 26th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Cloudy this morning, looks like rain.  Jim Holley is talking of 
going home today.  5 o'clock, we had a considerable shower this 
evening, and the wind blew very hard.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-27" id="d18"> 
<head>June 27th Thursday</head> 
<p>Fine morning.  One of Kirkpatrick's <ref n="30" target="hanger30">[30]</ref> men was 
shot today, whilst on Pcquet 
guard at the river.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-28" id="d19"> 
<head>June 28th Friday</head> 
<p>Had Battalion drill this morning as [usua[l] {corner torn} Fine 
pleasent day.  Very warm.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-29" id="d20"> 
<head>June 29th Saturday</head> 
<p>There were only 15 men out on drill this morning at 10. o'clock.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-06-30" id="d21"> 
<head>June 30th Sunday</head> 
<p>No battalion drill this morning.  Cloudy this morning, looks like 
rain.  Cleaned our guns this morning for Inspection.  11 o'clock it is 
now raining right hard.  We have to lay in our blanket rag houses. 
Pay roll was called this morning.</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-07" id="d22"> 
<head>July 1861
 <!-- <ref>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-01" id="d23"> 
<head>July 1st Monday</head> 
<p>Still cloudy. and I think we will have more rain today.  Messrs 
Laird <ref n="31" target="hanger31">[31]</ref> and 
Bougher <ref n="32" target="hanger32">[32]</ref> got Furloughs to 
go home to day until the 16th.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-02" id="d24"> 
<head>July 2nd Tuesday</head> 
<p>Whilst eating our breakfast this morning we received orders, to 
pack up &amp;c. and be ready to move in 10 minutes.  The West Augusta 
Guards<ref n="33" target="hanger33">[33]</ref> were put in front, our Co. 
next, for skirmish.  When we got about 2 miles from Camp, we were 
halted.  The Augusta Guards went crossed the fence, and demployed 
along a fence running perpendicularly to the road.  Our regimnet (the 
5th). Then formed into Platoons, and from platoons into a square 
[picture of a square] in the road.  The fire was opened by the Augusta 
guards, we (our Co) was then ordered to jump the fence and deploy a 
long with and in rear of W. A. G.'s.  the remainder of the Regt. 
pressed on in the road and commenced firing.  In deploying my three 
Companions were McCampbell  
<ref n="34" target="hanger34">[34]</ref>,  A. C. McClure,  
<ref n="35" target="hanger35">[35]</ref>, and McCoun  
<ref n="36" target="hanger36">[36]</ref>. we all kept up a constant firing.  In 
a short time the enemy began to give way, running &amp;c.  We were still 
firing into them, we advanced then fell back.  We repulsed them 3 
times, at last they rallied their forces, and commenced to advance we 
then gave way.   Capt. Pendleton then opened of one of his 
6 pound cannon on them, but they still continued to advance, the 
Artillery then also gave way, we retreated on back, to withn 3 miles 
of Martinsburg, we here took our respective positions again to meet 
them. but they didn't come on , and we got orders to move on again, So 
we came on to martinsburg. and camped for the night at the big Spring 
2 1/2 miles from town.  In our Co. only 2 were wounded.   Mr 
McNamara <ref n="37" target="hanger37">[37]</ref>, who was shot in 
left arm ball glanced and cut his breast considerably  Mr. Arthur 
McCluer <ref n="38" target="hanger38">[38]</ref> got a slight wound on 
the head from a spent grape shot, it is just a mere sckrah [scratch]. 
In the W. A. G.s,  Jack Doyle  
<ref n="39" target="hanger39">[39]</ref> received a slight wound from explosion 
of a shell.  One of Capt. Doyl's  
<ref n="40" target="hanger40">[40]</ref> men was killed, and one Continental 
<ref n="41" target="hanger41">[41]</ref> under Capt. Avis  
<ref n="42" target="hanger42">[42]</ref> from Winchester.  Balls flew in every 
direction, the shell passed over our heads, and fell about 50 paces in 
the rear and exploded, the balls were whiselling in the trees above us 
in a hurry It is thought that the enemy numbered about 10,000. 
against us of about 380 men.  Col. Jackson <ref n="43" target="hanger43">[43]</ref> says, 
we did most capitally.  Stewarts 
<ref n="44" target="hanger44">[44]</ref> Cavalry brought in 40 prisoners 
this morning to martinsburg.  9 more were brought in whilst at Big 
Spring.  One was a Surgeon in Northern army, one Lieut, a cavalry man, 
and 6 others, privates.  I suppose, we had the post of honor in the 
retreat (the rear).</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-03" id="d25"> 
<head>July 3rd Wednesday</head> 
<p>We camped here last night at the Spring 2 1/2 miles from 
Martinsburg.  We were waiting for reinforcements under 
Johnson [sic], from Winchester We came on from the Spring 
back to Bucklestown, alias Darksville, and here met Col Johnston and 
his force numbering I think about 12,000 men.  We camped in the same 
place we did before.  Col Johnston's camp is on the end of town 
towards Winchester his forces have now moved above us next to 
Martinsburg, in the fields and have divided up into different 
Companies in different fields, and have taken their positions, and I 
suppose will camp there the night.  We understand that the Yankees are 
in Martinsburg, there are about 10,000 of them.  We took every thing 
we could carry easily out of our knapsacks, they were talking of 
burning them, but L. M. Booker <ref n="45" target="hanger45">[45]</ref> is going to take 
charge of them, and 
send them to Winchester.   Capt. Middleton <ref n="46" target="hanger46">[46]</ref> Came 
here today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-04" id="d26"> 
<head>July 4th Thursday</head> 
<p>We stayed here again last night, We are now drawn up in line we 
don't know which way we are going, thogh I suppose towards 
Martinsburg.  2 O'clock we have not moved yet, still here.  We drew 
rations this morning for 3 days. and are now cooking 1 days.  
6 1/2 o'clock we had battallion drill and Dress parade this 
evening, we will stay here tonight again.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-06" id="d27"> 
<head>July 6th Saturday</head> 
<p>We had a little rain about 7 o'clock this morning, still cloudy. 5 o'clock our 
Picquet were driven in this morning. We are now drawn up in line of battle here 
Pendleton's battery on our left, we remained in line of battle for an hour or 
two, and finding that the Yankess were not coming, we retired from the field, 
and went to cooking supper.  Col. Johnston reviewed us whilst in  
line of battle.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-05" id="d28"> 
<head>July 5th Friday</head> 
<p>I made a slight mistake here. This ought to have come before the above.  
6 o'clock got up this morning at 3 o'clock. and got breakfast. and packed our 
blankets. and put them in the wagon, and sent it off towards Winchester 8. 
o'clock. 2 more prisoners were brought in just now. 9 o'clock 3 more were 
brought in. they have all been sent to Winchester.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-07" id="d29"> 
<head>July 7th Sunday</head> 
<p>9. o'clock, we are now drawn up and I think we are going to Winchester, though 
it is hard to tell. It is very warm this morning. ll o'clock. we are now at 
Bunkers Hill resting and wattering. 6 o'clock were are now quartered for the 
night, in the woods, 5 miles from Wincester, we are all very tired and very 
much fatigued. We left behind us beautiful fields of wheat, already cut and 
shocked which I suppose will all be destroyed by the enemy. As we passed along 
to day Sunday. the people were not in their harvest fields cutting wheat, every 
thing is left to the mercy of the enemy.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-08" id="d30"> 
<head>July 8th Monday</head> 
<p>6 o'clock. Fine morning. I suppose we will go on to day. 10. o'clock we have 
moved our Camp about 1 1/4 miles towards Winchester in the woods. We have water 
to carry about 1/2 mile. 6 o'clock we have battallion drill this evening. We are 
camped about 100 yds from Harpers Ferry and Winchester R. R.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-09" id="d31"> 
<head>July 9th Tuesday</head> 
<p>8 o'clock, It is a very warm morning and we have Company drill at 10, 3 o'clock 
John Edmondson brought us our baggage &amp;c He went to Winchester  
and opened all 
our baggage, and brought us some of our things, all mixed up to gether half of 
the men got none of their things.  Capt. Middleton  came with them  
and brought us 
some of our tents, and we are putting them up. 5 o'clock It is raining very 
hard now, and we have to stay in our tents we have only 2. we will have hard 
times to night I expect. 9.o'clock we got orders whist retiring to our bed to 
pack up every thing but what we were sleeping on, and put them in the wagon. 
after that to draw rations and cook it that night for the next day.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-10" id="d32"> 
<head>July 10th Wednesday</head> 
<p>7 o'clock. We will start in a few minutes I guess, We are going towards 
Winchester 12 o'clock. We are now near Winchester The Militia are throwing up 
breastworks here about 1/4 mile from town, and our cooks 
(McClure  Campbell  
 Mullen <ref n="47" target="hanger47">[47]</ref> and 
Charlton S.) went to cooking 4 o'clock we had a very hard rain 
this evening. I was very damp and cool last night.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-11" id="d33"> 
<head>July 11th Thursday</head> 
<p>9 o'clock. It looks like rain again. Thought the sun came out beautifully this 
morning. The Rockbridge Artillery go a very large piece of cannon yesterday 
evening. </p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-12" id="d34"> 
<head>July 12th Friday</head> 
<p>Fine day. The Richmond (Thomas) Artillery came here today. Messrs 
Deaver<ref n="48" target="hanger48">[48]</ref>, 
Rollins<ref n="49" target="hanger49">[49]</ref>,  
Caffrey<ref n="50" target="hanger50">[50]</ref>, Lewis<ref n="51"
target="hanger51">[51]</ref>, and Charles 
Tanquary<ref n="52" target="hanger52">[52]</ref> are all  
here now.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-13" id="d35"> 
<head>July 13th Saturday</head> 
<p>moved our tents on a line with the others 5. o'clock, We were this evening 
transfered to the 4th Regt Va. Vols.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-14" id="d36"> 
<head>July 14th Sunday</head> 
<p>No battallion drill at 6 or Company drill at 10  We have been laying in our 
tents all day Mr. Laird of our Co returned today we had Dress  
parade this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-15" id="d37"> 
<head>July 15th Sunday</head> 
<p>5. o'clock we were reviewed by Gen Jackson<ref n="53" target="hanger53">[53]</ref> 
today. after that, had drill and 
Dress parade 8 o'clock. (night). we were ordered out went to Headquarters, in 
the yard around the house. halted stacked arms, we were then orded to lay down, 
and keep perfectly quiet, so as to surprise the enemy if they attacked the 
house. 2 or 3 men wer detailed to go after our blankets, some of the Regts were 
ordered to tear down some old houses near here. to get axes, cut down the brush 
and trees &amp;c. We were in the yard about an hour, were then ordered to go 
to our quarters, which we did without being distured any more.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-16" id="d38"> 
<head>July 16th Tuesday</head> 
<p>Cloudy, I think it will rain shortly. We understand that the Yankees are coming 
on, they drove our Cavalry in, they are now at Darksville.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-17" id="d39"> 
<head>July 17th Wednesday</head> 
<p>No drill this evening. Dress parade pleasant day, warm.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-18" id="d40"> 
<head>July 18th Thursday</head> 
<p>ordered to pack up and be in readiness to move. 11 o'clock not moved yet. 3 
o'clock we are now on our way to Manassas Junction. 9. o'clock (night) we have 
to cross the Shenandoah river, we have to wade, the sick were put across in 
boats. The Artillery men rode across on their Caissons and Limber boxes. We 
then crossed the Blue Ridge, and got to a little town (Paris) at the foot of the 
mountain about 1.o'clock.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-19" id="d41"> 
<head>July 19th Friday</head> 
<p>We took up line of march again this morning at 4. o'clock, giving us only about 
2 hours rest we came on to Pidmont [sic] Station<ref n="54" target="hanger54">[54]</ref>. 
got here about 6.o'clock. we 
remained here until about 2 o'clock when we took the cars for the Junction. When 
we had gotten about 2 miles from Winchester, a general order was read 
"That Gen Patterson<ref n="55" target="hanger55">[55]</ref>, was marching by way of 
Harper's Ferry, and was going on to Manassas 
Junction. and that they were right there now and that we were going to 
reinforce Beauregard<ref n="56" target="hanger56">[56]</ref>. It took us about 6 hours to 
cross the Shenandoah river. It is a forced march and we have to get there as soon as 
possible. we got to the Junction about 4. o'clock this evening. we will remain here at the 
Junction to night I guess.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-20" id="d42"> 
<head>July 20th Friday</head> 
<p>We moved down about 4 miles towards Centreville to camp this morning. 2 o'clock 
we were drawn up in line of battle in a corn field near here. We can easily see 
the Camps of the Enemy across the hills.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-21" id="d43"> 
<head>July 21st Sunday</head> 
<p>5 O'clock A.M. we can hear the cannon firing from the hills in front, and a 
little below us, The Yankees are endeavoring to draw un in that direction. The 
Junction is strongly fortifiyed, with breastworks and entrenchments around in 
every possible direction. 8 o'clock they are now fighting in a hurry above here 
about 2 miles. we are moving briskly in that direction.. The enemy still 
Cannonading below.. Actium is our Countersight and and Sumpter [sic] our 
Watchword. our Regt the 4th was ordered to different places at 1 o'clock PM we 
was ordered on the field our Regt and the 27th was drawen up behind 8 peaces 
of Artilery<ref n="57" target="hanger57">[57]</ref> and was ordered to lay low  
we lay there for 3 1/2 hours had several 
men killed there. then we was ordered to rais and fire and charge bayonetts. 
There was an Awfull fire kept up The yankees had flanked round on our left had 
planted six peaces of Artilery &amp; had A cross fire on us when we we charged 
the yankees fell back and we captured their artilery The ground was covered 
with dead &amp; wounded George Chapin 
<ref n="58" target="hanger58">[58]</ref> and myself was togather when 
Miller<ref n="59" target="hanger59">[59]</ref> was 
wounded I was struck with A peace of shell and was helped of the field by 
John Donald 
<ref n="60" target="hanger60">[60]</ref> &amp; John Middleton  When we got to  
the fence in the rear it was Capt. Letcher 
<ref n="61" target="hanger61">[61]</ref> who got Mr John Laird.s horse for  
me to ride to the camp A distance 
of 3 miles aide camp [aide-de-camp] Marchell 
<ref n="62" target="hanger62">[62]</ref> came to camp with Me 
General Jackson came in at dark Mr Right 
<ref n="63" target="hanger63">[63]</ref> of our Company got him something 
to eat and 
gave him some of our Boys blanketts to sleep on The company did not all get 
to camp tonight Leiut Paxton came in None of our officers was  
hurt all come up safe We lost in the R[ockbridge] Rifles.  Fred 
Davidson<ref n="64" target="hanger64">[64]</ref> and Asbery 
McClurer, Wounded, 
Bourger<ref n="65" target="hanger65">[65]</ref> 
Neff<ref n="66" target="hanger66">[66]</ref> Rollins 
Moody<ref n="67" target="hanger67">[67]</ref> Press 
Davidson<ref n="68" target="hanger68">[68]</ref> Miller. 
Northern<ref n="69" target="hanger69">[69]</ref>. 
Parks<ref n="70" target="hanger70">[70]</ref>. 
Rahle [Reilly].  Wallace Ruff 
<ref n="71" target="hanger71">[71]</ref>. In the Artillery (Rockbridge) None killed,  
wounded, Jack Jordan<ref n="72" target="hanger72">[72]</ref>,  
Brockenbrough<ref n="73" target="hanger73">[73]</ref>, and 
Singleton<ref n="74" target="hanger74">[74]</ref></p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-22" id="d44"> 
<head>July 22nd Monday</head> 
<p>It is now raining very hard, and has been all night. the wounded on the battle 
field must have suffered greatly last night. It is a very muddy and disagreeable 
day. A great many more forces came to the Junction today I went to the battle 
feild to help bury the dead the Awfulls scene I evir witnessed In my life 
hundreds of dead &amp; wounded on the feild yet the yankees sent in a flag of truce 
and got some of thier wounded.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-23" id="d45"> 
<head>July 23rd Tuesday</head> 
<p>The sun came out beautifully to day It is very pleasant today. The Artillery 
brought in the Captured Cannon &amp;c today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-24" id="d46"> 
<head>July 24th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Nothing of importance going on today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-25" id="d47"> 
<head>July 25th Thursday</head> 
<p>Fine morning very pleasant.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-26" id="d48"> 
<head>July 26th Friday</head> 
<p>All has bin quiet to day.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-27" id="d49"> 
<head>July 27th Saturday</head> 
<p>Cloudy today I think we will have rain shortly. 4 o'clock. we were ordered to 
pack up &amp;c. 5 o'clock. we have moved our brigade Camp. about 1/2 mile towards the 
battle field. near an old house. we have gotten our tents again 
McCampbell came 
back to our Co. again from being detailed with the Artillery.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-28" id="d50"> 
<head>July 28th Sunday</head> 
<p>Foggy this morning. This day was appointed by the Confederate Congress as a 
general Thanksgiving day. No duty to day except guard duty, lO.o'clock the sun 
came out beautifully this morning. 4 o clock it is very cloudy now and 
thundering very hard we will have a shower shortly. 6 o'clock we had a great 
storm. It thundered and lightened in a hurry. We kept dry though in our tents, 
we had dinner and supper together today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-29" id="d51"> 
<head>July 29th Monday</head> 
<p>Drill at 7.A.M. It is raining a little Co. drill at 10 o'clock. We had a 
considerable shower about 8 this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-30" id="d52"> 
<head>July 30th Tuesday</head> 
<p>None of us got breakfast in time to drill this morning. We drilled at 10 It is 
very warm to day. 2 Rifledcannon and 2 Caisons passed here just now for the 
Rockbridge Artillery.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-07-31" id="d53"> 
<head>July 31st Wednesday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. I think it will be very warm to day. we had no breakfast at our 
Company. This morning Some of them eat this morning's bread last night, We 
were put into Messes this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-08" id="d54"> 
<head>August 1861
 <!-- <ref>Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-01" id="d55"> 
<head>August 1st Thursday</head> 
<p>It is raining very hard and has been all morning. It looks like it would rain 
all day. We will have no duty to attend to today 3 o'clock we are ordered to 
cook every thing and be ready to march at 5 o'clock in the morning. 
Turpin<ref n="75" target="hanger75">[75]</ref> came 
here today, and he intends, going home tomorrow to stay.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-02" id="d56"> 
<head>August 2nd Friday</head> 
<p>Got up early this morning, packed blankets &amp;C. struck tents and got ready to 
move. We came on to Centreville and camped about 1 mile from the town towards 
Fairfax C.H. (Camp Harman) This the camp in which the Yankees camped before 
the battle of the 21st July, Their old brush tents and still here. we have very 
good water here though a great distance to carry it.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-03" id="d57"> 
<head>Aug. 3rd Saturday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. Lieut Paxton came back from Lexington last night he brought 3 
new recruits with him, and Seal<ref n="76" target="hanger76">[76]</ref>. Adams<ref n="77"
target="hanger77">[77]</ref>. Champ<ref n="78" target="hanger78">[78]</ref>. James 
Smith<ref n="79" target="hanger79">[79]</ref>. Radford<ref n="80"
target="hanger80">[80]</ref>We had Dress perade at 5 o'clock.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-04" id="d58"> 
<head>Aug. 4th Sunday</head> 
<p>This will be a warm day I think Had Dress perade at 5. It was read out that 
the Rockbridge Rifle Co. was transferred to the 27th Regt Our Company didn't 
go to Dress perade. This is great dissatisfaction in the Co. [over the 
transfer].</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-05" id="d59"> 
<head>Aug. 5th Monday</head> 
<p>A fine. though very warm day. We have struck our tents, and packed our baggage. 
We are going to move over to the 27th Regt. 11. O'clock we have moved over and 
have pitched our tents, and are now clearing away the brush &amp;c and 
burning it.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-06" id="d60"> 
<head>Aug 6th Tuesday</head> 
<p>Fine morning, had drill this morning Capt Letcher is now acting Colonel of 27th 
He does capitally.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-07" id="d61"> 
<head>Aug. 7th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Warm day. had drills as usual today.  
Nothing of importance going on today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-08" id="d62"> 
<head>8th Thursday</head> 
<p>Warm day. Had drills at 7 and 10 this morning. Lieut 
Paxton is on special duty at Headquarters.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-09" id="d63"> 
<head>Aug. 9th Friday</head> 
<p>It is a cloudy morning. It looks like rain, They are paying off the 5th Regt 
today. At battallion drill they make two Co"s of ours. We are ordered to be in 
readiness to move without baggage At 10. o'clock. Prince Louis Napoleion passed 
here yesterday He is now at Centreville We are going to Centreville to pass 
review before him. We went to town and passed the review, It was a great 
Military display certain. We had a great thunderstorm this eve". there was no 5 
o'clock drill</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-10" id="d64"> 
<head>Aug. 10th Saturday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. It was very foggy this morn but the sun came out and it is now 
very warm. We received our pay this morning, we got $42.00. It is clouding up 
again. I think we will have more rain. We had no drill this eve. but Dress 
perade.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-11" id="d65"> 
<head>Aug. 11th Sunday</head> 
<p>The sun came out beautifully this morning. but now (7 o'clock) it is getting 
cloudy. We had a great shower last night it drove several of our boys out of 
their tents</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-12" id="d66"> 
<head>Aug. 12th Monday</head> 
<p>This is a damp morning, still cloudy Lieut Edmondson 
<ref n="81" target="hanger81">[81]</ref> (now acting Capt) got 2 
more tents for some of our men this morning. Nothing going on to 
day</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-13" id="d67"> 
<head>Aug. 13th Tuesday</head> 
<p>we had a considerable rain this morning about 7 o'clock. It is still cloudy, 
though the sun comes out occasionally. It is windy and cool this 
evening. Chas Rollins came back last night. We drew rations of Potatoes 
today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-14" id="d68"> 
<head>Aug 14th Wednesday</head> 
<p>It is cloudy and cold this morning Loker 
<ref n="82" target="hanger82">[82]</ref> came here today, he looks very well. 
We heard cannonading towards Leesburg, and Fairfax C. H. this morning 
Jim Holley <ref n="83" target="hanger83">[83]</ref> is talking of  
going home tomorrow</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-15" id="d69"> 
<head>Aug 15th Thursday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. Jim Holley hasn't gone yet. 9 o'clock Jim has now 
gone. Had drills this morning. 11 o'clock we hear cannonading in the same direction as 
before. Cloudy now.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-16" id="d70"> 
<head>Aug 16th Friday</head> 
<p>Pleasant day. S. McCampbell went to the Junction to day.  
It commenced raining about 12 o'clock today and has kept up all evening  
it is very disagreeable.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-17" id="d71"> 
<head>Aug 17th Saturday</head> 
<p>Still cloudy and windy. Mr. Thomas Deaver, got a discharge today from the Gov. 
No drill today too rainy.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-18" id="d72"> 
<head>Aug 18th Sunday</head> 
<p>we have now been in service 4 months. It is still damp and cloudy.  
There was no drill at 6. this morn. still cloudy and very disagreeable. No drills this eve 
Nothing going on to day, unusual</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-19" id="d73"> 
<head>Aug. 19th Monday</head> 
<p>We had a very hard rain last night. We have no drills this bad weather. It is 
very muddy. and disagreeable weather, too muddy for drilling purposes 
&amp; </p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-20" id="d74"> 
<head>Aug. 20th Tuesday</head> 
<p>It is still cloudy and damp yet we will have more rain yet. 6 o'clock (in the 
evening). it has now cleared off beautifully. 8. o'clock this is a beautiful moonlight 
night.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-21" id="d75"> 
<head>Aug 21st Wednesday</head> 
<p>This is a fine beautiful morning perfectly clear. We didn't have any drill 
before. breakfast. I suppose it was on account of being too muddy. We had drill 
at 10. o'clock. The Staunton Band <ref n="84" target="hanger84">[84]</ref>  
is here now. These are beautiful moonlight night now</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-22" id="d76"> 
<head>Aug 22nd Thursday</head> 
<p>we had a little rain this morining still windy and cloudy. 
Wallace Ruff came back last night The sun comes out occasionally but goes back again. 
Our Quartermaster  [Sgt. Henry T.] (Campbell) had to draw Crackers,  
we also drew potatoes again</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-23" id="d77"> 
<head>Aug 23rd Friday</head> 
<p>We got orders last night about 9 o'clock. to fall in with guns and 
accoutrements. we did so. our guns were inspected, and the No. of Cartridges 
taken. it then commenced to rain, and we were ordered to disperse, &amp;c. We got 
orders, to day to put our guns in order &amp; c. We got orders to fall in, and leave 
every thing but our Canteens Haversack &amp;c. behind. the sick were left to cook. 
and sent it on. Our Brigade then formed, and marched to Fairfax C. H. We got 
here about 7. We went a little yon side of the town We were halted we were 
then ordered to march back, All the force about C. H. has moved farther down 
towards Alexandria. They had a little skirmish below there, they drove the 
Yankees back a piece. When we got back  Jim Holley  had come with boxes Ac for 
our Co.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-24" id="d78"> 
<head>Aug 24th Saturday</head> 
<p>This is a fine clear morning, though windy and cool.  Jim Holley 
 brought a great many boxes with him. One for me also We had a fine time last night 
eating &amp;c.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-25" id="d79"> 
<head>Aug. 25th Sunday</head> 
<p>Fine day. We are ordered out again today. We formed, marched down about 2 miles 
towards Fairfax C. H. about face and marched back again</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-26" id="d80"> 
<head>Aug. 26th Monday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. We had Co drill at 10. o'clock. and battallion drill at 5 It was 
read out at Dress perade that  Lieut Edmondson  was appointed Adjutant of 27th 
Regt. and that there was to be a regular price paid for things brought there by 
hucksters for sale. It was also read out that we should have Reveille at 5. A.M. 
breakfast at 7. sick call at <unclear></unclear> o'clock. We have 4 drills a day.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-27" id="d81"> 
<head>Aug. 27th Tuesday</head> 
<p>Cloudy today. We had a little mist or rain several times today. We drilled 3 
times today. We had no battallion drill on account of rain.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-28" id="d82"> 
<head>Aug 28th Wednesday</head> 
<p>we were ordered this morning at 5 to pack up, get breakfast and be ready to 
march as soon as possible. Cloudy morning. 9 o'clock are now about 1/2 mile from 
C.H. resting and waiting for orders We heard that the Picquets had a little 
skirmish with the Yankees yesterday, below C.H. Killed 4 Yankees and took 8 
prisoners. Our men drove them from a hill there. (Nason's) and took possession 
of it. Washington City, and Alexandria can be seen from it after resting and 
waiting here near CH for about 2 hours. We were ordered to about face and 
return to our camp again. It has been raining almost the whole day.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-29" id="d83"> 
<head>Aug. 29th Thursday</head> 
<p>Still raining, and I think will continue all day. We have orders to draw and 
cook 1 days rations and have our Canteens filled with water. 1 o clock we have 
not yet gotten any further orders. 3 o'clock it has now stoped raining and 
cleared off a little. 7 o'clock no orders yet.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-30" id="d84"> 
<head>Aug. 30th Friday</head> 
<p>Fine morning, the sun came out beautifully. We got orders to clean up our 
quarters for Inspection. We had no dress perade to day</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-31" id="d85"> 
<head>Aug. 31st Saturday</head> 
<p>A clear and beautifuly morning we were ordered this morning to pack every thing 
portable up put on our knapsacks Ac. we were then formed, marched out in the 
field for Inspection and Muster roll, call, we then went to our quarters, and 
after dinner, got orders to pack every thing up, and strike tents. We then moved 
out of the woods into the field, pitched tents &amp;c. we are now fixed up again</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-09" id="d86"> 
<head>September 1861
 <!-- <ref>Battle Description, Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-01" id="d87"> 
<head>Sept 1st Sunday</head>  
<p>Fine morning, though a little cloudy and cool Ordered to fall in with 
knapsacks, guns &amp;c for inspection. We have had no drills yet, we had dress 
perade.Jim Holley goes home again tomorrow</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-02" id="d88"> 
<head>Sept 2nd Monday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. Jim hasn't gone, 12 o'clock he will go to the Junction this eve 
We had battalion drill at 8. Co. drill from 11. to 12. It is very warm to day. 
The Officers are all making off their pay rolls.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-03" id="d89"> 
<head>Sept 3rd Tuesday</head> 
<p>Pleasant morning very warm to day. Our Company got permission from Capt 
Letcher to go to the Creek and take a bath &amp;c. We didn't have any drill until 5 
3 o'clock. Lynch, <ref n="85" target="hanger85">[85]</ref> who left us 
at Winchester, came here today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-04" id="d90"> 
<head>Sept 4th Wednesday</head> 
<p>It rained a little, though very little this morning, early. But the sun came out 
and it is now very pleasant. I am beginning to think that we will have some 
creapers in camp shortly. We had no drill at 2 battallion drill and dress 
perade at 5. We have Tatoo at 8 1/2 o'clock. and Taps at 9. o'c. The drum is 
beating Tatoo now.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-05" id="d91"> 
<head>Sept. 5th Thursday</head> 
<p>We had a considerable shower last night. about 2 o'clock. 7 o'clock It is very 
cool, cloudy, and windy. I think we will have more rain to day. 8 o'clock we 
were ordered to fall in for battalion drill, we marched out to the field, Maj 
Grigsby <ref n="86" target="hanger86">[86]</ref>, then ordered us to break for our quarters, 
it was raining too hard 10. O'clock, no drill still raining, very muddy and 
disagreeable.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-06" id="d92"> 
<head>Sept. 6th Friday</head> 
<p>Very foggy this morning. I think it will clear off today. we had our usual 
drills. Col Massie <ref n="87" target="hanger87">[87]</ref> has gotten back. he was at our 
quarters this eve Northern has also gotten back. also</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-07" id="d93"> 
<head>Sept. 7th Saturday</head> 
<p>Very foggy this morning. we were ordered to strike tents, and let our baggage 
&amp;c dry and air. At 10 o'clock Lieut Lewis marched us down to the spring and 
back. that was all the drilling we had then. We have now to clean our guns for 
inspection tomorrow.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-08" id="d94"> 
<head>Sept. 8th Sunday</head> 
<p>Fine morning though cool and windy. Head inspection this morning. Mrs Gen 
Jackson <ref n="88" target="hanger88">[88]</ref> came here today. Bishop Johns <ref n="89"
target="hanger89">[89]</ref> preached at Headquarters 
this eve". Had dress perade as usual</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-09" id="d95"> 
<head>Sept. 9th Monday</head> 
<p>We heard that Jim Holley had gotten to the Junction yesterday. 
Tuck Thomas <ref n="90" target="hanger90">[90]</ref> and Crawford <ref n="91"
target="hanger91">[91]</ref> went up to help him down with the boxes Ac. The Sergt. 
is calling for us to fall in for battallion drill Jim came this eve with the boxes &amp;c.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-10" id="d96"> 
<head>Sept. 10th Tuesday</head> 
<p>We got permission to take another wash. A beautiful morning. we will have no 
duty to perform until 5.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-11" id="d97"> 
<head>Sept. 11th Wednesday</head> 
<p>A very pleasant day, drills as usual to day. Gordan <ref n="92"
target="hanger92">[92]</ref> &amp; McCampbell got permission to go to Centreville to day. 
It commenced raining very hard about 3 o'clock this evening. It rained as hard as I ever 
saw it.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-12" id="d98"> 
<head>Sept. 12th Thursday</head> 
<p>It was too muddy for drill at 8. we had the other drills though. It is a very 
fine day overhead. Nothing unusual going on today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-13" id="d99"> 
<head>Sept. 13th Friday</head> 
<p>It is very warm to day. We went out on battallion drill, and Just made a "right 
wheel by Companies" and then a left in to line wheel. Capt Letcher then gave us orders to 
appear on perade at 10 1/2, for review. we were then marched to our respective camps. 
Genls Johnston. and Jackson reviewed us we were out about 1% hours we all had a very 
pleasant time last night. It was a beautiful moonlight night</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-14" id="d100"> 
<head>Sept. 14th Saturday</head> 
<p>A beautiful day, warm, and, pleasant..We got orders just now to strike tents and 
let our blankets &amp;c, air and dry. We had no drills to day. Capt Letcher went up 
to the Junction to day. This is a beautiful moonlight night. clear. and mellow 
like.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-15" id="d101"> 
<head>Sept. 15th Sunday</head> 
<p>Very warm and pleasant morning, We had review as usual at 8. o'clock Dress 
perade at 6 1/2 o'clock. We got orders to pack every thing up &amp;c. and be ready to 
move by 8 o'clock in morning We are going towards Fairfax C.H. We are going to 
move our Camp there. Mr Norgrove <ref n="93" target="hanger93">[93]</ref> came here this 
evening</p> 
</div3> 
     
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-16" id="d102"> 
<head>Sept. 16th Monday</head> 
<p>It is a little cool and cloudy, though a capital day for travelling we are 
fixing up our things now and getting ready to march. At 8 we all fell in and 
moved off as wer came on, we heard tremondous cannonading in direction of C.H. 
we came on within 2 miles of C.H. and turned in to the right about a mile. we 
are here halted to camp we are about 1 mile from CH. and not far from Fairfax 
Station. The Station is now our Post Office. We are camped here on a high hill. 
a very bad place for water. Worse than Camp "Harman". Jim Holley 
is talking of going home again. he is talking of not coming back again.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<milestone unit="section" n="Camp Fairfax"/> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-17" id="d103"> 
<head>Sept. 17th Tuesday</head> 
<p>Very foggy this morning. Jim Holly started home this morning. We had a 
tremendous Thunderstorm this evening about 4 o'clock. The sun came out 
afterwards beautifully. The rain got in our tents and was about to wash us 
away.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-18" id="d104"> 
<head>Sept. 18th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Very foggy.this morning. we all went out and cleared off a piece of ground here 
in the woods. we had dress perade this evening (not uncommon.)</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-19" id="d105"> 
<head>Sept. l9th Thursday</head> 
<p>It is a little cloudy this morning. There was Company drill from 11 to 12. We 
had drill also from 3. to 5. and dress perade. Nothing going on to day uncommon</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-20" id="d106"> 
<head>Sept. 20th Friday</head> 
<p>Little foggy. We are getting breakfast now. we had drill from 10 to 11. and it 
was almost intolerable warm. we had as usual drill from 2. to 3</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-21" id="d107"> 
<head>Sept. 21st Saturday</head> 
<p>Pleasant day. We had battalion drill at 9 o'clock this morning. we will have no 
other drills today we have to police our quarters now. We have some great game 
of Quoits here. Capt Letcher and Lieut Lewis, take an active part in it. 6 
o'clock. It is now raining very hard.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-22" id="d108"> 
<head>Sept. 22nd Sunday</head> 
<p>Very windy, and cloudy today. The wind came near blowing our tents, we didn't 
have review this morning 4 o'clock. We now hear great Canonading. below the C.H. 
One of our Picquet was killed down below the C. H.. He was buried this evening. 
Sergt Boude <ref n="94" target="hanger94">[94]</ref> has just called for us to fall in for dress 
perade</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-23" id="d109"> 
<head>Sept. 23rd Monday</head> 
<p>Pleasant day drills as usual today. We had a little disturbance last night over 
at the Wheeling Company <ref n="95" target="hanger95">[95]</ref>. Kothing worth 
mentioning transpired today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-24" id="d110"> 
<head>Sept. 24th Tuesday</head> 
<p>One of the Lieuts in the Alaghaney Co. <ref n="96" target="hanger96">[96]</ref> who 
was taken prisoner at Manassas fight of 21st July, escaped from Washington. and got here 
safe last night. He tells 
wonderful stories of his narrow escapes &amp;c. It is a little cloudy and cool 
today. We had our usual drill today. The 4th Reg came back off Piquet this 
evening</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-25" id="d111"> 
<head>Sept. 25th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Fine day. It was very cool last night. Loker came to camp again from Hospital., 
We will have go down on Picquet tomorrow I expect, down towards Mason's and 
Kunson's Hills. Yes we have to go to morrow.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-26" id="d112"> 
<head>Sept. 26th Thursday</head> 
<p>We are now making preperations to start on Picquet. We came on through Fairfax 
C.H. and are now resting and watering at a Pump about 4 miles from C.H. Capt 
Letcher is in command so far. It is very warm travelling today. We started off 
this morning in great glee as usual. 2 o'clock we are now on Mason's Hill, We 
Can plainly see the Theological seminary near Alexandria. The river is in plain 
view. We can see 3 schooners floating beautifully on the waters oh! how 
beautiful is the view I cannot describe it. Magnificent, Picturesque. grand We can see for 
miles, away across the blue waters of the Potomac, into the 
land of the Yankee The waters lay as placid as eve. We can see the flags 
flying in the Camps of the enemy. We can see their breastworks. and 
entrenchments. &amp;c. We can see the smoke issuing from the Yankee Camps. As the 
scene is too magnificent for me to describe. Ill pass on, we soon got orders to 
go to Munson's Hill When we had gotten here, Were were again ordered to return 
to Mason's Hill. Which we did. We got there about 6 o'clock in the evening. We 
were then put on Picquet.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-27" id="d113"> 
<head>Sept. 27th Friday</head> 
<p>It commenced to rain last night about 8 o'clock. and has been raining ever 
since, It is now day break. We can hear the Yankee drums beating Reveille. We 
can occasionally hear the repeat of agun. The Picquet firing at one another. The 
Yankees drums have been beating all morning. We can plainly see the Yankees. on 
guard. They wave a white hankercheif at us. They have white flags waving. We 
can see them moving about in every direction. It is raining now very hard 
We have to keep under shelter the best way we can. we are all waiting for 
breakfast now, The Yankees keep waveing their flags, for us to meet them half 
way, to have a talk &amp;c. Laird and McCluer went and met 
2 or 3 of them. One of them said he had a brother in one of the Va Regts his name was 
Butt. When we 
were releived we went to our quarters on the hill It did rain terribly, and the 
wind blew awfully, we had to cook in all the rain and wind. 10't o'clock (night) 
we were ordered to get ready to get a way from there as quiet as possible, the 
wind blew. It was a perfect hericane. Cold ("good gracious", we marched off. and 
about 12 o'clock. (at night) got to Anadale [Annandale]. (a little village about 
a miles west of the Hill.) We here made some fires. There was the greatest 
excitement, I ever saw. the enemy was advancing it was thought, Munson's Hill was 
also evacuated great excitement prevails. All our Picquet hadn't gotten in yet 
The Wheeling Co. was left behind. It was thought they were taken prisoners, We 
remained here for orders &amp;c until 3 o'clock. the following morning.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-28" id="d114"> 
<head>Sept. 28th Saturday</head> 
<p>We (Our Company) got orders this morning about 3. o'clock, to go back to 
Mason's Hill, and see about the Wheeling Company and if they were taken prisoners to 
rescue them at the risk or cost of our lives. We went in advance 
of an other Co. We had also a battery behind us. Which Col Preston <ref n="97"
target="hanger97">[97]</ref> said should protect us. We all moved back. every person 
we met said the Yankees were at the 
Hill. and were advancing. We moved on, determined to see them out, if we died in 
the attempt. We sliped along a little piece and then would halt awhile and 
listen. Then move forward again a piece and so. on. till we got to the Hill, 
without seeing or hearing any thing of our men (Wheeling) So we concluded we 
would go down, where they were posted, the Moon was shining beautifully, and 
reflected upon our bayenets &amp;c. We sliped along cautiously We at last got to the 
post. "Merabile dictu." They were all there on their posts, and knew 
nothing of us leaving the Hill &amp;c. We got them and came on back. much rejoiced. 
It seems our Sergt Major, was afraid to go to their posts and releive them 
after the Regts left the Hill. The forces in this part of the Country are all 
falling back. towards the C.H. We, all. came on apiece towards the C.H. and 
halted about 2 miles from Anandale There we went into a field and got breakfast 
&amp;c. we will remain here all day I guess. We hear the Yankees are at Munson's 
and Mason's Hills.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-29" id="d115"> 
<head>Sept. 29th Sunday</head> 
<p>We stayed here last night. near Anadale. It is difficult to get any thing to eat 
here. Captain White's Cavalry Co. <ref n="98" target="hanger98">[98]</ref> passed here just 
now going to Anadale. The 
Yankees havn't gotten there yet. One of our men was shot last night. We hear 
wonderful stories of the Yankees advancing &amp;c we were put on Picquet, this 
evening We expect the Yankees to make their appearance every minute.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-09-30" id="d116"> 
<head>Sept. 30th Monday</head> 
<p>We were releived off Picquet, this morning by the Monroe Guards <ref n="99"
target="hanger99">[99]</ref>. The Yankees are 
still advancing slowly. 3 o'clock. they have a balloon 
<ref n="100" target="hanger100">[100]</ref> up now trying to find our 
position. We can see the balloon very plainly. It is about Falls Church we 
think. It looks beautiful. We can see the basket with two men in it. It stands 
in one place. It has again gone down. Jim Holly came back Sunday and brought 
some things for us</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1861-10" id="d117"> 
<head>October 1861
 <!-- <ref>
Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-01" id="d118"> 
<head>Oct. 1st Tuesday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. thought it was very cool last night. The balloon made its 
appearance again this morning, in the same place. We are still here near Anadale 
and about 4 miles from Fairfax C.H. It is time we were releived. We can see the 
blackest kind of smoke rising towards Mason's ... <unclear></unclear>tunson's Hills. We are all 
looking at it now. The Yankees are burning houses, and every thing as they 
come. They are now about 1 mile from Anandale. It has been very warm all 
morning. It is clouding up now 12 o'clock) We have nothing to eat here but corn 
and Potatoes. 5 o'clock. We moved down under the hill, to conceal ourselves. The 
grass is very high here. We have hard time cooking here</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-02" id="d119"> 
<head>Oct. 2nd Wednesday</head> 
<p>Very very foggy this morning. We are all getting breakfast now, Press. Davis 
[President Jefferson Davis] is at the CH., and has been for some time. I hope we 
will be releived today, so we can go back to our camp near C.H. 8 o'clock. it 
has been raining almost the whole morning Major Grigsby, gave us orders this 
morning to get dinner, and be ready to move. I think our Releif has come and we 
are going to camp at last 12 o'clock. not raining but still cloudy There is some 
talk of us going to Western Virginia. but I suppose it's all a hoax. <ref n="101"
target="hanger101">[101]</ref> We have 
great times here roasting corn. Thought it is getting most too hard. We will 
start shortly for our Camp.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-03" id="d120"> 
<head>Oct. 3rd Thursday</head> 
<p>Foggy again this morning. We started yesterday about 5 o'clock (eve) and got 
here about 6 o'clock. We came in a hurry. It has [been] very warm all day. we 
have fixed up again in our camp.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-04" id="d121"> 
<head>Oct. 4th Friday</head> 
<p>Fine morning. pleasant. John Donald and Jerry Rilley got their discharges to go 
home. they started this evening Capt Letcher is promoted to Lieut Col in some 
Regt. Our Co. wants to go with him. we have up a paper to the affect, and all 
have signed it. The Capt is going to Richmond shortly. We will have to elect a 
Capt now.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-05" id="d122"> 
<head>Oct. 5th Saturday</head> 
<p>Pleasant day. we have no flour this morning, have to draw corn meal Laird was 
sent to Greenbrier County to see about some deserters. 8 o'clock we received 
orders to pack up every thing except what we realy need put them together by 
the time the wagon comes around. They are going to send them to the Junction. 
The wagon was packed and sent off to the Station. Wright &amp; Northern were the 
guard. 5 o'clock The Sergt called to us to fall in, that Capt Letcher was going to tell us 
goodbye. Which we did, the Capt commenced at the head of the Ranks, 
and shook hands with all of us. He cried like a child. He is going to Richmond 
first I believe</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-06" id="d123"> 
<head>Oct. 6th Sunday</head> 
<p>We understand that about 30,000 of the enemy crossed the river at the mouth of 
Aquitink [Accotink] Creek. night before last, They are having a bread oven built 
at the Station, Mr Waltz <ref n="102" target="hanger102">[102]</ref> is going to bake for our 
brigade, We had inspection at 
9 this morning. Sheltmans <ref n="103" target="hanger103">[103]</ref> gun took the premium. 
thought it was hard to decide 
between his and McCouns [McCown's]. It is a little windy to day. The 4th Regt 
started again on Picquet today There was peaching [preaching] at Headquarter's 
in a barn this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-07" id="d124"> 
<head>Oct. 7th Monday</head> 
<p>Cloudy this morning, I think we will have some rain shortly. There was 
inspection this morning, Drill at 2. P.M. after drill, had an election, as 
follows.</p> 
<p> 
J. K. Edmondson - Cap't<lb/> 
 
P. C. Boude ---- 2nd Lieut<lb/> 
 
G. W. Chapin ---- 1st Sergt<lb/> 
 
A. W. Varner ---- 2n <lb/> 
 
McCampbell ------ 3rd <lb/> 
 
Campbell ------- 4th <lb/> 
 
Gordan -------- 1st Corp<lb/> 
 
Mullen -------- 2nd <lb/> 
 
Davis --------- 3rd <lb/> 
 
Rollins -------- 4th <lb/></p> 
 
<p>We had a great shower this evening, It will be very disagreeable to night.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-08" id="d125"> 
<head>Oct 8th Tuesday</head> 
<p>We had a tremondous storm last night. The guard was releived last night. Cloudy, 
and cool to day, I will be cold tonight</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-09" id="d126"> 
<head>Oct 9th Wednesday</head> 
<p>It was very cold last night, and is still so this morning. The result of our 
Election was read out on dress perade this evening, 2 o'clock still cloudy. and 
cool. Nothing of importance transpired.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-10" id="d127"> 
<head>October" 10th Thursday</head> 
<p>Cool today. Had battallion drill at 9 o'clock. 2. o'clock our Company and the 
Monroe Guards joined together and we had a battallion drill, single ranks 
formed into Companies we had a capital drill certain, 4 o'clock there is a very 
heavy mist or rain falling now. Tuck. Thomas is going to Harpers Ferry. to see 
about some clothes. which our Company left there.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-11" id="d128"> 
<head>Oct. 11th Friday</head> 
<p>Pleasant morning. though a little foggy Drill as usual at 9. It is a ldttle 
windy now. The whole brigade is out in the field now they are passing in 
review, or something. Gen Beauregard Johnston and an English Gen. are all over 
in the field reviewing</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-12" id="d129"> 
<head>Oct. 12th Saturday</head> 
<p>It commenced to rain last night about 10 o'clock. and rained all night very 
hard, We all got pretty wet. It was also very windy. The sun came out this 
morning. though it was very cold It is reported. that tomorrow is the 
appointedKfor a great battle here They got a barrel of whiskey today for us 
soldiers. I suppose they will commence giving it out in the morning.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-13" id="d130"> 
<head>Oct. 13th Sunday</head> 
<p>It is windy and cool. Campbell gave us our gigger this 
morning. Last night was a beautiful night. we had review at 9. Dr 
Pendleton preaches over at a barn near Headquarters at 4 o'clock. 
It was a very pleasant evening not withstanding the wind. We all feel lazy 
today. Had dress perade as ususal. </p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-14" id="d131"> 
<head>Oct. 14th Monday</head> 
<p>Fine pleasant morningw we had battallion drill as usual, We drill at Pendleton's 
Battery this evening at 2 o'clock. We went over went through the drill, came 
back and went on battallion drill. We went through 2 or 3 movements, when Col 
Echols <ref n="104" target="hanger104">[104]</ref> received a dispatch. We  
were then ordered in. and ordered to pack up and 
be ready to move, (on Pisquet again I suppose) about 5 o'clock. the order was 
countermanded, the order was we didn't go till morning.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-15" id="d132"> 
<head>Oct. 15th Tuesday</head> 
<p>we cooked our bread last night, we got up this morning about 3, o'clock. and 
packed up and got breakfast. We have just packed the wagon. We will start 
directly. this is a beautiful morning. We came on to the Toll gate. where we 
camped before and turned off to the right by the spring, we came on the road 
about 1 mile, from the main road, we releived the 5th Regt" 3 or 4 of the front 
Companies. went on Picquet, immediatly after we got there, As we wer3 6th Co. we 
didn't have to go first. We have Capital water here, and a creek running along 
by our camp. we have made brush huts, Our Mess has finished our hut. ("Cabin 
home"). We heard considerable firing down about Anandale this morning. 
McCampbell Hartigan. S.A. Gordan and myself concluded we would go over to the 
Turnip patch. We got some Turnips &amp;c as as we came back. we stoped at a 
beautiful spring. there a while, and talked about things generally, Sandy and 
myself went up to the house near there and tryed to get some brandy. but it 
wouldn't go. We had a very pleasant time there at the Spring</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-16" id="d133"> 
<head>Oct. 16th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Got orders this morning. to draw off Picquet get breakfast as early as 
possible. and be ready to move back. We started and Came over to the 
"Braddock Road" came on about 3 or 4 miles. Col Echols here 
received a dispatch. to send back 4 companies, to Aquitinck Creek. (A 
creek where we came into the Braddock Road) Consequently. The Wheeling 
Co., our Co., Aleghany Co. and Greenbrier Co. 
<ref n="105" target="hanger105">[105]</ref> had to about face and come back. We came 
back to the Creek. There are breastworks all along the creek. it's well 
fortifyed, We (Our Co) was put behind these breastworks. some of the other 
Companies have gone further on Our guns are all loadened Maj 
Grigsby is in Command of us. We are concealing ourselves behind the 
breastworks, we are in the entrenchments. It is cloudy today, I think it 
well rain before night. All our blankets &amp;c are back in the wagons All our 
Picquet have been drawn in all around about this part of the Country, Some 
of our men were sent back to camp near C H. to take down tents and move 
things generally. </p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-17" id="d134"> 
<head>Oct. 17th Tuesday</head> 
<p>We got orders yesterday evening (after we had fixed for the night) to go back 
and Join the rest of the Command. it was Just getting dark. We came on to  
where 
we had left the Regt. but they had moved on about 1 mile. Supper was ready for 
us when we got there. We ate supper, and immediately moved on again to within 2 
or 3 miles of Centreville. When we go orders to go back about 1 mile, to a 
small creek, we came on back, and, our Company and 1 or 2 others had to go on 
Picquet. It was very dark. and we were almost broken down. We were certainly 
tired. We were releived this morning at 12 We came to Camp at Creek. fixed up 
to start again on another tramp We are now packing the wagon now we 
understand that our troops are burning us all the public buildings about the 
Station [Fairfax Station]. and elsewhere. Most all of our forces have fallen 
back to Centreville. It is now rainings we started to go towards Centreville. 
met the 3rd Alabama Regt it releived us here. We got orders immediately to go 
over to the Turnpike (main road to C.H.). we were ordered to keep perfectly 
quiet. We started. and it commenced to rain very hard, we had and awful time., 
it was so dark we could almost cut it with an knife we came out in the main 
road about 2 1/2 miles below Centreville, and came on the road towards the C.H. 
about 1 mile we stoped on a hill here It rained on us all the time. after we 
got some large fires built, we didn't get much sleep, too wet and disagreeable 
We got plenty to eat though. disagreeable disagreeable.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-18" id="d135"> 
<head>Oct. 18th Friday</head> 
<p>Still cloudy. We have got marching orders again. We marched to the left of the 
hill about 2 mile. here we were halted. We sat here till about 4 o'clock this 
evening. We then came to about face. Came back about 1 mile, halted in the 
woods. Col rode in a field near. and ordered the Capts of each Company to come 
too. When they came back. they ordered us all to stack arms, take of[f] 
accoutrements &amp;c we then marched out in the field on the hill, and went to 
making a breastwork out of rails &amp;c. when we came back we were ordered to go 
to cooking every thing we had, and then to pack up every thing, and be ready 
for action at any moment. to sleep in rear of our guns. 6 o'clock P.M. It has 
cleared off now.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-19" id="d136"> 
<head>Oct. l9th Saturday</head> 
<p>Very foggy this morning. we were not disturbed last night. we have had nothing 
to do to day. we had a little rain about 2 this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-20" id="d137"> 
<head>Oct. 20th Sunday</head> 
<p>Windy to day. Our Company has orders to go on Picquet today, 10. o'clock. we are 
now on Picquet, in the Alexandria and Winchester Road Leesburg road &amp;c. We hear 
heavy firing out to the right of us, The Countersign is = Inkerman, We have the 
same old signal. Halt any one, throw up the left arm, he whom you halt must 
then take off his hat or cap. and pass it down below his face. If he fails to 
do this "Fire". this is the day signal.) The night signal is the sentinel strikes 
his leg 2 or three times with his hand. the person whom he halts. has to cough 
2 or 3 times or clear his throat, if he fails to do this. "Fire" at him. We were 
releived about 11. o'clock today. We came on to Centreville, we got here about 3 
o'clock P.M. Joe Neff. Kahle <ref n="106" target="hanger106">[106]</ref>. and H. Smith 
<ref n="107" target="hanger107">[107]</ref> were here Bill Kahle gave us a treat 
this evening. Our forces are fortifying here in a hurry.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-21" id="d138"> 
<head>Oct. 21st Monday</head> 
<p>Cloudy and a little windy. Our Messes were rearranged yesterday. The 
noncommissioned officers are heads of the different messes now. we had nothing 
but dress perade today</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-22" id="d139"> 
<head>Oct. 22nd Tuesday</head> 
<p>Raining this morning. very disagreeable We have a hard time cooking in the 
rain. It rained all day. we had no duty to day. except Retreat</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-23" id="d140"> 
<head>Oct. 23rd Wednesday</head> 
<p>Cold, very, this morning. the wind blows very hard. Had dress perade at 5 
o'clock. Grisby is now elected Lieut Col. and Paxton is appointed Major of 27th 
Regt. (ours)K</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-24" id="d141"> 
<head>Oct. 24th Thursday</head> 
<p>Cold morning. Had an election for 2nd and 1st Lieuts. consequent of Paxtons 
promotion. Boude was Elected 1st Lieut Chapin 2nd Gillock <ref n="108"
target="hanger108">[108]</ref> 4th Sergt in 
Campbell's place (resigned)Northern, Orderly [lst Sergeant]. Had Company drill 
at 3.P.M.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-25" id="d142"> 
<head>Oct. 25th Friday</head> 
<p>This was a beautiful morning early. but now. 10 o'clock, it looks like snow. 
Chas. Cizer <ref n="109" target="hanger109">[109]</ref> came back yesterday from Hospital 
Dr Graham <ref n="110" target="hanger110">[110]</ref> (old man) was at our 
camp to day</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-26" id="d143"> 
<head>Oct. 26th Saturday</head> 
<p>The sun came out beautifully this morning but now (9 o'clock) it is very cloudy. 
looks very much like rain. Rev. Dr. White <ref n="111" target="hanger111">[111]</ref>. came 
to this camp to day. The Co. is 
out on battallion drill now. We have just got orders to strike tents to dry our 
baggade &amp;c There are several Good Bands near us here, they play beautifully. 
Nothing new</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-27" id="d144"> 
<head>Oct. 27th Sunday</head> 
<p>Fine cool windy morning. Dr. White preached at our Col's tent at 10. after 
preaching . Gordan McCampbell and myself took a walk up the road a piece. got 
some persimmons &amp;c when we got back Jim Holly had gotten back from Lex. with 
George Johnston <ref n="112" target="hanger112">[112]</ref>. Dr White preached at 4th Regt 
this evening.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-28" id="d145"> 
<head>Oct. 28th Monday</head> 
<p>Awful cold to day. Drills as usual. Have to clean up quarters today. Nothing new 
today.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-29" id="d146"> 
<head>Oct. 29th Tuesday</head> 
<p>We got orders to strike tents today to air the ground, dry cloths &amp;c. Drills as 
usual nothing new.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-30" id="d147"> 
<head>Oct. 30th Wednesday</head> 
<p>Gov. Letcher <ref n="113" target="hanger113">[113]</ref> came here today. 
It is very pleasant. though a little windy we had 
review to day. The Gov" brought some flags with him. which he is going to 
present to the Va Regts this evening <unclear></unclear> o'clock we had a grand presentation 
this eve. The Gov presented flags to all the Va Regts</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
</div1> 
</body> 
 
<back id="d148"> 
 
<div1 id="AD1001conc" type="conclusion"> 
<head>Conclusion
<!-- <ref>AD1001conc</ref> -->
</head> 
<p>Hanger's diary ends abruptly here. The remaining pages have been torn out of 
his small notebook, and may have continued the diary. Hanger was wounded at 
Gaines Mill on June 27, 1862. In March of 1863 he transferred to Company C, 5th 
Virginia Infantry, an Augusta County unit, the "Mountain Rifles". He was wounded 
in the head and leg at Chancellorsville in May of 1863. While on leave he 
married Naomi Francis McCormick in Lexington on March 12-, 1864. Hanger returned 
to duty and was captured with most of his regiment at Spotsylvania Court House 
in May, 1864. He was fortunate enough to be exchanged in November of the same 
year. During December of 1864 he deserted to the Union forces at Clarksburg, 
West Virginia. Hanger took the oath of allegiance and was released. a ther his 
bride accompanied hiS is unknown. His wife is believed to have died early in 
life and he remarried in Fayetteville, Arkansas. Hanger later moved to Dayton, 
Columbia County, Washington. He died there on May 16, 1918 and is buried in the 
Dayton City cemetery.</p> 
</div1> 
 
<div1 id="AD1001note" type="notes"> 
<head>Notes 
<!-- <ref>AD1001note</ref> -->
</head> 
 <note place="end" n="1" id="hanger1"><seg type="note-symbol">{1}</seg><p> F. C. Tebbs, a Methodist Minister in Lexington.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="2" id="hanger2"><seg type="note-symbol">{2}</seg><p> Francis McFarland, the minister at Bethel Presbyterian Church in 
Augusta County.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="3" id="hanger3"><seg type="note-symbol">{3}</seg><p> Elisha Franklin Paxton (1823-5/3/63). A Rockbridge native and 
a graduate of Washington College, Yale and the University of Virginia Law School. He 
was a lawyer, farmer and President of the Bank of Rockbridge. He was the 1st 
Lieutenant of the company when they left Lexington. He was commended at Bull 
Run for gallantry on the field, in bearing the colors of a Georgia regiment, 
whose standard bearer had been shot down "...advanced before the regiment, 
waving his hat, was the first to plant our banner upon their battery." In 
August Paxton served as Aide de-camp to General "Stonewall" Jackson. In 
August, 1862 he was appoint Major and Quartermaster on Jackson's staff, 
although his duties involved those of the Assistant Adjutant General. With 
Jackson's urging he was promoted to Rrigadier General on 1 November, 1862 
and placed in command of the "Stonewall Brigade." Paxton was killed at 
Chancellorsville on 3 May, 1863 at the head of the "Stonewall Brigade," 
leading a charge.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="4" id="hanger4"><seg type="note-symbol">{4}</seg><p> Probably James E. McCormick (1819-1893), a farmer who 
resided near Fairfield.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="5" id="hanger5"><seg type="note-symbol">{5}</seg><p> Andrew Wallace Varner (1831-l910). A Lexington native and a 
carpenter and cabinetmaker. He was elected 2nd Lieutenant of the Rifles in April, 1862. 
Varner was shot through the leg and lost an arm at Gettysburg on 7 July, 
1863. Taken prisoner, he remained in Federal prisons until the end of the 
war, despite the loss of his arm. Varner returned to Lexington and worked as 
a coachmaker, undertaker and furniture manufacturer with his brother, 
Charles Van Buren Varner (1838-1907) who also served in the company.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="6" id="hanger6"><seg type="note-symbol">{6}</seg><p> Joseph H. R. Marston (circa 1841- ) A native of Maryland, 
Marston was working as a clerk in a Lexington business when the war began. He was 
later-captured at Gettysburg. After 13 months in prison Marston took the oath of 
allegiance and was released in January, 1855. He listed his residence as 
Baltimore, Md.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="7" id="hanger7"><seg type="note-symbol">{7}</seg><p> John William Middleton (1835-1907). Mildleton was born in 
Harrisonburg and was listed as a "Gentleman", residing in Lexington when he enlisted. He 
was wounded in the elbow and captured at Gettysburg and sat out the rest of 
the war in prison. Middleton returned to Rockbridge and farmed in the Kerr's 
Creek area. later in life he moved to Tennessee.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="8" id="hanger8"><seg type="note-symbol">{8}</seg><p> Dr. Alfred J. Hamilton (1830-1865). He resided at Midway, on 
the border of Rockbridge and Augusta counties, as he is listed in both counties on the 
1860 census. Hamilton served as a Surgeon in the Confederate army. He died 
soon after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="9" id="hanger9"><seg type="note-symbol">{9}</seg><p> Asbury C. McClure (1840-1861). A native of Fauquier County, 
he was a 21 year old carpenter when he enlisted. Killed at Bull Run 21 July, 1861. "fell 
in th first charge made by the Regiment, shot through the breast... ."</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="10" id="hanger10"><seg type="note-symbol">{10}</seg><p> William Piper Hartigan (1837-1902). A Lexington native and a 
cabinetmaker, Hartigan enlisted in the 1st Rockbridge Dragoons the same day 
the Rifles were enrolled. He was captured on the retreat from Gettysburg and 
spent most of the next two years in prison. Hartigan returned to Lexington, 
where he worked aB a mechanic and cabinetmaker. His brother, John Wesley 
Hartigan (1835-1863) was a member of the Rifles at this time. His other 
brothers James A. (1875-1863), Robert M. (1848-1927) and Walter Dougas 
Hartigan (1843-1895), later served in the company.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="11" id="hanger11"><seg type="note-symbol">{11}</seg><p>Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="12" id="hanger12"><seg type="note-symbol">{12}</seg><p> Lieutenant John F. Stafford (1827-1867), was a Staunton 
merchant who had enlisted in the "Staunton Rifles", Company G, 5th Virginia 
Infantry.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="13" id="hanger13"><seg type="note-symbol">{13}</seg><p>Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="14" id="hanger14"><seg type="note-symbol">{14}</seg><p> Daniel McGuire Reilly (1840-1916) An Irishman who was a 
jeweler and silversmith in Lesington. He survived the war and returned to his trade in 
Lexington until his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="15" id="hanger15"><seg type="note-symbol">{15}</seg><p> John S. Edmondson (1842-1861). Another Lexington 
carpenter, he died of diptheria in Lexington on 29 August. 1861 age 19 years and 2 
months.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="16" id="hanger16"><seg type="note-symbol">{16}</seg><p> The 1st Rockbridge Dragoons, under Captain Mathew X. 
White, Jr., had been sworn in and departed Lexington the same day as the Rifles. This 
company had been organized as part of the militia at Fancy Hill in 1859. 
They became Company C. 1st Virginia Cavalry under J. E. B. Stuart.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="17" id="hanger17"><seg type="note-symbol">{17}</seg><p> John B. Hanger (1836-1861) A farmer in Augusta County in 
1860, he had apparently moved to Rockbridge. Hanger was wounded in the foot at Bull 
Run on 21 3uly, 1861. He died from hls wound and diptheria on 9 September, 
1861.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="18" id="hanger18"><seg type="note-symbol">{18}</seg><p> George Washington Bailey, Jr. (lS39-1901). A carpenter 
working in his native county of Rockbridge, Bailey served throughout the war, 
surrendering at Appomattox Court House on 9 April, 1865. He moved to Sherando in 
Augusta County after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="19" id="hanger19"><seg type="note-symbol">{19}</seg><p> Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="20" id="hanger20"><seg type="note-symbol">{20}</seg><p> George W. Effinger (1822-1892), a Harrisonburg 
merchant.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="21" id="hanger21"><seg type="note-symbol">{21}</seg><p> Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="22" id="hanger22"><seg type="note-symbol">{22}</seg><p> Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="23" id="hanger23"><seg type="note-symbol">{23}</seg><p>Jacob H. Fonshill (1836- ). A 25 year old saddler when he 
enlisted in Lexington, he was ordered discharged by the Secretary of War on 15 December, 
1861, presumably to resume his occupation.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="24" id="hanger24"><seg type="note-symbol">{24}</seg><p>Before departing the company was presented a flag by the ladies 
of Harrisonburg.  Robert H. Campbell described the banner as  
representing the "Confederate States, with a star for Virginia in the 
center."</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="25" id="hanger25"><seg type="note-symbol">{25}</seg><p> Alfred B. Tanquary (1823-1883). He was a tinner in Lexington 
and a native of Frederick County. Tanquary was discharged for disease of the heart 
in December, 1861. He served as a member of the Lexington Patrol and 
manufactured wool in Lexington during the war. After the war he turned to 
making tobacco and then was a merchant in Lexington.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="26" id="hanger26"><seg type="note-symbol">{26}</seg><p> General Joseph E. Johnston (1807-1891) For some reason 
Hanger refers to him as "Colonel."</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="27" id="hanger27"><seg type="note-symbol">{27}</seg><p> Here Hanger failed to write in his diary for a considerable 
period and later brought it up to date about June 23rd.  For some reason his 
spelling became much improved</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="28" id="hanger28"><seg type="note-symbol">{28}</seg><p> Captain William Nelson Pendleton of the 1st Rockbridge 
Artillery (1809-1883). A West Point graduate, he became a teacher and then an Episcopal 
minister after a brief military career. He was the pastor of Grace Episcopal 
Church in Lexington when the war began. Pendleton often preached to his 
company, and his sermons always drew crowds of soldiers from other units. He 
was promoted Colonel and Chief of Artillery under Joseph E. Johnston on 19 
July, 1861, but commanded the Rockbridge Artillery at Bull Run. He was later 
promoted Brigadier General and commanded the artillery of the Army of 
Northern Virginia. Pendleton returned to Lexington after the war. He was often mistaken 
for Robert E. Lee.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="29" id="hanger29"><seg type="note-symbol">{29}</seg><p> Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="30" id="hanger30"><seg type="note-symbol">{30}</seg><p> Unidentified.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="31" id="hanger31"><seg type="note-symbol">{31}</seg><p> David Edward Laird (1832-18'30). A Rockbridge native and a 
graduate of Washington College, Laird was teaching in Atlanta, Georgia when the war 
began. He hurried home and enlisted on April 28, 1861. Laird transferred to 
the 1st Rockbridge Dragoons in 1862 because of leg problems. He farmed at 
Riverside after the war and taught school in Lexington and Fancy Hill until 
his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="32" id="hanger32"><seg type="note-symbol">{32}</seg><p> Edward Nicholas Boogher (1831-1923). He moved from 
Frederick County, Maryland to Lexington in 1850 and was clerking in a local firm when 
the war began. He apparently only served a short time, as he is not listed on the 
muster rolls until 1862. In March, 1867, he was exempt because of his work 
in a foundry and again in 1864 as a manufacturer of iron utensils and 
detailed to make shells at Vesuvius. Boogher reenlisted or was conscripted 
back into the Rifles by October, 1864, as he was issued clothing in November 
and December, 1864. He returned to Lexington after the war and was a 
successful carpenter and builder.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="33" id="hanger33"><seg type="note-symbol">{33}</seg><p> The West Augusta Guard was organized in Staunton on April 
17, 1861, as Company L, 5th Virginia Infantry, under Captain James Hurley Waters 
(1828-1913). In November, 1861 the unit was converted to artillery. The West 
Augusta Guard continued to serve in the Virginia Militia and National Guard 
until World War II.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="34" id="hanger34"><seg type="note-symbol">{34}</seg><p> Samuel John Nelson McCampbell (1837-1909). A Rockbridge 
native who had attended Washington College, McCampbell was a dentist in Lexington 
when the war began. He was wounded in the mouth and throat at Chancellorsville and 
captured in the Valley in 1864, and spent the last months of the war in 
prison. He returned to Lexington and resumed his career as a dentist.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="35" id="hanger35"><seg type="note-symbol">{35}</seg><p> See footnote 9.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="36" id="hanger36"><seg type="note-symbol">{36}</seg><p> Robert McDowell McCown (1843-1901). A Lexington native, 
McCown was working as a saddler when he enlisted. He transferred to the 1st Rockbridge 
Dragoons in 1862 and served as a courier at Stonewall Jackson's 
headquarters. After the war he continued as a saddler and harness maker in 
Collierstown.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="37" id="hanger37"><seg type="note-symbol">{37}</seg><p> Lawrence McNamara (1843- ). He was an 18 year old laborer 
when he enlisted. He served faithfully until deserting to the enemy at Centreville 
on 1 September, 1862.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="38" id="hanger38"><seg type="note-symbol">{38}</seg><p> Arthur David McClurer (1839-1862). A Rockbridge native who 
had attended Washington College, he was farming near Lexington when he enlisted. 
tIcClurer was appointed Color Sergeant on November 20, 1861, a post of both 
honor and danger. He was mortally wounded at Malvern Hill on July 1, 1862.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="39" id="hanger39"><seg type="note-symbol">{39}</seg><p> John Merritt "Jack" Doyle (1845-1920). Although born in 
Carrolton, Green County, Illinois, he had resided in Virginia nearly all his life. He was a 
carpenter in Staunton when he enlisted. He was wounded in the neck and leg, 
and the first man in the 5th Virginia Infantry to be shot. He was again 
wounded in the leg at 2nd Manassas and detailed to gather conscipts and 
deserters in 1863. He later reenlisted in Company D, 62nd Virginia Infantry. 
He was working as a Clerk and Saleman in Greenville in 1920.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="40" id="hanger40"><seg type="note-symbol">{40}</seg><p> Robert Lewis Doyle (1812-1864). An Augusta County native, 
Doyle had attended Washington College, and was a lawyer in Staunton. He raised the 
"Mountain Guard", Company C, 5th Virgina Infantry. He was not reelected in 
1862 but was appointed Lieutenant Colonel of the 62nd Virginia Infantry in 
September, 1862. He resigned in November, 1863, because of failing health 
and to become Commonwealth's Attorney of Augusta County. He raised Company 
B, Harper's Augusta County Reserves in April, 1864. Doyle was wounded in the 
battle of Piedmont on June 5, 1864, while trying to rally his men. "His men 
placed him under a tree - shot and bayoneted after his capture." Father of 
John M. Doyle.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="41" id="hanger41"><seg type="note-symbol">{41}</seg><p> The "Continental Morgan Guards," Company K, 5th Virginia 
Infantry, were raised in Frederick County by Captain John Avis (1818-1883).</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="42" id="hanger42"><seg type="note-symbol">{42}</seg><p> The "Continental Morgan Guards," Company K, 5th Virginia 
Infantry, were raised in Frederick County by Captain John Avis (1818-1883).</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="43" id="hanger43"><seg type="note-symbol">{43}</seg><p> Brigadier General Thomas Johnathan "Stonewall" Jackson 
(1824-1863). He had been promoted on June 17, 1861 but Hanger still referred to his as 
"Colonel". The battle of Hainesville was Jackson's first combat of the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="44" id="hanger44"><seg type="note-symbol">{44}</seg><p> Lieutenant Colonel James Ewell Brown "Jeb"  
Stuart (1833-1864). He was commanding elements of the 1st Virginia Cavalry at this time. 
The "Valley 
Rangers," from Augusta County, under Captain William Patrick (1822-1862), 
with Stuart, captured most of a company from the 15th Pennslyvania Infantry.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="45" id="hanger45"><seg type="note-symbol">{45}</seg><p> Unidentifed.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="46" id="hanger46"><seg type="note-symbol">{46}</seg><p> John C. Middleton (1810-1867). A blacksmith and the Mayor 
of Lexington in 1860. The "Captain" probably refers to a militia rank.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="47" id="hanger47"><seg type="note-symbol">{47}</seg><p> Thomas Bradley Mullen (1839-1885). A native of Franklin 
County, Pennsylvania, Mullen had moved with his parents to Rockbridge County in 
1847. Like his father, he was a foundry worker. Mullen was wounded at Mine 
Run and captured at Spotslyvania Court House and spent to rest of the war in 
Ft. Delaware. Returning to Lexington, he was a foundry and machine shop 
owner and operator until his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="48" id="hanger48"><seg type="note-symbol">{48}</seg><p> Thomas Henry Deaver (1828-1906). He was shoemaker in 
Lexington who later enlisted in the company but was soon discharged by order of 
Governor Letcher to make shoes for the Confederacy. Deaver continued his occupation in 
Lexington after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="49" id="hanger49"><seg type="note-symbol">{49}</seg><p> Either Charles A. Rollins (1842- ) or his father, William H. 
Rollins (1814-1863), Charles A. Rollins was another Pennslyvanian who was a printer 
in Lexington. He served in the Rifles and was wounded at Bull Run and Mine 
Run and captured at Spotsylvania Court House. He resided in Florida after 
the war. William H. Rollings later enlisted in the "Liberty Hall Volunteers" 
and was captured at Gettysburg and died of disease at Fort Delaware.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="50" id="hanger50"><seg type="note-symbol">{50}</seg><p> Thomas Caffrey (1823- ). He was a matress maker in 
Lexington during the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="51" id="hanger51"><seg type="note-symbol">{51}</seg><p> Either William W. Lewis (1831-1890) or his father. William 
W. Lewis was native of Lexington and a merchant when the war began. He was appointed 
Adjutant of the 27th Virginia Infantry in 1862 until retiring for disability 
in 1864. He returned to Lexington after the war. Lewis later moved to West 
Virginia and then to Texas.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="52" id="hanger52"><seg type="note-symbol">{52}</seg><p> Charles W. Tanquary (1846-1863). The younger brother 
Andrew B. Tanquary of the Rifles. He died of typhoid pneumonia before his 18th 
birthday.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="53" id="hanger53"><seg type="note-symbol">{53}</seg><p> Jackson was promoted to Brigadier General on June 17, 
1861.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="54" id="hanger54"><seg type="note-symbol">{54}</seg><p> Piedmont Station on the Manassas Gap Railroad. Now Salem, 
Va.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="55" id="hanger55"><seg type="note-symbol">{55}</seg><p> General Robert Patterson who had commanded the Union 
forces in the Valley and the troops Jackson and his men had engaged at Hainesville on July 
2. 1861.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="56" id="hanger56"><seg type="note-symbol">{56}</seg><p> General P. T. G. Beauregard who commanded the Confederate 
forces around Manassas Junction.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="57" id="hanger57"><seg type="note-symbol">{57}</seg><p> Four of these guns belonged to the Rockbridge 
Artillery.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="58" id="hanger58"><seg type="note-symbol">{58}</seg><p> George W. Chapin (1844-1863). He was a 16 year old clerk in 
Lexington when he enlisted. Despite his youth he was elected Sergeant and later Second 
Lieutenant in the Rifles. He declined reelection and enlisted as a Private 
in the Liberty Hall Volunteers. He was wounded at Chancellorsville but 
returned in time Mine Run, November 27, 1863.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="59" id="hanger59"><seg type="note-symbol">{59}</seg><p> Adam W. Miller (1831- ). Miller,a carpenter by trade, enlisted 
in the company while they were in Harrisonburg. His wounds caused him to be 
discharged a few months later. He apparently reenlisted in the Rifles in 
1864. He came to Rockbridge County some time after the war and farmed in the 
Denmark area. Miller entered to Old Soldier's Home in Richmond in December, 
1898 but left after several weeks.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="60" id="hanger60"><seg type="note-symbol">{60}</seg><p> John A. Donald (1839-1894). Donald was a shoemaker in 
Lexington when reenlisted. He was discharged in October because of the need for 
shoemakers. He reenlisted in the company in 1864 and was captured in Rockbridge County 
during Hunter's raid and spent the rest of the war in Camp Chase, Ohio. He 
continued his trade in the Natural Bridge District until his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="61" id="hanger61"><seg type="note-symbol">{61}</seg><p> Captain Samuel Houston Letcher (1828-1868). Letcher was a 
Rockbridge native who had graduated was the Washington College Law School in 1850. 
He was a lawyer and newspaper editor in Lexington when the war began. Letcher 
was promoted to Lieutenant Colonel and assigned to the 58th Virginia 
Infantry. He resigned in 1862. Letcher resumed his career as a newspaper 
editor until his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="62" id="hanger62"><seg type="note-symbol">{62}</seg><p> James W. Matchett, Jr., (1840-1912). He was apparently a 
volunteer aide-de-camp on Jackson's staff. Matchett was exempt in Rockbridge County in 
March, 1862 for defective vision, which may explain why he is not listed as 
a Confederate soldier. He was a farmer in Rockbridge after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="63" id="hanger63"><seg type="note-symbol">{63}</seg><p> William G. Wright (1817-1904) One of the oldest members of 
the Rifles. Wright was born in Rockbridge County and a tailor by trade. He was 
discharged for overage after one year's service. Wright worked in the 
Clothing Department for the Confederate army in Richmond until the end of 
the war. He returned to Lexington and resumed his trade and later expanded 
his buslness to include selling sewing machines.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="64" id="hanger64"><seg type="note-symbol">{64}</seg><p> Frederick Davidson (1836-1861). A Lexington native who had 
attended Washington College and the University of Virginia. His dying request was 
that he be buried on the battlefield at the Lewis house. His last words were 
"Tell my mother I died for a glorious cause." His remains were later removed 
to Stonewall Jackson cemetery.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="65" id="hanger65"><seg type="note-symbol">{65}</seg><p> David Guthrie Bowyer (1837-1898). A native of 
Charlottesville, he had come to Lexington in the 1850's and was a painter. His skull was 
fractured, one leg was shattered and he had a wound in his right side. He was 
discharged from the hospital a few months later. He returned to Lexington 
and resumed his trade after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="66" id="hanger66"><seg type="note-symbol">{66}</seg><p> Joel L. Neff (1828-1898) Neff was working as a stonecutter in 
the county when the war began. His wounded hand kept him out of action for several 
months. He later enlisted in the cavalry, was captured during Hunter's raid 
and spent the last year of the war in Camp Chase, Ohio. After the war he 
returned to Rockbridge and resumed his trade. Neff moved to Jamestown, Ohio 
in 1888.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="67" id="hanger67"><seg type="note-symbol">{67}</seg><p> John E. Moody (1828- ). A native of Chesterfield County and a 
coachmaker by trade, Moody had enlisted in Harpers Ferry. His shoulder wound caused 
him to be discharged in 1862.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="68" id="hanger68"><seg type="note-symbol">{68}</seg><p> Preston A. Davidson (1842-1914). He was a student at 
Washington College when the war began. A native of Indianapolis, Indiana, he was the 
son of one of the Davidson family originally from Rockbridge County. The wound in his 
right shoulder caused anchylosis of the joint and he was discharged in 1862. 
Davidson farmed in Rockbridge for a number of years before returning to 
Indiana.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="69" id="hanger69"><seg type="note-symbol">{69}</seg><p> Edward Y. Northern (1833-1894). Northern was a tailor in 
Lexington when he enlisted. His wounds must have been minor, as he returned to duty and 
was promoted to 1st Sergeant in October, 1861. He was elected 2nd Lieutenant in 
the Rifles in 1862 and served to the end of the war. He returned to 
Lexington after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="70" id="hanger70"><seg type="note-symbol">{70}</seg><p> Joshua Parks, Jr. (1836-1861). A Lexington native, Parks was 
a plasterer and mason before he enlisted. His wound was apparently minor as he 
returned to duty and was killed at Honeywood Mills Dam or Dam No. 5 in 
Morgan County on 19 December, 1861. Stonewall Jackson was attempting to 
destroy the dams on the upper Potomac river to prevent the water flowing 
into the vital Cheasapeake and Ohio Canal.</p></note> 
 
<note place="end" n="71" id="hanger71"><seg type="note-symbol">{71}</seg><p> Samuel Wallace Ruff (1843-1884). A native of Lexington, Ruff 
had no occupation on the 1860 census and gave none when he enlisted. His wound was 
apparently minor as he was back on duty in October. He served faithfully 
until after Gettysburg when he deserted to join the Page Cavalry. Following 
the war he farmed in the Natural Bridge area.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="72" id="hanger72"><seg type="note-symbol">{72}</seg><p> John W. "Jack" Jordon, Jr. (1839-1871). A Rockbridge native, 
he was managing a hotel when he enlisted. His wound was minor, as he was present a 
month later. He was promoted rapidly up through the ranks to 2nd Lieutenant 
in May of 1863, reportedly because of his ability to manage horses in 
difficult situations. Jordan received a slight wound in the arm at 
Gettysburg, but never left the battery. He surrendered at Appomattox Court 
House. After the war he was involved in railroad construction.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="73" id="hanger73"><seg type="note-symbol">{73}</seg><p> John Bowyer Brockenbrough (1836-1901). A native of 
Lexington, Bowyer had attended Washington College and graduated from the University of 
Virginia and the Washington College Law School. He was a lawyer in Lexington and one 
of the organizers of the Rockbridge Artillery. He received a slight wound in 
the foot. He resigned in August of 1861. In 1862 he was elected Captain of 
the Baltimore Artillery. Brockenbrough was wounded in the arm at 
Fredericksburg in December, 1862, while serving as a gunner, although he was 
on the staff of General Taliferro. Promoted to Najor of Artillery in 1863 
but he retired in 1864. Brockenbrough was a lawyer in Lynchburg until 1886 
when he was appointed special agent for the Department of the Interior by 
President Cleveland. He moved to Baltimore in 1900.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="74" id="hanger74"><seg type="note-symbol">{74}</seg><p> William Francis Singleton of Kentucky. He was a student at the 
University of Virginia when the war began. His wound was in the arm but he 
was back on duty by August. Singleton was wounded and captured at Port 
Republic. Following his exchange in 1863 he joined Morgan's Kentucky 
cavalry.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="75" id="hanger75"><seg type="note-symbol">{75}</seg><p> Richard C. "Sergeant" Turpin (1815-1880) A native of Henrico 
County, Turpin moved to Le:rington in 1856 and was employed as a coach painter. He 
was absent from the company as a hospital steward in Winchester. He was 
discharged in December for an old fracture of his left leg. Turpin served in 
the Lexington Patrol and as Captain in the Rockbridge Senior Reserves. He 
returned to his occupation after the war but later was a bartender in 
Lexington.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="76" id="hanger76"><seg type="note-symbol">{76}</seg><p> Morgan Francis Seal (1829-1881). Seal served in the company 
only a month before being discharged and sent to Richmond to make harness for the 
Confederacy. He returned to Lexington after the war as a harness maker.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="77" id="hanger77"><seg type="note-symbol">{77}</seg><p> Charles A. Adams (1830-1909) A native of Williamsburg, 
Adams came to Lexington in 1852 and was employed as a tailor. He was discharged in 
1862 to be the tailor for the V. M. I. Adams was captured during Hunter's raid and 
sent to Camp Chase, Ohio. He returned to Lexington and served as the tailor 
for the V.M.I. for over 50 years.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="78" id="hanger78"><seg type="note-symbol">{78}</seg><p> Andrew Jackson Champe (1818-1896) A Craig County native, 
Champe came to Lexington in 1852 as a bricklayer. He was discharged for rheumatism in 
1862 and served in the Lexington Patrol and the Rockbridge Senior Reserves. He 
resumed his career as a brick mason and later manufactured brick in 
Lexington.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="79" id="hanger79"><seg type="note-symbol">{79}</seg><p> James W. Smith (1825- ). Smith was a shoemaker by trade and 
reportedly deserted in 1862. However, he was exempt as a shoemaker in Lexington in 
1864.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="80" id="hanger80"><seg type="note-symbol">{80}</seg><p> Calvin Radford (1827- ). Radford was a coach maker in 
Lexington. He was soon discharged because of his skills and assigned to government 
work. He returned to Lexington after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="81" id="hanger81"><seg type="note-symbol">{81}</seg><p> James Kerr Edmondson (1832-1898). He was born near Buena 
Vista and attended Washington College. Edmondson was the Town Sergeant of Lexington 
from 1853-1860 and was Clerk of the City Court of Lexington in 1861. He 
enlisted as a private but was soon elected 2nd Lieutenant. In August he was 
appointed Adjutant of the 27th Virginia, but returned to the Rifles in 
October as their Captain. Edmondson rose to Lieutenant Colonel of the 27th 
in July of 1862 and was promoted Colonel in November of the same year. 
Edmondson was wounded severely at Chancellorsville in the breast and lost 
his left arm at the shoulder. He resigned later in the year and served as 
the Provost Marshal of Lexington until the end of the war. In addition to 
his military duties he served as the County Clerk from 1864-64 and for 4 
years after the war. He served as treasurer of Washington College from 
1865-1868. Edmondson graduated from Washington College in 1870 B. L. and as 
a lawyer was almost immediately appointed a Judge in the county. He also 
served as the Mayor of Lexington for 9 years and as a trustee for Washington 
College. Edmondson found time to serve in the Virginia legislature from 
1870-1880.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="82" id="hanger82"><seg type="note-symbol">{82}</seg><p> William H. Loker (1837- ). Loker spent most of his military 
career absent sick or absent without leave. He transferred to the 12th Virginia 
Cavalry in 1863 but soon deserted that unit.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="83" id="hanger83"><seg type="note-symbol">{83}</seg><p> James Holly (1828- ) Holly was married in Rockbridge County 
in 1850 but does not appear on the 1860 census. He was traveling back and forth from 
Rockbridge County bringing boxes of food, mail and other items to the 
troops.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="84" id="hanger84"><seg type="note-symbol">{84}</seg><p> The Staunton Mountain Sax Horn Band or Turner's Silver 
Cornet Band. Formed in 1855 with 14 members, the band performed at many civic, 
politican and military functions. They had played for the Rockbridge Rifles when they 
departed Staunton for Harrisonburg. The band, depleted by a number of its 
members serving in the 5th Virginia Infantry, was only visiting the troops 
at this time. On April 1, 1862 Stonewall Jackson authorized the 5th Virginia 
Infantry to have a band. 14 men, including 8 former members, made up the 
regimental band. The bandsmen were not without military duties, as they 
acted as stretcher bearers for the wounded and took casualties as a result. 
When Jackson's troops crossed the Potomac into Maryland in September, 1862, 
the band played "Maryland, My Maryland" as the men waded the river. In 1863 
the bandsmen were officially designated the "Stonewall Brigade Band" and 
served to the end of the war. This organization still exists in the city of 
Staunton.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="85" id="hanger85"><seg type="note-symbol">{85}</seg><p> Eugene Lynch (1835-1863). A shoemaker by trade, he spent 
much of his military career detailed to make shoes for the troops. He was found murdered 
in Richmond on July 12. 1863.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="86" id="hanger86"><seg type="note-symbol">{86}</seg><p> Andrew Jackson Grigsby (1819-1895) A native of Rockbridge 
County, Grigsby had attended Washington College before serving in the Mexican War. 
He moved to Missouri for a short time, but was teaching school in the 
Lexington District of Rockbridge County in 1860. Grigsby was living in Giles 
County when the war began. He was appointed Major of the 27th Virginia in 
June, 1861, promoted to Lieutenant Colonel in October and Colonel in May of 
1862. Grigsby was wounded at Malvern Hill on July 1, 1862. He returned to 
duty and resigned, along with several other officers when Major Elijah F. 
Paxton was promoted to Brigadier over the other senior officers in the 
Stonewall Brigade. He served with the Kentucky troops briefly and in the 
Confederate House of Representatives from Kentucky as its Speaker 1863-64, 
and as Counsel in France 1864-65. He farmed in Albemarle County until his 
death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="87" id="hanger87"><seg type="note-symbol">{87}</seg><p> James Woods Massie (1826-1872) An Augusta County native, 
he had graduated from the V. M. I. in 1849 and the Washington College Law School in 
1851. Massie was a lawyer in Lexington, represented to county in the 
Virginia legislature 1858-59 and Colonel in the militia. Hewas appointed 
Lieutenant Colonel of the 51st Virginia Infantry in July, 1861. He 
apparently was serving with Stonewall Jackson at this time. He commanded the 
51st Virginia in the battle of Ft Donelson, Tennessee but was not reelected 
in May, 1862 Massie returned to the V. M. I. as professor of mathematics 
until 1871.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="88" id="hanger88"><seg type="note-symbol">{88}</seg><p> Mary Anna Morrison Jackson (1831-?)</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="89" id="hanger89"><seg type="note-symbol">{89}</seg><p> Bishop EO Johns</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="90" id="hanger90"><seg type="note-symbol">{90}</seg><p> James S. Thomas (1840-1863) A Bedford County native, he 
was working as a clerk in Lexington when he enlisted Thomas was wounded at Port 
Republic and Kearneysville. Promoted to Sergeant Major of the regiment, he was killed at 
Gettysburg on July 3, 1863.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="91" id="hanger91"><seg type="note-symbol">{91}</seg><p> Henry Crawford (1829- ) Crawford was working as a carpenter 
in the Glenwood District of the county when he enlisted. He was wounded at 2nd 
fanassas and Fisher's Hill. Crawford returned to his trade in the Natural 
Bridge area after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="92" id="hanger92"><seg type="note-symbol">{92}</seg><p> Samuel A. Gordon (1839- ) Gordon was a clerk in Lexington 
before the war. He was captured near Spotsylvania Court House on May 20, 1864. He 
was released from the Elmira, New York prisoner of war camp on June 30, 1865. He 
apparently died on his way home, as he is listed as "dying in service" on 
all postwar rosters.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="93" id="hanger93"><seg type="note-symbol">{93}</seg><p> Henry Norgrove (1814-1881) A native of Berkshire near 
Oxford, England, Norgrove immigrated to Richmond and moved to Charlottesville before 
coming to Lexington in 1837. He was a tailor and clothes merchant. One of his sons, 
Edward W. Norgrove (1843-1863) was serving in the Rifles. He was mortally 
wounded at Chancellorsville His other son William H. Norgrove (1840-1863) 
served as a Lieutenant in the Botetourt Artillery and died of wounds 
received at Port Gibson, Mississippi in May, 1863. Henry served in the 
Lexington Patrol during the war. He continued his tailoring career in 
Lexington until his death.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="94" id="hanger94"><seg type="note-symbol">{94}</seg><p> John Clinton Boude (1833-1896) Boude, a Clarke County 
native and a cabinetmaker, moved to Rockbridge County in 1855. He was soon promoted 
2nd Lieutenant and later 1st Lieutenant and Captain. Boude was wounded at 2nd 
Manassas and lost his left leg at Chancellorsville. He served as the 
Enrolling Officer in Lexington until the end of the war. Boude also served 
as Clerk of the County Court from 1864-1888. He graduated from Washington 
College in 1870 B. L. and practiced law in Lexington. Boude was the owner of 
the "Rockbridge Citizen" newspaper and served on the town council.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="95" id="hanger95"><seg type="note-symbol">{95}</seg><p> The "Shriver Grays" were organized by Captain Daniel X 
Shriver from the best families of Wheeling. They secretly left Wheeling on the last boat not 
requiring military inspection. This company was never able to obtain many 
recruits or conscripts and dwindled away to a few survivors by the end of 
the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="96" id="hanger96"><seg type="note-symbol">{96}</seg><p> There were three companies from Alleghany County in the 
regiment The "Alleghany Roughs" under Captain Thompson McAllister, the "Hiberians" 
under Captain Harry H. Robertson and the "Alleghany Rifles" led by Captain Lewis 
P. Holloway.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="97" id="hanger97"><seg type="note-symbol">{97}</seg><p> Colonel John Thomas Lewis Preston (1811-1890) A Lexington 
native, Preston attended Washington College and the University of Virginia. He was 
one of the founders of the Virginia Military Institute and was an instructor 
there from 1839-1861. He led the Cadets to Richmond in April, 1861, where 
they were assigned as drillmasters for the new regiments flocking to the 
capital of the Confederacy. Preston was appointed Lieutenant Colonel of the 
9th Virginia Infantry on 7 July, 1861. He as assigned to Jackson's staff 
officially as Assistant Adjutant General in October. Preston was ordered 
back to the V. M I. in December, 1861, where he served until 1882.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="98" id="hanger98"><seg type="note-symbol">{98}</seg><p> Captain Mathew X. White Jr.'s 1st Rockbridge Dragoons, now 
Company C, 1st Virginia Cavalry.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="99" id="hanger99"><seg type="note-symbol">{99}</seg><p> Company D. From Monroe County, now West Virginia, where 
they were organized in May, 1861.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="100" id="hanger100"><seg type="note-symbol">{100}</seg><p> Insert corrected text.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="101" id="hanger101"><seg type="note-symbol">{101}</seg><p> The rumor proved to be true. Jackson was assigned to 
command the Valley District and he managed to get the Stonewall Brlsade and the 
Rockbridge Artillery assigned to the Valley in November, 1861.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="102" id="hanger102"><seg type="note-symbol">{102}</seg><p> William Frederick Walz (1835-1908) A native of Germany, 
Walz came to the United States at age 14. He was a baker in Lexington when the war 
began. He is listed as having deserted in December, 1862, however, he was probably 
discharged as a foreigner, since he served in the Lexington Patrol and was 
examined by the Conscript Officer in Lexington in February, 1864 He is 
listed as a baker and confectioneer in Lexington in 1872, but was a milliner 
and saloon owner by 1880.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="103" id="hanger103"><seg type="note-symbol">{103}</seg><p> Mathew R. Sheltman (1835-1895) Sheltman was farming in 
the <unclear></unclear>the District of Rockbridge County when the war began. He served faithfully 
throughout the war and was paroled at Staunton in May, 1865 He returned to 
farming in the county after the war.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="104" id="hanger104"><seg type="note-symbol">{104}</seg><p> Colonel John W. Echols (1833-1896) Echols was a native of 
Lynchburg and a graduate of Washington College. He attended the V. M. I. briefly and 
graduated from Harvard Law School. Echols was Gommonwealth's Attorney of 
Monroe County when the war started. He was promoted MaJor of the regiment in 
May and Colonel in October. Echols was wounded at Kernstown in March, 1862 
and was promoted to Brigadier General a month later. He commanded a brigade 
in southwest Virginia and later at New Market and Cold Harbor. Promoted to 
Major General, he was placed in command of Western Virginia in March, 1865. 
He surrendered with Johnston's army in North Carolina. Following the war he 
was an attorney in Staunton and served in the Virginia legislature. After 
serving as president of the Valley Bank, he was elected president of the C &amp; 
0 Railroad and moved to Louisville. Kentucky. He died in Staunton and is 
buried there.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="105" id="hanger105"><seg type="note-symbol">{105}</seg><p> Company F, the "Greenbrier Sharpshooters" under Captain 
Gabriel C. Smith.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="106" id="hanger106"><seg type="note-symbol">{106}</seg><p> William Henry Harrison Kahle (1837-1863). A Lexington 
cabinetmaker, "Bill" Kahle had been wounded at Bull Run on July 21st. He was killed at 
Gettysburg on July 3, 1863.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="107" id="hanger107"><seg type="note-symbol">{107}</seg><p> Henry D. Smith (1832- ). Smith was the butcher for the V. M. 
I. and was a new recruit for the Rifles. He surrendered at Appomattox Court House on 
April 9 1865.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="108" id="hanger108"><seg type="note-symbol">{108}</seg><p> James William Gillock (1843-19l6) A Lexington native, 
Gillock rose quickly through the ranks to 1st Lieutenant in 1862. He was captured at 
Gettysburg and spent the rest of the war in various federal prisons Gillock 
returned to Lexington and served as the military storekeeper for the V. M. 
I. for 44 years.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="109" id="hanger109"><seg type="note-symbol">{109}</seg><p> Charles W. Sizer (1840- ) Sizer was working as a mason 
before his enlistment. Wounded in the abdomen at Gettysburg, he was captured at 
Fairfield, Pennslyvania. Federal records show him as a deserter, who was 
sent to Ft. Delaware and took the oath and Joined the 3rd Maryland Cavalry, 
U. S. Confederate records show him hospitalized at Orange Court House from 
19 September-20 October 1863, then no further record.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="110" id="hanger110"><seg type="note-symbol">{110}</seg><p> Probably Dr. Alexander Graham from Rockbridge County, 
who later served in the Virginia Legislature.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="111" id="hanger111"><seg type="note-symbol">{111}</seg><p> Dr. William S. White, pastor of the Lexington Presbyterian 
Church.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="112" id="hanger112"><seg type="note-symbol">{112}</seg><p> Possibly refering to George W. Johnson of Company F, 27th 
Virginia Infantry.</p></note> 
<note place="end" n="113" id="hanger113"><seg type="note-symbol">{113}</seg><p> Governor John Letcher (1813-1884). A Lexington lawyer and 
Virginia's "War Governor."</p></note> 
</div1> 
</back> 
</text> 
</TEI.2> 
 
 
