<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B0539"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B0539">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando
                    Brown, November 3, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, november 3 1865</title>
        <author>How, W. Storer</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B0539</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500798</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando Brown, November
                            3, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, november 3 1865</title>
            <author>W. Storer How</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and
                            Abandoned Lands, Record Group 105, Box E4302.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-11-03">1865-11-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Administration/Bureaucracy, Health/Illness, Women,
                        Employment/Labor, Local Government, Race Relations, Slavery, Military
                        Authority</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B0539T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>How files a report about the condition of blacks in his District. He writes that
                    there is a pervasive fear about what will happen once the Bureau ceases its
                    protection, citing the attitudes of their "implacable neighbors." His report
                    also discusses employment conditions and the situation of the poor and
                needy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <abbr expan="Bureau">Bu.</abbr> &amp;c
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst. Commr.</abbr> &amp;c</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-11-03"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 3d 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have the honor to report that the condition of the freedmen in this district is
                    generally good, and that the operations of this Bureau have positively, and by
                    its presence negatively, added greatly to the attainment of such condition. The
                    freedman having learned that they will be protected in the exercise of
                    unquestionable rights and the former masters now knowing that they may not
                    ill-treat nor unjustly use them with impunity. The freedmen have however a vague
                    dread of being soon deprived of the assistance now given by this Bureau, and are
                    thus repressed in their aspirations for manhood through fears of being left at
                    the mercy of implacable neighbors, who now secretly vaunt the terrible things
                    they will do when "the yankees" and (with undescribable sneers) the "Freedmens
                    Bureau" are gone.</p>

                <p>The freedmen are generally at work under verbal contracts
                    <unclear>terminating</unclear> at Christmas and are averse to written contracts
                    for a future period, because they can hardly be induced to look beyond that time
                    -- though I hope during this and the succeeding months to aid and persuade them
                    to the exercise of forethough and providence -- and the prospect now is that
                    effective labor will continue to be required in excess of the supply.</p>

                <p>Among the old and infirm and <pb n="2"/>women with three or more little children,
                    there is now considerable suffering which will increase with the approach of
                    winter. Partial issues of rations prevents starvation but wood is also needed to
                    defend them from the cold. The local authorities profess inability to and until
                    compelled by law will not make any provision for the support of colored paupers,
                    and the former masters are only prevented from setting many adrift by the
                    knowledge that it is not permitted; although there are instances in which the
                    old ones are cherished on account of family associations, and for long and
                    faithful services.</p>

                <p>The Board of Agents authorized by Circular dated Richmond <abbr expan="September"
                        >Septr</abbr> 27, 1865 has not been organized by all the <abbr
                        expan="Assistant Superintendents">Asst. Supts.</abbr> because the citizens
                    will not act, nor serve, and can hardly be compelled to accept an invitation.
                    For Winchester, where there are a few loyal men a Board is in successful
                    operation with business enough for two half day sessions in a week. Its
                    decisions are respected and enforced.</p>

                <p>The question of compensation is for the present waived but should be provided
                    for. In Woodstock a Board is organized but is without cases for trial.</p>

                <p>The <abbr expan="Military">Mil.</abbr> Authorities afford all the assistance in
                    their <unclear>power</unclear>
                    <pb n="3"/>which in men, ways &amp; means is very limited.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, Colonel &amp;c</salute>
                    <signed>W.S.H.<lb/><abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> &amp;c</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
