<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1015"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1015">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to
                    Orlando Brown, August 31, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, august 31 1867</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1015</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500883</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to Orlando Brown, August
                            31, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, august 31 1867</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 47.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-08-31">1867-08-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior, Employment/Labor, Family,
                        Race Relations, Slavery, Women, Health/Illness</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1015T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jackson's report is optimistic in regards to the employment situation and general
                    economic condition of blacks in Augusta County, but he writes that the moral
                    condition leaves less to be desired, citing drunkeness and frequent
                    cohabitation. He also remarks that local whites view the political independence
                    of blacks as "little less than a heinous crime."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees">Ref.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Freedmen">F.men</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Abandoned">Aban<hi
                        rend="super">d</hi></abbr> Lands<lb/>Office 4th <abbr expan="Division"
                            >Div.</abbr> 9 <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet">Brvt.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Brigadier">Brig.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Orlando">O.</abbr> Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr> State of <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va</abbr><lb/>Richmond (Through <abbr expan="Headquarters">H<hi
                                rend="super">d</hi>Qrs</abbr> 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District">SubDist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>)</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-08-31">August 31. 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with the requirements of <abbr expan="Circular">C.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Order">O</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 6 S. 1866 (<abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B.R.F. &amp;
                        A.L.</abbr>) I have the honor to report on condition of Bureau affairs in
                    4th <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr> of 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District"
                    >SubDist.</abbr> that there is no change to note in condition of Freedpeople.
                    Employment is readily procured at fair wages and many farmers are making
                    arrangements with Freedmen for cultivation of land during coming season on
                    shares. Numerous complaints are still made at this office of unfair treatment in
                    settlements or refusal to pay wages earned but I find as a general rule parties
                    are willing to settle when I bring the account to their notice and in many cases
                    the difficulty arises from ignorance on the part of Freedmen of the terms of the
                    contracts they have signed or forgetfulness of the amount and value of supplies
                    they have received. A great obstacle in the way of advancement among Freedpeople
                    is the frequent changes they make of employers, thereby losing much valuable
                    time from profitable labor and incurring heavy expense in <pb n="2"/>shifting
                    their families and goods.</p>

                <p>There is not much pauperism, at this time, in this Division, still there is much
                    poverty not perhaps as much as might, under all the circumstances, be expected
                    nor more than can be readily relieved by local public and private charity.
                    Strangers, widows and deserted wives with young families, and the aged who have
                    been brought from other counties are the majority of persons needing help.</p>

                <p>The social relations between white and colored present no change. The senseless
                    fears of "social equality" make the prejudiced whites unable to see any steps
                    made in advance by Freedmen, in any other light than an encroachment upon their
                    own rights and safety, and the idea of political independence seems to them
                    little less than a heinous crime. The demeanor of the Freedmen is however
                    peaceable and without so decided and general in their expression of loyal
                    sentiment, that I anticipate no difficulty during coming canvass and election.</p>

                <p>The moral condition of the Freedpeople is not what it should be. There is much
                    loudness, and cohabitation without marriage in common and will continue to be so
                    until the statutes against this demoralizing <orig reg="practice"
                    >practise</orig> are en- <pb n="3"/>forced by the courts.</p>

                <p>The Record of Marriages, (under Act <abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="27, 1866">27/66</abbr>) is carefully preserved in this office, in
                    good order for reference, and is frequently consulted. <unclear>For</unclear>
                    additions have been made to the List of names during past month, but I have
                    directed several parties to the County Clerk for licence to marry.</p>

                <p>I regret I cannot report the organization of any branch of "Lincoln National
                    Temperance Association" in this Division, but I am pressing the matter with some
                    of the leading colored men here and I do not despair of success. I am sorry to
                    report that too much of the harvest wages earned by Freemen has found its way
                    into bar rooms and with two Circus exhibitions during the month there has been
                    more drunkeness than any previous month I have been here.</p>

                <p>I am pleased to find there is a prospect of a small supply of Medicines from Dr.
                        <unclear>De Lamath</unclear> Surgeon in chief <abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands"
                    >B.R.F.&amp;A.L.</abbr> for the benefit of Indigent Freedpeople. When
                    received care shall be exercised that none save the class for whom it is
                    intended draw upon it.</p>

                <p>The desire for reunion of families (colored) separated in years past by the vile
                    traffic of the slave trader, is general and often, through medium of this
                    office, successful.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>One great obstacle in the way of prosecuting such <orig reg="inquiries"
                    >enquiries</orig> is the destruction or <unclear>secretion</unclear> of the
                    books of the large Slave Marts at Richmond.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted<lb/><abbr expan="Your obedient servant">Yr obt
                            servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed><hi rend="underline">Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> P.
                        Jackson</hi><lb/>Agent</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
