<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1014"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1014">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to
                    Orlando Brown, July 31, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, july 31 1867</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1014</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500882</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to Orlando Brown, July
                            31, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, july 31 1867</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 47.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-07-31">1867-07-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior, Employment/Labor, Legal
                        System, Politics/Political Attitudes, Race Relations, Health/Illness</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1014T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jackson writes that while the condition of most freedmen in Augusta County is
                    tolerable for the present, more support will be needed as winter approaches.
                    Jackson renews his request for a medical requisition, but also mentions the need
                    to try to reunite the familes of the aged and orphaned. His report also
                    discusses temperance and the political attitudes in the county.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R. F. &amp; A.
                        L.</abbr><lb/>Office 4 <abbr expan="Division">Div.</abbr> 9 <abbr
                            expan="Sub-District">S Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brigadier">Brig.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Orlando">O.</abbr> Brown<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst. Comr</abbr> (Bureau <abbr
                            expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R. F. &amp; A.
                        L.</abbr>)<lb/>Richmond (Through <abbr expan="Headquarters">H<hi
                                rend="super">d</hi>Qrs</abbr> 9th <abbr expan="Sub-District">S.
                            Dist.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-07-31">July 31/1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with the requirements of <abbr expan="Circular Order">C.O.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Number">No</abbr> 6 S. 1866 (<abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B.R.F. &amp;
                        A.L.</abbr>) I have the honor to report on the conditions of Bureau Affairs
                    in 4th <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr> 9 <abbr expan="Sub-District"
                    >S.Dist.</abbr> that since date of my last report there is no change in the
                    general condition of Freedmen. The amelioration and elevation of their condition
                    is progressing favorably, slowly it is true but perhaps all the more surely.</p>

                <p>Employment continues abundant, much of the crop not yet being housed and
                    threshing of that already saved, pretty general. So far as has been brought to
                    my notice the farmers have paid <hi rend="underline">harvest</hi> wages promptly
                    and in cases of disagreement under old contract where the amount involved is
                    within the jurisdiction of magistrates I can obtain prompt settlement, but with
                    the larger claims of which I have several I can make very little progress as the
                    Freedmen are too poor to sue in the courts in form of law and contend with their
                    richer debtors.</p>

                <p>The physical condition of the aged, sickly and orphan colored persons is much
                    alleviated by fine weather and abundance of vegetable food and although there
                    are cases of need they are within reach of the local <pb n="2"/>authorities and
                    I do not expect to have to draw any rations until the Fall of the year unless
                    sickness becomes prevalent. Having by ample notice prepared the persons who have
                    hitherto been assisted for a suspension of Bureau aid, I hear few complaints on
                    account of the stoppage of issue of Rations.</p>

                <p>The political relations between white and colored present no change in this
                    Division. The whites say little except occasional individual threats, being at
                    last satisfied it is useless to continue the endeavor to make the Freedmen
                    believe they are their "best friends" and the large majority of white over
                    colored voters registered 3,484 <abbr expan="white">W.</abbr> &amp; 1,206
                        <abbr expan="colored">C.</abbr> = 2,248 White majority in Augusta <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr> and a still greater proportionate majority in
                    Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> makes them more indifferent, as they
                    think they can easily out-vote them at the Polls. The conduct of the Freedmen is
                    most praiseworthy and I do not anticipate any collision in case of an election.
                    In reference to Circular <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 14 <abbr
                        expan="Headquarters">H<hi rend="super">d</hi>Qrs</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Commissioner">Comr</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> July <abbr expan="10, 1867">10/67</abbr> I
                    respectfully refer to my Report of Bureau Affairs forwarded June <abbr
                        expan="3, 1867">3/67</abbr> "If a copy of the Constitution and By-Laws of
                    the Central (Lincoln Temperance) Society at Washington can be furnished to me, I
                    have no doubt branch organizations can be established here" As yet I have not
                    received such copy of Constitution &amp;c Drunkenness is more prevalent
                    among white than colored people in both counties and with but two exceptions
                    white men <pb n="3"/>are the keepers of the drinking places.</p>

                <p>I regret that some provision cannot be made to furnish medicine for poor Freedmen
                    here. Sickness is most common in families where poverty exists and although Dr.
                    C. R. Harris continues to prescribe gratis for the needy poor colored people, as
                    I have reported in previous months, he cannot furnish medicine also and in some
                    pressing cases I have had to pay for prescriptions out of my own pocket. A
                    trifling appropriation by the Bureau would do much good and if this cannot be
                    made with a small assortment of medicine be furnished to me on requisition?</p>

                <p>The aged and orphan colored people will need much attention through the coming
                    winter and I know nothing which will tend more to alleviate their condition than
                    affording facilities for the reunion of familes most of the needy old colored
                    people in this county having been deprived of their natural supporters by the
                    sale of their now adult chilren to other States.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, General,<lb/><abbr expan="Your obedient servant"
                            >Yr obt servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed><hi rend="underline">Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> P
                    Jackson</hi><lb/>Agent</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
