<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1023"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1023">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: John W. Jordan to John A.
                    McDonnell, April 30, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records john w jordan to john a mcdonnell, april 30 1868</title>
        <author>Jordan, John W.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1023</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500891</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: John W. Jordan to John A. McDonnell, April
                            30, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records john w jordan to john a mcdonnell, april 30 1868</title>
            <author>John W. Jordan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 49.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-04-30">1868-04-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Employment/Labor, Race Relations, Legal System, Politics/Poiltical
                        Attitudes, Community Values/Local Behavior, Education</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1023T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jordan files his first report as the Bureau's agent in Augusta and Highland
                    counties. His initial observations reflect much of what Jackson reported in
                    earlier reports, including the reluctance of freedmen to use the courts to
                    settle claims against their employers. Jordan notes that there is surprisingly
                    little drunkeness in his Division, and that the schools appear to be
                    flourishing.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands,<lb/>Office 4th Division, 9th
                    Sub-District, Virginia.
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="John">Jno.</abbr> A. M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Donnell<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Sub Assistant Commissioner">Sub Asst Comr</abbr><lb/><abbr
                            expan="Bureau">B</abbr> of <abbr
                            expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R.F. &amp;
                        A.L.</abbr><lb/>Winchester <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-04-30">April 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr>
                    </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In accordance with the requirements of Circular <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr>
                    VI from Head Quarters <abbr expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst Comr</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B of R.F.
                        &amp; A.L.</abbr> Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr> 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1866 I have the
                    honor to report the following showing the condition of "Freedmen's" Affairs" in
                    this above named Division at this date.</p>

                <p>By reason of the fact that I have been here but a short time, and consequently
                    not sufficiently acquainted with Freedmens affairs <hi rend="underline"
                    >here</hi> to enable me to make satisfactory report this must necessarily be
                    brief and confined to those facts only which have come under my personal <pb
                        n="2"/>observation.</p>

                <p>The Freedmen as a general thing seem to be employed and industrious and so far as
                    my observations extend they seem anxious to secure honorable, permanent
                    employment and no doubt would make much more rapid advancement in substantial
                    prosperity than they do make if the same liberality characterized their
                    employers treatment that is observable in the relations existing between the
                    white employers and the white laborers. It is a remarkable fact that the white
                    man expects to receive the labor of the colored man for about two-thirds of what
                    he is willing to pay the white laborers for the same service.</p>

                <p>The Colored people continue to rely upon the Bureau Officer for the settlement
                    and adjudication of business between themselves as well as between the white and
                    colored and seem to shrink from having their differences <pb n="3"/>settled by
                    the Courts. This I think is attributable to the fact that the white man
                    generally is not interested in the advancement of the freedmen and is not
                    inclined to protect his interests or to do anything looking in the directions of
                    a recognition of <hi rend="underline">their</hi> rights <orig reg="etc"
                        >&amp;c</orig>.</p>

                <p>Intemperance does not prevail to any serious extent amongst this class, in fact I
                    am surprised to find such limited indulgence in strong drink when I remember
                    that <orig reg="whiskey">whisky</orig> at least in this portion of the country
                    is at any time within the reach of the poorest.</p>

                <p>The colored people seem here to have an intelligent idea of their duties and
                    relations to each other and daily show evidences of their appreciation of their
                    new obligations and capacity to become a thrifty self-supporting and industrious
                    population. They seem to <pb n="4"/>be <unclear>insensible</unclear> to the
                    influences brought to bear upon them by which to poison their minds against
                    Government and Government officers.</p>

                <p>The School interests I am informed are in a flourishing condition and I am
                    contemplating a tour through my Division for the purpose of developing this
                    interest generally.</p>

                <p>This report is necessarily brief by reason of the fact that I have only been here
                    a few days, and am therefore unable to furnish a more extended statement.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr><lb/>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your
                            <abbr expan="obedient">obt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="servant">servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John">Jno</abbr> W. Jordan<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Sub Assistant Commissioner">A.S.A.Comr</abbr><lb/><abbr
                            expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B of R.F.
                            &amp; A.L.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
