<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1029"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1029">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Roswell Waldo to Orlando
                    Brown, October 31, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records roswell waldo to orlando brown, october 31 1868</title>
        <author>Waldo, Roswell</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1029</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500897</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Roswell Waldo to Orlando Brown, October
                            31, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records roswell waldo to orlando brown, october 31 1868</title>
            <author>Roswell Waldo</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 49.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-10-31">1868-10-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behaviour, Education, Women,
                        Employment/Labor, Race Relations, Administration/Bureaucracy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1029T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Waldo's report comments on the rising need for Bureau aid as demand for labor
                    decreases, as well as the prevalence of intemperance, which has largely gone
                    unnoticed accoring to Waldo because of the efforts to keep alcohol consumption
                    "clandestine."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands,<lb/>Office 4th Division, 9th
                    Sub-District, Virginia.
                    <name type="recipient">General O. Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr>
                        Commissioner<lb/>Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-10-31">October 31, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with Circular <abbr expan="Number">No</abbr> VI - dated Head
                    Quarters, <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr> Commissioner Richmond <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> January 29, 1866 I have the honor to submit the
                    following Report of Bureau Affairs in 4th Division (Comprising the Counties of
                    Highland and Augusta) 9th Sub District of Virginia viz:</p>

                <p>On account of the many difficulties arising between the freedmen and their
                    Employers relative to the proper and just settlement of their accounts, this
                    office is much sought by the former for aid and advice in forwarding their
                    claims.</p>

                <p>I regret to say that many freedmen having confidence in the honor and integrity
                    of their employers, have entered into verbal contracts with them, and in many
                    instances, it is not until their duties have been performed and final settlement
                    made that they discover themselves in the power and at the mercy <pb n="2"/>of
                    dishonest and unscrupulous men, who would not hesitate to resort to any trickery
                    to deprive the laborer of his earnings, and thereby lay up for themselves an
                    "honest penny" -- It is this class of men, who boastingly claim to be the
                    colored man's benefactor &amp; friend and who bitterly complain of the
                    Freedmen's Bureau. The result of its withdrawal as long as this state of feeling
                    prevails would be plainly manifested to all well disposed, and honest men.</p>

                <p>The season is now approaching when the demand for labor decreases, and many who
                    have had steady employment through the season have already been discharged from
                    their work, and although a majority of them have been successful in finding
                    other employment of a temporary character sufficient to provide for the wants
                    and necessities of their families there are still numbers who are in actual
                    suffering and distress and to whom aid should be extended during the coming
                    winter. By this class I have many applications daily for Clothing and other
                    things necessary for the alleviation of their sufferings, but I have such a
                    limited supply of the former on hand that I have been compelled to deny many
                    applications of the <pb n="3"/>needy and deserving ones in order to be able to
                    provide for extreme cases where immediate help was necessary and essential.</p>

                <p>I am obliged to modify the opinion expressed in my last report regarding <hi
                        rend="underline">Intemperance</hi>. A more extended observation has resulted
                    in discoveries that a more superficial man would fail to make. It cannot be
                    denied that liquor is used to a considerable extent by the freedpeople of both
                    sexes, but for the fact that so much is disposed of in a clandestine manner, the
                    show of actual inebriation is much avoided. In this respect if no other have the
                    colored people advantage over the whites, as it seems the latter take special
                    pleasure to make themselves as obnoxious as possible while under the influence
                    of liquor.</p>

                <p>The progress made up to this time in opening the schools in this Division is not
                    very gratifying. The colored people in some localities are doing all in their
                    power toward the futherance of this object, but their limited means prevents
                    their doing very much. Efforts are being made to open schools in Greenville
                    &amp; Westview, but the extreme difficulty in procuring rooms for the
                    purpose, has prevented their suc- <pb n="4"/>cess as yet. If the prejudices of
                    the white population against the Educational interests of the freedpeople were
                    not so great less difficulty would be experienced <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >in</add> establishing these schools, and the freedmen benefitted and
                    encouraged. But viewing matters in their present light, unless pecuniary aid is
                    afforded these people by the Bureau or some Charitable Association there is
                    little hope of opening many schools in this Division this winter and the
                    progress &amp; enlightenment of the race greatly retarded.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfull<lb/>Your obedient servant</salute>
                    <signed>Roswell Waldo<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Sub Assistant Commissioner"
                                >A.S.A.Com<hi rend="super">r</hi></abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
