<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1021"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1021">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to
                    Orlando Brown, February 29, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, february 29 1868</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1021</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500889</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to Orlando Brown,
                            February 29, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to orlando brown, february 29 1868</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 48.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-02-29">1868-02-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior, Economy, Employment/Labor,
                        Politics/Political Attitudes, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S&gt; Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1021T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jackson's report to Brown describes the ongoing problems with contract
                    negotiations, relief efforts, the rise in drinking, and the political views of
                    whites and blacks in Augusta County.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands,<lb/>Office 4th Division, 9th
                    Sub-District, Virginia.
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brigadier">Brig</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com<hi rend="super">r</hi></abbr> District of
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>Richmond (Through <abbr
                            expan="Headquarters">H<hi rend="super">d</hi>Qrs</abbr> 9<hi
                            rend="super">th</hi>
                        <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>)</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-02-29"><abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 29, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In compliance with Circular Order <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 6 S. 1866 <abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands"
                    >B.R.F.&amp;A.L.</abbr> I have the honor to forward the following report of
                    condition of Bureau Affairs in this 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Division">Div.</abbr> of 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub Dist.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <orig reg="comprising">comprizing</orig> the counties of Augusta and Highland.
                    This office is still visited by many Freedmen asking assistance in making
                    settlements or seeking redress for grievances. Most of the crop accounts of 1864
                    are now adjusted and the unsettled claims for wages are generally against men
                    who cannot pay and where no written contract exists. Contracts to labor for the
                    year are not so common as could be wished. Two reasons for this are assigned by
                    freedmen. Some say their employers will not make contracts for the year as they
                    intend to discharge them if they do not vote to suit them but most say they can
                    do much better when their agreements are by the month as they can have monthly
                    settlements and know how they stand. <pb n="2"/>I encourage written contracts by
                    the year as much as possible because my experience shows men so employed prove
                    best off at the end of the year, provided they refuse to open store accounts
                    with their employers. The great drawback to Freedmen not employed by the year,
                    is the outrageous rents demanded for Tenements in which to live. <hi
                        rend="underline">As a class</hi> freedmen here are not making much progress
                    in material prosperity, the long hard winter eats up the surplus earnings of the
                    harvest season and the sick &amp; widowed and deserted women experience much
                    suffering. The distribution of clothing at this office has done much good,
                    enabling many to go out to labor who otherwise from want of clothing would have
                    been prevented. The corporation and county officers relieve such cases of
                    distress, as have been presented, and no complaints can now be made, except
                    perhaps about the regulations in some county districts, which disallow out <del
                        hand="h1"/> relief and present to the poor only the option of poorhouse or
                    nothing. This month there has been less than usual number of complaints by
                    freedmen of ill usage at the hands of white citizens.</p>

                <p>Little is now said on political questions it appears <pb n="3"/>to be conceded
                    useless to "fish" for the colored vote with the "base hook," and not worth while
                    to offer anything, as the conservatives are confident they will reject the
                    Constitution whatever it may be, either by remaining at home on election day, or
                    dragging every white man to the polls to vote it down. The freedmen are uneasy
                    but hopeful, and will generally cast their votes, but not near so unanimously as
                    at the last election a large proportion of the white men will stay at home
                    anyway.</p>

                <p>No prospect has been made in organizing Temperance organizations in this Division
                    and I regret that since the distillers here have resumed operations whiskey
                    drinking has become too common among freedmen in country districts where it can
                    be procurred from the still houses.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, General<lb/>Your <abbr expan="obedient">obt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="servant">servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="Thomas">Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi></abbr>
                            P Jackson</hi>
                        <lb/>
                        <abbr expan="Assistant Sub Assistant Commissioner">Asst Sub Asst Comr</abbr>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
