<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1182"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1182">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando
                    Brown, May 5, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, may 5 1866</title>
        <author>How, W. Storer</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1182</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501041</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: W. Storer How to Orlando Brown, May 5,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records w storer how to orlando brown, may 5 1866</title>
            <author>W. Storer How</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 14.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-05-05">1866-05-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Military Authority, Education, Legal System</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1182T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>How writes to Brown before what appears to be his resignation from the Bureau.
                    How proposes a reorganization of the Sixth District due to conflicts with
                    General Terry, the Military Commissioner for the Valley. He suggests that two
                    counties be placed under the jurisdiction of West Virginia, where much more
                    progress has been made in terms of laws protecting the rights of free blacks,
                    and further splitting the district into two parts, one of which would be
                    commanded from Staunton. His letter constantly alludes to conflicts and
                    misunderstandings between the Bureau and the Military Commissioners.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-05-05">May 5th 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It seems to me that it will soon be necessary to modify the organization of this
                    District and change its present anomalous relations to the Command of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Terry, to that of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl</abbr> Hancock and to the state of West Virginia. By the
                        <unclear>deposition</unclear> of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Ayres the
                    command of a District <unclear>embracing</unclear> Rockingham, Shenandoah, Page,
                    Warren, Frederick, Clarke, Buckley, Jefferson and Linden Counties <del hand="h1"
                    /> upon a Major, <abbr expan="United States Army">U.S.<hi rend="underline"
                        >A</hi></abbr> who is apparently desirous of fixing the
                    <unclear>precise</unclear> relations in which Bureau officers stand to him and
                    he to them. And he does not understand how, for instance, I can be in and
                    exercise jurisdiction within the command of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Hancock yet be under the direction of yourself and <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl</abbr> Terry.</p>

                <p>This is my interpretation of his remark that he does not understand the Bureau
                    arrangements and has written for instructions, and it <unclear>seems</unclear>
                    to me that the <unclear>ordering transactions</unclear> of the Bureau are
                    irregular enough without the continuance of such a complication as this.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p><unclear>These two then</unclear> are Buckley and Jefferson Counties in the State
                    of <hi rend="underline">West</hi> Virginia.</p>

                <p>So long as Harpers Ferry was a Military Post and occupied as such I felt secure
                    enough in the exercise of Bureau funtion with proper care and caution, but now
                    that the <unclear>sunflower</unclear> of Military Authority is withdrawn I feel
                    that the jurisdiction of the Bureau in these counties is liable to be
                    questioned.</p>

                <p>By a law of <abbr expan="West Virginia">W.Va</abbr> passed <abbr expan="February"
                        >Feby</abbr> 27th 1866 it is enacted that "no person shall be incompetent as
                    a witness on account of race or color," and there is also a law establishing
                    free schools for colored children. These laws are not in full operation but soon
                    will be, I trust, and there will be no need for Bureau supervision, in fact it
                    may now be advisable to withdraw. Should this District be reorganized I suggest
                    a <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt</abbr> at Winchester for Frederick <abbr
                        expan="County">Co</abbr> and in charge of Clarke, Warren, Page &amp;
                    Shenandoah. Also a <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt</abbr> at Staunton for
                    Augusta with (4) assistants for Rockingham, Rockbridge, Alleghany and Bath,
                    adding Highland to Augusta.</p>

                <p>This as I think would be the best arrangement until the Valley RRoads shall be
                    completed, probably a year hence</p>

                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>I have given this information and <unclear>thrown</unclear> out these suggestions
                    in an informal way so that you might initiate any action in accordance with your
                    own opinions and desires.</p>

                <p>I have hitherto managed to avoid conflicts that I now think are likely to occur,
                    for since I began this I have <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl</abbr> Terry had succeeded you, as I had expected.</p>

                <p>It is a fact as far as my experience goes that the absence of an understood
                    organization of the Bureau has <unclear>constituted</unclear> its effectiveness.
                    The Army couldn't understand it and were afraid to oppose it. The people <orig
                        reg="couldn't understand it and were afraid to oppose it.">" " " " " " " "
                    "</orig></p>

                <p>If only they could have promoted to distinct, comprehensible positions they could
                    have kept us within them and given us trouble. As an illustration, just so soon
                    as orders come here from <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Terry which affect
                    this post commander they will be referred to <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Hancock while an order from you as "<hi rend="underline">
                        <abbr expan="Assistant Commissioner">Assist Comr</abbr>
                    </hi>" would be respected That - incomprehensible "Assist Comr" does the
                    business.</p>

                <p>I am sorry your relinquished command but should yet never regret it did I not
                    think it a wise thing to do, and were I to remain.</p>

                <p>I hope soon to hear of your action in my behalf and that you will send
                        <unclear>Capt. White</unclear> in <unclear>Maj. Bates</unclear> to relieve
                    me sometime between the 15th &amp; 25th.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With best wishes<lb/>yours <unclear>faithfully</unclear></salute>
                    <signed>W. Storer How<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"/></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
