<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1187"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1187">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: George B. Carse to
                    Orlando Brown, October 11, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george b carse to orlando brown, october 11 1866</title>
        <author>Carse, George B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1187</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501046</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: George B. Carse to Orlando Brown, October
                            11, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george b carse to orlando brown, october 11 1866</title>
            <author>George B. Carse</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 12.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-10-11">1866-10-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Violence/Crime, Race Relations, Women, Community Values/Local Behavior</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1187T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Carse updates Brown on the murder case of Patrick Thompson and the escape of his
                    killer, J. C. Johnson, about which he originally notified authorities from
                    Staunton. According the the October 16 Stauton Spectator, Johnson escaped from
                    Lexington to Augusta County, where he was arrested in Fishersville.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau of <abbr expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R. F. and
                        A.L.</abbr><lb/>Sub District No. "8", 7th District <abbr expan="Virginia"
                            >Va</abbr><lb/>Rockbridge, Bath and Alleghany Counties
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet Brigadier General">Bt Brig<hi
                                rend="super">d</hi> Gen'l</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Adjutant General">A.A.G.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-10-11">October 11th 1866</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="Headquarters">Hd Qrs</abbr> Lexington <abbr
                            expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>General</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>On the 10th inst. I telegraphed to <abbr expan="Brevet Brigadier General">Br
                            Brig<hi rend="super">d</hi> Gen'l</abbr> Horace Neide the information
                    that a freedmanm had been shot on the evening of sunday the 7th inst. by a law
                    Student at this place named J. C. Johnson -- it seems, from what I can learn
                    that Johnson was in company with a colored woman, named Milly, a freedman who
                    was nearby was accused by Johnson of watching him. The freedman, viz Patrick
                    Thompson denied that he was watching Johnson, some words passed, Johnson went
                    off and borrowed a pistol came back and called the negro a damned son of a bitch
                    at the same time discharging the pistol he had borrowed at him. Johnson
                    immediately turned and walked away, Thompson at first did not know that he was
                    shot, but after Johnson disappeared in the darkness the freedman placed his hand
                    upon his side and exclaimed I am shot.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>This occured about 8 <abbr expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> P.M.</p>

                <p>The ball entered the body of the Freedman below the fifth rib and passed
                    downwards severing the intestines and lodging in the abdomen. Thompson died on
                    the day following (Monday) between the hours of twelve and one <abbr
                        expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> PM.</p>

                <p>Owing to the indifference and want of energy manifest on the part of the civil
                    authorities Johnson was not arrested, on the contrary it seems that every
                    facility was afforded Johnson to enable him to make his escape, notwithstanding
                    the general opinion of the public pointed to Johnson as the guilty party, a
                    citizen of the town cashed a cheque for him, before bank hours, and he hired a
                    pair of fine horses at the livery stable connected with the Lexington Hotel, and
                    a freedman was sent to drive the horses for Johnson to Goshen, (a railroad
                    station on the <abbr expan="Virginia Central Railroad">Va.C.R.R.</abbr> some
                    twenty miles from this point) and then to return the horses to the Hotel at
                    Lexington.</p>

                <p>Johnson started at 1/2 <abbr expan="past">p</abbr> 7 or eight <abbr
                        expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> in the morning (Monday) so you see it was not
                    necessary for him to steal away, but on the contrary he was allowed to go off in
                    good style and in broad daylight, and according to all reports armed with a pair
                    of revolvers and a bowie knife.</p>

                <p>When Johnson's guilt could be concealed no longer, a warrant for his arrest was
                    placed in <pb n="3"/>the hands of the town sergeant, but he was for a long time
                    unable to obtain a horse or any one who would consent to accompany him.</p>

                <p>Finally he secured the assistance of a one legged Englishman (with two horses)
                    who consented to accompany him. Several parties attempted to <orig
                        reg="dissuade">dissuaide</orig> the town sergeant from pursuing Johnson,
                    stating that Johnson was well armed and would resist any force under six men.</p>

                <p>Owing to the difficulty the town <abbr expan="sergeant">serg't</abbr> met with in
                    obtaining horses and a man to accompany him, he was unable to start in pursuit
                    of Johnson until about 8 <abbr expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> P.M. of the 8th inst
                    thus giving Johnson twelve hours start.</p>

                <p>Now sir, if the above facts are not sufficient to prove that the mass of the
                    people were not desirous of bringing Johnson to justice, the fact that two men
                    were allowed to start in pursuit of him, one an old man of small stature, and
                    the other a man with only one leg, (while Johnson is a man six feet tall and
                    stout in proportion) I think is conclusive evidence that the pursuit if such it
                    may be called was only a sham.</p>

                <p>And I am told by reliable white men who reside here that many of the citizens
                    express a hope and desire that Johnson will not be caught.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>As his trial will only add to the expenses of the county, some again seem to
                    think it would be well if a few more were shot.</p>

                <p>This is the second man who has been shot in cold blood in this place during the
                    past two months.</p>

                <p>I trust troops will be sent here in a few days, as it is quite evident the civil
                    authorities cannot keep the students and cadets in subjection.</p>

                <p>Should you desire a copy of the evidence aduced before the <orig reg="coroner"
                        >corroner</orig>, I will obtain it and forward it to you.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am Sir<lb/>Your <hi rend="underline">
                            <abbr expan="obedient">obdt</abbr>
                        </hi> Servant</salute>
                    <signed>G B Carse<lb/><abbr expan="Brevet">Bt</abbr> Colonel and <abbr
                            expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> Bureau of <abbr
                            expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R.F. and
                    A.L.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
