<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1201"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1201">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: H. H. Peck to [W. Storer
                    How], March 28, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records h h peck to w storer how, march 28 1866</title>
        <author>Peck, H. H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1201</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501060</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: H. H. Peck to [W. Storer How], March 28,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records h h peck to w storer how, march 28 1866</title>
            <author>H. H. Peck</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 57.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-03-28">1866-03-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Aid/Relief, Economy, Local Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-06">June 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1201T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Peck, President of the Augusta County Overseers of the Poor, explains what
                    resources the county may be able to provide to help support poor blacks. He
                    seems optimistic that the county will be able to provide such support through a
                    tax levy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">The Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen &amp; Abandoned
                        Lands<lb/>Winchester <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-03-28">March 28 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Augusta County <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>As President of the Board of Overseers of the Poor of Augusta County, I beg to
                    make the following reply to your communication of the 26th inst.</p>

                <p>I cannot undertake to anticipate what the County Court of said County (the only
                    body having power to raise money for County purposes) will do at its annual levy
                    courts in June next, but I feel authorized to say that the Board over which I
                    preside will ask that a sufficient sum shall be levied for to meet the
                    necessities of the destitute persons having a claim upon legal residence in the
                    County without regard to color or class, and I entertain no doubt but that said
                    Court will make such levy and to that end, will assess an equal poll or
                    capitation tax on <hi rend="underline">all</hi> male inhabitants of the fixed
                    age &amp; who may not be exempt on account of physical infirmity.</p>

                <p>We expect to provide as heretofore for all the destitute alike if
                    <unclear>our</unclear> people can stand the burden. We have a house of reception
                    for the paupers (to which is attached a farm) capable of accomodating about
                    sixty persons and have always made special appropriations (administered <pb
                        n="2"/>by members of our board) to aid in the support of poor persons not
                    inmates of the poorhouse.</p>

                <p>In asmuch as we cannot forsee what number of helpless or idle persons may be
                    thrown upon the charity of the county for support, and as it cannot be
                        <unclear>expected</unclear> that any large amount of tax will help
                        <unclear>amply</unclear> or be collected of the freedmen it is impossible to
                    anticipate <unclear>whether</unclear> the amounts we may have levied will be
                    sufficient to meet all wants of the poor &amp; needy.</p>

                <p>I cannot say <hi rend="underline">now</hi> what the poll or other tax will be. We
                    have our <unclear>stated</unclear> meeting to fix the sum <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> apply for in the <unclear>deemed</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in next month. If an estimate shows <unclear>f---</unclear>
                    that of the population in view it will be because there are more from in our
                    county having <unclear>d------</unclear>, than we are aware of or because our
                    people are too poor, under present circumstances, to meet the demand, and if
                    there should be a deficiency we <unclear>have</unclear> the Federal Government
                    will <unclear>continue</unclear> it and its funds.</p>

                <p>Nothing can be expected from the <unclear>contemplated</unclear> levy until the
                    end of the present year as the collection cannot account for the time &amp;
                    any help given before that time <hi rend="underline">must</hi> be in the faith
                    &amp; credit of the County.</p>

                <p>I am not the representative of the Town of <pb n="3"/>Staunton, but feel
                    justified in saying that the overseers of the Poor acting in its behalf are
                        <unclear>activated</unclear> by sentiments similar to those I have expressed
                    for my board, but in as much as there has been an <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> influx of
                    freedmen into the corporation from surrounding counties, I think it <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> at present the people can well meet all demands the destitute
                    may make on its means, and <unclear>consequently</unclear> help may be needed of
                    the Federal Government.</p>

                <p>Of one thing we can speak with certainty, everything humanity &amp; justice
                    may require within our ability to come up to will be done to
                    <unclear>alleviate</unclear> &amp; make contented &amp; compatible the
                    freedmen who have been thrown upon us for support, protection &amp; <del
                        hand="h1"/>.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am very respectfully<lb/>your <abbr expan="Obedient">Obt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Servant">Servt</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>H. H Peck, President of the Board of Overseers of the Poor of <abbr
                            expan="Augusta County">A.Co.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
