<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1219"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1219">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Frederick S. Tukey to
                    Orlando Brown, March 11, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records frederick s tukey to orlando brown, march 11 1867</title>
        <author>Tukey, Frederick S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1219</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501068</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Frederick S. Tukey to Orlando Brown, March
                            11, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records frederick s tukey to orlando brown, march 11 1867</title>
            <author>Frederick S. Tukey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 67.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-03-11">1867-03-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Church/Religious Activity, Community
                        Values/Local Behavior, Education, Legal System, Patriotism,
                        Politics/Political Attitudes, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-06">June 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1219T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Tukey responds to a request from the Assistant Commissioner, and provides a list
                    of six whites and six blacks who can possibly serve as community leaders. Tukey
                    comments on the political attitudes and loyalty of the white citizens, and on
                    the literacy and general character of the black citizens he lists.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet Brigadier General">Bvt. Brig.
                        Genl</abbr> O. Brown<lb/>Richmond, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-03-11">March 11th 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr>
                    </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have the honor to report in compliance with yours of the 8th inst. the names of
                    six white citizens and six Freedmen of Augusta County, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr> who I think answer all the points mentioned in yours.</p>

                <p>1st. David Fultz - a Lawyer by profession, of eminent legal attainments, a
                    consistent loyal man during the war and since, an "old line Whig" stands
                    politically on middle ground between the President and Congress, is opposed to
                    the "<unclear>Sherman</unclear> Bill" as a means of punishing the south, but
                    very decided in his opinions, that Davis, Lee and all the leading spirits of the
                    rebellion should be hung, expresses these sentiments freely to loyal and
                    disloyal, capable of filling any position in the State.</p>

                <p>2nd John B. Evans, Merchant, an "old line Whig," moderate and conservative, is a
                    representative man of the middle class of southern Society, known to have
                    entertained Union sentiments through the war, neither of the above mentioned men
                    held any position whatever under the Confederate <abbr expan="Government"
                    >Govt</abbr>.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>3d John W. Alby, Merchant - an "old line Whig," moderate and highly conservative,
                    has always been in favor of accepting the "constitutional ammendment," held no
                    position under Confederate <abbr expan="Government">Gov't</abbr>, and is
                    perfectly reliable under all circumstances.</p>

                <p>4th Edward M. Cushion - Commission Merchant &amp; Auctioneer, an "old line
                    Whig" was a general <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt</abbr> in the <abbr
                        expan="Quartermaster">Q.M.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Department">Dept.</abbr> under the Confederate <abbr
                        expan="Government">Govt.</abbr> and is now a Magistrate, is much respected
                    by all classes of white and black, was for many years a leader of a colored
                    class in the <abbr expan="Methodist Episcopal">M.E.</abbr> Church and is much
                    respected by Freedmen, very conservative upon the doctrine of secession, and
                    denounces the Southern press generally.</p>

                <p>5th Jacob Stover - an "old line Whig" loyal all through the war, had a Son in the
                    federal Army, a man of intelligence and reliability, and all right.</p>

                <p>6th John M. Gates - "old line Whig" loyal through the war, for which he was twice
                    imprisoned in <unclear>Castle Thunder</unclear>, has the confidence and respect
                    of all classes. Post Office address, "Mount Sidney," <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va.</abbr> at which place he is <abbr expan="Post Master">P.M.</abbr></p>

                <p>This completes the six, and the Post Office addresses of all, except the last, is
                    Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. I have been particular to select men
                    who would answer all your requirements, and at the same time, have mentioned
                    some points not alluded to by you.</p>

                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>Freedmen</p>

                <p>1st John Christian, keeps an eating Saloon, is a man of good sound, common sense,
                    and writes a very good hand, is all right in sentiment and principle, and
                    repsected by both races.</p>

                <p>2nd James Carter - Farmer, writes a very good hand, is a Christian man, and much
                    respected by both races.</p>

                <p>3d - Frank Overton. Laborer, writes his name indifferently, but has good common
                    sense and the respect of all classes.</p>

                <p>4th Jacob Thornton. Laborer, writes his name, is intelligent, and answers all the
                    points.</p>

                <p>5th, Henry Davinport - cannot read or write, but has a high degree of practical
                    common sense, and eminently noted for his piety, and it is said (I cannot vouch
                    for the truth of it) that when he prays in a building that has a shingled roof,
                    the roof always has to be patched the next day.</p>

                <p>6th Wright <orig reg="Bolding">Boldin</orig>. Laborer and is all right.</p>

                <p>It will necessarily take me several days, and perhaps a week, to obtain the
                    desired information from Highland County, for there are not probably more than
                    one hundred Freedmen in the <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> and they are so
                    scattered, that it will be very hard to ascertain their whereabouts, and select
                    suitable ones.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>F.S. <hi rend="underline">Tukey</hi>, <abbr
                            expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst. Supt.</abbr></signed>

                    <pb n="4"/>

                    <seg type="postscript">Should you, judging from my description of the white men,
                        think that either one of them will not answer the purpose, you can
                        substitute the name of John Parris, an old line Whig and all right. Post
                        Office Address, <hi rend="underline">Staunton, VA</hi><lb/>F.S.T.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
