<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1237"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1237">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Annie A. Dunn to Orlando
                    Brown, March 23, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records annie a dunn to orlando brown, march 23 1867</title>
        <author>Dunn, Annie A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1237</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501085</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Annie A. Dunn to Orlando Brown, March 23,
                            1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records annie a dunn to orlando brown, march 23 1867</title>
            <author>Annie A. Dunn</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 23.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-03-23">1867-03-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Education, Administration/Bureaucracy, Community Values/Local Behavior,
                        Family, Women, Employment/Labor</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-06">June 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against the original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1237T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Dunn contests her dismissal as teacher in Staunton and her transfer to North
                    Carolina by N.C. Brackett, the Superintendent of Schools for the Shenandoah
                    Valley. She claims that her dismissal is the direct result of evidence she gave
                    in the case related to the conduct of Frederick Tukey (her brother-in-law) and
                    George Cook, both Bureau Agents in Staunton. The students and parents of her
                    school would later sign a petition for her reinstatement.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="section" id="endorsement">
                <p>Bureau <abbr expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R.F. &amp;
                    A.L.</abbr><lb/>Sub <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr> Augusta &amp;
                    Highland<lb/>Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="April">Ap.</abbr> 15, 1867<lb/>Respectfully returned to <hi
                        rend="underline">J.A. McDonnell</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Superintendent"
                    >Supt.</abbr> 9th <abbr expan="District">Dist.</abbr>, ample school facilities
                    are already provided at Staunton for the education of Freedpeople. I cannot
                    recommend that the request of Mrs. <hi rend="underline">A.A. Dunn</hi> be
                    granted, so far as it involves expense to the Bureau <abbr
                        expan="Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">R. F. &amp;
                        A.L.</abbr><lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho.P. Jackson</hi><lb/><abbr
                        expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr></p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d5">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Brevet Brigadier General">Bvt. Brig.
                        Genl.</abbr> O. Brown<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Commissioner">Asst. Comr.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands">B. R. F.
                            &amp; A. L.</abbr><lb/>Richmond, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-03-23">March 23rd 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Feeling that I have been unjustly dealt with in regard to School matters at this
                    place, and hoping you will pardon the liberty I take in thus addressing you upon
                    the subject, I have concluded to submit a plain statement of the facts in the
                    case, for your kind consideration. First then permit me to say that this is my
                    third year in the work, the first two being under the <abbr
                        expan="American Missionary Association">A.M.A.</abbr> and this, the third,
                    under the Baptist Home Mission Society and I think I can truly say that I have
                    labored as earnestly, and zealously, as perhaps any other teacher, and been as
                    deeply interested in the education of the freed children, as I possibly could
                    have been, and never to my knowledge has there been one word <pb n="2"/>of fault
                    found with me until now. And even now the <abbr expan="Superintendent"
                    >Supt.</abbr> of the Schools here informs me, that he has no fault whatever to
                    find with me as a teacher. What then, may I ask, have I been guilty of, that
                    should cause my dismissal? - before answering this question however, permit me
                    to state the facts in the case, everything so far as I know, up to the time that
                        <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> McDonnell came here, was going on
                    smoothly, when I was called upon, in connection with all the rest of the
                    teachers, to state what I knew about <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr>
                    Cook's conduct while here, and my answers to the questions put to me,
                    necessarily cast some reflections not only upon him, but some of the teachers,
                    and perhaps the general conditions of the Schools - but I only answered such
                    questions as were asked me, volunteering nothing, and leaving out much that I
                    might have said.</p>

                <p>Soon after the <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> left here, I receieved a letter
                    from the <unclear>rooms</unclear> at New York saying that Mr. Brackett had
                    informed them, that I could be spared from the Valley and assigning me to
                    Goldsboro <abbr expan="North Carolina">N.C.</abbr> and saying that my
                    transportation would be forwarded in a few days. To this I immediately replied
                    requesting them to withhold my transportation a few days. In the meantime I had
                    a conversation with Mr. Brackett (the <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr>)
                        <pb n="3"/>in which he informed me of his action, but said he had found no
                    fault with me as a teacher, and the only reason he had given for my removal was
                    that some of the teachers had united against me on account of my evidence. I
                    then wrote to <abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr> again stating to them that I
                    was twelve hundred miles from home, and was boarding with my Sister here, and I
                    thought it very hard to be sent away for no other offense than simply telling
                    the truth, which to answer my question, is the only crime of which I have been
                    accused. To this letter I received a response in substance saying that they had
                    been informed by Mr. Brackett that I was not needed here nor in the Valley.
                    Notwithstanding this, one new teacher has been brought here since, and one
                    school now stands adjourned for the want of a teacher. I was, as you will
                    readily see, forced either to go to Goldsboro, or give up my school. And in
                    deciding which to do, I took it into consideration that I was the only teacher
                    here that was here last year, and that I had a Sister here with whom I was
                    boarding, and not one of the others had any family connections here whatever.
                    And as I had been guilty of nothing for which to be transfered, painful as it
                    was to me, I could not make it appear to be my duty <pb n="4"/>to go. And now in
                    conclusion, I desire to know if you in your official capacity, cannot employ me
                    as a teacher, under the Auspices of the Bureau. If this is impossible, will the
                    Bureau furnish me with a building in which to teach, provided I do it
                    gratuitously? I had a very large school of 95 Pupils, and to which I had become
                    very much attached. Now if you can do me the favor to arrange matters so that I
                    can stay with it, you will place me under great obligations to you. Hoping to
                    hear from you at an early date.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am Very Respectfully Yours,</salute>
                    <signed>Mrs. Annie A. Dunn</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
