<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B2020"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B2020">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to R.
                    M. Manly, October 17, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to r m manly, october 17 1867</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B2020</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501135</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Thomas P. Jackson to R. M. Manly, October
                            17, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records thomas p jackson to r m manly, october 17 1867</title>
            <author>Thomas P. Jackson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Superintendent of Education for the State
                            of Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands,
                            1865-1869, Record Group 105, M1053, Roll 7.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-10-17">1867-10-17</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Aid/Relief, Education, Women, Violence/Crime,
                        Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-06">June 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B2020T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jackson writes to Manly about a conflict between the Bureau and its school with
                    the Methodist Episcopal Church in Staunton. Jackson alleges that Frederick
                    Tukey, the Bureau's former agent in Staunton forged a letter and made
                    unspecified claims about the current condition of schools there. Jackson refers
                    to Tukey's tenure as the "old regime" and urges Manly not to appoint any
                    teachers associated with Tukey, including his wife. The letter also discusses in
                    some detail the conflict with the church about the allocation of space for a
                    school room.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <hi rend="underline">Confidential</hi>
                    
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> R. M.
                        Manly<lb/>Richmond</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-10-17"><abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 17 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>A letter dated Staunton <abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 4/67 <hi
                        rend="underline">purporting</hi> to be but <hi rend="underline">not</hi> in
                        <hi rend="underline">E. Lawson's</hi> handwriting, forwarded by you to Mr.
                    Whipple <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 8 has been sent here for <hi
                        rend="underline">recognition</hi>. Some statements are palpably and some
                    inferentially untrue and did it not reflect upon the present condition of
                    schools and lead to a possible supposition that my application for aid in
                    fitting up the room here was unnecessary, <del hand="h1">I will</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">should not, as I <hi rend="underline"
                    >must</hi></add> say the letter is written by Mr. Tukey and is only a
                    continuation of the <unclear>undermining</unclear> operation which the schools
                    here have had to contend against from the same source. In fact, "the house" was
                    rented for school purposes at $25 per month because there was <hi
                        rend="underline">no place</hi> in which to teach school as the church
                    building spoken was <hi rend="underline">not even roofed in</hi>. Through the
                    influence of Mr. Brackett, seconded by yourself the <abbr
                        expan="Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands"
                    >B.R.F.&amp;A.L.</abbr> appropriated $300 in aid on the condition that the
                    building aided should accomodate all scholars in Staunton.
                    <unclear>Promises</unclear> were fairly made but when Mr. Bowser, the
                        <unclear>co'd</unclear>
                    <pb n="2"/>presiding elder came to Staunton he candidly told me that under no
                    circumstances would he permit the use of the church upper room for school
                    purposes, nor ever <add hand="h1" place="inline">give</add> an assurance of
                    continued possession of the basement (which <hi rend="underline">only cost
                    $150</hi> in addition to the contract) for school purposes if I paid over the
                    $300 which I of course declined to do. The basement has not been <hi
                        rend="underline">fitted up even yet</hi> and when the estimable ladies who
                    have left, taught a <hi rend="underline">pay</hi> school <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">after the close of regular session</add> which of course was
                    small <unclear>compared</unclear> with a <hi rend="underline">free</hi> school
                    the room was unfit to accomodate any orderly school, but when school was talked
                    of for the winter and I applied for the room the Trustees, induced I expect by
                    the writer of the letter in question, asked $15 per month and would not <hi
                        rend="underline">fix up for a school room</hi>. Feeling that after the
                    church had <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> $1,000 from the N. <abbr
                        expan="Methodist Episcopal">M. E.</abbr> conference and repeated aid from
                    the Bureau and Teachers, I proposed to expend $100 in fitting up the room to be
                    occupied <hi rend="underline">rent free</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">for the season</hi> which they refused, and took no steps
                    to fit up at all. The parents of the children began to complain bitterly, many
                    claiming they had subscribed their money for a school house, not a church. Mr.
                    Brackett came here and a meeting was called which I attended with him and laid
                    the case so strongly before them that the <pb n="3"/>Trustees were shamed into
                    doing something and agreed to give the room free if I would get them $100 to fit
                    up, which thanks to you, I have obtained from the Bureau and I expect to have
                    the room ready for permanent school on Monday <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr>
                    21. The $60 alluded to was begged I believe in aid of the main building if used
                    for a school but (as I with the $300) they properly refused to give it to a
                    church who would not <hi rend="underline">encourage</hi> even a school. The
                    conceit spoken of was got up at great labor by the Teachers and the money raised
                    which was a mere trifle expended for <hi rend="underline">school</hi> but not
                        <hi rend="underline">church</hi> purposes. The <hi rend="underline"
                    >real</hi> writer of the Lawson letter did not even attend the concert nor has
                    given a cent or even an hour labor in Sabbath school. The <hi rend="underline"
                        >real object</hi> of the letter is not to aid the cause of education but to
                    bring Mr. Scott here under <abbr expan="American Missionary Association">Am.
                        Miss. Assn.</abbr> &amp; through him employ Mrs. Tukey and Miss Dunn as
                    Teachers. To accomplish this "financial" desideratum every effort has been made
                    and if fair means <pb n="4"/>were used or good would result I should gladly say
                    "Take the work". We have now 112 scholars registered for Miss Rowells school a
                    number she cannot possibly control but I cannot recommend that Mr. Scott or any
                    one who would bring back the "old regime" be sent to aid her, as the <hi
                        rend="underline">joint</hi> work would certainly prove unpleasant and so far
                    unprofitable.</p>

                <p>I fear my letter to you may offend Mr. Brackett and I trust it will be
                    confidential <hi rend="underline">except</hi> in so far as it may affect your
                    opinion of my application for aid, and even by inference reflect upon the
                    active, conscientious and able management of Mr. Brackett or his teachers.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Faithfully yours</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">Thos P. Jackson</hi>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Excuse my hurried letter, TPJ</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
