<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="BD4000"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 

<TEI.2 id="BD4000"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Freedmen's Bureau Register of Complaints</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county freedmens bureau register of complaints</title>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Desi Hopkins, Virginia Center for Digital History</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 546 kilobytes</num>
      </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">BD4000</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>copyright 1993-2006, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2005">2005</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500342</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Freedmen's Bureau Register of Complaints</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county freedmens bureau register of complaints</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>321 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records Administration, Records of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, Record Group 105, Box E4273.</idno> 
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt> 
            <note>
              <p>Register of Complaints consists of 2 bound volumes, both of which are waterstained, resulting in the high frequency of illegible words. The two bound volumes are chronological, with the exception of some court case summaries from 1865 inserted at the beginning of volume 2. The transcription of the register follows a strictly chronological format.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1865" to="1868">1865-1868</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Aid/Relief, Community Values/Local Behavior, Education, Employment/Labor, Family, Legal System, Property, Race Relations, Slavery, Violence/Crime, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="BD4000T">

<body id="d2">

<div1 id="BD40001865" type="part" n="1865">
<head>1865
<!-- <ref>BD40001865</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1865-11" id="d4">
<head>November 1865, W. Storer How 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Women, Family, Property, Violence/Crime, </ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-14" id="d5">
<head><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 14 1865</head>
<p>Dinnah Ross. Complains that Mr <orig reg="Hoshour">Hushour</orig> owes her for two months Labor from April 3rd to June 1st 1865</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-15" id="d6">
<head>15</head>
<p>Melinda Dyer complains that Mr Chample refuses to give her clothes for Hire.</p>

<p>Lusum Bell complains Mr <orig reg="Hoshour">Hushour</orig> at the insane <orig reg="Asylum">Assylum</orig> owes her for two months Labor at five Dollars per month</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-16" id="d7">
<head>16</head>
<p>Eliza Jackson complains that her Brother Samuel turned her out of Doors and drove her from his House under circumstances <unclear>perticularly</unclear> trying to her and refused to pay her her wages which he collected from her Employer.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-24" id="d8">
<head>24</head>
<p>William Crosby complains that the <unclear>Freedmen</unclear> in his precincts refuse to work out their <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>supt</unclear> precinct is on Morris Mill Road 2 1/2 <abbr expan="miles">ms</abbr> from Staunton.</p>

<p>Edward Walton<lb/>
<unclear>Cherish</unclear> Brigg complains that you owe her Seven Dollars that you borrowed of her if this is true you will please pay her</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-25" id="d9">
<head>25</head>
<p>Abraham Griffith complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Morris</unclear> <del hand="h1">complains</del> owes him three Dollars for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> which he refuses to pay</p>

<p>Harry Spears complains that George <unclear>La---</unclear> owes him ten Dollars which he refuses to pay lives near Turks Gap.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-11-27" id="d10">
<head><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 27</head>
<p>Lucy Moore complains that Sarah Lavelle owes her for two months Hire at four Dollars ten months which she refuses to pay Lives near Mint Springs</p>

<p>Dolly Mines complains that John Dooms beat her boy in an unmerciful Manner lives on Winchester Pike 2 1/2 <abbr expan="miles">ms</abbr> from Staunton</p>

<p>Samuel <unclear>Shirpie</unclear> complains that himself &amp; four brothers have worked for the Widow Harper since the first of April &amp; she refuses to pay them Lives on South River near Sherando Draft</p>

<p>James Richard complains that David Koiner owes him for seven months work which he refuses to pay Lives for <unclear>Mo</unclear> on Port Republic Road</p>

<p>Benjamin Robinson complains that Franklin Myers owes him for six weeks Hire at fifty <abbr expan="cents">ct</abbr> per week</p>

<p>Joseph Jones complains that John <unclear>Rich</unclear> owes him for eight months &amp; eleven days Hire at ten <abbr expan="Dollars">Dolls</abbr> per month which he refuses to pay</p>

<p><unclear>Sherril</unclear> Woods complains that <unclear>Lucah</unclear> Bouman owes his wife for Hire from about the first of March until about one week before Christmas which she refuses to pay, lives six <abbr expan="miles">ms</abbr>
 from <unclear>S</unclear> on the Middlebrook Road</p>

<p>Allen Lewis complains that Daria <unclear>H--ts</unclear> owes him for hire from the Fall of Richmond to July 1st 1865 which he refuses to pay, lives on Christians Creek.</p>

</div3>

</div2>

<pb/>

<div2 type="section" n="1865-12" id="d11">
<head>December 1865, W. Storer How 
<!-- <ref>Legal System, Race Relations, Violence/Crime, Employment/Labor, Property</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1865-12-22" id="d12">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 22</head>
<p>Cases tried before the <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> of Bureau Refugees, Freedmen &amp;c and Board of Commissioners at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></p>

<p>W<hi rend="super">m</hi> J Shumate (<abbr expan="white">w</abbr>) vs Elijah Strother (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>)<lb/>
Defendant charged with assult and Battery and trespass.<lb/> Court met at 10 o'clock.</p>

<p>Testimony of W<hi rend="super">m</hi>. J Shumate Complainant.<lb/> Defendant had been in my employ, but went off, then came back and said I was not satisfied with him - told him I was not. Defendant became angry, when I told him get his clothes, and leave my premises. Went in the kitchen where <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>d----</unclear> <unclear>knives</unclear> and seemed much in a rage. Got my gun and approached him, when he went <unclear>of.</unclear> <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> came again to the <unclear>Cabin</unclear>, then <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> struck him with a stick, <unclear>collared</unclear> him and took him to town.</p>

<p>James Spears (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) evidence for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.<lb/> <unclear>Plain</unclear> called me over to his house and asked my advice <del hand="h1">my</del> about the matter. Said defendant came out of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> with knife drawn. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> went off grumbling <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> no threats to Mr. Shumate.</p>

<p>Thomas <unclear>Stegdale</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) evidence for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.<lb/> <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> struck Def, several times with a stick <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> went off saying he would make <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> pay for it.</p>

<p>Geo. Stegdale (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) Evidence for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.<lb/>
Saw <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> come out of the cabin with his <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>in his</unclear> pocket. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> struck <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> with a stick. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> made no resistance.</p>

<p>Testimony of Elijah Strother (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) - Defendant<lb/>
Went to <orig reg="Plaintiffs">Plaintifs</orig> house in the morning <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> asked me if I was going to work - told him no. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> told me to leave. Went to the Cabin to get my clothes, there saw <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> approaching with gun and took my knife in my hand for protection. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> said he would kill me
<pb/>
if I did not leave in five minutes, and would blow my brains out if I came there again. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> then struck me several times with stick. I made no resistance.</p>

<p>Benjamin Morton (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) testimony for <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr><lb/>
Only saw the last part of the difficulty. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> struck <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> several times with a stick - saw no arms.</p>

<p>Sarah Morton (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) testimony for <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr><lb/>
<abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> came to the cabin after his clothes. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> struck <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> several times. Def could <add hand="h1" place="inline">not</add> have gotten his clothes in five minutes.</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Judgment</hi><lb/>
Charge of assault and Battery not sustained. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> found guilty of trespass, and reprimanded by the Court, and instructed to keep off Mr. Shumates premises.<lb/>
The Court then Adjourned</p>

<p>Kendal Rhodes (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">m</hi>
</hi>. McCausland &amp; Whitmore (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>)<lb/>
Defendant charged with violently assaulting <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> with <unclear>intent</unclear> to maim Disfigure &amp;c<lb/>
Court met at 10 o'clock</p>

<p>Testimony of Kendal Rhodes (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) - <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> that McCausland accused him of removing some hogs. <unclear>Next day</unclear> McCausland came to see him about the hogs. Did not call him any bad names. Drew a pistol and made him go to the Barn. McCausland and Whitmore attacked him McC. struck him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> blows on head and arm. Had a rock to defend himself. Did not use the rock.</p>

<p><unclear>Wm</unclear> Swishers (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for <del hand="h1"><orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig></del> Defendant.<lb/>
Saw nothing of the assault. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> led him to believe that he referred to Defendant as having killed the hogs.</p>

<pb/>

<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">m</hi>
</hi>. Harner's (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Saw Whitmore raise the stick over <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>, who back to the stable and picked up a rock to defend himself with. Saw McCausland strike <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> with stick and then told Whitmore to hand him a pistol. McC struck <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> a heavy blow.</p>

<p><abbr expan="Doctor">Doct.</abbr> Kennerly's (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
There was a rumor about the hogs. Suppose the <unclear>Blow</unclear> was given on horseback, and that it would be heavier than if given on foot. Would not suppose the blow to be very serious. Defendants have a good character.</p>

<p>Judgment<lb/>
Whitmore to pay a fine of fifteen Dollars and give Bond to the sum of one hundred Dollars ($100.00) to keep the peace to all freedmen for 1 year. McCausland to pay a fine of five Dollars ($5.00) and give Bond in the sum of fifty Dollars ($50.00) to keep the peace against all Freedmen for one year.<lb/>
<hi rend="underline">Court adjourned</hi></p>

<p>Lindsay Mitchel (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Jacob Sherer (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>)<lb/>
Defendant charged with assaulting and beating <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> in the street of Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.<lb/>
Court met at 10 o'clock.</p>

<p>Testimony of Lindsay Mitchel (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) - <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.<lb/>
Was passing quietly along the street when Defendant threw a popcracker at him. Told Defendant not to repeat the offense when Defendant assaulted him, think other parties assisted in the assault.</p>

<p>Franklin Rhodes (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) testimony for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Only saw blows passed between the parties. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> asked Defendant not to throw <unclear>squi-</unclear> at him. Scherer then struck <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.</p>

<pb/>

<p>W<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">m</hi></hi>. Fretwell's (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Thinks Scherer threw a squib. Saw Defendant going towards <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>, and had a knife in his hand. Knows that the squib was not thrown at any particular person.</p>

<p>J. Johnson's (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for Defendant<lb/>
Saw Defendant throw a squib which struck <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> on his hat. No harm was intended.</p>

<p>Jacob Parent's (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) testimony for Defendant.<lb/>
First saw <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> and Defendant fighting, Separated the parties.</p>

<p>Judgment<lb/>
Defendant discharged.<lb/>
<hi rend="underline">Court adjourned</hi></p>
</div3>

</div2>

</div1>



<div1 id="BD40001866" type="part" n="1866"><pb/>
<head>1866
<!-- <ref>BD40001866</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-01" id="d14">
<head>January 1866, W. Storer How 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Property, Women, Family, Community Values/Local Behavior, Patriotism, Violence/Crime, Legal System</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-01" id="d15">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr>
 1st 1866 Staunton <unclear>June</unclear></head>

<p>Nancy Carter complains <sic>than</sic> Jno. Shuey owes her for the hire of her son from the fall of Richmond to 23 <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 1863. Also that Shuey will not deliver her sons clothing <orig reg="bedding">beding</orig> &amp;c. Shuey lives 8 miles out on the Middlebrook Road.</p>

<p>Jefferson Nash complains, through Geo Steel that Robt. Banks will not pay <del hand="h1">for</del> the value of a watch said money to have been paid 6 months since. <del hand="h1">Steel</del> Banks lives in town. <abbr expan="amount">amt.</abbr> $13</p>

<p>Thos Jefferson complains that R J Hope is indebted to him for services rendered from the fall of Richmond to 20th <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> Case tried before the Court. Judgement for <abbr expan="Plaintiff">Plain</abbr> for <unclear>$1.50</unclear> settled.</p>

<p>Jacob Page complains that Jno R Circle owes him for services rendered from the fall of <abbr expan="Richmond">Rich.</abbr> to June 1st Circle lives 8 miles below <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig> on South River</p>

<p>Hanible Lewis complains that Wm B Keys owes him for services rendered from the fall of Richmond to <abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 25th 1865 lives in town.</p>

<p>Ashbury Baily complains that Wm Newman is indebted to him the sum of $2.25</p>

<p>Reuben Brackenridge complains that James A Austen owes him for services rendered from the fall of Richmond to 25th <abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr>
 1865 Austen lives on South river beween Greenville and <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig>.</p>

<p>Hanible Lewis complains that James Bumgardner refuses to deliver his daughter to him.</p>

<pb/>

</div3>


<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-02" id="d16">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 2nd</head>

<p>John Ashby (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains through John P How, <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Winchester, that Alexander Gardner owes him for 30 Days services rendered. <del hand="h1">Jo</del> Alex. Gardner lives at Mint Spring.</p>

<p><unclear>Wm</unclear> Ingleman complains that Ben. Stewart owes him $19 for making and trimming part <unclear>a coat</unclear>  Stewart has sent him word to sell the cloth as he was not able to pay for him <unclear>Mr.</unclear> Ingle has been authorized to sell the cloth and if <unclear>he brings</unclear> more than $19 - the excess is to be turned over to this office.</p>

<p>Archer Brack complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Fishburn at <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig> will not <unclear>fi--</unclear> him possession of a horse which is his property. Case dismissed.</p>

<p>Isac McChesney (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Wm L Dinkle owes him $10.28 Dinkle lives at Buffalo Gap. Complaint satisfied.</p>

<p>Isac Halker (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Washington <unclear>Patterson</unclear> owes him for three <unclear>months</unclear> labor Patterson lives 1 mile below Fishersville</p>

<p>Ashbury Baily complains that William Jordan residing ten miles <add hand="h1" place="inline">from</add> Lexington owes him fifteen Dollars Matter referred to <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Lexington May 26th write to <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Lexington <abbr expan="received">Rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> <abbr expan="answer">ans</abbr> to effect nothing has been done</p>

<p>Charles Brown complains through Taylor Nichols that Henry Koiner will not deliver his child to him.</p>

<p>Chas Brown complains through Taylor Nichols that Jno Koiner will not deliver his child to him.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-06" id="d17">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 6th</head>

<p>Eliza Murray complains that her Husband W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Murray deserted her some three weeks since and married another woman in Richmond. Matter referred to <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> Merril <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Richmond.</p>

<p>Lavenia Carter complains that Mr. Houshour hired her son during the year 1864 for which to furnish him with board and clothing and has failed to furnish him with his winter shoes.</p>

<p>Harrison Keys complains that Richard <unclear>Terril</unclear> will not deliver a house in <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig> which Keys has rented  <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>  treated the order with contempt</p>

<p>Harriet Irving complains that Jerome Sellers will not furnish her clothing as per agreement <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the <unclear>girl</unclear> or send her to this office address Churchville</p>

<p>Samuel M Hawkins Loyal White refugee <unclear>complains</unclear> the year 64 Rudolph Tusk rebel Quartermaster <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> his horse for the <unclear>allies</unclear> of Rebel Government  horse <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> placed in <unclear>Chas</unclear> Byers possession who gave him to his Father in law Samuel Bell who used him for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> case to be considered.</p>

<p>Allen Stewart (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Wm Robinson owes him wages from the fall of Richmond to 1st Day of <abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> 66. Mr. Robinson will pay the <abbr expan="amount">amt.</abbr> in about 2 weeks. Balance $14.00</p>

<p>Paid. Burke Henderson complains that Wm Snead owes him $12.25 <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> paid.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-06" id="d18">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> 6</head>
<p>[Text from summary of: "Cases tried before the <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> of Bureau Refugees, Freedmen &amp;c and Board of Commissioners at Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>"]</p>

<p>James Roswell (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) V.s. Cha<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">s</hi></hi> Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>)<lb/>
Defendant charged with assaulting and beating Defendant<lb/>
Court met at 10 o'clock</p>

<p>James Roswell (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <orig reg="Plaintiffs">Plaintifs</orig> testimony<lb/>
Jacksons son promised a girl a shawl. Called me a liar son of a Bitch &amp;c at Church. Jacksons son asked to go with him. Went to the house of Jackson father, Jacksons father then beat me without enquiring into the matter.</p>

<p>Testimony of Geo. N. Burgis, for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Saw young Jackson hunting for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>. Defendants son called <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> a son of a Bitch at church.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Testimony of Alexander Nallins for <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Saw Defendants son draw a knife on <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>. <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> did not want to <del hand="h1">call</del> go and fight Defendants son, when Defendants son called <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> a d__m coward.</p>

<p>Cha<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">s</hi></hi>
 Jackson's (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) testimony - <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig><lb/>
Heard that my son and Roswell was in a fuss - warned my son not to have any difficulty, was at home and heard Roswell call my son out to settle the matter - went out and thrashed <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig></p>

<p>Testimony of James Queen (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) for Defendant<lb/>
Saw <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> and Defendants son quarreling at Church. Saw Defendant strike <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> at Defendants house</p>

<p>Testimony of W<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">m</hi></hi>
 Washington (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) for Defendant<lb/>
Saw <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> and Defendants son clinch at Church. Heard nothing said</p>

<p>Testimony of Ben Downing (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) for Defendant<lb/>
Saw <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> and Defendants son quarreling Defendants son swore he would whip <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig> before he went away.</p>

<p>Judgment<lb/>
Defendant found guilty and fined three Dollars ($3.00)<lb/>
Court adjourned</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-15" id="d19">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 15th</head>

<p>Joshua Jons (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Washington Dudley (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) has charged him with receiving stolen corn from Jno Boyer (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) thus injuring his good name and character. Dudley lives two miles <unclear>this</unclear> of Churchville  <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> denied the charge.</p>

<p><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 15</p>

<p>Joseph Black (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Mr. Walker owes his daughter ten Dollars <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear</p>

<p>Eliza Trimble complains through her husband Chas Trimble that Ben Lines, near <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig> will not deliver her clothing to her. Party notified Evidence to be sent in form of affidavit.</p>

<p>Betsey Lockley (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) complains that Morris Porter owes her for 5 or 6 months work. <abbr expan="Defendant">Defen.</abbr> notified.</p>

<p>Frank <unclear>Pai</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Geo. Moyers owes him $24.50 <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> required to appear. <abbr expan="defendant">def</abbr> will pay a part in a week and the balance some <add hand="h1" place="inline">time</add> after.</p>

<p>Joe Berry (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Jno Noonan (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) violently assaulted him by striking him on the head with a rock. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-18" id="d20">
<head>Jan 18</head>
<p>John <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>----estian</unclear> complains that Marcelles Taylor (<abbr expan="white">w</abbr>) owes him ten Dollars <add hand="h1" place="inline">borrowed</add> from him under false pretense want his money. Taylor lives with L Harrison, Barber, Lynchburg to be referred to the <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Lynchburg, Referred.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-18" id="d21">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 18th</head>

<p>John J Christian (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Betty Bird (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) borrowed two Dollars from him under false pretenses wants his money  <abbr expan="defendant">def.</abbr> paid 1.50.</p>

<p><del hand="h1">Dave</del> A freedman named Dave Copple complains that Mr. <add hand="h1" place="inline">Add.</add> Henry owes him twenty Dollars <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> lives at Midway.</p>

<p>James Harris complains that Harman Green owes him 7.50. Defendant to appear. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> admits the Debt and will pay as soon as he can.</p>

<p>Sarah Jackson <add hand="h1" place="inline">complains</add> that Caroline Minor stole 500 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> minor <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> is at Louisa <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> House at <abbr expan="Doctor">Doct.</abbr> McClains.</p>

<p>Joe Sawers (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that James <unclear>Hi---</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him a balance of $30 and fifty five bushels corn <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> lives 1 mile above <unclear>Churchville</unclear>.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-23" id="d22">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 23</head>
<p>Sallie Price complains that Robert McCutchen owes her for two or three months pay since the fall of Richmond. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-24" id="d23">
<head><abbr expan="January">"</abbr> 24</head>
<p>John Venable complains that James Crawford (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him three months wages. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> notified to appear.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-25" id="d24">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 25</head>

<p>Lewis Pryor (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John VanLear (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) assaulted him with a pitchfork - struck him and attempted to stab him with the same <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear. Case dismissed.</p>

<p>Mrs. Julia Hurly (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that Robt Kenney (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) is indebted to her in the sum of twenty two Dollars and fifty cents. <abbr expan="defendant">def</abbr> appeared - settled to the mutual satisfaction of both.</p>

<p>Mariah Moor complains that Henry Moore owes her five Dollars and that Bob Kenny owes her two dollars for a watch guard and Ben. Brock owes her seventy five cents.</p>

<p>Lucinda Brooks complains that Jacob Farmer has a horse which is her property. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def. </abbr>
notified to appear.</p>

<p>Addison Stewart (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that <abbr expan="Doctor">Doct</abbr> Theadore Davis has two children which he (Stewart) wishes possession of. Ordered that <abbr expan="Doctor">Doct.</abbr> Davis retain the children in his possession.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-01-31" id="d25">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 31st</head>

<p>Freedman Isac complains that Joshua Jones and Geo See assailed his house with rocks and clubs and tried to get him out and threatened to kill him at some future time. <abbr expan="Defendants">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>

<p>Thomas <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Mitchell (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that he has a child, 9 years of age in his possession and that an Uncle of the child wishes to take her away. Mr. Mitchell claims that he has taken care of the girl since she was born, clothed her &amp;c and wishes her to be bound to him. M lives 5 miles west of Staunton on the Central <abbr expan="Railroad">R R</abbr>.</p>

<p>Ann Banister (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) complains of Mr. MC Locklin in regard to a house. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear.</p>

<p>Hudson Harris complains for his wife that Jno Thomas owes her for 1 months pay <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> will pay for three weeks and wishes to have his house now occupied by <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>.</p>

<p>Jerry Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Finley Humphreys near <del hand="h1">Lexington</del> Greenville, owes him for more than two months work. <abbr expan="Defandant">Def</abbr> required to appear.</p>

<p>May 25 Sent Notice to Humphries to appear. - Brown states that he has 6 six <abbr expan="bushels">Bu</abbr> of wheat of him since the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>. Settled by <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> G.T. Cook June 11th 1866.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-02" id="d26">
<head>February 1866, W. Storer How 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Legal System, Family, Women, Property, Patriotism, Violence/Crime, Slavery </ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-02-01" id="d27">
<head><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 1st 1866</head>

<p>Caroline Peneton (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) complains that her husband is in <orig reg="Charleston">Charlestown</orig> and will not support her. has three children.</p>

<p><unclear>Kinny Brow</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John Avis former rebel <abbr expan="Provost Marshall">Pro. Mar.</abbr> of Staunton sold her in Richmond the first of last year and kept her bed, chest of valuable clothing, sold her furniture &amp;c, Complain wants to bring action against him for the recovery of the same. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> lives in <orig reg="Charleston">Charlestown</orig> <orig reg="West Virginia">Va.</orig> Matter referred to <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at Harpers Ferry. <orig reg="Plaintiff's">Plaintifs</orig> witnesses Margaret Pain and Patsy Lee. Dicey White.</p>

<p>Jno Carter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Martin Murray (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him seventeen Dollars. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear. Settled to the satisfaction of both parties.</p>

<p>Mary Jane Robinson complains that Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> Lindsay will not deliver clothing to her Daughter Nancy Robinson. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>

<p><unclear>Cot</unclear> Williams complains that Henry Jackson stole a quantity of Boots &amp;c on the night of the 7th. Evidence heard. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> admits the theft and most of the goods has been recovered. <unclear>Prisoner</unclear> remanded to Jail.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Eveline Stewart complains that Charlotte Terrey will not comply with contract in regard to renting a house. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> to appear.</p>

<p>Thos Gilbert (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Thos Burk owes him fifty Dollars. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear. Case dismissed.</p>

<p>Jeff Bell (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that <add hand="h1" place="inline">your</add> J. McChesney is going to put him and family out of Doors after promising to let them remain during the winter. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> notified.</p>

<p>Ben Brock complains that V. Huffman owes him Eight Dollars <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> required to appear.</p>

<p>J H Hill complains that <unclear>Chas Bethel</unclear> owes him $10.00 in specie and $11.00 in Greenbacks.</p>

<p>Ben. Downing complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Margaret Crawford owes his Daughter labor performed from 3rd April 63 to 1st <abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 64. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-02-23" id="d28">
<head><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 23</head>

<p>Antonia Bannister complains that A K Snapp owes her ($1.50) <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> appeared and paid <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> claimed.</p>

<p>Milly <del hand="h1">Patter</del> Sibert complains that during the war Jacob Sibert, her former master, died leaving a provision in his will for her support during her life. Sibert lives in three miles from Monterey, Highland <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. Henry and Jacob Sibert were the administrators. <unclear>Witnesses</unclear> to will, Thomas and <unclear>Mo</unclear> Beveridge.</p>

<p>Henry Jones (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John Ecker (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him and his son for labors performed. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to settle.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-02-24" id="d29">
<head><abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 24</head>

<p><unclear>Harvey</unclear> Hawkins (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that James Thomas owes him for value of a watch. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear next Saturday at 10 o'clock</p>

<p>Martha Stewart complains, for her Brother that Henry Bannister got a pistol from him and has probably gone to Winchester.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-02-29" id="d30">
<head><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 29</head>
<p>Henry Lacy and Eliza Jones complains that John Opie owes them ten Dollars each for a job of work. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>
 ordered to appear.</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-03" id="d31">
<head>March 1866 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Legal System, Property, Community Values/Local Behavior, Women, Violence/Crime, Slavery, Politics/Political Attitudes, Local Government</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-05" id="d32">
<head><abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 5th</head>

<p>John Sea <add hand="h1" place="inline">(<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>)</add> complains that Harrison <unclear>--let</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) has failed to comply with a contract to haul him two loads of hay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>

<p>Philip <unclear>Haters</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that W <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Lange</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) has failed to comply with an agreement for a compensation if he would stay to work for him up until the 1st of <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr>
 1866. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear. <hi rend="underline">Dismissed upon investigation</hi>.</p>

<p>Carter Jones (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Jack Nicholas (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him three Dollars and fifty cents <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he refuses to pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay it</p>

<p>Maria Miller (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) complains that Robert Coleman (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) deceived her <unclear>by promise of marriage</unclear> and now refuses to have anything <unclear>to do with her</unclear> <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-06" id="d33">
<head>" 6th</head>
<p>John Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Kinkade (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him thirteen Dollars <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he <del hand="h1">was</del> is in great need of and can get <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>faction from the <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> ordered to appear. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> ordered to pay the debt and has arranged to do so.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-07" id="d34">
<head>March 7th</head>

<p><unclear>Cyrus</unclear> Johnson &amp; Addison Day (<abbr expan="Freedmen">F</abbr>) complain that <unclear>Jos</unclear> Reynolds (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owe them seven Dollars and 50/100 which he refuses to pay <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear. <hi rend="underline">Settled</hi>.</p>

<p>Addison Day (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Jos Reynolds (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) made an assault and battery upon him without provocation. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear. Fine of $1.<hi rend="super">00</hi> imposed &amp; paid.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-09" id="d35">
<head>"  9</head>
<p>George Vaughn (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that William McKee (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him the balance of $22. 50/100 on four months <del hand="h1">work</del> and half's work @ $8.00 per month. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to settle with him or appear here and show good reasons for not doing so.</p>

<p>William Gibson (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that George (formerly slave of Dr. Straus) has been notified to leave his present abode but has not done but still remains and is in various ways using the said Gibson's property.</p>

<p>Mrs Harper is to be seen on complaint of W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Boyer (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) she lives near Barter Brook.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-10" id="d36">
<head><abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 10th</head>

<p>Sophia Huskel <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> complains that Benjiman T Bagby has cruelly treated her son <abbr expan="Defendant">Def.</abbr> ordered to appear on Saturday 17th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>. <hi rend="underline">Dismissed</hi>.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-12" id="d37">
<head>"  12</head>

<p>Saml Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that David Effinger (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) refuses to pay him $6 25/100 for chopping ten cord of wood. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. ordered to pay or show reasons for not doing so.</p>

<p>John W. Barger (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Archie Smith (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him <hi rend="super">$2.<hi rend="underline">00</hi></hi> for a coat and will not pay him. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. ordered to pay or appear here &amp; show good reasons for not doing so.</p>

<p>John Alexander (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Ja'<hi rend="super">s</hi>
 Bryan (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) made an assault and battery on him without provocation. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. ordered to appear on Tuesday the 13th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>. Dismissed.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-14" id="d38">
<head>"  14</head>

<p>T M Mitchell (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that James Henry (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) has possession of his house and does not fulfill his bargain to work <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to appear.</p>

<p>John Shiffley (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Nelson Reeves has a horse which his father bought from one Preston Reeves. Nelson Reeves ordered to give up the Horse or appear here &amp; show reasons for not doing so.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Henry Robinson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Ms. Louisa Gibson owes him a balance on his wages from April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1865 - up to <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1866. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. ordered to pay or appear here on Wednesday <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1866 &amp; show cause for not doing so.</p>

<p>John Galaway (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John <unclear>Heurley</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him $1 80/100 cents and will not pay him <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-15" id="d39">
<head><abbr expan="March">"</abbr> 15</head>
<p>Dan<hi rend="super">l</hi> Carter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John Stafford (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him $86.67 which <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> he will not pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay or appear here to show cause for not doing so.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-17" id="d40">
<head><abbr expan="March">"</abbr> 17</head>

<p>Lewis Farrow (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that John A Brownlee (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him $23.<hi rend="super">50/100</hi> for <orig reg="labor">labour</orig> and refuses to settle <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> order to appear or settle with the <abbr expan="Plaintiff">Plt.</abbr><lb/>
 Decided by payment of $13.65 to <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintive</orig>.</p>

<p>Adam Lambert (Refugee) entered the <abbr expan="United States">U S</abbr> Service 23d of <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 1864 &amp; was discharged 28 day of June 1865 - offered to vote at two Elections but was refused.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-19" id="d41">
<head><abbr expan="March">"</abbr> 19</head>
<p>John Beck (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that Calvin Trice (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him $5.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">00</hi>
</hi> for rent and will not pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay or show good cause for not doing so.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Michael McGuinty (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that Sam<hi rend="super">l</hi> Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him $26.<hi rend="super">64</hi> and refuses to pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay or appear at this office on Thursday 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> to show good cause for not doing so</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-23" id="d42">
<head>" 23d</head>
<p>Austin Harden (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Benj M Lines (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes him $10 <hi rend="super">00/100</hi> and will not pay him. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. order to pay or appear &amp; show cause for not doing so. <hi rend="underline">Dismissed</hi>.</p>

<p>Henry Gordon (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that a Mr. Mathew living about 3 miles from Afton Depot Albemarle <abbr expan="County, Virginia">Co Va</abbr> owes him $9.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">00</hi>
</hi> for horse hire. Case referred to <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt</abbr> Joyce at Charlottesville for investigation.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-26" id="d43">
<head>" 26th</head>
<p>William Huskil (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Benj T Bayley owes him $44<hi rend="super">00/100</hi>
 and a pair of boots and will not pay him.</p>

<p>George Davis F complains that Dan'l Carter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes $4<hi rend="super">30/100</hi>
 &amp; will not pay <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr>. ordered to pay immediately.</p>

<p>Dr William Chapman (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that Chas Wollford (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him $9.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">00</hi>
</hi> and desires the debt &amp; will not pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> at work for Mr Riley's near Mr Shumates.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-28" id="d44">
<head><abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 28</head>
<p>Mr R G Bickle complains that David Lewis (<abbr expan="colored">cold</abbr>) owes him for rent and will not pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-29" id="d45">
<head>" 29</head>
<p>Malinda Arkett (<abbr expan="colored">cold</abbr>) complains that Mrs Addison Fisher (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes her $2 <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">50/100</hi>
</hi> for attention to her daughter during her confinement &amp; will not pay: <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-03-31" id="d46">
<head>"  31</head>
<p>Jimmie Eidson (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) complains that William Stuart owes her one Dollar balance for making an overcoat. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay.</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-04" id="d47">
<head>April 1966 
<!-- <ref>Property, Employment/Labor, Family, Legal System, Community Values/Local Behavior, Violence/Crime, Local Government, Women, Aid/Relief, Military Authority, Slavery</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-01" id="d48">
<head><abbr expan="April">Apl</abbr>
 1st</head>
<p>Miss Elizabeth Doom complains that George (a Freedman) owes her six months rent and will not pay and refuses to vacate the premises. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay &amp; vacate</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-03" id="d49">
<head>"  3<hi rend="super">d</hi>
</head>
<p>Henry Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that Joe McCutchey (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him $6 <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">90/100</hi>
</hi> and will not pay. <abbr expan="Defendant">Def</abbr> ordered to pay or appear at this office on Saturday April 7th to show cause if any for not doing so.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-07" id="d50">
<head><abbr expan="April">Apl</abbr> 7<hi rend="super">th</hi>
</head>
<p>John Robinson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that having made contract with Mr. Hushour, <abbr expan="Steward">Stew<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> of the Hospital by which his wages $10 per month, were to be paid monthly Mr. Hushour has neglected to pay him as agreed upon having <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> only one <add hand="h1" place="inline">half</add> months pay in four months; also that he, John, is not allowed to visit his family as often as agreed upon.</p>

<p>Case of Betsy Galloway and Sarah Craig to be heard on Monday 9th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> at 2 p.m</p>

<p>Mrs Jeannette Martin asks for the custody of her nephew and niece, now with Dr Davis, order given her revoking any previous orders in the case.</p>

<p>Joshua Baker complains that Dabney Trice neglects and refuses to close a contract with him after having put him off from time to time and in the meanwhile keeps Joshua at work without any contract between them, the matter has been standing three months.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-09" id="d51">
<head>" 9th</head>
<p>W. A. Davis (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) leaves bill against Richmond Brown (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) with request that if <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Monday next 16th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>, Browns <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> $5.00, has been due since 20th <abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr>.</p>

<p>Mrs Francis Parrish, Harpers Ferry wishes to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> information of her two children, Virginia <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Elizabeth, and also of her Mother Charlotte Casell <unclear>were</unclear> in the <abbr expan="Freedman's">F</abbr> School here in <unclear>D</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> send money to pay their fare to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> where they are.
<lb/>She has also two children Eliza <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at Bridgewater, living with Mr. <unclear>J----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sibert at that place, gave her order to <unclear>K---y</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-xx" id="d52">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p>Mr J B Finley, <unclear>Willow Spout</unclear> <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> Augusta wishes to obtain a good female cook, washer and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> who can also milk.</p>

<p>Case of Betsy Galloway &amp; Sarah Craig heard <unclear>this</unclear> P.m. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> loaned to Betsy a silk dress valued at $29 and some <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and borrowed from Betsy some clothing, valued at $10.50 Betsy afterward sold Sarah's dress for $4.00, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> ordered to pay Sarah $10.00 in full settlement.</p>

<p>Melinda Askill, or Mrs. Addison Fisher, upon complaint of Mrs. <unclear>----kill</unclear> that <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> had sold her furniture and was about to leave for Richmond, issues summons to appear at 3 p.m <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to show cause &amp;c &amp;c</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-10" id="d53">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 10</head>
<p>at 10 a.m. commenced investigation of the case of Commonwealth vs A.W. <unclear>Greaver</unclear>, adjourned at 5 P.M. until 10 A.M. tomorrow.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-11" id="d54">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 11</head>
<p>Continued the investigation &amp; at 5 P.M. adjourned until 9 A.M. tomorrow.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and at 3.30 P.M., having heard <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> closed the investigation.</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-12" id="d55">
<head><abbr expan="April">Apl</abbr> 12</head>
<p><unclear>W</unclear> <unclear>--pa</unclear> <unclear>Williams</unclear> makes a complaint that <unclear>Dav---</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> bought a bonnet from her valued at $13.00 and made it a present to a <unclear>freedwoman</unclear> of this City, that he left the City and is <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at Hot Springs <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Defer action for a few <unclear>days</unclear>.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-13" id="d56">
<head><abbr expan="April">Apl</abbr> 13.</head>
<p>Mr. Risk reports that Tom <unclear>Ho------</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> has in his possession a <unclear>freedgirl</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Mary Jane Philips, and Mrs <unclear>Jane</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> same place has a boy, John E. <unclear>Gr----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the same way , whom they refuse to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> their mother Phebe Ann Philips, <unclear>Philips</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brownsville, Rockbridge <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. </p>

<p>Robert Miller (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains <add hand="h1" place="inline">that</add> Charles <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> taken down a fence belonging to him, and had <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the materials, sent Thompson note asking him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> this office to explain; parties live at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>. (<hi rend="underline">note afterwards <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to Mr. Lilly</hi>).</p>

<p>Upon complaint of Marian <unclear>Hinde</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> issued summons to <abbr expan="Defendant">dft</abbr> to appear <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> now to answer plea of debt.</p>

<p>Heard case of ------ and Caroline <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> wife.</p>

<p>Forwarded report of inquiry to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Commonwealth over to <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> <abbr expan="Orlando">O.</abbr> Brown.</p>

<p>W<hi rend="super">m</hi>
 Brown vs W<hi rend="super">m</hi>
 Dinkle: -<lb/> Witnesses: John Stover, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Lambe</unclear> to be heard <abbr expan="Saturday">Sat.</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Richard Brown to W.A. Davis <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $5.00 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of books; if not paid before <abbr expan="Monday">Mon.</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> that summons issued, Davis is <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>

<pb/>

the country to work, money may be paid to his wife Mrs. Kitty Davis, Witness for <abbr expan="plaintiff">pltf</abbr>, W. M. Craig.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-xx" id="d57">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Par--t</unclear> Chief of Police reported having arrested <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> a colored man named Dick <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> drunk and disorderly in the streets.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  Crawford reports that his sister, Becky Crawford <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> three children has been working for Samuel Finley <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Middle River, all the time since the Surrender, and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--sed</unclear> no pay or wages of any kind, has been turned away <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the place with her children with hardly clothes enough <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> them.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>B---son</unclear> complains that Mr. Rosenbaum employed him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> carrying wood and cleaning out his home, and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> paying him offered him an old coat which <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> want, to call at <unclear>0</unclear> <abbr expan="o'clock">o'clk</abbr> on Monday</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>hearing</unclear> of the case of Commonwealth vs Chas Trayer, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> as Rafe Willis, Trayer (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) was charged with <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and disorderly and with obstructing the steps at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Willis, and when requested by W to leave, violently <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> chasing him into his own (W's) room and there <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>until</unclear> dragged away by a third party, Magistrate <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> over in $50 each to keep the peace for six <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> gross injustices had been done to the colored <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> this decision forwarded report of the case to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brown.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to Mrs. Addison Fisher to appear tomorrow at

<pb/>

10 AM answer Melinda Askill, and have <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> some service upon her.</p>

<p>Melinda Askill vs. Ms. Addison Fisher, dismissed, it <unclear>appearing</unclear> that the debt was not contracted by <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr>, but by the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> daughter.</p>

<p>W. A. Davis vs Richard Brown - <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> appeared and denied that he owed the amount claimed, deferred until Davis returns to the City.</p>

<p><abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> of Mr. J. E. Hiden, Twenty Dollars <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the claim of Martha ---- against Mrs. <unclear>Walker</unclear></p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-18" id="d58">
<head>"  18</head>
<p>Issued summons to Jas E. Carson, <orig reg="Middlebrook">Middlebrooke</orig> to appear on Saturday 28th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>, to answer complaint of Jos Harrison - : enclosed it to Adam <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>table</unclear> at <orig reg="Middlebrook">Middlebrooke</orig> for services.</p>

<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Brown, statement of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Chaney, under sentence of death.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-19" id="d59">
<head>"  19</head>
<p>Mrs Lucy J. Snyder complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> owes her $3.50, which he refuses <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Harvey Turner through Mr. Parkins <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he was set for by his <unclear>marchers</unclear> with <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> died about 10 years ago: has been working <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>sation</unclear> except <unclear>brandg</unclear> and clothes: <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> looked into.</p>

<p>Mrs. Martha A. Myers (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) represents that Mrs. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Robinson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) has been at her house since last fall, that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Franklin Myers owes Lorinda for hire and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of

<pb/><unclear>dress</unclear> and refuses to pay her.
<lb/>Summons to appear on Monday 23rd at 10 a.m.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-20" id="d60">
<head>"  20</head>
<p><unclear>Benj</unclear> <unclear>---lton</unclear> vs Elijah Strotter, debt, summons to appear Monday 23rd at 10 a.m.</p>

<p>Rafe Willis vs. Mrs. Louisa Greaver, Louisa has a <unclear>counterpane</unclear> belonging to Willis which she is about to sell for half its value, for a debt which Willis owes her, summoned both parties to appear this <abbr expan="evening">evg</abbr>.</p>

<p><unclear>Sophie</unclear> Witt complains that her husband Walter Witt has deserted her and refuses to support her, married at Nelson <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> by clergyman last August, summons to <abbr expan="appear">app</abbr> tomorrow morning at 10 o'clock.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brown vs W<hi rend="super">m</hi>
 Dinkle issued summons to parties for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 28th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> at 10 o'clk; forwarded them to Jos <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> constable for service.</p>

<p><unclear>A---y</unclear> Bailey (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) made complaint against his <unclear>em-----</unclear> H.M. McCont for non fulfillment of his contract <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for defendant, and in settlement received note <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for $29.00 at 60 days, note to be retained <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> maturity.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> vs Jas Kinkaide, Rent due 10.50, half <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> April, not paid yet.<lb/><unclear>Kinkaide</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Dr Dold, near Tinkling Spring Church.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-21" id="d61">
<head>"  21</head>
<p>Bartley Gillan makes complaint in regard to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> who owes him Six Dollars, will accept <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> who employs them both.
<lb/>Also B.G. has an order of Sarah Strong <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="Blacksmith">Blksmith</abbr> in Irish Ally for 1.45 for <unclear>Sch----</unclear> <unclear>Mem</unclear>: to see Neliger and Moore, and call upon <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> day <abbr expan="evening">evg</abbr>.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-23" id="d62">
<head>"  23</head>
<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> How, statement of case of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> a colored woman of Carrol <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>.</p>

<p>Summons to George Vance, McDonnell, Highland <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> colored girl named Hughes, sent through Wm <unclear>Lowell</unclear> <unclear>Esq</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of Highland County.</p>

<p>Addison Wilson, a colored boy complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> working for his old master Dr John <unclear>McCh---y</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> render until last Christmas, Dr. Jno <unclear>McC-----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Creek <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O</abbr>.</p>

<p>William Patterson complains that a family of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> with him, unruly, &amp;c, and that he is <unclear>unable to</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he is given some authority over them.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-24" id="d63">
<head>"  24</head>
<p>Charles Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to his shop some six weeks ago, with a <unclear>note purporting to be</unclear> signed by Mr. Fisher, and upon that refuses <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> a pair of boots that had been made for <unclear>Fisher</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> afterwards that it was not so:<lb/>
Sent for Mr. Fisher requesting him to bring the note to this office.</p>

<pb/>

<p>W. F. Mills complains that Henry ------ has stolen from his barn some bacon; referred to civil authorities.</p>

<p><unclear>Harriet Sage</unclear> (at Mr Taylor at the Bank) makes complaint that Henry Moore has been owing her $12.00 since last <unclear>fall</unclear> sent him a summons to appear.</p>

<p>Issued summons to Sam'l Scott, assault upon his sister in law.</p>

<p>Betty Scott, old and infirm, requested transportation for <unclear>herself and</unclear> great grand son Wm Nelson, five years old and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to Warm Springs.</p>

<p>Wm. J Dews vs John Briggs, debt $3.00 <unclear><abbr expan="Defendant">Def't</abbr> ordered</unclear> to appear at 2 P.M., Settled by <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft</abbr> and <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> paid to Dews</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr> vs Harriet Diggs, rent due $10.00, <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft</abbr> ordered to pay on 1st May</p>

<p>Wm <unclear>McCourt</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) reports that Jacob <unclear>Bachi</unclear> on South River owes Louisa Greaver 3 <abbr expan="Dollars">Dolls</abbr>, her husband <unclear>Prix</unclear>------- lives with his mother on head of Rockfish, and refuses to support her, Sent for <unclear>Louisa</unclear> to come in and make her own statement. Sent summons by Louisa to settle or appear on Saturday <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-25" id="d64">
<head>"  25</head>
<p>Present at hearing before <abbr expan="Justices of the Peace">J.P.s</abbr>
 H.H. Peck <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of Henry Woodson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) on charge of stealing <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> cow property of Wm. F. Mills, forwarded <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of Commonwealth, case continued until tomorrow <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>.</p>

<p>------- Sarah Calloway vs George Hall, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> barter <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> $2.16, <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft</abbr> directed to pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-26" id="d65">
<head>"  26</head>
<p>Received notice of the arrest of Robt <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for stealing goods from Adams Express <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Samuel M. Hawkins vs Samuel Bell <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Joseph <unclear>Wanger</unclear>, witness: Summons issued to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> appear on Saturday May 5th at 10 A.M.</p>

<p>Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> Wholey vs Jas Cooper (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>), it appearing that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> about to leave town with his family and not pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  summons to appear at 8 A.M. tomorrow.</p>

<p>Henry Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) confined on the 5th <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>------ Present at a hearing before Justice <unclear>E---</unclear> of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Ann L. Lewis <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> on charge of stealing a box <unclear>con----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> discharged</p>

<p>--- Case of Henry Woodson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <unclear>continued</unclear>, Deft <unclear>committed</unclear> to term of County Court</p>

</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-27" id="d66">
<head>April <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  a hearing of Elijah <unclear>Strotter</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) on a charge <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> a peice of calico from Mr Waller, Justice Evans <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $30 - for appearance at County Court.</p>

<p>Issued warrant to Jacob <unclear>Larrent</unclear> for arrest of James <unclear>Gib---</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> goods under false pretenses.</p>

<p><unclear>Forwarded to</unclear> <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Brown requesting transportation for Betty <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  to <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Meige. Papers of Dr. Shelton; to <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> <unclear>Fel--</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>provision</unclear> return for May</p>

<p><unclear>Robert</unclear> Logan complains that James Harris owes him <unclear>$-.00</unclear> sent notice for <abbr expan="Defendant">Def't</abbr></p>

<p><unclear>Thos</unclear> <orig reg="Wholey">Wholley</orig> vs Jas Cooper; dispute as to rent, decided that Cooper should release the house of <orig reg="Wholey">Wholley</orig> on the 2d May and pay him $12-- rent for the month of April</p>

<p><unclear>Louisa Greaves</unclear> <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> complains that her employer Wash'<hi rend="super">t</hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> has turned her and her boy off, refusing to pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and retaining the boy's overcoat, summons to appear for Monday, <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> called &amp; settled to <abbr expan="paying">payg</abbr> $<hi rend="underline">1.00</hi>.</p>

<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> How, statement of case of Mrs. Ellen <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of a refugee</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-28" id="d67">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 28</head>
<p>Summons to Jas Kincade to answer John Jackson on Monday <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Debt for rent $10.50</p>

<p><unclear>Mrs Hughes</unclear> makes statement that Mr <unclear>Crase</unclear> is about <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>a bakeoven</unclear> attached to her house by the Rebel  <unclear><abbr expan="Quartermaster Department">Q.M. Dept</abbr>
</unclear> during the war, and possession of which had been guaranteed to her; sent for Mr. Crase and <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> <unclear>B----</unclear>

<pb/>and after having directed the removal of the oven to be suspended until Tuesday morning.</p>

<p>Rhoda Brock states that she was freed by <unclear>de----</unclear> of her mistress some three years ago; was afterward hired by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> master to Dr McFarlane, has <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> nothing but a <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of <unclear>flour</unclear> send request to Dr McFarlane at appear</p>

<p>Wm Brown vs Wm Dinkle; postponed at request of defendant until Saturday, May 5th</p>

<p>----- Present at hearing before Justice Evans, Commonwealth vs James Frayer, and same vs James Robinson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="defendants">dfts</abbr> bound to keep the peace in $100 for six <abbr expan="months">mos</abbr>.</p>

<p>Jonas Laney (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) states that the wife and children of <unclear>W---</unclear> Davis have been depending upon him for support since last <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> that Davis is in a dying condition, and that he <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>not</unclear> able to keep the family, having one of his own, the Overseer of the Poor of his <abbr expan="District">Dist.</abbr>, refuses to do anything <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> an order from the Court; overseer is Jas Wilson, <unclear>Churchville</unclear> <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> (see below)</p>

<p>Joseph Harris vs James Carson, <unclear>Wednesday</unclear> <add hand="h1" place="inline">May <unclear>9th</unclear></add> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><unclear>Ms Margt Trevey</unclear>; property destroyed by Federal troops, papers sent to Richmond some months ago, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> heard from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Jonas Lainy as above complains that Francis <unclear>Gilken</unclear> agreed last fall, to pay him of keeping the woman and children above named: has not done so, summoned Gilken for Monday May 21.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Received information of the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Ransom (Jr) on a charge of breaking into home of <unclear>Wm Dinkle</unclear> and stealing goods to amount of <unclear>$</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> prisoner committed for trial upon his own confession of the crime.</p>

<p>Allan Lewis (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that his two daughters <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> aged 22, the other 16, have been seduced; and the oldest by a white man <add hand="h1" place="inline">name unknown</add> the youngest by a colored man who has a wife and two children; both the girls have children, he asked that some action may be taken to compel these men to contribute to support of the children.</p>

<p>Miss Amanda Hall complains that two of her fathers <unclear>h--</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> from her on Tuesday last, without any legal process <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Tullermans</unclear> Constable, upon a claim of Rudolph <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> father William Hall kept out of the Rebel Army <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> spring of '64, served in it about a year and the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and went to Missouri &amp; Indiana; horses went <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the ground that the family were about to leave <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> him; Hall owes <unclear>Tuck</unclear> about $500, for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the horses were taken, address <orig reg="Middlebrook">Middlebrooke</orig> <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr>
</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-05" id="d68">
<head>May 1866 
<!-- <ref>Administration/Bureaucracy, Property, Employment/Labor, Women, Community Values/Local Behavior, Violence/Crime, Slavery, Legal System, Military Authority</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-03" id="d69">
<head>May 3d</head>
<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="Major">Maj.</abbr> How, Monthly reports, and Requisition for Postage, Stamps</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>shirts</unclear> $1.25 each, <abbr expan="United States Government">U.S. Govt</abbr>. <abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> for contract between W.G. Snapp and <unclear>G</unclear> Washington <unclear>$0</unclear></p>

<p><unclear>W F Snapp</unclear> Distiller, four miles out on Parkersburg road wanted a colored woman to do housework</p>

<p>Ellen Jackson vs <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt</abbr> Francis Roberts, Debt $14.00 sent summons to <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> through <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr>
</p>

<pb/>

<p>Mrs Diana Koiner <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> makes complaint against her husband, George Koiner, for desertion since shortly after their marriage in June last, mailed warrant for arrest of Koiner to Wm Bush, Constable, Waynesboro; Mrs. Koiner's address is Arbor Hill <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> at Mr Franklin Strauss</p>

<p>Cyrus Crawford complains that he and his wife have been working for Mrs Lavinia Allen, and her son L. B. Allen, and that the Allens refuse to comply with their agreement made in <abbr expan="October">Octo.</abbr> '65.</p>

<p>Richard H. Brown complains that while engaged on the <unclear>platform</unclear> getting baggage from the Car he was assaulted <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the head with a stick by Mr <unclear>Doon Water---</unclear> <unclear>at the platform</unclear></p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-04" id="d70">
<head>"  4</head>
<p>D McGuffin (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) charged Harvey <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (Jr) with stealing a <unclear>front</unclear> wheel from his buggy on Saturday last, referred to civil authorities, hearing at 9 A.M. before Mayor Trout, continued till tomorrow at 9 A.M.</p>

<p>John K Kaiser states that Fielding Washington holds in his possession a note which Kaiser assigned to him against John D Brooks, of <unclear>Shaw &amp; Brooks</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> it collected for Washington's benefit, sent summons to Brooks by Mr Kaiser for Saturday May 12th</p>

<p>Same complains that Antony Jackson neglects to provide for his family, and idles his time, sent notice to him by Kaiser to be served by Wm. <unclear>Bush</unclear> Waynesboro</p>

<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="Brigadier General">Brig Gen'l</abbr> James, Receipts of Bumgardner &amp; <unclear>McC</unclear> and Thos Bethell, to R.M. Atwood, <abbr expan="Medical Officer">Med. Offr</abbr>, Report of <unclear>Blind</unclear> Refugees; to Jas M. Seig, Monterey, Circular in regard to <unclear>Taxes</unclear></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-05" id="d71">
<head>May 5</head>
<p>Present at a hearing of Henry ------ charged with taking a wheel belonging to D. McGuffin; <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> bound over in $100 to answer before Hustings Court in July next</p>

<p><unclear>James</unclear> Hawkins vs Sam'l Bell; postponed until Saturday 19th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr></p>

<p>Wm. Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Wm Dinkle, case heard before the Freedmen's Court, present, Risk, Dews, &amp; Tukey <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> decision of the Court that the case be dismissed upon each party pay the cost of summoning its own witnesses</p>

<p><abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> from William Boyd - $2.00 for <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> of Mary Ann Hunter <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> paid the <abbr expan="amount">amt</abbr> to Mary Hunter May 12th</p>

<p>John Wm Alexander vs Mansfield King, Jackson's River <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr>, John was formerly owned by King, last May and June, two months he worked for King for $10 per <abbr expan="month">mo</abbr>; never got anything for it, it appearing that <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> resides in Alleghany <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <unclear>advised</unclear> <abbr expan="Plaintiff">Pltff</abbr> to bring case before <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> Carse</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-07" id="d72">
<head>"  7</head>
<p>Washington Ellis complains that his wife and two daughters have been working for Daniel Wilson, near West View, since the surrender, received no pay or clothing; <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> is father of Jas A. Wilson, Constable at West View</p>

<p><unclear>O---</unclear> Dunning vs Benj T. Bagby, <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> refuses to pay for labor done <unclear>upon a</unclear> house; summons sent by <abbr expan="Plaintiff">Pltff</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> heard and decided that Henry Moore was to pay <unclear>Oby</unclear> the <abbr expan="amount">am't</abbr> which he (Moore) had received of Bagby</p>

<p>Forwarded to <abbr expan="Major">Maj</abbr> How, Report of cases tried week ending May 5th to <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> Cook, letter of <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Vance, McDowell</p>

<p>Summons for arrest of John Stafford handed to Mr <unclear>Parrent</unclear>

<pb/>

<abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> arrested: - and having postponed till <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-08" id="d73">
<head>"  8</head>
<p>Parties in above case Billy Addison vs John Stafford settled by Stafford paying $.95 <abbr expan="cents">cts</abbr></p>

<p>W. D. <unclear>Poe</unclear> complains that a colored man named <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--ber</unclear> has slandered his character by representing that <unclear>Poe</unclear> is living with his Barber's wife; summons for Saturday 12th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> at 1 P.M. - Witness - Robert Van Lear &amp; Mrs Henry Palmer</p>

<p>Brown Lidsay vs W<hi rend="super">m</hi> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Fall; <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> for wages, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> to settle or appear. <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> settled May 15th <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>his</unclear> paying $2.00 <abbr expan="balance">bal</abbr> of <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr></p>

<p>W. D. Poe vs Ben Barber, dismissed at request of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Joseph Harrison Jr., vs Geo Greaver Sr, debt: - <abbr expan="balance">bal</abbr> of <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> $6.80</p>

<p>Joseph Harrison Sr. vs James Carson, before <unclear>Board</unclear> of Agents, postponed until Monday June 4th to take testimony of one Jacob Thornton living in Ohio</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-09" id="d74">
<head>"  9</head>
<p>Same vs George Hall, <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> given one week to pay it <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Otto Pfahl (late 5th <abbr expan="Pennsylvania Cavalry">Penna Cav</abbr>) vs B. T. Bagby, <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> settled by paying $<hi rend="underline">4.00</hi></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-11" id="d75">
<head>May 11</head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs W. F. Snapp; wages since <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> <unclear>6----</unclear> per <abbr expan="month">mo</abbr>; summons to <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft</abbr> to appear Saturday <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>, Dismissed</p>

<p>John W. Greaves (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) vs Nancy Thornton <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> Debt $1.00 summons to appear forthwith. <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> allowed until Saturday 19th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> to pay</p>

<p>Melinda Vanderbilt, wife of Nathan V------- (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) complains that David Sherer, for whom she has been working is about to put her out of the house; doesn't know exactly where her husband is working, but expects him back in a week or two, <abbr expan="Examined">Exd</abbr> &amp; Dismissed 12th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>.</p>

<p><unclear>E. F.</unclear> Johnson complains that Billy Shumate (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) owes him about $3.50; and neglects to pay him; Settled.</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-12" id="d76">
<head>"  12</head>
<p><unclear>J. D.</unclear> Kaiser vs Shaw and Brooks; Mr Brooks appeared and <unclear>asked</unclear> that he be allowed to fix a day for trial, will inform the Bureau by letter.</p>

<p>Present at a hearing before Justice Evans, of Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi>
 Ellis (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <unclear>charge</unclear> stealing chickens, <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> committed in default <unclear>of the bail</unclear></p>

<p>Sam'l Hayes vs John D. Lilly, Greenville: Debt for wages $16.50, Summons for Saturday 19th at 10 A.M.</p>

<p>Benj Hill vs same ------, Debt for wages $6.00 summons same as above</p>

<p>Miss Rebecca Greaves vs James Carter; Debt for a balance due on a table $4.00; summons to Wednesday next 10 A.M.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Louisa Reeves vs Preston Reeves, Desertion, Reeves is at Charlottesville, summons by mail to <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> at <abbr expan="Charlottesville">C</abbr>: lives with Benj Hughes</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-14" id="d77">
<head>"  14</head>
<p>Rosetta Fayer <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs John Ed Hamilton <abbr expan="White">W.</abbr> <unclear>debt</unclear> for wages from about 15th <abbr expan="October">Octo.</abbr> '64 to about 14th <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> wages were to be $3.00 per <abbr expan="month">mo</abbr>; - summoned <abbr expan="defendant">dft</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> appear 19th at 9 A.M. <unclear>Settled</unclear> May <unclear>23</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> paid $3.00</p>

<p>James Henry Robinson &amp; Lindsay Mitchell vs <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brown: Debt <hi rend="underline">$53.00</hi>: summons to <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> to appear Wednesday 16th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> at 10 A.M.; <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> took a watch from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp;c &amp;c Dismissed for the present until further evidence <unclear>can be obtained</unclear></p>

<p>J.M. Cline (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) a <unclear>Drunkard</unclear> complains that in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> while endeavoring to escape in company with <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> lines, he was arrested with his party and taken to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> where the money and pocketbooks of himself &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--ken</unclear> from them by <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Marion Sibert, <unclear>P---------</unclear> <unclear>(C.--------</unclear> about a week afterwards all were returned but <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> has never yet received it</p>

<p>Diana Koiner vs George Koiner; <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> appeared and upon evidence that the <abbr expan="Plaintiff">Ptf</abbr> had been, <unclear>both</unclear> before and since the marriage <abbr expan="leading">leadg</abbr> an immoral life of prostitution and that the contract had been an enforced and compelled by the Military authorities without proper investigation the case was dismissed, and <abbr expan="Defendant">Dft</abbr> advised to procure <unclear>divorce</unclear> from the Civil Courts</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-16" id="d78">
<head>"  16</head>
<p>Mrs Mahala Bannister complains that her husband Cyrus Bannister went to <abbr expan="Parkersburg">Parkersbg</abbr> last fall and since then she has been obliged to support herself and five children. Mrs B lives at Conly Craigs at Deerfield.<lb/>June 20 wrote to him</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-21" id="d79">
<head>May 21</head>
<p><unclear><abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> of</unclear> Robert Venable in <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> with Anderson <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> sum of two 50/100 dollars settlement <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> regard to a bridle</p>

<p><unclear>Submitted</unclear> papers in regard to application for <unclear>Jany</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Miss Ellen C. Cox, Long Glade <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></p>

<p>Louisa Reeves vs Jacob Bear <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr> claims <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to the <abbr expan="amount">amt.</abbr> of three 25/100 Dollars <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--tice</unclear> to Bear to appear on the 23d <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> A.M. - settled <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> for $3.00</p>

<p>Martin Hill vs T Mitchell in regard to rent of house and labor, send Mitchell a <unclear>summons</unclear> to appear May 23<hi rend="super">d</hi> at 10 <abbr expan="o'clock">O'clk</abbr> A.M.</p>

<p>John Jackson vs James Kingcade - sent an order <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to pay installment of rent due <unclear>or be</unclear> arrested - lives with <abbr expan="Doctor">Doct.</abbr> Tinkling Spring <abbr expan="Church">Chh</abbr>
</p>

<p><unclear>Pryncis</unclear> Vanderbilt (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Joseph Vanderbilt (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) claims <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 1st April/65 to fall - send note to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> him either to settle with <unclear>Pryncus</unclear> or <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>---plain</unclear></p>

<p><unclear><abbr expan="Received">Recd</abbr></unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $2.50 to be paid to Joe Harrison on <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> with <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-23" id="d80">
<head>May 23</head>
<p>Richard Spears (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Logan Morpin (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> from 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">st</hi>
</hi> April 65 to 30th August <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Morpin to appear June 1st <unclear>10 Octo</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> appeared, settled the case and brought colored <unclear>witness</unclear> Spears not present - ordered settlement at 8 Dollars per <unclear>month</unclear> 3.70$ to be paid to Monroe Rhoads- <unclear>money l---</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-24" id="d81">
<head>24</head>
<p>Jas Williams (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs James Greaver (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <unclear>threatening</unclear> his wife at his own door drawing knife telling her he would cut her heart out &amp;c - the woman is without <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> so frightened as to be sick confided to her <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the occurence seen also by Mrs Lelia Hill <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> this on the eve of May 22 1866 - lives about 5 miles out Sent him to Magistrate to report if no <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-25" id="d82">
<head>25</head>
<p>Ruben Golden (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs John Mix (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) Claims <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> threw stones at him, knocked him down <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> on him, this at Mr Burks furnance <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del hand="h1">Brocks</del> Pond Gap - 2 <abbr expan="miles">mi</abbr> from Staunton <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 17th/66 Thursday. (Witnesses: John <unclear>Shiff</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sailor the latter abetting the act of Mix <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sent request to Benj O <unclear>F--ngers</unclear> <unclear>Magistrate</unclear> investigate the case notified this Office of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> trial enclosed copy Circular 10.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>
<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-26" id="d83">
<head>May 26</head>
<p><unclear>Th----us</unclear> Gamble (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) owes Leanna Tayler <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> for <unclear>work</unclear> from the fall of Richmond until May 4th 1866 sent him note to appear Wednesday May 30th/66 10 <abbr expan="O'clock">Ock</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> Address Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>, Reported at time but the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> was not present</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-27" id="d84">
<head>27</head>
<p>Joseph Black (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Dr. F Walker, <abbr expan="White">W</abbr> lives in Middle River near Mt. <orig reg="Meridian">Meridean</orig> - is executor for the estate Alex <unclear>W----</unclear>, Debt due Black for wages of his daughter from July until 25 December /65</p>

<p>Rhoda Brock vs Dr M<hi rend="super">c</hi>
Farlin lives near Mint Spring <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> Address - owes her for year hire - <abbr expan="account">a/c</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 29</p>

<p>Ja<hi rend="super">s</hi> Carter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Peter Murray (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) Staunton - claims wages to <abbr expan="amount\">amt</abbr> of $3.00 wrote note requesting him to settle - called per Order and prove that the work was done by another man Geo W. Brown - Carter was paid by Brown</p>

<p>Holmes <unclear>Devenfort</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Moffit Cochran lives in Staunton claims wages from <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 1865 to April 1866 Discharged the claim</p>

<p><unclear>Diana</unclear> Bumgardner <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs George Koiner Sherando, about the desertion of his wife - married 1865 lives with Mr. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> - Surrender Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
 <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-29" id="d85">
<head>May 29</head>
<p>Rebecca Payne <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> <unclear>Bl-----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> that he owed her $1.50 sent him note <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> settled</p>

<p>Amos Winegardner (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Jas S. <unclear>Wight</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> five dollars is due him for labor <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at Smokey Row 5 miles, sent note by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> settle</p>

</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-30" id="d86">
<head>30</head>
<p>George Crain (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) states that had boy <unclear>Wm B------</unclear> bound to him as an orphan some 8 <unclear>years</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> have been destroyed at Harrisonburg <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> where <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> action if any is necessary</p>

<p>John Hurly (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) rec<hi rend="super">d</hi> Stolen dress and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of colored woman <add hand="h1" place="inline">of whom <unclear>recd</unclear></add> Betsey Kinney, <unclear>Mr Tukey</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> time since that ten (10) dollars should <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> dress but Hurley has fail to comply - <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-05-31" id="d87">
<head>31</head>
<p>Wesley Miner (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Brown Allen (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> claims that Brown refuses to settle his <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and he wishes to get it done has worked for him five years - sent note to Allen telling him to settle before such <unclear>whole</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> may choose or I should take it in <unclear>house</unclear></p>
</div3>
</div2>

<pb/>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-06" id="d88">
<head>June 1866 
<!-- <ref>Family, Women, Health/Illness, Aid/Relief, Violence/Crime, Legal System, Property, Employment/Labor, Local Government, Military Authority, Race Relations</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-01" id="d89">
<head>June 1</head>
<p>James Watson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs <unclear>Quinlans F--ry</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) has child by him named Rosa Lee 6 years old - by him wishes him to help support the child</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-02" id="d90">
<head>2</head>
<p>Abraham <unclear>Telford</unclear> is old and blind - his son John Morris supports him partially but wishes to have him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> care of - lives 2 miles out on the Buffalo Gap road</p>

<p>James H Alexander (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs J.P. McCutchin <orig reg="Summerdean">Summer Dean</orig> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> has 150.00 paid to him by father of the <unclear>complainant</unclear> for safe keeping about seven years ago - the case has been up but not decided before the complainant is acting in name of his Mother Ellen Alexander</p>

<p>Attended trial of Peter <unclear>Raisner</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) before Circuit Court sentence <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> prisonment
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Robert <unclear>Seites</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) stealing watches - found guilty new trial granted</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-04" id="d91">
<head>4</head>
<p><unclear>Sent</unclear> James <del hand="h1">Cochran</del> Carson notice to appear thursday <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> A.M.</p>

<p><unclear>Julian</unclear> Reynolds (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Susan Alexander W. Monterey Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> owes for labor from fall. Richmond to <abbr expan="March">Mch.</abbr> 1866 - wrote July 21/'66</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-06" id="d92">
<head>June 6</head>
<p><abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> of <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> G. T. Cook three (3) dollars for <unclear>Louisa Reeves</unclear> <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> paid by James Bear wages due her</p>

<p>Charlotte Temple <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs Amos Winegarner (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Claims right to have him support two children got by Amos. Decided that she is to receive two (2) dollars a month from him to support the children for one year from date.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-07" id="d93">
<head>7</head>
<p>W. A. Parson (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) for Mrs. <unclear>Fagan</unclear> vs Rebeca Strander <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> who lives at Parkersburg <abbr expan="West Virginia">W.Va.</abbr> - claims pay for a <unclear>Cloak</unclear> sold her valued at $20.00 vs <unclear>loan</unclear> cash $1.50.</p>

<p>Patrick Carter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Wyatt Smith (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) claims $10.00 due him for which friend of Smiths named <unclear>Benj Sheffy</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) wishes to leave as security a silver <unclear>watch</unclear> to be forfeited of the debt is not paid for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> June 7th 1866. <abbr expan="Received">Rec'd</abbr> the watch (C.B. 63323-7)<lb/>June 19 Watch delivered to Pat. Cater - witness O. Morris</p>

<p>Summoned Charles Byers, Samuel <unclear>Hawkins</unclear>, John K. Bowers &amp; Joseph Wanger to appear on Tuesday next at 10 o'clock A.M. the 12th <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr>, also <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-08" id="d94">
<head>8</head>
<p>Joannah Obie <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs Tho<hi rend="super">s</hi> Drumhiller <abbr expan="White">W.</abbr> <unclear>Collywine</unclear> Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>, states that he is father of her child and will not assist her - sent him note to do so or would <unclear>look----</unclear> the facts of the case.<lb/>July Drumhillers sons bring for assault <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Mr. Asa Pierce, New Hope. Civil Authorities refused to grant support to the child - made statement to <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Brown <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 82.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-09" id="d95">
<head>June 9</head>
<p>Wallace Woodstock (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) was tried before the Mayors Court in Harrisonburg and committed for trial in July sent to Circuit Court, <abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> next</p>

<p>Willis Strother (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) makes complaint against Geo Herring (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) and White <unclear>Schif--</unclear> that they burned his house down making the statement that they had been ordered to do so by the <unclear>neighbor</unclear> Strother lives near Conrads Store Rockingham <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>
 <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> warrant June 2d <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> wrote account of the affair to W.H. Effinger, <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com.</abbr> <unclear>W----</unclear> &amp; Rockingham <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>
 <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-14" id="d96">
<head>14</head>
<p><unclear>Eliza</unclear> Johnson <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs Perry Sheffy (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) lives near Barter Brook - complains that Sheffy has two wives and one is a white woman the other is <unclear>out the</unclear> country -is a public <unclear>union</unclear> as they <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> live together. Mr. Adam M<hi rend="super">c</hi>
Cheseny told him to mention the case.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-15" id="d97">
<head>15</head>
<p><unclear>S---</unclear> <unclear>--icky</unclear> vs Joseph Peck's estate now in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>legalties</unclear> Frank Kiner &amp; David Kiner who live near Fishersville &amp; Waynesboro respectively. Claims that the estate was to support his <unclear>step-father</unclear> a cripple - the will of Peck ordered his support</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-16" id="d98">
<head>June 16</head>
<p>Peter Whitesel formerly 11th <abbr expan="Virginia Infantry">Va inft.</abbr> enrolled 14th August 1862 Discharged 22d April 1863 - at Parkersburg <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. Now lives with Mr. David Whitesel near Fishersville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> wants to get assistance from the <abbr expan="Government">Gov.</abbr> or Bounty if any <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>L &amp; E</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-18" id="d99">
<head>"  18</head>
<p>Attended the trial Augustus Mosely W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Johnson and George Thompson who have been committed to jail and will be tried on Monday next for entering the house of Nelson <unclear>S---kel</unclear> of Harrisonburg a Silver Watch valued at $50 and a pocket book containing $30 or 40 in National Currency, some silver and valuables.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-19" id="d100">
<head>19</head>
<p>Eliza <unclear>Wan</unclear> <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs William Banks lives on Middlebrook Road <abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr> Staunton owes for serving in 1865 <unclear>12.00</unclear> Mr. Peter Ingram</p>

<p>George Hawkins (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Reports that he <unclear>was</unclear> tried before <unclear>Benj Furgeson</unclear> - Magistrate at <unclear>Greenville</unclear> on charge of received stolen goods, notified the Magistrate of Circular No. 10 <abbr expan="Circular Series">C.S.</abbr> and information that should report to <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Terry of explanation of the violation of the order are <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-21" id="d101">
<head>21</head>
<p>Wrote Wm. Drumes <add hand="h1" place="inline">(<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>)</add> to pay Archie Smith Freedman for a Saddle sold by him belonging to Smith.</p>

<p>Wrote to <abbr expan="Justice of the Peace">J.P.</abbr> <orig reg="MCutchen">McCutcheon</orig> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) of <orig reg="Summerdean">Sumer Dean</orig> in relation to the claim of James H. Alexander made on Page 40.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-22" id="d102">
<head>June 22</head>
<p><unclear>Leslie</unclear> Henderson <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs John <unclear>S--</unclear> lives near <orig reg="Arbor Hill"><unclear>Harbor</unclear> Hill</orig> - states that he is her lawful husband that he deserted her June 13th 1866 and married Ann Harris <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> with a county license. Wrote to <del hand="h1">Just</del> Magistrate Archibald A McPhetus Arbor Hill, Mint Springs</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-23" id="d103">
<head>June 23</head>
<p>Sam Lewis (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Andy R Crawford lives above <abbr expan="Mount">Mt</abbr> Solon - claims he worked himself and son worked for him until after Harvest /65 and then his son left when he and family were turned off, no exact rate of pay was promised but they were to have grain</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-24" id="d104">
<head>June 24</head>
<p>Richard Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Adam Huff who lives at Greenville <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> complains he turned his family outdoors, wrote to John Newton Magistrate</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-25" id="d105">
<head>June 25</head>
<p><unclear>Archibald</unclear> Bailey (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Washington Patterson (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) lives <add hand="h1" place="inline">beyond</add> Fishersville wages from April/65 to June</p>

<p>Francis McDowell vs Mr. Henry Wright Moffitts Creek</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-27" id="d106">
<head>"  27</head>
<p>Catherine Torbett complains that Robert Hunter of New Hope has employed her son without consulting her she admits having received $4.00 Charles has been employed since April</p>

<pb/>

<p>Sent Summons to Adam <unclear>Russmer</unclear> for Ja<hi rend="super">s</hi> E Carson to appear at this office on Saturday June 30 to show cause why the demand of Harrison (Freedman) has not been settled</p>

<p>Thomas J Jones late a private <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> G 1st <abbr expan="United States Infantry">U.S. Inft.</abbr> was enrolled 22<hi rend="super">d</hi> <abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 1864 for 3 years - Discharged, <unclear>pur <abbr expan="Missouri">MO.</abbr></unclear> <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Order No. 33 <abbr expan="Department">Dept.</abbr> <abbr expan="Missouri">Mo.</abbr> <abbr expan="Circular Series">C.S.</abbr>                                                                                                                      <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr> 10 1866 and paid to day of discharge 21st May /66 at Fort Leavenworth Kansas. Wishes to know if he is entitled to any thing beside his month pay - never having received anything else - lives Monterey Highland <abbr expan="County Virginia">Co Va</abbr>. Wrote <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Brown June 29th 1866 <unclear>-&amp;E</unclear> 45</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-28" id="d107">
<head>Freedman's Agency Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr><lb/>June 28th 1866</head>
<p>Board of Agents met in accordance with call of <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr> Geo. T. Cook 24th <abbr expan="Veterans' Reserve Corps">V.R.C.</abbr> <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst. Supt.</abbr><lb/>
Present all the members<lb/>
President</p>

<p>George T. Cook Recorder</p>

<p>Case of Joseph Harrison vs. James E. Carson</p>

<p>Case having been tried at former meeting and Adjourned to await the arrival of Depositions from Jacob Thornton of Highland <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>. Ohio, the recorder Geo. T. Cook <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst. Supt.</abbr> here produced the Deposition of said Jacob Thornton.<lb/>
The Court after mature deliberation upon the evidence adduced to decide that the Defendant James E Carson pays to the <orig reg="Plaintiff">Plaintif</orig>, Joseph Harrison, freedman, the sum of thirty five (35) dollars and ninety-five (95) cents with interest to the first of June 1866 to the amount of five dollars and Eleven cents.<lb/> 
Wm. J. Dews</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-06-29" id="d108">
<head>-  29</head>
<p>Sampson Hamilton (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs R. Hodge (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) lives Craigsville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>, complains that he worked for Hodge until <abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 22<hi rend="super">d</hi>
 1865 and only <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> 2 <abbr expan="Pair">Pr</abbr> Pants 2 Shirts Hamilton lives with Russel Wallace</p>
</div3>
</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-07" id="d109">
<head>July 1866 
<!-- <ref>Women, Slavery, Property, Violence/Crime, Family, Community Values/Local Behavior, Legal System, Race Relations</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-04" id="d110">
<head>July 4</head>
<p>Millie Sibert <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs Horsten <unclear>Guinn</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <unclear>W------</unclear> <unclear>Ch--d----</unclear> and Widow Seal. Sibert (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) - executor of will Jacob Sibert Henry Sibert - all live at Monterey Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
 <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. Jacob Sibert died and left this woman to be supported during her lifetime by Andrew Sibert; Andrew died and the next heir sold her - names above. L &amp; E 520</p>

<p>Henry Baxter (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs James W. Craig Fishersville - Baker is at Geo. Shuey, near Middlebrook, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> Claim unsettled <abbr expan="amounts">amts</abbr> to $12.12 question in Corn <abbr expan="amounts">amts</abbr> to $28.00</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-06" id="d111">
<head>July 6<hi rend="super">t</hi>
</head>
<p>Elizabeth F Fuller (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) lives near Waynesboro <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> has a child (colored) 8 years old named Alexander he is an orphan raised by her - reported the fact of having him to save any trouble, <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr> her son</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-10" id="d112">
<head>July 10</head>
<p>Woodson, colored, was <del hand="h1">tried</del> re-tried in Circuit Court the Court <unclear>Egbert</unclear> R Watson of Albemarle - allowed a compromise of some kind on last trial; when he was sentenced for three years but allowed new trial on <unclear>different</unclear> <orig reg="indictment">inditement</orig> - and sent him to Penitentiary for two years, I was not summoned to attend the trial.<lb/>
Re-trial of Rob<hi rend="super">t</hi> Lewis for watch stealing, first trial June 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>, <abbr expan="through">thro'</abbr> flaw in <orig reg="indictment">inditement</orig> tried again Today, not summoned<lb/>
<unclear>Verdict</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-11" id="d113">
<head>July 11</head>
<p>Meredith vs <del hand="h1">Lewis Bumgardner</del> Isaac Vines - Greenville Assault referred to Lewis Bumgardner Magistrate</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-20" id="d114">
<head>"  20</head>
<p>Eliza Rhodes complains that her husband Kendall Rhodes has forsaken herself &amp; child, it appeared on examining Register that he had Registered himself as the husband of Rosanna who is Dead, is at work at Holmes Bell 5 <abbr expan="miles">ms</abbr> from Waynesboro</p>

<p>Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi> H. <unclear>Saupe</unclear> vs W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Gearing <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> - statement was that Gearing came into the portion of house occupied by Saupe and asked S. wife why she called his wife names &amp;c Saupe came in and without remark seized a chair and struck him Gearing three times, <unclear>then comes</unclear> &amp; <unclear>savears</unclear> the Peace</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-21" id="d115">
<head>July 21</head>
<p>James Harris complains that Mr Powell struck him on side of the Head because he declined to take a piece of Meat after he selected it for him.<lb/>
Case tried before J M Hardy <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr> <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft</abbr> discharged on payment of cost</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-14" id="d116">
<head>"  14</head>
<p>John Sherer vs Margt. Johnson <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> statement was that <abbr expan="Defendant">Deft.</abbr> struck her several times on the Head case tried before J M Hardy <abbr expan="Esquire">esq</abbr>; - both parties bound over to keep the peace in the sum of $100 each.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-21" id="d117">
<head>21</head>
<p>S. L. Bailey vs Abraham <unclear>Sawyers</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Hebron Church, complains that S has rented house of him but is making it a <unclear>unsa--</unclear> by keeping crowd of people there &amp; - July 23 <unclear>S---</unclear> in and gave him advice</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-23" id="d118">
<head>23</head>
<p>David Collins <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> vs P.O. Palmer, Valley Mills, case annulling of contract <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Witnesses S. Keller &amp; S. Ott, Annulled July 28<hi rend="super">th</hi>
 1866</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-24" id="d119">
<head>24</head>
<p>Alex. <unclear>Props</unclear> &amp; <abbr expan="Brother">Bro.</abbr> Charles (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Taylor <unclear>D---l</unclear> <abbr expan="White">(W)</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Brother">Bro.</abbr> Robert, Spring Hill <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> - case of assault the white men assaulting and using pitchforks, afterward taking whips and deliberately whipping them tried July 27th 1866 before H. M. Peck, County Magistrate the attack was admitted by the white men <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> also the whipping but the Magistrate dismissed the case entirely</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-29" id="d120">
<head>July 29</head>
<p><unclear>W--</unclear> Nelling <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> vs Tom Harris <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> complains of assault on his wife and that Tom threatened his life &amp;c - Discharged Harris July 30 1866</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-07-30" id="d121">
<head>July 30</head>
<p>Lucinda Nelson <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> vs John Barger <abbr expan="White">(W)</abbr> New Hope <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> - states she lived with them formerly but during war left with <unclear>Hunter's</unclear> Men - they sold all her clothing given her by her Mother</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-08" id="d122">
<head>August 1866 
<!-- <ref>Violence/Crime, Military Authority, Community Values/Local Behavior, Employment/Labor, Property, Family, Women, Legal System, Church/Religious Activity, Politics/Political Attitudes</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-01" id="d123">
<head>August 1</head>
<p>John Hill vs <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> O Farrell, assault <unclear>provn</unclear> bound over in sum of ($200.) to <del hand="h1">keep</del> answer to Grand Jury, <abbr expan="Colored">Col<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> boy Joe Williams original <unclear>c----</unclear> of assault bound in $50 for being drunk</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-06" id="d124">
<head>Aug 6</head>
<p><unclear>Ed</unclear> Gooding <abbr expan="Freedman">(F)</abbr> vs Nathan Greaver, debt of ten 00/100 Dollars. Gooding lives 6 miles this side of Lexington has Blacksmith shop Greaver is to leave the money here to be sent to Major Carse for Gooding</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-11" id="d125">
<head>Aug 11</head>
<p>Julia Porterfield <abbr expan="Freedwoman">(F)</abbr> vs. Joe Harris Mt. Tabor <unclear>case</unclear> sale of some hogs and things of Julias <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Joe</unclear> when living with her. Claims 11.00</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-13" id="d126">
<head><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 13</head>
<p><unclear>Philander</unclear> Smith (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Robert Craig - Craigsville owes him for work since <abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> at 8 dollars per month. Referred to Lawyer</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-14" id="d127">
<head><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 14</head>
<p>H. M. <unclear>Lolland</unclear> says he has got two orphan children which the Grandfather wants to take from him ordered to keep them until further orders.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Commonwealth vs James Bergie &amp; Ruben Hill arrested for stealing Butter Molasses &amp; Chickens preliminary hearing before Magistrate both committed for trial before Grand Jury, Witnesses mostly colored - tried Circuit Court <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> years November 5th 1866</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-17" id="d128">
<head>17</head>
<p>Commonwealth vs. Harry Gilman Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi> <unclear>Greaver</unclear> &amp; Henry Brown (<abbr expan="colored">cold</abbr> boys) - breaking into a Church and stealing a lot of Sabbath school books sentence that they furnish security for good behavior in the sum of $100 or go to jail</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-18" id="d129">
<head>18</head>
<p>Patrick Carter vs Mary _______. Trial before Civil Magistrate on charge of stealing purse containing $2.50 in silver and $3.00 <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Currency</p>

<p>John F. Readman vs Commonwealth - claims that he has been forced to pay poll tax for the year</p>

<p>A. N. Dallas Waynesboro <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> in regard to freedman <unclear>Anthony</unclear> Jackson <add hand="h1" place="inline"><unclear>laziness</unclear></add> also Kendal Rhoads claims children</p>

<p><del hand="h1">Henry <unclear>Grea---ld</unclear></del><lb/>Robert Steele - Steele's Tavern is living with Emily Kinney, an improper character</p>

<pb/>

<p>Spottswood Johnson complains that A.S. Hunter beat and stabbed his Boy with a Pitchfork - lives at Mount <orig reg="Torry">Torrey</orig> Furnace. <unclear>Moses</unclear> Ellis <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr>
 is Magistrate of the locality referred the case to him.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-20" id="d130">
<head>20</head>
<p>W<hi rend="super">m</hi> Jones (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Mrs A. <unclear>Brenham</unclear> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) claim one Dollar <unclear>more</unclear> wages due him Contract for $8.00 - deduct on broken crockery, 75c <abbr expan="Paid">Pd</abbr> <unclear>here</unclear> due $1.25. William Kenney.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-21" id="d131">
<head>21</head>
<p>Jack White (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) lives with <del hand="h1">Char</del> <unclear>Judge</unclear> Sheffey - states has daughter with four children living 4 miles from Scottsville Albemarle <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
 - Name Harriet Porter, in <unclear>house</unclear> belonging to Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi> Thompsn (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) who has torn down chimney &amp;c leaving her <unclear>no way to</unclear> live - striking her &amp; wrote to <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> W.S. <unclear>----hall</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-22" id="d132">
<head>22</head>
<p>Nichodemas Shuey complains that he has worked for George <unclear>Shemey</unclear> since the surrender and has received no clothing or Money, with the exception of five dollars, Elias Bowman &amp; Thomas Spetter Witness</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-24" id="d133">
<head>August 24</head>
<p>Eliza Johnson alias Berry, lives with Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi> Berry Middlebrook - made complaint against George Jefferson, colored, that he <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>father</unclear> of her child - now complains that <unclear>Samuel</unclear> Gould (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) struck her and children <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> charging her with stealing</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-27" id="d134">
<head>27</head>
<p>Mary Doom complains that <unclear>Milly</unclear> Williams is living in her House and will not move out or pay the rent</p>

<p>Isaac A. Steele states that his father died in 1853 leaving certain property which was sold by order of Court, <del hand="h1">and the</del> in year /53, <unclear>notes</unclear> being taken for one two &amp; three years - last payment due in 1858, of which he <abbr expan="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> <add hand="h1" place="inline"><unclear>lvg</unclear> statement</add> the first payment in /53 of $500. the balance the heirs being minors was put in the hands of a trustee, John Newton <del hand="h1">Steele</del> <add hand="h1" place="inline">Greenville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></add> the money was paid to all the heirs but Isaac A Steele who was absent in the State of <unclear>Maine</unclear> During the late war Steele served in the <abbr expan="United States">U.S.</abbr> Army, and the trustee making a report of the funds in his hands the County Court ordered the money <abbr expan="amounting">amting</abbr> to <unclear>$5040</unclear> <add hand="h1" place="inline">in Gold</add> to be transfered to the <abbr expan="Confederate Government">
 Confed Gov.</abbr> and bonds of the <abbr expan="Confederate Government">Confed. Gov.</abbr> deposited instead which is now offered him as money</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-30" id="d135">
<head>30</head>
<p>George James complains that he has worked nearly one month for Crawford Miller and that Miller has now driven him off without provocation and refuses to pay him.</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-08-31" id="d136">
<head><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 31</head>
<p><unclear>Mary</unclear> Eliza Dawson vs Oliver her husband that he beats and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> her</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-09" id="d137">
<head>September 1866 
<!-- <ref>Women, Property, Violence/Crime, Employment/Labor, Politics/Political Attitudes</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-09-05" id="d138">
<head>Sept 5</head>
<p>Mary Tyne complains that James Bush Bush has turned her out of Doors without any notice whatever</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-09-08" id="d139">
<head>"  8</head>
<p>Austin Brown complainst that Calvin Davis who works at Peter Hangers near Waynesboro struck him with the Tongs and broke his arm <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> over to <abbr expan="answer">ans</abbr> Grand Jury next <unclear>May</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-09-10" id="d140">
<head>10</head>
<p><unclear>A--nt</unclear> Miller <del hand="h1">Trice</del> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Mr Fields - complains that while boy <add hand="h1" place="inline">Samson</add> working in Brick yard he was struck and beaten by Fields</p>

<p>Joe Sawyers (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complains that their meetings in Churchville are disturbed by colored men who are trying to <unclear>break</unclear> <unclear>them up</unclear> - referred case to John Huff Magistrate Churchville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
</p>

<p>Nelson Kenny (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Commonwealth states man named Mr <unclear>Pagr</unclear> Moore owed him $4.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">06</hi>
</hi> and left some boots to pay debt <add hand="h1" place="inline">with Jacob McNett</add> boots have been attached and sold favor to Mr Sampson. Referred to J.A. Patterson <abbr expan="Esquire">Esq</abbr> <abbr expan="Magistrate">Mag.</abbr>
</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-09-19" id="d141">
<head><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 19</head>
<p>Absalom Ross <abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr> vs Peter Hanger <unclear><abbr expan="White">W</abbr></unclear> Waynesboro <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> complaint that he cannot <unclear>get money</unclear> due him and when he <unclear>applied for the</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he was assaulted by Hanger and threatened with a drawn knife - Wrote Geo. <unclear>Bruce</unclear> Magistrate</p>

<p>Martin <del hand="h1">Harris</del> Dickerson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Martin Harris Old Providence Church below Greenville owes his neice Lucinda Jackson for service from April 1st 1865 to <abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 31st/65 has paid $5.00 - Wrote Mr Harris</p>

<p>Randal <unclear>Bowlin</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs <add hand="h1" place="inline"><unclear>widow</unclear></add> Kate Hart Fishersville <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> - Rented house and garden upon to field Mrs. Hart <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> cattle in to eat up his garden and thereby destroyed the same <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> old difficulty about a <unclear>coppy</unclear> <unclear>--th</unclear> <unclear>found</unclear> by Bowlyn which led Mrs Harts <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to pay he never should have the benefit of the garden. Wrote for information to Wm Bush, Constable.</p>

<p>Isaac Carter freedman lives in New Market with Sam <unclear>Grime</unclear></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-09-26" id="d142">
<head><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 26</head>
<p><unclear>Phil---</unclear> Ransom (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs John Rullins (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <unclear>Sherando</unclear> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> - complains that Rullins struck <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> - John repeatedly so as to require <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> attendance, the boy was picked up <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> street and carried home</p>

<p><unclear>----cis</unclear> Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Oliver Dods on <unclear>F</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $2.00 - works on Peytons Farm</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-10" id="d143">
<head>October 10 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Legal System, Health/Illness, Aid/Relief, Women, Violence/Crime, Property</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-10-xx" id="d144">
<head>Oct</head>
<p> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Cochrane (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Felix Sheets <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Creek- complains of threats with a <unclear>club</unclear> to strike him and also complains <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of threats to turn him out of his home</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> P. Wardell (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <orig reg="Middlebrook">Middle Brook</orig> road 3 miles <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> black boy one foot burnt off <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> child - thinks if bound to a shoemaker <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> able to make a good living</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Smith (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Henry Fuller (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Bridge <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>near</unclear> confinement and wishes assistance <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Wrote Philander Herring <abbr expan="Magistrate">Mag</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) vs Nathan Crawford (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <unclear>Rockland</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to eject him from house on a <unclear>claim</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the house rented by month Crawford <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> year - Monday 22 <abbr expan="October ">Oct.</abbr> trial in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Got Mr. Fultz as Counsel <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-10-17" id="d145">
<head><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 17</head>
<p>Robt Sheffy (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) Mint Spring <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> complains that he had <unclear>contract</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to work but Sheffy not only <unclear>req----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> still keeps possession of his House - <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sheffy up</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-10-22" id="d146">
<head><abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 22</head>
<p>John Brent (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Joseph Mills - Brownsburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> Owes hime wages since <abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> 1st 1866 to <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> <unclear>15</unclear> /66
<lb/>
<abbr expan="Owes">"</abbr> Wife <abbr expan="wages since Jan. 1st 66 to Oct">"   "   "  " " "</abbr> 1st 66<lb/>Made out bill giving after <unclear>C----</unclear> balance due John Brent of $73.10 <unclear>Cr.</unclear> 23.90 <unclear>Chg</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>
</div2>


<div2 type="section" n="1866-11" id="d147">
<head>November 1866 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Property, Violence/Crime, Women, Family</ref> -->  
</head>

<pb/>

<p>{ALMOST ENTIRELY ILLEGIBLE}</p>

<pb/>

<p>{ALMOST ENTIRELY ILLEGIBLE}</p>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-11-xx" id="d148">
<head><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Scott (<abbr expan="colored">col'd</abbr>) vs John O'Hare, Staunton <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> retained two dollars of her pay, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> one silver spoon which was lost in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Wood (<abbr expan="colored">cold</abbr>) vs George Crowbarger <abbr expan="White">W</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> road running from Greenville to <unclear>Waynesboro</unclear> 2 1/2 miles from Greenville - Complaint <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Crowbarger</unclear> struck him several blows <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>his</unclear> fist - he was lifting with him and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> hurt Crowbargers fingers</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Adams (<abbr expan="Colored">Cold</abbr>) Children Martha S. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Hannah</unclear> 11 - Nancy J 4 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Esquire Adams <abbr expan="Colored">Col'd</abbr> Parkers <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> care <unclear>F.</unclear> J. Dewey</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Carson</unclear> <del hand="h1">Sp</del> Moscow - 12 miles <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Staunton</unclear> - wants a boy 14 yrs <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Mrs. Julia Kenney (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> is from <unclear>tuesday</unclear> last - Wm T. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> one months wages $4.00</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Powell</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs James Harris (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Dodson .50 <hi rend="super">c</hi>
</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-11-27" id="d149">
<head><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 27</head>
<p>Samuel Baskins <abbr expan="White">W</abbr> - owes <unclear>H-------</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) for servies of daughter <unclear>Ju----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> July 27th until <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 21st, 66 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-11-29" id="d150">
<head>29</head>
<p>James Harris (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) is to be <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> house he is living in <unclear>Albert</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> </p>
</div3>

</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1866-12" id="d151">
<head>December 1866 
<!-- <ref>Women, Family, Community Values/Local Behavior, Property, Employment/Labor, Legal System, Military Authority, Slavery, Health/Illness, Aid/Relief</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-01" id="d152">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 1</head>
<p>Henry Jackson (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs John Gregory (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $5</p>

<p>Jourdan Washington vs <unclear>H---y</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Middlebrook <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> threatens to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> out of his house</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-03" id="d153">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 3</head>
<p>Ruth Gateway vs Moses <unclear>B-----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Road - he is free born <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> assist her children - she <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by him. She lives <unclear>W---</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Widow Blair - 12 miles <unclear>B----</unclear> 
<lb/><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 19 denies that she is his wife. Wrote <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p>Jessie Lewis vs John <unclear>Churchman</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> wife's wages from April 1st <unclear>65</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> as cook - Jessie lives <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> place 3 miles from town</p>
</div3>
 
<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-xx" id="d154">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr>
</head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Keep (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Jacob Koiner - Waynesboro <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>that</unclear> Koiner <unclear>26th</unclear> of <abbr expan="November">Nov.</abbr> 66 shot at him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>public</unclear> highway reported to Geo Brown <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> but no action has been taken</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brown (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) wants to get three months pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>-----ter</unclear> - states that he served in train of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Brown <abbr expan="Quartermaster">Q.M.</abbr> to <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Sheridan when in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> but was discharged, <orig reg="although">altho'</orig> promised pay <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the trains of the Sixth Army Corps were <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> over preparatory to the return of the 6th Corp <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Petersburg from the Valley, in the fall of <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> remained with the Corps cooking for <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> some time after but never got the pay due.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-xx" id="d155">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>---uel</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) vs Wm <unclear>Prol</unclear> - struck her <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> B Evans who issued warrant <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Magistrate refused to try the case.</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>---son</unclear> &amp; Osborn Burn's <unclear>Profits</unclear> aged 60 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> turned out of the house in which they <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by Thomas Mitchel, they are now living <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Rileys land in Middlebrook <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> right at <orig reg="Arbor">Harbor</orig> Hill also <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--o</unclear> children Jane &amp; Mose - old man <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Mary</unclear> Francis - all small children</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-05" id="d156">
<head>5</head>
<p>Mary Jones (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) says Ja<hi rend="super">s</hi> <unclear>Wright</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del hand="h1">Harrisonburg</del> <add hand="h1" place="inline">Spring Hill Road</add> road 5 miles <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  months wages her by <unclear>me----</unclear>
<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> dollar in money - she is an <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  morning after she left the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> came to town and forced her to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> pair of shoes she had worn <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> </p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-14" id="d157">
<head>14</head>
<p>Jno W Carson Parnassus <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> pike - 2 miles from Staunton <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-21" id="d158">
<head>21</head>
<p>Joseph Ermine - <unclear>Toll Gate</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sailsbury - he is sickly and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> but his Father William <unclear>Sa-----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> taking him away - <unclear>Al--</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> bound for 2 years</p>

<p>Mary Queen (<abbr expan="Freedwoman">F</abbr>) vs <unclear>J-----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>----boro</unclear> <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> complains of not <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> promised</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-22" id="d159">
<head>22</head>
<p>Julia A Henning (White) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> clothing for self &amp; 2 <unclear>children</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> side of Churchville</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-2x" id="d160">
<head><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></head>
<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>----ft</unclear> (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) vs Hugh Guthrie (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>) for value <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>----lled</unclear> corn, wrote note to Mr. G. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--heeley</unclear> Hermitage - two old <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  on his place</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Baley lives at Mr Jewels - long white <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Main St. - has 3 children on her <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> White men Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi>
 <unclear>Train</unclear> - Theodore <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Jacob Shier - Wm. Long - Wm <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Witness Brisco Dull</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> vs Mrs. Hall - <unclear>town</unclear> owes him <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> </p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-25" id="d161">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 25<hi rend="super">th</hi></head>
<p>John Green (<abbr expan="colored">col<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr>) live on <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Assaulted by a crowd of young <unclear>men</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> town who were Drunk - he <unclear>was</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to the evidence on trial assaulted by <unclear>Jacob <unclear>Sh---</unclear></unclear> and others then joined the attack <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>rocks</unclear> &amp; clubs
<lb/>Court consisted of<lb/>
A. M. Bruce, J. B. Evans - Magistrates trail at 4 P.M. 25th <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr>
<lb/>The presiding Magistrate - J.B. Evans <unclear>warned</unclear> the parties against purgery, assuring them if they attempted it they should be presented for <unclear>indictment</unclear>
<lb/>Witnesses: B. Dull, Wm. Long, Dr. Wm. S. <unclear>McChesney</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>who</unclear> testified as to the nature of the wound, <unclear>Harvey</unclear> Loring, Theodore Long, John Scheller, <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> A. Long, Thepholius Randall (colored)
<lb/>During the trial Brisco Dull was thrown <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> a witness and arranged as a principal. The following persons were <del hand="h1">indicted</del> <add hand="h1" place="inline">held to answer to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></add> for assault and bound over to keep the peace for one year <unclear>each</unclear> in the sum of $100.
<lb/>
<table>
<row><cell><hi rend="underline">Person Bound to keep peace &amp;c</hi></cell><cell><hi rend="underline">Sureties</hi></cell></row>
<row><cell>Jacob Scher</cell><cell>---- Noonan</cell></row>
<row><cell>Brisco Dull</cell><cell>N. Gregory</cell></row>
<row><cell>Wm Gregory</cell><cell>A. Gregory</cell></row>
<row><cell>C. H. Drayer</cell><cell>Theodore Long</cell></row>
<row><cell>Patrick Ryan</cell><cell>---- Noonan</cell></row>
</table>
</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-12-28" id="d162">
<head><abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 28</head>
<p>Richard Johnson (<abbr expan="colored">cold</abbr>) has two old people <unclear>on his hands</unclear> <del hand="h1">Peter</del> Jacob Howard &amp; Betsey his <unclear>wife</unclear> lives south Baptist <abbr expan="Church">Chh</abbr>.</p>
</div3>

</div2>


</div1>


<div1 id="BD40001867" type="part" n="1867">
<head>1867
<!-- <ref>BD40001867</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1867-01" id="d164">
<head>January 1867 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Women, Family</ref> -->  
</head>

<pb n="66"/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-01-04" id="d165">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 4</head>
<p><unclear>Castellah</unclear> <unclear>Heeling</unclear> complains that W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">m</hi>
</hi> Booth is indebted to him for 3 Months Labor a $8 per month - Bill drawn off and given to Magistrate</p>

<p>Wm Burke complains that George Tate refuses to pay him for his sons labor - letter sent to Tate and he explains the matter satisfactorily</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-01-05" id="d166">
<head>5</head>
<p><del hand="h1">5 Edward Bishop</del></p>

<p>Edward Bishop complains that Wm. Crawford broke his contract with his son - investigated and found that he had broken the contract and not Bishop</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-01-06" id="d167">
<head>6</head>
<p>Emma Trice complains that W<hi rend="super">m</hi>
 Smith will not pay her son for the months Labor in Brick yard - Bill drawn of and put into the Hands of a Constable for collection</p>
</div3>


<div3 type="entry" n="1867-01-09" id="d168">
<head>9</head>
<p>Abraham Sims complains that James Crawford owes him $25 dollars and will not pay - Letter sent to Crawford and he promises to settle the matter next week</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-01-09" id="d169">
<head><abbr expan="January">Jany</abbr> 9th</head>
<p>John B. Carson, farmer lives 12 miles from Staunton wants a boy for 2 months to chop wood. Will Pay by the month, if <orig reg="desired">Disired</orig></p>

<p>Peyton Harris (<abbr expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) complaints that Adison <unclear>Rhoa--</unclear> will not pay him $4.50 in <unclear>money</unclear> <unclear>4.--</unclear> <orig reg="bushels">bushells</orig> of <unclear>corn</unclear> for work</p>
</div3>

</div2>

<pb/>

<div2 type="section" n="1867-03" id="d170">
<head>March 1867 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-03-03" id="d171">
<head>March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>
</head>
<p>J. W. Gillespie wants to get a boy <orig reg="about">abought</orig> 15 years old or a old man to clean a horse and attend to his garden this summer. Good wages paid for <orig reg="either">eather</orig> lives at New Hope <unclear><abbr expan="Augusta County">Aug. Co</abbr></unclear></p>
</div3>

</div2>

<pb/>

<div2 type="section" n="1867-04" id="d172">
<head>April 1867, Thomas P. Jackson 
<!-- <ref>Employment/Labor, Church/Religious Activity, Education, Health/Illness, Women, Family, Aid/Relief, Violence/Crime, Property, Legal System, Local Government, Community Values/Local Behavior</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-09-09" id="d173">
<head>April 9</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">Patsy Brown</hi> complains that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">Brown Allen</hi> <add hand="h1" place="inline">of Churchville</add> hired her at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for one year. Did not <unclear>treat her well</unclear> so she left some time in <unclear>February</unclear> Claims wages for one month <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>but</unclear> will accept $3 or use of <unclear>teac----</unclear>
<lb/> Wrote to Brown Allen to settled April 27/67 Mr. Brown Allen called <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and that contracts of <unclear>him</unclear> made by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of Patsy Brown family <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> all broken <add hand="h1" place="inline">she owes nothing to anyone that the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></add></p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Lizzy Wallace</hi> complains that <hi rend="underline"><unclear>An---</unclear></hi> had possession of her clothes and that on April 1st she asked for her clothes <unclear>Annie</unclear> gave her <unclear>more</unclear> that day but told her if she came after <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> she would beat her &amp; put her out the gate. Send Sam <unclear>Bau----</unclear> yesterday April 8 for <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of her clothes which word brought out <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> put in <unclear>-ate-</unclear> <unclear>robbed</unclear> the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>with</unclear> them &amp; then threw <unclear>them</unclear> our doors
<lb/><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 9 Sent for Annie Wood to bring clothes in dispute to office <abbr expan="which">wh.</abbr> she did &amp; handed to L. Wallace.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Settled</hi></p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Dr. Alexander</hi> Waynesboro <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> relief for <hi rend="underline">Eliza -------</hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> with 4 small children <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 3 weeks old</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Samuel McCune</hi> <unclear>h----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 1865 <hi rend="underline">Samuel Winston</hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Bowen Albemarle <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
<lb/>Wrote <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> JA McDonnell <abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 9/67
<lb/><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 12/67 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 9th <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr> Freedmen <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> pay from <unclear>Ap 3/67</unclear></p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-19" id="d174">
<head><abbr expan="April">Apr</abbr> 10</head>
<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Margaret Branham</hi> complains that <hi rend="underline"><unclear>George</unclear> Morgan</hi> seduced her under promise of marriage and refuses to do anything for her
<lb/>Morgan lives at Mr John Byers house Wrote to <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> Eph. Lawson to see Morgan &amp; induce him to marry &amp; provide for the woman</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><unclear>George</unclear> Reynolds</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline">Alfred Schifflet</hi> struck him twice on the evening of April 9 &amp; threatened to shoot him if he caught him
<lb/>Directed him to get witness of threat &amp; if <unclear>continued</unclear> make a complaint to magistrate &amp; would attend to it with him</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Thornton</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) living at Mr Gallager <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>House</unclear> asks for meat on <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of sickness.
<lb/>Informed <unclear>him</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> rations here</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Gordon</hi> wife of James Gordon living <unclear>with</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> John Gilkeson on the Greenville <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> clothing for her daughter a <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> one (1) other child <unclear>Boyd 12</unclear> wife has $6 <add hand="h1" place="inline">a month</add> &amp; husband $100 per an</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Scott</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains to <hi rend="underline">John <unclear>Hope</unclear></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $3 for three weeks work from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> /67
<lb/>Referred to William <unclear>Craig</unclear> <unclear>constable</unclear> for collection</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-13" id="d175">
<head>13</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">Marshall Dawson</hi> Sugar <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> claims William Lange <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 11 days, on work <unclear>actrt</unclear> <unclear>rent</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  and that having made a <unclear>contract</unclear> with him to work for one <unclear>year</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> October 1865 &amp; Lange now <unclear>wants to</unclear> discharge him
<lb/>Referred matter to William Montgomery <abbr expan="Justice of the Peace">J.P.</abbr> Deerfield Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>
 who <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>ap</unclear> contract</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Richard Lewis</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for William <unclear>Given</unclear> <unclear>neared</unclear> having <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> pasture Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 1866 to <abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 28 1867 with the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> that Givin was to provide Lewis <unclear>with</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp; winter clothing for himself &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and in the Spring would <unclear>settle</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the <unclear>overplus</unclear> in cash and <unclear>make</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> contract for 1867. Lewis <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  in extra provisions and <unclear>ha----</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> in clothes or money &amp; Lewis <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> pay him anything
<lb/>Referred matter to George Eagle <abbr expan="Justice of the Peace">J.P.</abbr> <unclear>Sh---</unclear> Fork Highland <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
<lb/>Saml Marshal <abbr expan="Justice of the Peace">J.P.</abbr> same district <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Shaws Fork Highland <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 
<lb/>Mr William Givin<lb/><abbr expan="Freedman">Fr</abbr> Richard Lewis <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
<lb/>27 <abbr expan="months">mos</abbr> labor performed <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 15/66 <unclear>yo</unclear> <abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 28/67 @ $10 per month $25.00 <abbr expan="Received">Rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> payment</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-14" id="d176">
<head><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> <unclear>14</unclear></head>
<p><unclear>Made</unclear> contract dated April 1/1867 between <hi rend="underline">John Sanderson</hi> of Churchville and <hi rend="underline">Tom Kenny</hi> father of <hi rend="underline">Sam Kenny</hi> <unclear>for 9 mos</unclear> from <abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 1/ for $20<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $5</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><unclear>Ch--</unclear> Brown</hi> (care of G.H. Hudson Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>) <unclear>asks</unclear> part of her sons earnings (<hi rend="underline"><unclear>Paton</unclear></hi> living with <unclear>J.L.</unclear> Belt, Rockhall <unclear>Monreacy</unclear> <abbr expan="Maryland">Md</abbr> &amp; that said boy <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> back to Staunton</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">Margaret Platt</hi> Augusta <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Staunton complains that <hi rend="underline">Louisa Washington</hi> and <unclear>her</unclear> children are living in a Kitchen attached to her house. She is unable <unclear>to let</unclear> her remain rent free and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>summon</unclear> her
<lb/>Mr. George Bunch is overseer of Poor for Staunton</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>---kle</unclear></hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) Waynesboro complains <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Saturday</unclear> April 13/67 his house was <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by William Bush town sergeant by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> warrant issued by W<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">m</hi></hi>
 Chapman <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> charge that Jesse Pickle &amp; his <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> had stolen meat from <hi rend="underline">John <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> No meat was found and Pickle <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> as to claim for slander.
<lb/>Pickle is not disturbed w <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of and asked by Forbes <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>--nter</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>pro---</unclear> each warrant was issued <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> is only remedy was <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for slander but rather <unclear>a----</unclear> him not</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>----hington</unclear></hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> (<abbr expan="white">w</abbr>) Churchville owes her $6 <unclear>for services</unclear> rendered in 1866</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-15" id="d177">
<head><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 15</head>
<p>Witnessed verbal agreement <unclear>between</unclear> <hi rend="underline">Mr. P. Funkhouser</hi> and <hi rend="underline"><unclear>Howard Alexander</unclear></hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>)<lb/> <hi rend="underline">Alexander</hi> is to take up and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> for relaying all the Bricks <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and bottom, forming the <add hand="h1" place="inline">old</add> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of the Lunatic Assylum and to <unclear>pile</unclear> the <unclear>sams</unclear> outside the Resevoir ready for loading.<lb/><hi rend="underline">Funkhouser</hi> to pay $20 to Alexander on the completion of above job and give him in addition <unclear>one (1)</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> one (1) <unclear>Middlery</unclear> of Bacon.<lb/> Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>  <hi rend="underline">Thos P Jackson</hi><lb/><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 15/67   <abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr></p>

<p>Sent copies of <abbr expan="General Order">G.O.</abbr> No. 9 <abbr expan="Headquarters">H.Q.</abbr> 1st <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> - April 5 1867 to A J Jones <unclear>CC</unclear> Highland <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> W A Burnett <unclear>CC</unclear> Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Punch Fox</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) called on <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> claim against <hi rend="underline">John H <unclear>R------</unclear></hi> of Buffalo Gap (Garner farm) <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> of covenant of <unclear>Indenture</unclear><lb/>Wrote to <abbr expan="County Clerk"><unclear>cc</unclear></abbr> Nelson County for copy of indenture</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-16" id="d178">
<head>16</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">Harry Taylor</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> struck him with a stone <unclear>for not</unclear> <unclear>---tting</unclear> him had R Garber <unclear>whip</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Wm Garber told him not to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $1.00<lb/><unclear>Case</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by trial told him to make a complaint if he desired to before a magistrate</p>

<pb/>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Scott</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <del hand="h1">Wm <unclear>G</unclear></del> <hi rend="underline">Curtis Grayson</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) owes her $2.00<lb/>
The $2 appearing to be in proportion <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to a <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> he could not interfere</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-17" id="d179">
<head>17</head>
<p><hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="Reverend">Revd</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Peirce.</hi> Bridgewater Rockingham <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by Andrew L Lindsay of same <unclear>place</unclear> applies for assistance to a poor <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp; family of five (5) children See <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>/67</p>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Dickinson applies for rations for <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Jefferson</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) living at <hi rend="underline">Dr Madisons</hi> and <unclear>three</unclear> children Dick works at Bagby's <unclear>---yard</unclear>, Cornelius 8, Thomas 4 and <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> infant - live rent free for labor <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp; Dick</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Taliaferro</hi> (Toliver) Staunton <unclear>Gor---</unclear> St. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>relief</unclear></p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) Mt Meridian complains <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">Polly Johnson</hi> claims George <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (<unclear>Heyb--ck</unclear>) <add hand="h1" place="inline">12 <abbr expan="years">yr</abbr>
</add> son of Rachel <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>indentured</unclear> to her<lb/>
Directed him (Craig) to return custody of the boy &amp; if any claim was made it must be through this office</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">-------- Sims</hi> sent <hi rend="underline">George Sims (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>)</hi> to <unclear>answer</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">James Crawford</hi> <add hand="h1" place="inline">James Crawford &amp; William Crawford</add> who lives at <unclear>Little</unclear> Calf Pasture Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> just beyond Buffalo Gap has paid the $25 demanded <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> George Sims works for Blackburn Furnace <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>grain</unclear>
<pb/>
Sims &amp; Brother work at Furnace in Rockingham <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> - <unclear>Abb</unclear> &amp; <abbr expan="Company">Co</abbr> <unclear>proper</unclear> Blackburn manager. Wrote to them care of <unclear>Moses</unclear> Stricker See <unclear>E &amp; M C 5 VI/67</unclear></p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-20" id="d180">
<head>20</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">John Swisher</hi> lives on <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> River <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Waynesboro - states he hired <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> freedman Shelton <unclear>Jones</unclear> as a <unclear>first</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> (agreement in writing but not <unclear>produced</unclear>) that said Shelton Jones is in <unclear>poor health</unclear> and unable to perform <unclear>such labor</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> constitute a first class hand <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> if he be compelled to pay in full <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> services are not rendered.<lb/>Suggested parties had better agree between themselves, if not for Shelton Jones to come to this office.</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">John Worley Bunker</hi> complains that <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Harris</hi> owes him $2 for clothing <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>B--</unclear> at Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> <unclear>Am----</unclear><lb/>Charles Harris<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> John Worley Bunker<lb/>For clothing sold during <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="Received">Recd</abbr> payment</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-22" id="d181">
<head>22</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">James Washington</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that he rented a room from <hi rend="underline">Dr. <unclear>H-----</unclear></hi> agreement mutual that <unclear>Washington </unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> do work for him in payment of rent. Washington from his own statement in the wrong as he had not performed any work in lieu of rent.</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Kendall Roads</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <unclear>he hired</unclear> himself to <hi rend="underline">Henry Koiner</hi> by the month at $11 &amp; 7<hi rend="super">lb</hi>
 Bacon per month
<lb/>The fuss is all about a girl, no action called for</p>

<pb/>

<p><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Saulsbury</unclear> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) Waynesboro complains <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>Parent</unclear> <unclear>(<abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr>)</unclear> Hermitage Waynesboro <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> him for year 1866 worked for him from <abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 13 to August 12/66
<lb/>Sam'l Parent called and names Dr. Saml Kennerly <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Hermitage asks arbitration
<lb/>William Sawlsbury <unclear>names</unclear> the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to Dr. Kennerly
<lb/>Wrote to Dr. Kennerly Hermitage, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> </p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><unclear>Mr John</unclear> Hutchens</hi> Newport <unclear>P</unclear> Moffitts Creek applies <unclear>for relief</unclear> for Mrs <hi rend="underline">Amanda Atkins</hi></p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><unclear>S----lus</unclear> Randall</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) <unclear>on</unclear> Jacob Baylor on the <orig reg="Pond">Ponnd</orig> Gap road complains that <hi rend="underline">William <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> owes him $13.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">90</hi>
</hi> as per act <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  near Swoopes Depot.
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  33.20
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  <hi rend="underline">  .70</hi>
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  33.90
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>   7.50
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  <hi rend="underline"> 4.25</hi>
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $45.65
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 10.00
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 13.00
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  6.00
<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  2.75  <hi rend="underline">$31.75</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">$13.90</hi>
<lb/>Wrote WM <unclear>Tait</unclear> <abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 22/67 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> 
<lb/>See <abbr expan="Complaint Book">CB</abbr> <abbr expan="Page">Pg</abbr> 82
</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Poindexter</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that he worked <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> per day on the Wood train of the <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="March">Mch</abbr>/66 Hired by <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>S---d</unclear></hi> who lives at Pond Gap Augusta <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> $11.50.<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> was at <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Ian Henry <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Midway <abbr expan="Augusta">Aug</abbr> <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>.</p>

<pb/>

<p><hi rend="underline">Jonas Turner</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline"><unclear>Cy---</unclear> Huff</hi> took advantage of him in a settlement of <unclear>buckets</unclear> and poultry.<lb/>J Turner had made a settlement with Huff and <abbr expan="amount">amt.</abbr> small advised him to let it go.</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">William Saulsbury</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> McCreary</hi> Tinkling Spring Fishersville <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> indebted to him on open <abbr expan="account">act</abbr> for labor as blacksmith &amp;c Marshall/constable has the papers and promised to bring <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> them to this office on Tuesday next the 26 <abbr expan="Instant">Inst</abbr>.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-23" id="d182">
<head>23</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">Judy Brown</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) about 65 old &amp; <unclear>helpless</unclear> asks relief food or clothing<lb/>
Care apparently one of want &amp; <unclear>will</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> May 4/67 <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Peck to G Bunch that woman in his district <abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 29/67 Wrote G Bunch. </p>

<p>Received from <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">J.G. Stove</hi> $<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>for</unclear> <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Washington</hi>. See <unclear>Pg.75</unclear>
<lb/>Expended same ($2) by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> order for Provisions on her <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Dr. W. B. Young</hi> applies <unclear>as to</unclear> <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> See <abbr expan="Complaint Book">CB</abbr> <abbr expan="Page">Pg.</abbr>
 81</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">David Lewis</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) 65 applies for <unclear>help</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Ann Adams</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) living at <hi rend="underline">David <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>---ans</unclear> Creek is wanted by her <unclear>husband</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to join <del hand="h1">her</del> him at <unclear>Parkersburg</unclear> <abbr expan="West Virginia">W.V.</abbr> T. J. Dewey writes for him. See <abbr expan="Complaint Book">C.B.</abbr> F. 78</p>
</div3>

<pb/>

<div3 type="entry" n="1867-04-24" id="d183">
<head><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 24</head>
<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Edney</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that Mr <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> near Greenville hired his wife <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Edney for the year 1866 <add hand="h1" place="inline">agreeing to</add> pay her <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> furnish her with clothing <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>paid</unclear> her $7 &amp; furnished her with clothing <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> cannot pay her the $18 &amp; does not know <unclear>when</unclear> he can. April 25/67 Mr. Brown Lee called &amp; stated that Edney was consenting party to the agreement for year 1866 &amp; that $8 &amp; not $18 is due for 1866 &amp; will be paid to Anna as wanted - Under circumstances decided not to interfere as Edney is stated to be a very trifling fellow.<lb/>
Wrote Brown Lee <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> 47</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Adams</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) Westview complains that <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Harden</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) who works at Square <del hand="h1">Hills</del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Hill (<abbr expan="Post Office">P.O.</abbr>) had a child by Angeline <unclear>W----</unclear> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) his <unclear>sister</unclear> refuses to contribute to the support or marry the girl.<lb/><abbr expan="Referred">Ref.</abbr> case to Henry Eidson <abbr expan="Justice of the Peace">J.P.</abbr> Westview<lb/><abbr expan="Letter Book">L.B.</abbr> 48 v. 1/67</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Cox</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline">Thomas <unclear>K---y</unclear></hi> Scottsville, Albemarle <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> owes him <unclear>for four</unclear> (4) months work as a farm hand from April 1st 1866 at $6 per month<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del><lb/>George Herndon (<abbr expan="White">W</abbr>)<lb/><unclear>G----</unclear> <unclear>Carson</unclear> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>)<lb/><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Scottsville</p>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Madison</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) living in Staunton <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> his two sons. <hi rend="underline">John Madison</hi> about <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Madison</hi> about 15 <abbr expan="years">y</abbr>. When last heard <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at Baltimore.<lb/>Addressed him to a certain man <abbr expan="Colored">Col<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> minister at Baltimore <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> to be <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> See <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> v1/67 91.</p>

<pb/>

<p><hi rend="underline">Alfred Stribling</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) lives at <unclear>Buffalo Gap</unclear> complains that Mr. <hi rend="underline">James <unclear>Cook</unclear></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <abbr expan="Amherst County">Am<hi rend="super">st</hi> Co</abbr> owes him for 15 days work <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> in November 1866, which at <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> per <unclear>day</unclear> is $4.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">50</hi>
</hi>. Stribling complains that <unclear>although</unclear> he had engaged to work for Cook by <unclear>the year</unclear> he Cook did not permit Stribling <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> the dwelling house inhabitable <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Wrote orders Cork to pay <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> 59 v1/67<lb/><abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> 30/67 <abbr expan="Received">Rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> letter from Cook C4 v1/67<lb/>May 6/67 Wrote James Cook <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> 104 v1/67</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Reily McDonald</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) complains that <hi rend="underline">C W Oltmann</hi> <unclear>north</unclear> of Washington <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Lexington owes him $8.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="super">50</hi></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> made out Bill<lb/>Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> <abbr expan="April">Ap</abbr> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del><lb/>Mr. C W Oltmann<lb/>Dr to Reily McDonald<lb/><unclear>Washing</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del><lb/>Paid in <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <lb/>Baldwin informs <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <lb/>See <abbr expan="Letter Book">LB</abbr> v1/67 60 &amp; 61</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1866-04-25" id="d184">
<head>25</head>
<p><hi rend="underline">Frances McMullen</hi> in <unclear>Westview</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <hi rend="underline">Julia <add hand="h1" place="inline">A</add> Johnson (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>)</hi> 12 <abbr expan="years">y.</abbr> who <unclear>has been living</unclear> with Wm Shumate <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Has no clothing or food<lb/>Mr Shumate will support her for a reasonable time at <unclear>St-</unclear> Davenports until enquiry are made. Sent her there in charge of <unclear>Chas Reaple</unclear></p>

<p>Made contract between <hi rend="underline"><unclear>William</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del></hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) &amp; Gabriel <unclear>Cross</unclear> of Jennings Gap <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>say</unclear> till <abbr expan="December">Dec</abbr> 31/67 @ $12 <unclear>per month</unclear></p>

<pb/>

<p><hi rend="underline"><del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> Sheffey</hi> (<abbr expan="colored">c</abbr>) lives at Stuarts Draft Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>, complains that he rented by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> agreement from <hi rend="underline">Zachariah <unclear>McChes---</unclear></hi> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and about 25 acres land then <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> by Thomas <unclear>Pan---</unclear> at an <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> rent of $25 <unclear>1/30</unclear> the <unclear>front</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>lease</unclear> to be given in <unclear>March</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> at the latest. That <unclear>Pannel</unclear> has <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> &amp; <unclear>says</unclear> he shall not move <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> until coming Fall and that <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> <unclear>time</unclear> Perry Sheffey is compelled to <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> in consequence <unclear>--ss</unclear> to had <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>  room in Z McChesney.<lb/>Directed Sheffey to notify McChesney that he required place <unclear>vacated</unclear> by <unclear>Parnet</unclear> &amp; he report to this office results
</p>
</div3>
 </div2>
</div1>
 
</body>
</text>
</TEI.2>