<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0013"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0013">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    December 10, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 10 1862</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0013 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501188</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, December 10,
                            1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 10 1862</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-10">1862-12-10 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Medicine/Hospitals </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0013T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter describes the hospital in which he works and tells about distributing
                    medicine to patients.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-10">Dec. 10 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Casey </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p><orig reg="Mary's">Marys</orig> letter informing me of your sickness came safely
                    to hand &amp; I felt very glad that you got along so well with your fine
                    boy. I do not know what name to give him now. After I get home &amp; see him
                    I can find out a name for him. Take good care of him till I see him. I am glad
                    too that you have such good neighbors so that you had all necessary care in your
                    sickness. </p>

                <p>My <orig reg="duties">dutys</orig> in the hospital are to give out the medicine
                    the Surgeon prescribed. The sick call is at eight <orig reg="o'clock"
                    >oclock</orig> in the morning when all the sick in the companies come up to the
                    hospital with their sore toes, sore shins, sore heads, bad colds, rheumatisms
                    about 30 or 40 every morning come to get medicine &amp; it takes the <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> about 2 or 3 hours examining their ailments
                    &amp; prescribing the medicine for them which I have to put up for each one.
                    Some are sick in their tent. The doctor visits &amp; prescribes for them so
                    they are coming in all through the day for medicine &amp; some of us have to
                    be on hand to give it out. We have 10 patients in our hospital who have to have
                    their medicine &amp; my duty is to see that they get it at the right times
                    &amp; to see that the nurses do their duty keeping the hospital &amp;
                    patients clean &amp; properly warmed &amp; also to see that the patients
                    each one gets his proper diet so one of us have to overlook the cooks to get
                    what is suitable for the patients cooked. <del hand="h1">One poor soldier will
                        probably</del> So you see I am kept very close in the hospital. This
                    afternoon the other hospital steward Dr. Casey &amp; myself rode out for a
                    couple hours. We visited some of the forts handy. Fort Lincoln is in sight only
                    1/4 of a mile from our camp.</p>

                <p>Well Cynthia I would very much like to have been there with you. I have felt
                    uneasy for some time but now since it is over &amp; you are doing well that
                    care has been lightened &amp; I pray God that he may continue your health
                    that you may train up those children in the fear of the Lord &amp; I would
                    pray that your health that we may meet again &amp; enjoy each others society
                    &amp; have that pleasure in our children we have enjoyed.</p>

                <p>Josey must be a good boy to his little brother &amp; nurse him for me
                    &amp; I know Lucy &amp; Bell will like the boy they have got. Bell be a
                    good girl &amp; Lucy must be good to her sister Bell as well as her little
                    brother. Well Mary I feel proud of the compliment the old doctor paid you. You
                    are deserving it. May God bless you Mary &amp; enable you to grow in grace,
                    to adorn the Christian character &amp; to <orig reg="have">hav</orig> your
                    hope in heaven. Well Cynthia let us all still put our trust in that Almighty
                    power that has kept us all in the hollow of his hand &amp; we will be happy.
                    No more at present but remain</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
