<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0011"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F0011">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    December 2, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 2 1862</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0011</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501186</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, December 2, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, december 2 1862</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Pennsylvania Historical and
                            Museum Commission, Civil War Material, Misc. Diaries, and Letters,
                            Microfilm, MG-132</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>This transcription was made from a typescript of the original
                            letter.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-02">1862-12-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Family, Military Authority, Troop Movement,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against transcription; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0011T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter's letter expresses a faith in God, whatever his own fate may be, and
                    expresses his desire to see his children, including his youngest son.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-02">Dec. 2nd 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Casey</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I write to let you know that I am still in the good enjoyment of good health
                    &amp; hope you are enjoying the same blessing Well Cynthia tomorrow morning
                    at 8 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> we start for Fredericksburg to join <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen</abbr>
                    <orig reg="Burnside's">Burnsides</orig> army. I had hoped to get home to see you
                    before we left here but now I can not tell when it will be that I may see you It
                    is in the path of duty &amp; in the proper performance of it with a reliance
                    on the God of battles we may hope to have him smile on us. &amp; yet we do
                    not know in what manner he will glorify his name by us, whether by sparing our
                    health &amp; lives for future usefulness or by suffering &amp; death.
                    Whatever is his will let us say thy will be done in submission. Let us remember
                    that the bows of God are on us my dear wife &amp; endurance all things in
                    patience. I would like so much to see the children too with our youngest boy
                    Jimmy Sloan tell them that Pa would like so much to kiss them all this afternoon
                    &amp; take them on his knee. I will send this by a man from Washington Co.
                    &amp; you will find in it the key of my Carpet Sack &amp; a receipt from
                    Express Co. The sack will go to West Alexander to your address. I forgot when I
                    started it to keep out the berries that I had not used I was keeping them for a
                    time when I would be sick, as my health has been good all the time I forgot them
                    until the Carpet Sack was started &amp; then it was too late. Maybe you will
                    have a chance of sending <orig reg="them">the</orig> after a while with some
                    person. The box you sent has not come yet. The doctor was at the Express office
                    yesterday &amp; it was not there. One of the doctors has gone to town in an
                    ambulance. He will see if it is there &amp; if so will bring it out. I have
                    had no letter from you for 2 weeks now &amp; I would like very much to get
                    one soon to know how you all are. I feel uneasy lest some of you may be sick. No
                    more just now Cynthia but I pray that God may keep you in his Care &amp;</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I ask for your prayers for your affectionate husband</salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
