<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0028"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0028">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    February 8, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 8 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0028</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501203</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, February 8, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 8 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-08">1864-02-08 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0028T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter reports on recent skirmishes and suggests that the rebels are getting
                    "tired." He also notes that he is expecting five months of back pay.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-08">Feb 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16th Pa Cav, Near Warrenton, Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It is a week yesterday since I have received a letter from you. This is
                    occasioned some time ago in writing by my delay. You are waiting a letter from
                    me. Yesterday I got that Cake &amp; can of apples. I hoped to get a letter
                    in the box but their was nothing for me except the eatables which pitched into
                    &amp; I tell you they were good, expecially coming from your fireside. I
                    would have been pleased if Josey, Lucy, Bell, &amp; Jimmy were by me to get
                    a piece of it. They thought it would be good to make Pa better so Aunt Mary
                    writes. Well Pa is as well &amp; hearty as ever but the cake made him feel
                    better. Made the fireside of home more distinctly into view. Will Potters box
                    was brought without having anything in it disturbed or spoiled. Some of the boys
                    that get boxes <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    <orig reg="fare">fares</orig> so well. Will keeps hearty &amp; well. Will
                    Carrol has pretty good health. George McDaid has tolerable health.</p>

                <p>I got a letter from home on last Friday. They are all well. Mary says she was
                    down to see you &amp; found you all in good health. She wrote about Josey
                    wanting to go home with her &amp; Lucy told him to wait until Jimmy came
                    &amp; he could go home with her. Lucy wanted to go with Mother &amp;
                    Jimmy. Aunt Mary wrote too how Jimmy sat on her knee &amp; tried to talk to
                    her with all his might. He <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> say yes can he.</p>

                <p>There was cannon firing in the direction of Rapidan on Saturday. We could hear it
                    all day. We see by the paper today that the rebs moved some of their force down
                    to the river and opened on our men, when our forces turned on them &amp;
                    turned them back. The report here is that the pontoons were run down to the
                    river &amp; the 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> &amp; 3<hi rend="super"
                    >rd</hi> Corps crossed over &amp; thrashed the Johnnies. This is camp rumor
                    here how true it is I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know. The papers <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> give any particulars.</p>

                <p>Our division has been quiet ever since my return. We were saddled up one night
                    sometime ago expecting the <orig reg="rebels">rebs</orig>. Morning came but nary
                    a <orig reg="rebel">reb</orig>. The boys unsaddled.</p>

                <p>The pickets up about Warrenton have a few shots sometimes. The <orig reg="rebels"
                        >rebs</orig> are getting tired of it so we are having a quiet time.</p>

                <p>Dr. Lemon of the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> Pa Reserves has been made Surgeon of
                    our Regiment. Dr. Hermann is still the <orig reg="Assistant">Assisstant</orig>
                    &amp; we <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> have but one so my hopes are deferred
                    for the present.</p>

                <p>I certainly looked for a letter from you at the time the box would come but have
                    received none yet. Did you write. Mr. James Howe sent me a Washington Tribune
                    &amp; a <sic corr="Cincinnati">Cincinatti</sic> paper. Will you give him my
                    compliments for the acceptable reading matter.</p>

                <p>The Paymaster has not been here since my return &amp; I now have 5 months pay
                    coming. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know when he will pay off, probably not
                    soon towards spring. How are you getting along for money. Your wood <orig
                        reg="won't">wont</orig> cost as much as I supposed it would. The 1<hi
                        rend="super">st</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> Cavalry have got home. I hear the folks will be
                    very glad to see them. You will find that I have broken my promise about
                    writing. I felt so sure of getting a letter on Sabbath day from you I thought to
                    wait until yours would come &amp; then I could answer it. The box came but
                    no letter. You wrote I feel sure but it is lost.</p>

                <p>Everything is quiet today. No firing that we can hear. The boys feel better in
                    their cabins these times than they do <orig reg="bivouacking">bivuacing</orig>
                    these cold nights. We are having frost at night with clear bright sunshiny days.
                    Hoping to hear from you soon I remain your </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Send me a few stamps if you please. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
