<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0027"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0027">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    January 31, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 31 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0027</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501202</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, January 31, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 31 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-31">1864-01-31 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, Women </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0027T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter writes to his wife about how much he misses his family and reiterates his
                    faith in God.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-31">Jan 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16th Pa Cav, Turkey Run Near Warrenton </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> a letter from you this evening which not
                    only gladdened me by hearing from you but I had the pleasure of seeing you again
                    &amp; think you are as good looking as ever. It makes the place feel
                    brighter. In the letters written I have informed you of the move coming into
                    camp. I have a very good cabin to live in. It has a good fireplace, a good bed
                    &amp; is daubed with mud making a fine loghouse. The Doctor has dismissed me
                    from his featherbed, his wife &amp; little girl being here to share it with
                    him. I have a bed made of poles with an armful of hay on them. The man who is
                    living in the cabin with me has 3 blankets &amp; I have two so that we are
                    prepared for the cold weather. The weather the last 2 weeks has been beautiful.
                    Some of the days we have had no fire &amp; felt very comfortable. Yesterday
                    there was a change, foggy, drizzling all day. Today is <orig reg="cloudy"
                        >clouday</orig>, though not raining. Several officers have their <orig
                        reg="wives">wifes</orig> here. There are two little boys here about the size
                    of Josey, whiteheaded, they sing, "Rally round the flag boys" &amp; it
                    sounds for all the world like our little fellows at home sing, so you see Josey
                    Lucy &amp; Bell are brought &amp; kept in mind all the time. I think I
                    can hear them singing all the time. What are you doing this Sabbath evening. I
                    would like to enjoy it with you being in good health &amp; if I was in Good
                    Intent you may be sure we would have a pleasant evening. I would like so well to
                    hear the children singing at worship, no music would sound sweeter. This being
                    the last day of the month I had my report of the sick &amp; wounded for
                    month to make out. It takes up a good deal of time, as we have to give each
                        <orig reg="man's">mans</orig> disease &amp; in case of wounds we have to
                    give a full history of them. So you see my Sabbath has not been spent as we
                    spend it at home by our fireside. This evening will be a pleasant one to me as I
                    will spend the remainder of it with you. Knowing that you &amp; your little
                    ones will join in a Psalm in the praise of God I will suppose you to sing the
                        23<hi rend="super">rd</hi> and at bedtime I will join you. Although we will
                    not hear one another yet he to whose praise we will sing will hear us all
                    &amp; may we not hope unite our songs in Heaven uniting our prayers too. I
                    feel confident that yours &amp; the children are offered to God in my behalf
                    &amp; mine are offered for you. May we not hope for his blessing on us all,
                    that we may not be led from the path of Duty, that his blessings may be on our
                    labors, on our lives, on our children on us in all our relations in life, that
                    we may be good soldiers, good citizens, good christians &amp; then we will
                    be happy in each others society &amp; in the love &amp; respect of our
                    children. We have no news of any importance. There was some picket firing around
                    our camp last night &amp; I felt glad that my wife would not be alarmed by
                    it. There was no cause for alarm the picket said he saw a man approaching on
                    horseback, he halted him the man wouldn't halt so the picket fired a couple of
                    shots at him making the people in camp uneasy for awhile. Some of the officers
                    think it was only a bush moved by the wind. I am glad you got so fine a lot of
                    wood. Josey will have time to play after school is over. How <orig reg="are"
                    >is</orig> Lucy &amp; him getting along with their studies. Sam Porter came
                    here a week or two ago &amp; the next morning reported himself sick. The Dr.
                    asked him how long he had been unwell. Sam told a doleful story of his sickness
                    &amp; he was sent to the Hospital at Warrenton where he is now. Hoping to
                    have the pleasure of spending some of my Sabbath evenings with you I remain your
                    most affectionate </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>husband </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Will you please send me a few stamps as they are hard to
                        get here. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
