<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0031"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0031">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    March 25, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, march 25 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0031</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501206</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, March 25, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, march 25 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-25">1864-03-25 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Enlistment </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0031T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter sends his wife a copy of his regimental history for her safekeeping and
                    discusses his prospects for a furlough.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-25">March 25 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Hospital Department 16th Pa Cav, Turkey Run, Va </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the 15 <hi rend="super">th</hi> &amp; 18<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    were <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> this evening &amp; I feel sorry
                    for the little folk who are sick. I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be much help
                    to you &amp; hope you may get along without much trouble. I expect you had
                    better have Dr. Davidson to see Josey &amp; he can tell I suppose what
                    causes the pain in the side &amp; what you had better do for it. Give Josey
                    as nourishing diet as you can to keep up his strength, milk &amp; eggs if
                    you can get them. Nurse his appetite with anything nourishing you can get him to
                    eat. I got a letter from Father last Sabbath. Lizzie was about well &amp;
                    Susie had been sick 4 or 5 days when they wrote.</p>

                <p>On Wednesday morning we had about 8 inches of snow on the ground. Yesterday was
                    bright &amp; beautiful. This evening it is raining &amp; has been for
                    several hours &amp; there is not much prospect of it ceasing soon. It is all
                    quiet here. The <abbr expan="rebels">rebs</abbr>
                    <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> disturb us any. Our pickets near Bealton pick up
                    one every now and then.</p>

                <p>I hear that General Grant came down to the Army of Potomac yesterday &amp; as
                    soon as the roads are fit I suppose he will have us on the go again.</p>

                <p>I sent you today a history of our regiment for its first years operations. I wish
                    you would not let it get destroyed as it will be interesting to look at when I
                    get home. </p>

                <p>I would be very much pleased to cut your wood this evening &amp; take my pay
                    &amp; some of Lucy's molasses. Nothing could afford me more pleasure. Then I
                    could do something for Josey &amp; have my helpmate at hand!</p>

                <p>You speak of settling Ambless note. I expect that will be the best plan owing to
                    the distance he lives from Good Intent. There is some talk of the paymaster
                    coming around before long. Let me know how you get along with your money. In
                    regard to the office you may rest assured that I will make every effort to get
                    it but you see others have a say about it. Dr. Hermann was at Harrisburg this
                    week talking to Dr. King about his own &amp; my case. Dr. King promises him
                    as soon as there is a vacancy would occur he would procure a furlough for me so
                    that I can go to Harrisburg &amp; be examineed. Dr. H. will also go to be
                    examined for Surgeon as he is now only an <orig reg="Assistant"
                    >Assisstant</orig>. He &amp; I will go together as soon as Dr. King says so.</p>

                <p>If we get some more recruits I will get the position in this regiment as the
                        <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> has as much as promised to use his
                    influence. If our regiment is not recruited up I will have to wait until Dr.
                    Hermann is promoted Surgeon to some other regiment. Then I will get his place
                    here. So we must have patience. It is late bedtime &amp; I will not close my
                    letter until morning but go to bed asking the <orig reg="choicest"
                    >choisest</orig> blessing for my wife &amp; family that their lives may be
                    spared &amp; enabled to honor God in all that they do. Good night.</p>

                <p>Saturday March 26<hi rend="super">th</hi><lb/> Nothing new this morning. All
                    Quiet. I wonder how you all are this morning. I hope Josey is better. We had
                    about 20 recruits come in a few minutes filling up a little. It may be we will
                    get enough before long to give me an <orig reg="Assistant">Assisstant</orig>
                    Surgeons position. I will be rejoiced for your sake if it is so. I can get home
                    to see you &amp; have more means for your comfort at home. I am very busy
                    with reports today &amp; <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> answer your two
                    letters as well as I would like to do but remain with unchanged love</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your most affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Write soon </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
