<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0037"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0037">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    June 20, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, june 20 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0037</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501212</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, June 20, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, june 20 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-20">1864-06-20 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Battle Description, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 1st Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0037T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter describes in detail the "severe" fighting near Gordonsville, Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-20">June 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near White House Landing, Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Today we got in camp again after a long march during which we had no <orig
                        reg="communication">comunnication</orig>. We were near Gordonsville where we
                    had a severe fight, tore up about 5 miles of Rail Road, burning every tie
                    &amp; bending each rail. I got but one letter from you &amp; one from
                    Fathers folks. I was very glad to get them &amp; to know that you are all
                    well. Well we did not get into Richmond but hope Grant will work his way in some
                    way or other. As I feel very tired &amp; sleepy I <orig reg="can't"
                    >cant</orig> give you a very full account of our trip.</p>

                <p>This is the first letter since the last of May &amp; you know that I was
                    glad. Who is teaching school in your place. I am glad that all three of the
                    children are going. Can Lucy read yet. Oh yes you told me that she was in the
                    first reader. What is Bell studying now. Jimmy I suppose will soon be able to
                    say his A,B,Cs. June 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi>. Well the rebs got a position
                    here &amp; shelled wagon train driving it across the river. so yesterday
                    morning we had to get up at 2 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> &amp;
                    marched on foot driving the rebs until we came up to their <orig
                        reg="fortifications">fortifacations</orig>. We skirmished some with them.
                    Our regiment, the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Pennsylvania  
 Cavalry">Pa. Cav.</abbr> had about 4 killed
                    &amp; about 30 wounded, not having any one hurt. This morning we are still
                    in the fields &amp; I hear that the rebs have fallen further back so we are
                    quiet now but <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know how long it will last. We have
                    seen but one newspaper for the last fifteen days &amp; <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> know very much about what is going on in the outside world. A
                    great many negroes joined us in our last march willing to endure privations for
                    the sake of liberty. All kinds came along old men &amp; boys, Old women
                    &amp; children of all sizes from the infant at the breast to grown up boys
                    &amp; girls. Some of the sights would amuse the children for instance one
                    old grey-headed fellow was tramping along with a 3 year old astride his
                    shoulders. the little fellow looking happy as a king while he held on to the old
                    ones head. In our fight near Gordonsville we had quite a number of wounded which
                    we had to haul away loading all the wagons &amp; ambulances. We hauled them
                    here for about a week before coming here to ship them off. The sight at night
                    was a queer one. The <abbr expan="Doctors">Drs.</abbr> would get the wounded out
                    to dress them &amp; at a number of large fires the negro women were cooking
                    for themselves &amp; the wounded, children crying, wounded moaning, old
                    darks in confusion running around, mules bawling, all mixed up. We had about 400
                    prisoners along. The poor fellows did not have the best time of it marching on
                    foot along with a Cavalry column &amp; to make it harder we had but 5 days
                    rations for 15 days. Still a great many of the boys shared their hardtack with
                    the rebels &amp; then would forage corn meal flour &amp; bacon until
                    they arrived here &amp; drew rations. I am thankful to be able to say that
                    my health continues good, though we have seen a good deal hard service. We hope
                    to get a few days rest as our horses are nearly worn out. While I think of it
                    please send me a sheet of paper &amp; envelope in your next letter until we
                    get in camp, as this one came in very good play. I had some paper &amp;
                    envelopes in my saddle pocket. the boys were out &amp; expecting to get in
                    camp sooner to let one &amp; another have some until I am entirely out.
                    Accept my thanks for your foresight in sending this. I would like to write a
                    letter to Josey &amp; Lucy but have no paper &amp; am sitting in a field
                    my horse saddled up not knowing what minute the bugle will sound "to horse." Ask
                    them to excuse Pa this time as he does not forget them but still has the same
                    love &amp; care that he always had for them. Still praying that God will
                    bless &amp; take care of mother &amp; them. Ask them to continue to pray
                    that God will bless Pa &amp; Mother &amp; make them good children,
                    receiving them into his kingdom. The order is to move so I must close. Assuring
                    you my dear wife of the continuance of my love for you &amp; asking your
                    prayers at the throne of grace for </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your most<lb/> affectionate<lb/> husband </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
