<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0032"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0032">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    April 9, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 9 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0032</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501207</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, April 9, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 9 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-09">1864-04-09 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0032T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter asks about the health and well-being of his family at home and apologizes
                    that his letters have not been received regularly.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-09">April 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Hospital Department 16th Pa. Cav. Turkey Run, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> of April was received this evening
                    &amp; I am glad to know that you are well but feel sorry my dear wife that
                    you was disappointed in not getting my letter in good time. I mailed one to you
                    on the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> of April &amp; on Saturday the 26<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> of March one to Josey &amp; you &amp; a
                    pamphlet history of the regiment on Saturday the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> one.
                    I am too glad to get a letter from you to disappoint you in not writing. The
                    fault is in the mail department. Perhaps you will get them before this reaches
                    you. Major McFarland was here last Saturday the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    &amp; if you happen to see him he can give you an account of how we live
                    here. The paymaster was here. I got 2 months pay (60) Sixty dollars. (50) Fifty
                    of it I expressed to father, keeping (10) ten for my expenses. If you <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> get along for money you had better draw some from
                    him. Let me know how far your fifty goes.</p>

                <p>I am sorry you had to write without one of mine to answer if it gives you as much
                    pleasure to write as it does me to write to you all I fear is that I may make
                    myself look foolish for writing how dearly and tenderly I regard you &amp;
                    how anxious I feel for your happiness. If it is foolish I <orig reg="can't"
                    >cant</orig> help it &amp; am willing to bear the charge of foolishness as
                    long as I have your love and affection to cheer &amp; lighten my heart. </p>

                <p>I am sorry that I will have no chance to make garden for you, but still indulge
                    the hope of getting to Harrisburg before long &amp; then of course home to
                    see my wife and family. I will look for a letter from Josey some of these days.
                    I got a letter from fathers folks they are all quite well. You ask me to excuse
                    the short letter. A letter from you is always acceptable whether it is long or
                    not. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think of it being short for several days
                    then when I look at it I sometimes wish it was longer but one from you is always
                    welcome. The reason I did not write my name in the book was that it would have
                    to be classed with letters &amp; that would cost too much. <orig reg="Don't"
                        >Dont</orig> think that I am simple when I tell you that while I am writing
                    I am looking at you &amp; you have a smile so pleasant on your face for me,
                    while Jimmy looks sober as a judge. You ask me to join you in prayer. Most
                    cheerfully &amp; sincerely my wife will I join you &amp; hope to have
                    closer communion with you by our joining our hearts to God in prayer for his
                    blessings on us &amp; thanks for the many mercies we have enjoyed at his
                    hands. As he is the giver of every good &amp; perfect gift we will praise
                    his holy name for his goodness to us. We have nothing new here all is quiet. Dr.
                    Herrmann is quite unwell has inflammation of the lungs. My own health is very
                    good as it has been all winter. I am glad that your cold is better &amp;
                    hope the children will not have whooping cough until the weather gets warmer.
                    Bell wants you to write that she is a good girl. I feel sure that my children
                    all are. Are they not mother? I hope God will take care of them that they may
                    always be good be kept of temptation. Keep them out of bad company mother that
                    makes children bad &amp; I pray that God will crown you all with his richest
                    blessings. I will not close till morning. Friday April 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    a most beautiful pleasant morning all quiet. Well as I will have the sick here
                    in a short time &amp; the mail goes out at half past eight I must close
                    assuring you of my kindest regards. Give the children a kiss for me. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed> </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
