<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0042"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0042">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John
                    Taggart, July 26, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, july 26 1861</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0042</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501217</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Letterhead: This letter was written on stationery that pictures a man holding
                        the United States Flag with the words "Defend It!" written beneath.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, July 26, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, july 26 1861</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-26">1861-07-26 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Patriotism, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0042T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart tells his brother about getting used to camp life.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-26">26 July 1861 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Graham </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Dear John</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>My last letter to Mary was mailed from the Capitol building, in Washington. When
                    I had nearly finished it, I was ordered to report immediately at Camp and to be
                    ready to start in one hour and a half. It was four hours thereafter before every
                    thing was ready, and the word "forward" given. The boys were all very anxious to
                    know their destination, but of this they were all as ignorant as myself until
                    after a march of three miles, under a very hot sun, we were called to halt in
                    front of this place, which was formerly occupied as a Camp, and called "Graham,"
                    by a <abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr> regiment. Camp Graham is sit-<pb n="2"
                    />uated on an <unclear>eminence</unclear> called "The <unclear>Vidian</unclear>
                    Height" about three miles <abbr expan="North">N.</abbr> of the Capitol; and
                    being principally destitute of trees, is admirably adapted for receiving the
                    searching rays of the sun, during the entire day. We are surrounded on all sides
                    though, by woods, where we can resort during the day to rest. <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    <orig reg="Hays">Hay's</orig> and quite a number of other Pennsylvania
                    regiments, together with a part of Sickles Brigade, are all quartered around us
                    within a <orig reg="circle">sircle</orig> of two miles. Since leaving Pittsburgh
                    we have fared resonably well, although not in a manner to be compared to the
                    time spent in Camp Wilkins or Wright. The boys who grumbled so much in those
                    places bear up admirably under the change, suffering all the unavoidable
                    inconveniences of the "changing <pb n="3"/> wind" with commendable good nature.
                    During our journey we were unmolested by the secessionists, although between
                    Cokeysville, and this, there are numbers of them. It is said by folks in the
                    vicinity, that we came through Baltimore with greater demonstrations of national
                    devotion, and less annoyance, than any regiment that preceded us. Along the
                    entire route from one depot to the other, a distance of perhaps two miles, we
                    marched with flying colors to the tunes of "Yankee Doodle" "Hail Columbia" "Star
                    Spangled Banner" and such like national music, without meeting with any serious
                    interruption. Occasionally, some of the spectators, secure in their distance
                    from our boys, would indulge in almost inaudible hisses and groans,<pb n="4"/>
                    but never without the intended disparagement being returned and generally
                    without much regard to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>gance of language. </p>

                <p><abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> Barber arrived here on Saturday evening
                    and handed me my watch; also a box containing a revolver and all necessary
                    "fixings" for which handsome and, -- under present circumstances, -- very useful
                    present. I am indebted to that natural regard on your part for my welfare; of
                    which I have received so many indoubted evidences. I am indeed very grateful to
                    you for this and the many other favors I have received at your hand, and promise
                    to use the article when necessity demands for the purpose for which it was
                    intended. Such articles in regular battle are not<pb n="5"/>much used; but I am
                    informed by a number of the N.Y. <unclear>Zouaves</unclear>, and others, who
                    were engaged in the recent "<orig reg="Bull">Bull's</orig> run" affair, that
                    they proved the means of saving quite a number of the wounded from being
                    murdered. They say the <orig reg="secessionists">secessioninst</orig> have no
                    mercy on the <orig reg="wounded">wounded</orig>, but <orig reg="whenever">when
                        ever</orig> they pass on the field or elsewhere, one who cannot take himself
                    away, they instantly bayonet him. The game is now being played as a general
                    thing on both sides. </p>

                <p>Yesterday our regiment was mustered into the U.S. service. I was acting "Corporal
                    of the guard" during the day, and was not mustered with the rest, but suppose I
                    will be today. We have no idea when we will move from this; but the
                        impression<pb n="6"/> seems to prevail, that there will be no forward
                    movement on the part of any of our troops for two or three weeks. There are many
                    secessionists in and about this place, but they have to keep so decidedly quiet
                    that they do us but little harm. Not having got a wink of sleep last night, I
                    must now try and take a little. Give my love to Father Mary Lill Sam Lize Bill
                        <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> L. and Charley. My kindest regards to
                    enquiring friend and believe me</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>In Affectionate Remembrance<lb/>Your Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. My health is very good. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
