<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0051"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0051">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John
                    Taggart, October 11, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, october 11 1862</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0051</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501226</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, October 11,
                            1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, october 11 1862</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-11">1862-10-11 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0051T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart discusses military policies concerning promotions of officers like
                    himself. Also talks about soldiers' motives for fighting in the war. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-11">October 11<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Sharpsburg <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> came to hand last night and afforded me the
                    gratifying intelligence that you were all well. Sam was over a short time
                    yesterday afternoon. He received a letter the night before from you. I was over
                    at the Camp of the 123<hi rend="super">d</hi> on Thursday evening, and there met
                    Cas. Carpenter, who like all persons in citizens clothes looked odd, but well
                    enough. Yesterday morning Jimmy Sutherland and Sol. <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Schoyer">Schoyer</orig>
                    </unclear> were in camp. They represent things pretty <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    Pittsburgh. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Cushbertson of our <abbr
                        expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr> returned for duty yesterday also Dr. Sowen of
                        <abbr expan="Company">Co</abbr> A. The former was taken prisoner at the
                    Peninsula, and the latter at Bull Run. They are both perfectly satisfied with
                    trip to Richmond. The recent actions left some more vacancies in our <abbr
                        expan="Regiment">Reg</abbr> but only one above the position I now occupy.
                    That one a Captaincy, I might have had, but would not accept it because I
                    thought it would be injustice to an officer of the company whose bravery and
                    competency are beyond doubt; and in whom all the members of the company have the
                    utmost confidence but being so unfortunate as to get wounded on the Peninsula he
                    has been absent ever since and the boys were going to over-look what I
                    considered his just claim. </p>

                <p>You make <orig reg="inquiry">enquiry</orig> about <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
                    >Lieut</abbr> Pierce. I cannot say how he is. When he left the Regiment at
                    Upton's Hill to go to Washington he was as hearty-looking as any man in the
                    Regiment, and had a good appetite. More than that there was no one, if he left,
                    to take charge of the Company, but a wounded Sergeant <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and <del
                        hand="h1"/> is very much blamed for leaving. There are times <pb/> when an
                    officer might not be blamed for "playing off" a little, but the purpose of
                    having a "good time" but I must say, in the case herein mentioned, had I been in
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> place I would have gone on Crutches rather than <abbr
                        expan="Sergeant">Sergt</abbr>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> should have gone with the Company. But in this war some men
                    fight on principle others for <hi rend="underline">money</hi>. the past three or
                    four months have developed and exposed the true motives of such. <del hand="h1"
                    /> tendered his resignation. Resignations are not <hi rend="underline">now</hi>
                    accepted unless accompanied by a Surgeon's certificate, or a certificate from
                    commanding officer of Regiment to the effect that the service would be <hi
                        rend="underline">benefitted</hi> by the <hi rend="underline">acceptance</hi>
                    of said Resignation. I have not the last doubt but <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <hi rend="underline">will</hi> be accepted.</p>

                <p>Mr. Devore must have got with the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Pennsylvania Volunteers" cert="no">P.V.</abbr>, and not the 9<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Pennsylvania Reserve Volunteers" cert="no">P.R.V.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr>, two separate and distinct organizations.
                    The position of Ordinance Sergeant will just suit <hi rend="underline">Jim</hi>.
                    He can ride, either on horse or on wagon, if so minded, and is not necessarily
                    exposed to fire. We have been looking for <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Jackson back and would be glad to hear of his return. I am not with the company
                    but still act <abbr expan="Adjutant">Adjt</abbr>, and will probably continue
                    doing so. My love to all the folks, Mary &amp; Charley. Respects to <orig
                        reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig> friends. And believe me</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Affect</abbr> Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. We have just heard of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> being in
                        Chambersburg. Just take the "Reserves" up there will you, and you'll hear of
                        some of the biggest work yet done in the army. Bob </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
