<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0057"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0057">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John
                    Taggart, April 23, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, april 23 1863</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0057</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501232</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, April 23, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, april 23 1863</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-04-23">1863-04-23 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Women </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0057T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart describes a new encampment near the capitol in Washington and talks about
                    the unhappiness surrounding an colonel's dismissal from service. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863"> April 23<hi rend="super">d</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Capitol Hill <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Dear</hi>
                        <hi rend="underline">John</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I am back at the Regiment once more. Everything looks quite natural, and I feel
                    perfectly at home. The boys seemed all very glad to see me and I can assure you
                    I was no less glad to see them. They have been making many and anxious enquiries
                    about Mrs. <abbr expan="Taggart">T.</abbr> and some of them seem disappointed
                    that I did not bring her to Camp. But, of course, when she went off and married
                    another <hi rend="underline">feller</hi> I could not well ask her to come along. </p>

                <p>We are encamped on "Capitol Hill" about a quarter of a mile from the "Capitol."
                    The <hi rend="underline">site</hi> for a Camp is very good<pb n="2"/> and we
                    have quite comfortable quarters. My house is not quite as good as the one I
                    left, but it can be greatly improved at very little expense. The men are much
                    better fixed than they were before, and they have so far conducted themselves
                    very creditably. We will be put on Provost duty in and around the city.</p>

                <p>I suppose <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Anderson has started for Pittsburgh
                        <orig reg="before">ere</orig> this. It seems that the Secretary of War has
                    positively refused to act in his case. It is really a shame that such a <hi
                        rend="underline">man</hi> and such a soldier should be so sent home. I am
                    told that when the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> started from camp, there was
                    no little stir amongst the boys. and many of them actually <hi rend="underline"
                        >cried</hi>. He left Camp a day or two before the Regiment started for
                    Washington. As they were<pb n="3"/>
                    <del hand="h1">were</del> marching along the "Avenue" to this place, the <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> was standing in the door way of some public
                    building near the Treasury Department. Someone in the first company spied him.
                    The word soon passed along the line and such other <hi rend="underline"
                    >cheering</hi> it is said our boys <orig reg="never">nevery</orig> gave, except
                    to General <sic corr="McClellan">McClelland</sic> himself. and not only <hi
                        rend="underline">our</hi> Regiment but all the others of the Brigade joined
                    with a hearty good will. Some of the big men of the City, behind whom the <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> was trying to conceal himself (for he is very
                    modest) thought they were the object of the enthusiasm and commenced to
                    acknowledge the compliment; but the men soon set them right by crying, "not you,
                    not you, its <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> Anderson" until at last the old
                    Man had to come out on the steps and take off his hat. I think if the <abbr
                        expan="Secretary">Sec.</abbr> of War had witnessed the scene he would have
                    altered his determination. I promised<pb n="4"/> to write to Brother Herdman,
                    and let him know how the case stood. But as the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr>
                    will be home before a letter would arrive, there is not much use in me writing.
                    Please call on Brother Herdman and tell him why I have not written that he may
                    not think I have forgotten my promise.</p>

                <p>It has been raining all day. Give my love to all at home. Respects to <orig
                        reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig> friends, and believe me </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Affect</abbr> Brother </salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">Bob</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
