<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0107"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0107">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, April 27,
                    1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, april 27 1864</title>
        <author>Mox, Lucius P. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sarah Richardson </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0107 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501248</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, April 27, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, april 27 1864</title>
            <author>Lucius P. Mox</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Lucius P. Mox Papers, Archives of the U.S. Army
                            Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-27">1864-04-27 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement, Home Front, Women </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 17th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: B </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0107T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Mox describes recent troop movements and declares that he wants to get revenge on
                    the rebels. He also says he wishes he could be home with Jennie.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Jennie</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-27">April 27th 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Stoneman</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Jennie</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It has been so long since I heard from you but I believe I told you to direct
                    your last to my Regiment so I could not expect to receive it here when I wrote
                    last I expected to be sent to my <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg</abbr> - the next
                    day but we were sent to Camp <unclear>Cadwalader</unclear> where we stayed until
                    the 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> of April when we were sent to Alexandria and from
                    there back to this place again we are encamped on a high bluff on the Maryland
                    side of the Potomac and nearly half a mile from the river, we have a plain view
                    of Alexandria, Fairfax, Arlington, Georgetown, Washington, the long bridge<pb
                        n="2"/> and the navy yard besides almost innumerable camps on both sides of
                    the river.</p>

                <p>I have been well contented here and would be willing to stay till the close of
                    the war but that is more than I have a right to expect we have everything <orig
                        reg="very">verry</orig> nice we have good tents and shade trees planted
                    among them, pretty uniforms and splended new Sabres as bright as steel can be
                    made and several good Brass Bands playing every day with the booming of the big
                    guns on the forts rendering this quite a military place, indeed, Jennie I am <hi
                        rend="underline">quite</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">proud</hi> of my situation it is splendid. I just wish you
                    could be here to see how nice soldiers can live there is a great contrast
                    between this and what we will soon have to see. We will get our orders in a few
                    days and when they are drilled we will go "to fill the vacant ranks of our
                    brothers gone before."<pb n="3"/></p>

                <p>I must confess I was a little sorry to leave Philadelphia it is the best place I
                    ever found <hi rend="underline">in</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">some</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">respects</hi>. I mean but there are some more <hi
                        rend="underline">virtuous</hi> places in the world (Sherman's dale for
                    example) we are not bothered with many lady <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> about here but it is said that a brick building on a hill about
                    two miles from here that was once the home of some <orig reg="aristocratic"
                        >arristocratic</orig> rebel is now the residence of half a score of <orig
                        reg="very">verry</orig> pretty young ladies: for my part I have not seen
                    them so I will not pass my judgement upon them.</p>

                <p>It is my business now to learn how to handle the instruments of death so that my
                    life will not have to go as the price of my ignorance. I have a good sword and
                    intend to make good use of it. The rebels have lately been commiting some
                    horrible wholesale murders among our soldiers<pb n="4"/> and now "<hi
                        rend="underline">revenge</hi>" shall be our motto. there <orig reg="are"
                    >has</orig> more than forty thousand Yankee soldiers pass Washington this week
                    and where they go there will be something down there has been an almost
                    continual stream of soldiers crossing the long bridge for several days and they
                    are not all over yet I think that from present appearances we will soon be able
                    to write that lovely word <orig reg="peace">
                        <hi rend="underline">pease</hi>
                    </orig> with the heart blood of rebellion.</p>

                <p>Now Jennie I hope you will excuse me for not being more interesting this time for
                    I am a little inclined to be lazy this <orig reg="afternoon">after noon</orig>
                    my tent mates are all out on guard and I am alone; the weather is very warm and
                    the trees begin to look green. Indeed Jennie I really wished myself back in
                    Perry County some of these pretty moonlit nights last week but I must quit and
                    go to my supper. Give my love to all the rest of your family and believe me as
                    ever</p>
                <closer>

                    <salute>Your affectionate friend, </salute>
                    <signed>Lucius P. Mox<lb/>Camp Stoneman<lb/>1<hi rend="super">st</hi> Division
                            2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> Brigade<lb/>Co. I 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                        Pa Cav.<lb/>Washington </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Tell me when you got the letters I sent you some time
                        ago. L.P.M. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
