<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0108"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0108">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, May 13, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, may 13 1865</title>
        <author>Mox, Lucius P. </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Sarah Richardson </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0108 </idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501249</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lucius P. Mox to Jennie, May 13, 1865</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lucius p mox to jennie, may 13 1865</title>
            <author>Lucius P. Mox</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source copy consulted: Lucius P. Mox Papers, Archives of the U.S. Army Military History
       Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-05-15">1865-05-15 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>Regiment: none </term>
          <term>Company: none </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0108T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Mox expresses his excitement to return home at the end of the war. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Jennie</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1865-05-13">Monday May 13th 1865 </date>
      <name type="place">Chapel Point Md</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Jennie </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I received two letters from on Saturday evening one they were dated Apr 28<hi rend="super"
     >th</hi> and May 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> they were sent to Pleasant Valley and consequently I
     did not get them for so long I was beginning to fear that there was something wrong that I did
     not hear from you but it is all right now for I know you are well and still love as ever you
     have. Jennie your letters are <orig reg="very">verry</orig> interesting more so since you have
     begun to recover than they were some time ago.</p>

    <p>I am glad to hear that you have concluded to pay a visit to my old home, I <orig
      reg="consider">concider</orig> it a <orig reg="very">verry</orig> pleasant place and I expect
     to be<pb n="2"/> there myself in a few more days for it is reported that we will leave here
     this week perhaps tomorrow to join our Regiment at Washington and then we will all be sent to
      <hi rend="underline">Harrisburg</hi> to be discharged and sent home.</p>

    <p>I was somewhat surprised to hear that my "prodigal brother" has <orig reg="come">came</orig>
     home - it is a pretty time now for him to talk of going to the army when this war is over. It
     speaks well for his bravery but if he will go I hope he may have a fine time.</p>

    <p>The weather is very pleasant but the boys are getting very tired of camp they all want to get
     home and enjoy the <orig reg="peace">pease</orig> they have paid so dearly for I am sure they
     will be the happiest days of my life when I get out of this miserable camp and tiresome service
     Jennie I expect to spend some pleasant days in this world yet before I leave it</p>
    <pb n="3"/>

    <p>Jennie you must excuse me for this awkward letter for it is almost impossible to write here
     subject to the torment of these contrary boys. Geo. Stoufer is living with my brother and
     myself - he knows who I am writing to and he has told me his version of your history from the
     time you were a little girl at school but he does not know <hi rend="underline">all</hi> of
     your history and I mean to let him wait till he gets home before he learns the rest. Now dear
     Jennie I hope you will excuse me for not writing more this time if I have an opportunity I will
     write you a good long one some day and if not we will have the more to talk about when I get
     home. I shall be anxious to hear from you soon again. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Very Affectionately Yours, </salute>
     <signed>Lucius Mox<lb/>Co. I, 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> Pa Cav Camp Remount<lb/><orig
       reg="Chapel">Chappel</orig> Point Md. </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
