<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0386"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0386">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    August 5, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, august 5 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0386</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501285</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, August 5, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, august 5 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commisssion, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-08-05">1862-08-05 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company:H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0386T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel writes to his family to describe a series of artillery exchanges between
                    Union and Confederate troops along the James River.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-08-05">August 5<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Harrison Landing </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister! </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your welcome of July 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> reached me in good health, and I
                    was glad to hear that you all still keep in good health. I see by your letter
                    that you have a good deal of fun nowadays, but you never tell me any thing about
                    boys being there. I suppose you girls must have all the fun to yourselves. We
                    had a little fun here too last thursday night, playing balls with the rebels
                    across the James River, but which is rather a dangerous play. About one o'clock
                    on thursday night, the rebels opened fire on our camp with three batteries from
                    the opposite side of the River which wakened us up from our sleep. the balls and
                    shells whistled pretty sharp over our camp for a while. the shells just looked
                    like skyrockets going through the air. We had been expecting it for several
                    days, and the first Connecticut <pb n="1"/> artillery had planted their
                    seigeguns along the banks of the river which soon silenced the rebel batteries
                    when they opened on them. The river was <abbr expan="lying">laying</abbr> full
                    with vessels and schooners, but only one mast was hit by a ball. One man of our
                    regiment of <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> was killed by a shell. it only <orig reg="grazed">graced</orig>
                    his neck and shoulder and left a blue mark on it, but he was killed instantly.
                    we found the shell in the morning behind our camp. it had not exploded. the man
                    was <orig reg="sent">send</orig> home to be buried. Several other men and horses
                    were killed in the different camps along the river. In the morning several
                    regiments of our infantry were shipped across the river, but no rebels were to
                    be found any more. they burned several houses along the river, behind which the
                    rebels had their batteries stationed, a number of our troops cross the river
                    every day since they have cut down all the woods along the river, so that the
                    rebels cannot get near it any more without being seen. Early this morning we got
                    orders to get ready for a march, and to <pb n="2"/> take two days forage and
                    provisions along, but the order was countermanded again, and I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dondt</orig> think we will leave here today. There was heavy firing up the
                    river this morning, and I have just now heard that <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Sumner had a fight with the rebels this morning. he drove them over
                    towards the the river, and then our gunboats opened on them, and they cut the
                    rebels all to pieces. they ran and left everything behind them. I do not know
                    how long we stay here yet, but I expect we will make a forward move before long.
                    The weather is still very warm here, we had a pretty good shower last sunday,
                    and I told my messmate, William J. Moore that if it rained as hard up in your
                    neighbourhood it would spoil your calculations, as you said you expected to have
                    a good deal of fun if it did not rain. Sister Hannah gave me fits in her last
                    letter for plaking her about getting married. she said she guessed it was some
                    of your stuff. I <orig reg="sent">send</orig> last week, which I suppose she has
                    received before this <pb n="3"/> time. i have not seen any of the 104th lately,
                    but I intend to pay them a visit some of these days if we <orig reg="don't"
                        >dondt</orig> move from here. they have not been at our camp yet. they say
                    it is most too far to walk <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> this warm weather. I have not seen
                    Jonathan Harly lately either. they have moved their camp farther down the river.
                    I will close hoping that this letter may find you all in as good health as I
                    enjoy at present. give my regards to all our family. my compliments to your
                    companions, and my respects to all inquiring friends. I hope to have the
                    pleasure soon to hear from you again and remain </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>your affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> H 6<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                        <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn.</abbr> Cavalry <abbr expan="Colonel"
                        >Col.</abbr> R.H. Rush's Lancers Camp near Harrison's Landing of R. <abbr
                            expan="Virginia">Vir.</abbr>
                        <name type="recipient">N.B. I should be very much pleased if you would do me
                            the honor to send me your Photograph if it would not give you too much
                            trouble. </name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
