<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0390"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0390">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, March 10, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, march 10 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0390</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501289</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>There are several creases in the letter that make it impossible to discern
                        several lines of text. There are also page(s) missing. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, March 10, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, march 10 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-10">1862-03-10 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0390T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel writes to his family about being removed from the provost guard along the
                    Rappahannock.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-10">March 10<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Bell Blain Vir. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your welcome letter of the 1<hi rend="super">rst</hi> alt. and was
                    very happy to hear that you were all in good health. </p>
                <p>We were relieved from provost guard on the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and had a great
                    parting time. All the people on the place white and black assembled together to
                    take farewell from us. Mrs. Seddan gave us a boiled Ham and <orig reg="filled"
                        >filed</orig> our Haversacks with <unclear>
                        <orig reg="bushels">buishels</orig>
                    </unclear> to take along. they all said they were sorry that we were taken away
                    and they wished us to come down to see them if we could. the parting scene was
                    concluded by an old darky whom we called Uncle Tom asking blessings for us. i
                    was <orig reg="sent">send</orig> to the river a few days after we were relieved
                    on buisness by Gen. Patrick. they all said they wished we were back again, while
                    we were there. there was always some fun going on, but<pb n="2"/><del hand="h1"
                    /> the Infantry thats there now were like a set of Quakers. they used to call us
                    freemasons. We got to our camp near Whiteoak Church about an hour before sunset
                    and again we got our shelters put up. a snowstorm commenced, which lasted all
                    day sunday Feb <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> we missed our good quarters very much in such
                    rough weather but <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> without doing us harm. We were to move camp
                    on Feb. 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> but were prevented by the bad weather until
                    the 1<hi rend="super">rst</hi> of march on which day we moved. Our new camp is
                    about one mile from Bell Blain landing within sight of the Potomac river; it is
                    situated in a pine forest on the southside of a hill, and it is the most
                    convienient campground we have had since we have been in Vir. We were busy all
                    last week building log <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and cleaning up the ground, the whole
                    camp looked like a carpentershop , and we are now all very <orig
                        reg="comfortably">comfortable</orig> fixed. I wish you could see<pb n="3"
                        /><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> headquarters, they went home about <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    clock, their road led them past our headquarters and they halted and played us a
                    tune. they had a fiddle, <orig reg="tambourine">tamperene</orig>, bones, and dry
                    oncle. I expect we will go on picket again next thursday morning. I have not
                    much other news to tell you. eveything is quiet <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> think our army
                    will move from here before spring for it is impossible to move now now for the
                    roads down here are in very bad condition. it is raining every few days. it
                    commenced this morning again. Co. L. + M of our Reg. are still at frederick, Md.
                    yet but I believe our Col. has gone to Washington to get them down here. I am
                    promised to get a Furlough but I <orig reg="don't">dondt</orig> know how soon it
                    will come; one of our men who is home on a Furlough now is expected back
                    tomorrow. I would be very happy<del rend="none" hand="h1"/></p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed> </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
