<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0659"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0659">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to his brother,
                    November 1, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, november 1 1862</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0659</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501321</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to his brother, November 1, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, november 1 1862</title>
            <author>Samuel W. North</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-01">1862-11-01 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0659T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North describes the difficultly of marching through Pleasant Valley and explains
                    how a pontoon bridge is constructed.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-01"><abbr expan="November">Novem</abbr> 1<hi
                                rend="super">st</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp on the march </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Bro </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>We are resting in a field in a small <orig reg="valley">vally</orig> between the
                    mountains left our camp about two <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> on the
                    thirtieth, marched through Sharpsburg and on about 8 miles (it is only guess
                    work) and stopped on the other side of the south mountain in a woods. it was an
                    excellent place to spend the night. we had leaves for a bed Spread our tents on
                    top and slept first rate were up and on the line by daybreak and moved on
                    through a place called pleasant <orig reg="valley">vally</orig> and it was a
                    very beautiful place looked <orig reg="something">somthing</orig> like the
                    little cove we passed by dozens of deserted camps and one convalescent camp saw
                    some men with but one arm each out in the fields with a dog they seemed to be
                    enjoying themselves asked for N.Y. <abbr expan="regiments">regts</abbr>. we
                    moved on and pretty fast too our knapsacks<pb n="2"/> pulling back all the time
                    I tell you the marching is nothing but carrying a load of about 50 <abbr
                        expan="pounds">lbs</abbr> is as hard work as you ever tried on they <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> feel so heavy at first but grow amazingly a lamb
                    when we start but an old sheep when we stop. we can have some Idea how horses
                    feel after pulling all day my shoulders are so sore I can hardly move them
                    without hurting. I will not get my boots now and it is about as well, as most of
                    the boys who got new boots have sore feet. I will try to get a pair of
                        <unclear>good</unclear> shoes when my boots are worn out they are far easier
                    to walk in than home made ones which are too narrow in the sole. I will try and
                    send this letter with some citizens who are here from <sic corr="Greencastle"
                        >greenecastle</sic>. but I must tell you of harpers ferry. we got there
                    about dinner time there was a train passing with some very heavy cannon on the
                    mountains and close together<pb n="3"/> and rise most perpendicular the <abbr
                        expan="Rail Road">R.R.</abbr> canal river and a road on each side of the
                    river take up the whole distance. the government property has been very much
                    Injured one building has a broad crack from foundation to the roof it was a
                    strong stone building. we saw dozens of <orig reg="car">carr</orig> wheels the
                    bodies of which had been burnt and several cords of gun barrels which <orig
                        reg="were">wer</orig> destroyed there are workmen on the <abbr
                        expan="Rail  
 Road">R.R.</abbr> it is in <orig reg="running">runnin</orig>
                    order they have putup a <abbr expan="Rail Road">RR</abbr> bridge of trussel work
                    across the River We crossed on a pontoon Bridge it was made of boats fixed
                    straight up and down the stream about fifteen or twenty feet apart and fastened
                    above and below with anchors then beams laid on the boats and planks laid across
                    them it makes a very nice <orig reg="bridge">brige</orig> we marched through a
                        <unclear>gap</unclear> in the mountain and have stopped about five miles
                    south of <abbr expan="Harper's">Harp's</abbr> Ferry.</p>
                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>We have not moved this morning yet and the report is that we are to be mustered
                    in for pay our officers are fixing up the pay rolls. Thom Creigh has been
                    transferred into the signal corps it is a very nice position but they have a
                        <orig reg="good deal">goodeal</orig> of hard climbing to do as the signals
                    have to be at the highest points of mountains houses trees &amp; so on. Tell
                    mother I will answer her letter in a few days my shoulders are too sore to write
                    more.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Bro </salute>
                    <signed>S.W. North </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">We belong to <orig reg="Porter's">porters</orig> corps
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
