<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0658"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0658">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Brother,
                    October 14, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, october 14 1862</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0658</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501320</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>At least one page of the original letter is missing, following the first
                        page. The lines of the second page are written very close together, making
                        them difficult to transcribe. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Brother, October 14, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, october 14 1862</title>
            <author>Samuel W. North</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-14">1862-10-14 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0658T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North gives a detailed description of marching, crossing a river, fighting a
                    skirmish, and sleeping in wet conditions. He also refers to the invasion of
                    Chambersburg and and the theft of horses there.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-14">Oct 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Sharpsburg </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received a letter from you some time ago but as pap was here I did not think it
                    necessary to answer immediately. I am well. We have been most crazy on account
                    of the rebel raid into Franklin <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> the idea of 2500
                    Cavalry passing through one end of our lines capturing Horses &amp;
                    clothing, passing around the whole army and then unmolested going back into
                    virginia at the other end of our lines is the most ridiculous Slur on our
                    Generals and army ever heard of. We heard that Stewarts <abbr expan="Cavalry"
                        >Cav</abbr> to the <abbr expan="number">no.</abbr> of 2500 crossed over at
                    McCoys ferry or some place between clearspring and Hancock then coming in
                    through the valley road into the corner made a clean sweep of the horses, passed
                    through Mercersburg and got all the good Horses there that they could get hold
                    of. We heard that they took 20 head of horses from Adam Hoke four from
                        <unclear>Wilet</unclear> and two from McMurdy two from Seth Dickey and all
                    the good Horses about they did not get any of ours. It would be hard to describe
                    the effect it has had on the 126 the chambersburg boys were wild they say they
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> blame the rebels but give them credit for the
                    way the thing was accomplished and for the way they treated our people. but they
                    curse our officers and the way the army is commanded. It has had a most
                    unfavorable effect on the men of the 126</p>
                <pb n="2"/>
                <p>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                </p>
                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>thing to be done his <abbr expan="regiment">regt</abbr> will have the first
                    chance. Some say that the brigade will be separated. <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Tyler was very strict but he took good care of his men and we have
                    lost I say lost for his spine is affected and he is not likely to get well. he
                    was one of the finest looking men I ever saw. I want you to Send me the good
                    intent that has an account of <orig reg="the">th</orig> raid in it be sure and
                    send by Sharpsburg. give me all the particulars when you write give my love to
                    all the friends write soon <lb/>Your Brother S.W. North. <lb/>Address - S.W.
                    North Co. C <lb/><unclear>16</unclear>
                    <abbr expan="Regiment">regt</abbr> Pa. Vol. Sharpsburg <lb/>Washington Co.</p>

                <p>Oct. 18<hi rend="super">th</hi>. Since I wrote this letter we have made a grand
                        <orig reg="reconnaissance">reconaisance</orig> into Virginia on <orig
                        reg="Wednesday">Wensday</orig> night. were ordered out, to <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> We went to bed and slept until daylight. Then <unclear>
                        <orig reg="cornered and  
 moved">cornered and moved</orig>
                    </unclear> off we were about to take nothing but guns <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> over coats left <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig> else
                    behind. we thought it was but a strong picket but were moved to the river and
                    were soon in the cold potomac some of our artillery had crossed before and were
                    making some noise ahead. we moved on and when we got to the other side marched
                    to Shepherdstown. the Ladies there gave us a very cold reception some of them
                    held their noses, some made faces &amp; ugly mouths at us. one I saw waving
                    her hand at us but she stood back in the entry. there were a great many rebel
                    wounded there. We moved on about three miles when our batteries commenced
                    shelling the rebels and the fire was <orig reg="getting">gettin</orig> brisk
                    only from the artillery though. we were then thrown into the fire of battle in a
                    woods we lay there while our batteries were driving the <abbr expan="rebels"
                        >rebs</abbr> from the woods in front of us we were then ordered forward and
                    then we went it at a fast walk through the woods through fields over fences and
                    rocks through some of the thickest woods I ever saw. at last we pushed them
                    pretty close and their batteries commenced returning the fire very briskly the
                    shells burst within fifty or sixty <abbr expan="yards">yds</abbr> of us some
                    burst in the air above us and some burst in front of us but we got on a little
                    further and got under cover of a hole. then the musketry firing commenced pretty
                    briskly it sounded very strange I cannot describe it. it was on Thursday evening
                    &amp; we thought every minute we would get a chance at them when the cavalry
                    made a dash and then it was reported that we had taken two pieces of <orig
                        reg="cannon">canon</orig> though I saw none of them and <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> believe it. we were then about seven or eight miles into
                    Virginia only our division about eight thousand including a <abbr
                        expan="regiment">regt</abbr> of cavalry and two or three batteries perhaps
                    but one of these fell back a little and camped for the night. we lay down with
                    our overcoats only and had hardly laid down till it commenced raining.</p>
                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>Oct. 19 I do not make a practice of writing on sunday but as I have a chance to
                    send &amp; you are no doubt anxious to hear from me, as you no doubt heard
                    that our <orig reg="division">divission</orig> (Humphries) had a skirmish with
                    the rebs in virginia I will finish the one I had begun twice before. I left off
                    when we lay down to sleep. we had nothing but our overcoats to sleep in. we had
                    hardly laid down until it commenced raining or rather pouring down but I was so
                    tired I soon went to sleep slept a couple hours and got awoke wet and cold got
                    up and went to a fire the boys had made dried my clothes and laid <orig
                        reg="down">dow</orig> again and slept a while again so on till morning. in
                    the morning we went on again and soon <orig reg="passed">pased</orig> the place
                    we were the night before. it was the <abbr expan="Baltimore">Bal.</abbr>
                    &amp; Ohio <abbr expan="Rail Road">R.R.</abbr> it was torn up in several
                    places. we pushed on. were double quicked up to some cannons which were about
                    being charged by some rebel <abbr expan="cavalry">cav</abbr>. we moved on about
                    5 miles farther<pb n="5"/> and came near to a large force. they were evidently
                    drawing us on we lay <orig reg="down">dow</orig> near an old <abbr
                        expan="secessionist's">seceshs</abbr> house the home of Wilmot he was away
                    but there were some darkeys there who said the <abbr expan="rebels">rebs</abbr>
                    were in strong force near there, said they had them looking for them all night
                    we found some of our government overcoats in the house probably some of those
                    taken at <abbr expan="Chambersburg">Chambburg</abbr> we got half <abbr
                        expan="dozen">doz</abbr> or more of them a couple of horses very nice ones
                    Our advance said the rebels lay as far as the eye could see their force was
                    estimated at forty thousand we then commenced returning and moved on till dark
                    when our rear guard and artillery were firing very briskly we about faced and
                    marched back again our boys did not relish that as we were very tired our <orig
                        reg="provisions">provissions</orig>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">all</add> done and it was getting dark, but we
                    soon turned again and came on to the river and such a time as we had crossing
                    you would have been scared to see<pb n="6"/> long lines of men plunging and
                    wading the river it was dark and every now and then one of the tired fellows
                    would fall down in the water I did not get anything wet but my boots stockings
                    and drawers and I put on dry ones when I got to camp but going over before I
                    just walked in as I was and had no chance along but did not catch cold or feel
                    bad. when we were climbing the bank of the canal our capt. called "<abbr
                        expan="Company">Co.</abbr> C" "<abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> C" and we
                    were soon in water again we had kept pretty well together when we got to camp
                    our fellows who we left behind us were glad to see us safe as they had heard the
                    firing and thought our <abbr expan="regiment">regt</abbr> had been fighting we
                    cannot call it a fight but just a <orig reg="reconnaissance">reconaisance</orig>
                    in force. in the whole affair our <orig reg="division">divission</orig> lost but
                    four or five killed and some twelve or fiffteen wounded. we passed several of
                    their killed lying in the field took seven or eight prisoners. and got<pb n="7"
                    /> back safely across the river and slept at home When we were moving in line of
                    battle we drove <orig reg="rabbits">rabits</orig> and every thing up there were
                        <orig reg="sometimes">some times</orig> two or three <orig reg="rabbits"
                        >rabits</orig> running about the lines at once and some of the men caught
                    some partridges that were so scared at the firing that they did not move. we did
                    not (our <orig reg="regiment">regt</orig>) get firing at all, but some of our
                    companies which were out skirmishing on the right and left
                    <unclear>lost</unclear> their <abbr expan="cavalry">cav</abbr>, and Co. A was
                    within a few hundred <abbr expan="yards">yds</abbr> of a battery it shelled them
                    and they had to skedaddle back to us tell mother she may send my old blue vest
                    if she gets a chance we were out near to leetown about twelve miles into
                    virginia. I got a letter from pap to day &amp; will answer it in a few days.
                    give my best respects to all the friends.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Bro </salute>
                    <signed>Sam </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
