<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0664"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0664">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to his brother,
                    December 18, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his brother, december 18 1862</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0664</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501326</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>At least one page of the original is missing, starting after the first
                    page.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father, December 18, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, december 18 1862</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-18">1862-12-18 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0664T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North discusses the fighting at Fredericksburg and gives a report of the dead
                    there. He also mentions the pleasantries of camp life.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-18">Dec 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near <abbr expan="Fredericksburg">Fredksbg</abbr>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> is at hand. I wrote a letter to mother in
                        <orig reg="Fredericksburg">Fredricksburg</orig> on Sunday. it was just a
                    scribble with a pencil it was to let her know that I was safe then. but I knew
                    it was not all over for the shells were flying about pretty thick at the time.
                    we were sitting behind a stone wall at a grave yard in charles st. <orig
                        reg="yesterday">yester day</orig> I wrote to Sula but was in such a hurry
                    that I could not write particulars. We have failed to drive the enemy from their
                    entrenchments and have retired over on to this side of the river. on thursday
                    morning we were ready to move. the bombardment commenced at daylight and we
                    moved about the same time. we waited all day about a mile from the river. on
                    friday morning we were moved out to our batteries on this side of the
                    rappahannock but on Sat morning the troops commenced crossing and soon we heard
                    the musketry mingle with the artillery it was most terrific. we crossed about
                    three <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> when we were going down this side the
                    rebs threw shells at us but no one was hurt we crossed on the pontoon bridge and
                    as soon as we were in town the artillery commenced <unclear>playing</unclear> at
                    us but could not do us much damage as we were under the cover of the houses. the
                    town was all ransacked books chairs and every kind of furniture <orig reg="were"
                        >was</orig> lying in the Streets. we left our knapsacks in a store and moved
                    out on the battlefield. We were moved out and drawn up in position in a meadow
                    when a rebel officer on a white horse rode out in front of the fortifications
                    and soon a cannon was<pb n="2"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <pb n="3"/> but we got back safe to our old camp and saved our knapsacks and
                    tents most of us at least. I brought back all I took over and picked up a gum
                    blanket. the streets were full of knapsacks as we came through Some of the boys
                    got books and some other <unclear>things</unclear> Haze Boyd got <orig
                        reg="Milton's">Miltons</orig> complete works lying in the Streets. there was
                    abundance of flour fish pork and in short every thing but salt. the story of the
                    South starving is all a Hoax. they had things just as plenty as we have at least
                    in <orig reg="Fredericksburg">Fredricksburg</orig>. our soldiers helped
                    themselves as well as they could there were some people living in the cellars
                    Bruce and I went after water one night - it was not safe to go in daytime - when
                    a lady came out of the house and asked us to get her some water. we filled her
                    bucket and she said it would do till the next evening. I have heard of the
                    horrors of the battle field but the reality is terrible. in the action and
                        <unclear>existing</unclear> it is not realized but the thoughts and
                    impressions seem to be <unclear>
                        <orig reg="burned">burned</orig>
                    </unclear> in my brain the still pale faces of the dead and the shrieks and
                    groans of the wounded and dying, oh! it is <orig reg="awful">awfull</orig> I
                    think our loss must be very severe I saw a great many dead men we could hardly
                    step without tramping on them. I cannot praise our <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >capt</abbr> too highly and the boys with but few exceptions did their duty
                    nobly. I did not expect them to take that battery when we started but we tried.
                    The Second Maine boys say we made the eleventh charge on it we failed but we
                    done our duty it is said we lost nine commissioned killed and wounded in the
                        <abbr expan="regiment">regt</abbr> and over one hundred men. I forgot to say
                    that we heard of one of our missing boy - Fritz of the little cove he is in the
                    hospital has been run over and is badly injured he makes Co. C.<hi rend="super"
                        >s</hi> loss two killed and four badly wounded Capt Doebler of Co A is
                    wounded in the arm. but I am sick and tired of this subject and have done now.
                    Mother was anxious to know how we got along this cold weather we have a right
                    cozy chimney and fire place in our tent and have made ourselves pretty
                    comfortable and have not suffered any yet. Aunt Sade sent me a sleeping cap Aunt
                    Kate sent Jacob one I want you to write often my love to all friends</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your brother </salute>
                    <signed>S.W. North </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">tell pap that the other $27.00 are safe has not left here
                        yet but it will be sent on Immediately tell him to write when he gets
                    it</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
