<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0666"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0666">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father, May
                    7, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, may 7 1863</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0666</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501328</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>A note in different handwriting at the bottom of the last page reads, "We
                        enclose you Samuels letter we <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> your
                        &amp; mothers letter just now we are all well yours, M. M. North" </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to His Father, May 7, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to his father, may 7 1863</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-06">1863-05-06 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0666T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North's letter describes his division's part in the battle of Chancellorsville
                    and lists the wounded and killed among his comrades. He also mentions that his
                    term is almost up and that he does not intend to reenlist.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Father</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-07">May 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Falmouth Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter but had neither time nor of <orig reg="opportunity"
                        >oportunity</orig> to answer it sooner. As you have no doubt heard the Army
                    of the Potomac has fought another great battle. We left our camp on Monday the
                        27<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <unclear>ult</unclear> &amp; marched up the river about 25 miles where we
                    crossed &amp; then marched on to the rapidan river which We reached <orig
                        reg="Wednesday">Wensday</orig> evening the pontoon train passed <del
                        hand="h1">on before our corps</del> on did not lay a bridge for us
                    consequently we had to wade it, the water up to our middles &amp; so swift
                    we could hardly keep our feet moved down to <orig reg="Chancellorsville"
                        >Chauncersville</orig> I took up position our corps commenced the battle the
                    first fighting began on the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> but our <orig
                        reg="division">divission</orig> was not engaged until Sunday morning when
                    the battle opened most <unclear>furious</unclear> our brigade was ordered to
                    support another then ahead &amp; advancing into the woods when it<pb n="2"/>
                    came near the enemies lines. They fired a few shots &amp; then fell back
                    &amp; left us to stand it our selves we were engaged about
                    <unclear>2</unclear> hours the <orig reg="ammunition">amunition</orig> began to
                    run out &amp; there was neither support nor relief coming so we had to fall
                    back &amp; they followed us yelling like indians. I fired 30 rounds some
                    fired more but my gun was so hot I was afraid to load any faster</p>

                <p>We lost one killed, Nick Trout, Bro of lieut Wounded <abbr expan="William"
                    >Wm</abbr> Starliper dangerously in the leg. Luther Zimmerman in the arm. <abbr
                        expan="James">Jas</abbr> McConnell in the leg. <abbr expan="William"
                    >Wm</abbr> McDowell in the head, severely. <abbr expan="Thomas">Thom</abbr> C.
                    Metcalf in the back of the head. Bryson Bruce in leg &amp; amp;hand. J. O.
                    Parker finger shot off George Cole in the hand &amp; <unclear>Doug</unclear>
                    Coyle from a spent ball in the shoulder. he is still with us were all slightly
                    wounded Starlipers is the only one very dangerous. Although McConnell, McDowell
                    &amp; Zimmerman are very severe wounds. We got home late on the evening of
                    the tenth day, yesterday, tired and worn out. it rained a great deal &amp;
                    the roads were in an <orig reg="awful">awfull</orig> condition. The result is a
                    failure so<pb n="3"/> far as I can hear though we had the fight behind <orig
                        reg="Fredericksburg">Fredricksburg</orig> &amp; did not take measures to
                    hold them. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know who commanded the force which
                    crossed there. We may be home before this reaches you. We hope to leave this
                    tomorrow but are not sure but they will try to keep us a few days longer. it is
                    uncertain about leaving tomorrow. Co. C<hi rend="super">s</hi> time is up on the
                    evening of the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> Jacob &amp; I are in our usual
                    health, only a little stiff &amp; sore from the fatigue &amp; exposure
                    it rained most every other day I lost my knapsack in the fight &amp; had
                    nothing to sleep in but the clothes I had on &amp; a piece of tent excuse
                    this poor letter as I lost my writing material. as I have just come from the
                    battle field you need not fear that I will enlist again. there was five days
                    fighting. We were all disappointed in Seigles dutch 11<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    Corps they did not stand up to the work well<pb n="4"/> Our Brigade was
                    complimented by <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Meade, for our Bravery. the
                    battle will probably be called the Battle of <orig reg="Chancellorsville"
                        >Chauncerville</orig>. there was a battle going on at <orig
                        reg="Fredericksburg">Fredricksburg</orig> at the same time our men drove
                    them from the <orig reg="heights">heighths</orig> but they returned with
                    overwhelming force &amp; retook them.</p>

                <p>You have no doubt heard from the papers more correctly than I can tell you as
                        <orig reg="I have">Ive</orig> no way but hearsay to find out any news</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your affectionate son </salute>
                    <signed>S.W. North </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
