<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0677"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0677">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Henry M. Erisman to His Brother,
                    March 12, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county henry m erisman to his brother, march 12 1862</title>
        <author>Erisman, Henry M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0677</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501337</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>The last page or pages of the original letter are missing.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Henry M. Erisman to His Brother, March 12, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county henry m erisman to his brother, march 12 1862</title>
            <author>Henry M. Erisman</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Henry M. Erisman Records, Company K, 77th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Harrisburg Civil War Round Table Collection,
                            Archives of the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks,
                            Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-12">1862-03-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 77th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: K </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0677T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Erisman describes army life in Nashville. He also tells about skirmishes at the
                    picket line, including one involving a ruse by the rebels.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-12">March the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Andy Johnson Tennessee </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I now take this <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> to inform you that I
                    am well at Present hoping that these few lines may find you and all the Rest of
                    the folks in the same state of health we are now laying about five miles south
                    of Nashville we got here on the 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi> Nashville is a <orig
                        reg="pretty">Purty</orig> Place and it has the appearance of being a <orig
                        reg="business">buisness</orig> Place at one time but <orig reg="business"
                        >Buisness</orig> is suspended There now. all the stores and <orig
                        reg="business">Buisness</orig> shops are Closed and the City is <orig
                        reg="deserted">diserted</orig> of nearly all its inhabitants except the
                        <orig reg="ladies">Ladys</orig> and they are all <abbr expan="secessionist"
                        >secesh</abbr> and wear a <abbr expan="secessionist">secesh</abbr> flag for
                    Aprons and have a belt around their waists with an Ivory handled Colt Revolving
                    Pistol of the best quality sticking in it. Nashville and all the <orig
                        reg="surrounding">surround</orig> Country is <abbr expan="secessionist"
                        >secesh</abbr> and they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> try to hide it <orig
                        reg="neither">nether</orig> we <orig reg="were">was</orig> out on Picket
                    night <orig reg="before">afore</orig> last and towards morning about time the
                    moon went down the left end of our<pb n="2"/> Picket Line was fired into by some
                    Rebel Cavalry there was about 300 of them in all but they stayed about 200 or
                    300 yards away from our <orig reg="Picket">Picklet</orig> line with the
                    exceptions of 15 that dismounted and Came up to within hailing distance of our
                    Pickets they <orig reg="were">where</orig> 5 or 6 <orig reg="abreast"
                    >abrest</orig> as we Could judge for it was dark and the minute our Pickets <del
                        hand="h1">they fired</del> Challenged them they fired one <orig reg="volley"
                        >volly</orig> and Retreated our men fired on them while they were Retreating
                    but with what effect we <orig reg="couldn't">Could<hi rend="super"
                    >nt</hi></orig> hear if there was any of them hurt they <orig reg="were taken"
                        >was taking</orig> along by their Comrades on our side there was <orig
                        reg="nobody">no body</orig> hurt but I must say they did some tall shooting
                    for random shooting Te only guide they had was the Direction the Pickets voice
                    Came and he came near being Put out two balls struck the fence one each side of
                    him but Captain Philips made the Narrowest Escape of all the <orig reg="upper"
                        >uper</orig> band of his sword <orig reg="scabbard">scabard</orig> was shot
                    off one shot grazing the Back of his hand taking the skin <orig reg="off"
                    >of</orig> about an inch another struck about the<pb n="3"/>
                    <orig reg="center">Centre</orig> of his <orig reg="scabbard">scabard</orig>
                    bending the sword &amp; <orig reg="scabbard">scabard</orig> about 2 inches
                    out of Plumb while 3 Passed through his Coat tail the best Part of them being
                    Buckshot the Rebels Cartridges have three Buckshot &amp; one rond Ball in
                    them they have attacked 3 times now the first they attacked the 30<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">
                        <abbr expan="second">2nd</abbr>
                    </add> out of our brigade - In stationing the Pickets 4 <del hand="h1">go
                    on</del> goes on a Post 20 yards apart is the General Rule but the <sic
                        corr="Indiana">Indianna</sic> Boys <orig reg="were">where</orig> Placed
                    about 50 yards apart and the Rebels took advantage of the Distance and took 4 of
                    them off their Post in Broad day light and <orig reg="carried">Caried</orig>
                    them off as Prisoners and they <orig reg="have not">aint</orig> got Back yet
                    either the way they managed to do it there was about 25 of them (<orig
                        reg="Cavalry">Cavelry</orig>) <orig reg="rode">road</orig> up with about 30
                    yards of the Pickets taking care to keep behind a hill that the Pickets <orig
                        reg="couldn't">Could<hi rend="super">nt</hi></orig> see them when one of
                    them <orig reg="dismounted">dismound</orig> and to hide suspicion he had on one
                    of our uniforms on so he got to the Pickets without much trouble and got talking
                    them awhile when he give a certain signal and as quick as lightning the Rebels
                    galloped up to<pb n="4"/> them <orig reg="dragged">draged</orig> them on their
                    Horses and off with them it was done so quick that the rest of the Pickets <orig
                        reg="didn't">did<hi rend="super">nt</hi></orig> get a shot at them I tell
                    you <orig reg="they're">Theyre</orig> as sharp as they make them these days the
                    next attack they made was on the First wisconsin killing one and wounding five
                    The wisconsin killed 3 of their men wounded 3 and some of the 29<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> Indiana Boys took one of them Prisoner he belonged to the First
                        <sic corr="Louisiana">Louisianna</sic>
                    <orig reg="Cavalry">Cavelry</orig> he is a bold looking fellow and he says he
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> give a damn <orig reg="whether">wether</orig>
                    school keeps or not and he says if they let him go he will fight against the
                    Union Troops as hard as ever he says he <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be a
                    Prisoner 6 month he would be shot first. The next attack they made on us the
                        <orig reg="Particulars">Parteculars</orig> of which I have stated on the
                    other Page This morning about 3 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> there was
                    firing our Picket line again and at the same Place we were fired on yesterday
                    morning But I <orig reg="didn't">did<hi rend="super">nt</hi></orig> hear how
                    they made out The 49<hi rend="super">th</hi> Ohio Relieved us yesterday about 4
                        <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> in the afternoon and they will be relieved
                    by some other <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> at the same time to day and I
                        <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> Close this till I hear how the <orig
                        reg="Ohioans">Ohioians</orig> made out with the <abbr expan="secessionists"
                        >secesh</abbr> They'll be in about 4 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> But I
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think there was anything of any</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed> </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
