<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0907"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0907">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Francis Pleasants to Harriet
                    McElheney, May 10, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county francis pleasants to harriet mcelheney, may 10 1865</title>
        <author>Pleasants, Francis</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0907</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501374</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This transcription was taken directly from a typescript and a photocopy of
                        the original.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Francis Pleasants to Harriet McElheney, May 10, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county francis pleasants to harriet mcelheney, may 10 1865</title>
            <author>Francis Pleasants</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p> </p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Sylvester McElheney Papers,
                            Archives of the U.S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks,
                            Pennsylvania. </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-05-10">1865-05-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Medicine/Hospitals</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0907T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Pleasants describes Sylvester McElheney's last days before dying in a
                    Philadelphia hospital. McElheney's mental capacity suffered at the end, and
                    Pleasants reassures Harriet McElheney that the hospital staff treated him very
                    kindly.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <name type="recipient">Harriet McElheney</name>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-05-10">May 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>/ 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Germantown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mrs. McElheney - <lb/> Dear Madam,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your favor of the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> inst has been received, the answer to
                    it has been delayed on account of my waiting for the Chaplain to find out the
                    name of the Priest who was with your husband in his last moments, but the
                    Chaplain having so much to attend to has neglected doing so until I feared you
                    would wonder why I had not answered your letter. Why my letter was so long
                    delayed is a mystery to me - and how we wondered why you did not come to him -
                        <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> my friend it would have been but little
                    satisfaction for you to have been here as he would not have known you, he being
                    out of his mind for<pb n="2"/> three or four days. The first day his mind
                    wandered, I thought perhaps I could recall <del hand="h1">his mond</del> it by
                    taking a pen and paper sitting beside him and letting him <hi rend="underline"
                    >know</hi> I was writing to you - He knew me, I told him what I was writing
                    &amp;c - he remarked, "tell her I left Philadelphia and--" I interrupted him
                    by saying he was still in Philadelphia, then he told me he was with you all - I
                    pretended he was, said, "were they all well and were they glad to see you?"
                    "yes, indeed" "and were the little children glad?" he smiled &amp; said "I
                    bet they were," smiled again when I made mention you, said the little ones had
                    grown, it having been eight months since he saw them - said "the old woman was
                    sick" any of your friends ill?</p>

                <p>The wound was a severe one, it being near the left thigh, and discharged a great
                    deal of matter all the time.</p>
                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>When the Priest saw him he did not know <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> so that
                    I think he cannot tell you any more than myself as I was with him most of any
                    with the exception of his nurses who were soldiers, but <hi rend="underline"
                        >very</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">very</hi> kind to him, uncommonly so.</p>

                <p>I do not think he was conscious of his situation as he kept telling us he was
                    better all the time - I did not think, it best to tell him of his situation as
                    we expected you every hour and wanted you to be the one, as I assure you it is a
                    very painful thing to tell an entire stranger that he is dying - The hospital
                    has closed all patients having been removed from there yesterday - perhaps by
                    dropping a line to the Chaplain he will find out about the Priest as he will
                    have more time to attend to the matter now - his address is 410 North 11<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> St - It was really very kind in him to get the priest -
                    as it<pb n="4"/> is the first time in my recollection his doing so - but he
                    remarked to me he pitied him so much.</p>

                <p>I have written to you all the particulars I know of, of your husband and <orig
                        reg="though">tho'</orig> severe the trial it is to you, yet it may be a
                    dispensation sent you from on high, for your good - I remain in much sympathy.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your friend</salute>
                    <signed>Francis Pleasants<lb/> Germantown<lb/> Philadelphia</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">You must excuse the haste in which this is written, but
                        have so many letters to write at this time -</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
