<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0906"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0906">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Jacob Shearer to Harriet McElheney, March 26,
     1865</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county jacob shearer to harriet mcelheney, march 26 1865</title>
        <author>Shearer, Jacob</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F0906</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501373</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>This transcription was taken from a typescript and a photocopy of the original.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>


      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Jacob Shearer to Harriet McElheney, March 26, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county jacob shearer to harriet mcelheney, march 26 1865</title>
            <author>Jacob Shearer</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Sylvester McElheney Papers, Archives of the U.S.
       Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania. </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-03-26">1865-03-26</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F0906T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>At Sylvester McElheney's request, Shearer writes to Harriet McElheney to tell her that her
     husband has been wounded but is expected to recover. He was shot in the leg when Confederate
     soldiers broke through their regiment's picket line.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <name type="recipient">Harriet McElheney</name>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1865-03-26">March the 26<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1865</date>
      <name type="place">Camp In Front of Petersburg<lb/> Army of the Potomac</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Well Friend</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I feel it my duty this pleasant Sabbeth Evening to <orig reg="inform">In form</orig> you that
     I just came from the hospital from seeing your husband and he requested me to write you a
     letter to let you know how he was and what had happened him. the Rebs did make a break in
     through the picket line about one mile from this yesterday morning and we was called out about
     5 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> and about 6 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> we was in
     line of battle in front of the enemy and we had just gave them two volleys when Sylvester and
      I<pb n="2"/> was <orig reg="both">bouth</orig> wounded. Sylvester is wounded through the leg
     but I guess the bone is not <orig reg="fractured">fractered</orig> any at least he thinks so.
     He was in <orig reg="very">verry</orig> good spirits <orig reg="today">to day</orig> and I
     think that it <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> be sore <orig reg="very">verry</orig> long. I got a
     slight tap through one of my fingers on the left hand. Mine is a <orig reg="vrey">verry</orig>
     light wound but it is pretty sore <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. Sylvester was taken to the
     Hospital just shortly after he was wounded and I came back to camp. There was eight wounded in
     our Company and one killed. The rest of the boys are all out yet lying at the <orig
      reg="breastworks">brest works</orig>. There was some of them had to go on picket last night
     but they will come in this evening but we drove the rebs back and they <orig reg="lost"
     >loosed</orig> a good many men. They had taken two or three of our <pb n="3"/>forts before we
     got to them but we soon took them all back and the report is that we took fifteen hundred
     prisoners. There was over three hundred of the rebs filled and our loss <orig reg="doesn't"
      >dont</orig> exceed more than three hundred killed wounded and missing. The 100<hi
      rend="super">drth</hi> Reg and the 200<hi rend="super">drth</hi> Regt, 207<hi rend="super"
     >th</hi>, 208<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 209<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 211<hi rend="super">th</hi>
     was in the fight. Old General Lee told his men that they would go to City Point again. Eleven
      <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> when they started but the old fellow missed that game but if
     they would had one half hour more they would been at Meads Station and that is on the City
     Point <orig reg="railroad">rail roade</orig>. Well I must soon bring my scribling to a close
     for I will have to get at and get supper for Phillip and Will Sibert so I have it <orig
      reg="ready">redy</orig> when they come in. So nothing more at present<pb n="4"/> But before I
     close I will give you the names of the rest of the boys that was wounded in our Company. There
     is Corporal Samuel G. Smith, Corporal Daniel T. Ritter, David E. Saylor, Sergeant Smith, <abbr
      expan="William">Wm</abbr> Hull and George Emory had part of the sole shot off one of his shoes
     but did not <orig reg="touch">tuch</orig> his foot. And Corporal Shull was killed. So now I
     will close which I do in good health with the exception of a sore finger.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Respectfully yours</salute>
     <signed>Jacob Shearer</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Company F, 208<hi rend="super">th</hi> Regiment PV<lb/> 1<hi
       rend="super">st</hi> Brigade 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi> Division 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>
      <abbr expan="Army  
 Corps">AC</abbr><lb/> Washington<lb/>D.C.<lb/> Good Bye <name
       type="recipient">To Mrs. Harriet A. McElheney</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
