<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0938"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0938">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: William S. Garvin to Simon Cameron,
                    December 4, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county william s garvin to simon cameron, december 4 1862</title>
        <author>Garvin, William S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>


                <idno type="VCDH">F0938</idno>


        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501394</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: William S. Garvin to Simon Cameron, December 4, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county william s garvin to simon cameron, december 4 1862</title>
            <author>William S. Garvin</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Simon Cameron Papers, Microfilm
                            reel 7, Collection of the Historical Society of Dauphin County,
                            Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg,
                        Pennsylvania.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>

        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Historical Society of Dauphin County, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>


        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-04">1862-12-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home front, Military Strategy, National Government, State
                        Government</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0938T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William S. Garvin recounts the bravery of his son, mourns the loss of his
                    youngest daughter, and advises Cameron on Democratic support of a candidacy for
                    senator.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Simon Cameron</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-04">Dec. 4, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Mercer</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Gen.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In answer to your request for my son's name, (which is Edwin L.) I take the
                    liberty of sending you his letter to me describing his share in the battle of
                    Fair Oaks. I intended also to send you the copy of a letter of his cousin, Capt.
                    Oliver C. Garvin, to his father, describing a part which Ed's modesty would not
                    permit him to write to me - the fact, that when the Irish brigade would not
                    advance on their famous charge, but squatted behind the rail road, he took their
                    colors and put them up in the advance, in the midst of a shower of bullets from
                    the enemy. Also, when Gen. Sumner inquired of his Col. (Frank) for an officer of
                    intelligence and courage to perform a service outside of the
                    <unclear>Pines</unclear>, Edwin was called upon - that the General, when he was
                    presented turned to the Col. and said it was too dangerous a service to send him
                        on,<pb n="2"/> and then turned to Ed, and said, "I will remember you, sir,
                    in the future." The letter containing all this has been mislaid, and hence I
                    have to recount its contents. I say this, and send his letter, to prove, if you
                    will take the trouble to read it, that he is not unworthy the favor you did me
                    and him, in giving him an appointment in the regular army. The letter I send, I
                    wish returned to me, for it is highly valued at home. The addrefs of my son
                    is<lb/><lb/> Edwin S. Garvin<lb/> 1st U.S. Artillery<lb/> New Orleans</p>

                <p>I am sorry to hear that Mrs. Cameron did not enjoy good health while in Europe. I
                    had supposed that Russia was not so unpleasant in the summer, and that it might
                    have agreed with all of you. During your absence I received an awful blow in the
                    death of my youngest daughter, and the only one<pb n="3"/> in my house. Home is
                    no longer to me what it was. She died in June, and yet daily and sometimes
                    hourly, is her image before me.</p>

                <p>If I can, I will visit you this winter, if you will provide a pass for me.</p>

                <p>I read to <unclear>Rose</unclear> that part of your letter which referred to him,
                    and I can assure you that he was very much gratified. He now thinks that the
                    appointment will be given to him on that the force arrayed in his favor will be
                    irresistible.</p>

                <p>In my last, I told you the democrats believed you could be Senator, if you
                    choose. That is still their belief. But the man who leaves his party to support
                    you, will need be a very bold man - for they all know that the democracy just
                    now would be unrelenting in its wrath, and hence I make the remark. Give my
                    respect to Mrs. Cameron</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Wm. S. Garvin</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">To <abbr expan="Senator">Sen.</abbr> Cameron</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
