<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4048"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4048">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Benjamin L. Farinholt to Lelia
                    Farinholt, July 1, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin l farinholt to lelia farinholt, july 1 1863</title>
        <author>Farinholt, Benjamin Lyons</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4048</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501599</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Benjamin L. Farinholt to Lelia Farinholt, July 1,
                            1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin l farinholt to lelia farinholt, july 1 1863</title>
            <author>Benjamin L. Farinholt</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Benjamin Lyons Farinholt Papers,
                            1863-1864, Mss2 F2273b, Virginia Historical Society, Richmond,
                        Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Virginia.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-01">1863-07-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Family, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4048T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Benjamin Farinholt describes conditions near Chambersburg, including the wealth
                    of supplies that allows the army to live off the local population. Farinholt's
                    letter to his wife also includes his predictions regarding upcoming action in
                    the north, as well as the reactions of the local residents to their
                presence.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-01">July 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp of 53<hi rend="super">rd</hi>
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">V<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr>
                            <lb/> Near Chambersburg <lb/> Franklin <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Lelia,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>We have had some very hard marches lately as you may judge from the place and
                    date of my letter. We are you may say in the very heart of Yankeedom, passed
                    through Maryland Three days ago, a great many <unclear>reservists</unclear>
                    joined our Army from Maryland but we found all very bitter <orig reg="Yankees"
                        >Yankeys</orig> in Pennsylvania we met many secessionists in Hagerstown M.D.
                    a place of about 6000 inhabitants. We are living very well over here and the
                    amount of money saved to our Government every day by our subsisting on the Enemy
                    is about $200,000. We are impressing &amp; purchasing a great many fine
                    horses from the Enemy and our Commissaries are supplied with fine Cattle sheep
                    &amp;c, <pb n="2"/>the rations of Whiskey, Coffee &amp; Sugar remind me
                    of our living at West Point. We are about 20 miles from the Pennsylvania line,
                    and the farms are generally about 1000 acres in size and produce from 12 to 15 <unclear>
                        <abbr expan="bushels">bhls</abbr>
                    </unclear> corn and from 30 to 40 bushels of wheat to the acre. The owners are
                    generally of Dutch descent and are very much terrified at our presence and think
                    it horrible that we should invade Pennsylvania, indeed they have known nothing
                    of the war heretofore, and I believe unless we do bring it home to them in this
                    manner they would be willing to carry it on indefinitely. Of the plans of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee I know nothing our <abbr expan="Division"
                        >Div</abbr> is in the rear. <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Ewell
                    &amp; Hill and some of Longstreets <abbr expan="Division">Div.</abbr> are
                    near Harrisburg the Capital of <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> We can take
                    it very readily but whither it will be our plan to attack it or Baltimore or
                    Phil <pb n="3"/>adelphia I do not know, we have already supplied our Army with a
                    great many shoes hats &amp;c and I expect the advanced <abbr
                        expan="Divisions">Divs</abbr> have gotten more than we have. Our Army is in
                    excellent health, and if we keep up our present state of organization there is
                    nothing to fear from <unclear>any</unclear> force they can bring against us.
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Hood I understand is between us and
                    Washington - we are some distance north west of Baltimore and about 70 miles
                    from it. Chambersburg is a very pretty town of about 5000 inhabitants. I have
                    eaten many nice meals in Yankee land and the people take our money and feed us
                    on the best they have, such as nice pickles, brandies, wines, preserves, apple
                    butter, cherries &amp;c, our meals, (and I get <unclear>ma</unclear> all at
                    some houses where we stop, the houses are large, nice &amp; convenient) cost
                    us from 25 to 50 cents each. Hats of the best quality from 2 to 5$ - boots and
                    shoes from time to time. Sheep 3$ each <pb n="4"/> beef 8 cents per <abbr
                        expan="pound">lb.</abbr> bacon 12 cents. Coffee 7<hi rend="super">c</hi>
                    Sugar 15 to 20 cents per <abbr expan="pound">lb</abbr>, whiskey 1<hi
                        rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> per <abbr expan="gallon">gal.</abbr> The dutch farmers hate to see us
                    driving their fine horses to our artillery and killing their fat <orig
                        reg="bovines">beeves</orig> by hundreds. Our Army will not cost the
                    confederacy a great deal as long as we remain in <abbr expan="Pennsylvania"
                    >Pa.</abbr> I suppose we will necessarily have a big fight before we leave the
                    state, and expect it will be somwhere north of Baltimore probably near
                    Philadelphia or Harrisburg. Our Army is in fine spirits and willing to be led
                        <orig reg="everywhere">every where</orig> - or any where confidently
                    expecting success under the able leadership of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Lee.</p>

                <p>Our soldiers have burnt no houses and no barns as the Enemy do and are obeying
                    strictly <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee's orders to "take no property
                    unless we pay for it" but we have burnt some larger iron works, foundries
                    &amp;c, and are tearing up their Rail Road by whole-sale. I will not write a
                    very long or very particular letter as we are not very certain that our letters
                    may not be intercepted. I hope this may find you and Edgar and all
                    <unclear>our</unclear> family in good health. My love to <unclear>Mama</unclear>
                    and her family and to Sister <unclear>Mary</unclear> and all my relatives and to
                    Aunt Betsy &amp; family, and for myself and family accept all the love of</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your devoted friend and affectionate husband</salute>
                    <signed>B. L. Farinholt</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Kiss Edgar for me</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
