<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4049"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4049">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Julian T. Edwards to his Parents,
                    October 15, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county julian t edwards to his parents, october 15 1862</title>
        <author>Edwards, Julian T.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">19</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4049</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501600</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Julian T. Edwards to his Parents, October 15, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county julian t edwards to his parents, october 15 1862</title>
            <author>Julian T. Edwards</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Julian T. Edwards letter, Mss2
                            Ed969 a1, Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Virginia.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-15">1862-10-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Battle Description, Church/Religious Activity, Family,
                        Military Authority, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Doug O'Reagan</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4049T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Julian Edwards' detailed letter to his parents describes a scouting raid into
                    Franklin and Adams counties in Pennsylvania. Edwards gives an account of his
                    impressions of the local population, as well as his reaction to the behavior of
                    his fellow soldiers during the conduct of the raids. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-15">October 15th, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="Cavalry">Cvl.</abbr> Camp 8 miles of
                            Martinsburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Parents,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your very welcome, &amp; interesting letter just as we were
                    preparing to go on a grand scout into Pennsylvania, and in rear of the ever <hi
                        rend="underline">watchful</hi>, and <hi rend="underline">impregnable</hi>
                    Yankee army. Of course I could not then answer it, and as I have just got back
                    to camp, I now hasten to let you know I am here in our own Virginia all safe,
                    and sound, in order to relieve you of any feelings of anxiety in regard to me,
                    as Coly wrote you in his last that he heard we were in Pennsylvania.</p>

                <p>Knowing as I do the almost ever existing doubt in mother's mind, of my safety, I
                    am ever on the lookout, and shall always endeavor to remove any ground she may
                    have for feelings of apprehension in regard to it, and as a scout of such a
                    nature as the last we went upon is of course attended with great danger, I shall
                    write you a letter this morning though I am quite fatigued yet from our long
                    ride. As news from other points, and sources is very scarce I will endeavor to
                    give you something in detail a history of our trip, thinking it will interest
                    you as much as <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> else I can write.</p>

                <p>Well to begin at the beginning - last Wednesday an order came to our camp for a
                    detail of 120 of the best horses, &amp; men from our <abbr expan="Regiment"
                        >Regt.</abbr> of which number our Company furnished 12. Bill, myself among
                    the number. We were then issued five days rations to carry with us, and have
                    them all ready cooked to start next morning, and report to <abbr expan="General"
                        >Genl</abbr> Stuart at Darksville, some 6 miles from our Camp. Of course
                    when we received the order, <orig reg="everybody">every body</orig> wondered
                    which way we were going, and I <orig reg="reckon">recon</orig> 1001 conjectures
                    were made as to what was the object of the scout, and where we were going to
                    turn up. Some said one thing, and some said another until in the confusion of
                    opinions, and ideas the mystery was made deeper, and deeper and the excitement
                    grew higher, and higher because no one among us could get up and say "I declare
                    unto you this scout shall be for this purpose and to this end". But as we all
                    now know I will let the conjectures drop, and proceed to relate it to you just
                    as it was revealed to me. Thursday morning we were quite busy cooking rations,
                    and something interesting, and pleasant could be seen in the eye, and smile of
                    nearly every man; which betrayed to the observer, that something of interest was
                    going on and that a bright prospect was before them; which though it had not
                    opened, promised excitement - risks to run - dangers to escape - deeds to do,
                    and a field for the display of valor; all of which I am constrained to say;
                    youth alas! is too fond. After a short time all the rations were cooked, and the
                    horn sounded the notes to horse; we all then were soon in our saddles, and
                    having formed into line, and then into platoons, the notes were sounded to
                    forward, and off we went amid many exclamations, injunctions, and also cheers
                    from our comrades who were left behind. We then went on to Darksville where we
                    halted a few minutes to let a column pass on before us consisting of details of
                    other <abbr expan="Regiments">Regts.</abbr> We all then formed a long column in
                    the road; representing in our force <abbr expan="Generals">Genls.</abbr>
                    Hampton's, Robinson's and Lee's brigades of <abbr expan="Cavalry">Cavl.</abbr>,
                    and perhaps one, or two <orig reg="battalions">batalions</orig> making in all
                    about 1800 Cavalry, and six pieces of Artillery. We then marched down the
                    Winchester turnpike till within about 1/2 mile of Martinsburg, when we turned to
                    the left into a small road, and proceeded <orig reg="until">till</orig> within
                    about 3 miles from the Potomac, where we halted <orig reg="until">till</orig>
                    about 2 1/2 o'clock. About 2 1/2 o'clock Friday morning we were up, and off
                    again, and crossed the Potomac at Hedges ferry driving in the yankee pickets
                    wounding, and taking one prisoner. We then went on through, or rather cross
                    Washington County, <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> and then into Franklin
                        <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> where
                    we soon learned the object, or one of the objects at least of the scout, for
                    having halted the column <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Stuart ordered a
                    detail from each <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> to catch horses which
                    orders was accordingly carried out to the letter, and parties of men could be
                    seen in almost every direction chasing, and leading horses. Of course the
                    citizen could do nothing, and said little. They were so much surprised, and so
                    badly frightened they seemed perfectly willing to let us take every horse if we
                    would just pass on. Our Column did not stop at all, but proceeded in a slow
                    walk, so the men who went out from the road to capture horses could overtake us
                    easily. We proceeded on our way unmolested, passing through Mercersburg, a
                    little town of about 1200 inhabitants, and abounding in Union flags (I suppose)
                    all of which were torn down as I saw the shreds hanging to several flag staffs.
                    Here we got a good many horses from the livery stables, and some stores were
                    broken open, and goods taken by some of the men. Hats, boots, shoes, &amp;
                    rolls of goods could be seen tied to the saddles of good many men when we got
                    back. The citizens stood by looking on without saying a word, and if ever I saw
                    wonder &amp; surprise mingled with fear depicted upon the countenances of
                    any one I certainly saw it upon the countenances of the citizens of <abbr
                        expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> when the "<hi rend="underline">Rebel
                    Col</hi>". passed through there. We stopped only a few minutes in towns and then
                    went on again. The next place was a little village called St. Thomas where
                    pretty much the same thing took place. We then came to Chambersburg, quite a
                    large town. Though we rode quite fast we did not get to that place <orig
                        reg="until">till</orig> late at night. The body of <abbr expan="Cavalry"
                        >Cavl.</abbr> halted till about 1 hour of sunrise about 1 mile from the
                    town. We spent a miserable night of it, for it rained a cold drisley rain, and
                    we did not sleep, and scarcely, Saturday morning about 1 hour of sun we were up
                    again not much refreshed, and passed on through Chambersburg. When about a mile
                    beyond the town we halted <orig reg="until">till</orig> we could destroy the
                    Depot, and some government stores which were there. We found some 500 hundred
                    pistols, and 15,000 sabres. The pistols we took, and some few of the sabres. The
                    rest we destroyed, also the railroad, and all public property we could get hold
                    of. At first the home guard were called out to resist our passage through the
                    town, and our officers went in under a flag of truce to meet the mayor, and one
                    or two other officials, and he gave them a short time to consider the matter
                    telling them he intended to march into the town, and after a short deliberation
                    they came to the conclusion that discretion was the better part of valor, and
                    discreetly surrendered to us. Here also some things were taken but, very few as
                    we stationed guards in all parts of the town where we were likely to go, and
                    this prevented the men from breaking open the stores. After leaving Chambersburg
                    we went on down the Baltimore and Pittsburg turnpike, taking all the horses we
                    could find. We marched all day Saturday passing through a good many little
                    towns, and villages the names of which I do not remember, and crossed into <abbr
                        expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> again about 5 o'clock Saturday evening. The two
                    counties through which we passed, Franklin and Adams, seemed to be quite
                    wealthy, but I cannot say a great deal for the refinement of the citizens. As
                    for the county I think it was as fine a section as I have ever seen. It was a
                    continuation of the the Valley of <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, and
                    presented many very beautiful farm scenes. The lands were well laid out, and
                    well worked. The fields were smaller than the fields in <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va.</abbr> but they were more productive I dare say, as they are worked
                    principally by the owner, and of course have better attention paid them. </p>

                <p>The barns on the farms are by a long deal the best I have ever seen. They are
                    built upon a stone wall about 6 feet high which under room is used always for
                    stable. The barns are made very large, and the room under neath is generally
                    large enough to accomodate from 20 to 50 horses. It is frequently the case that
                    the barns are taken for the dwelling house they are so much larger, and
                    generally better built. These two generally compose the dwellings of a farm, and
                    are very close together for convenience. The male citizens have generally the
                    dutch build, and are hard looking customers, being all hard working men, they
                    are generally though (I think) very hospitable, and kind to travelers, and
                    strangers. We might infer this from the fact that for every 5 odd miles you will
                    see an inn, which would call to the minds of men of modern day, stories of olden
                    times and scenes in old English Inns. The ladies are round rosy faces, which
                    though they betoken health, and good spirits, are sadly wanting in those
                    qualities peculiar only to the southern girl, and which are so attractive to the
                    southern youth, but enough of the <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> men and
                    girls. During our whole march through the State we met with no smile of welcome,
                    but were greeted <orig reg="everywhere">every where</orig> with sour looks, and
                    dark frowns from those who were bold enough to show even in that way their
                    hatred to all from "rebeldom". While passing through one little village the
                        <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> in charge of our platoon, says to a
                    very large fat farmer standing n the corner of the street "How do you do sir".
                    "How are you tory" was the gruff reply, we all laughed heartily, and the old
                    farmer only looked a little more glum. I cannot say that I approve of such a
                    course on the part of our Government. I am not fond of horse stealing and, did
                    not enjoy the trip much when I found out that such was the object of it. We
                    stopped wagons in the road and took every horse. Often I passed large 4 horse
                    wagons, from which the horses had been taken, and the gear left in the road.
                    Little carriages were taken and driven off, and men were left to foot it home.
                    Horses were taken from harrows in the field, and farmers were left gazing in
                    mute astonishment after our men as they rode off leading his horses. Women came
                    to plead for a favorite, and follow it down the road begging for its restoral,
                    but all in vain. Men in mere wantoness, and cruel feeling, when they heard a
                    lady pleading for the horse, stopped as if he intended to let her have it, and
                    when she came up, whipped up the horses, and then stopped again and waited for
                    her to come up. This he did several times and after having taunted her long
                    enough, rode off leaving her standing in the road. This one man boasted of
                    having done. While some men were stealing the horses from the stables, and
                    leading them off in view of the owners, others were receiving bread, apple
                    butter, etc. from the ladies of the house, and they even expressed sorrow if
                    they did not have more to give, after they had fed some 30 perhaps. Bill
                    &amp; myself stopped to get some bread and butter after the lady had given
                    us all she had, she begged us to say to others who were coming in that she had
                    no more, and as proof of the statement opened her dairy to show us all had been
                    given away. She even expressed sorrow because her butter was not very good
                    though I thought it very good myself, and seemed anxious to do us all the good
                    she could for us. At another place I saw old age abused - old men bearing the
                    frost of years, and tottering beneath the strong hand of time insulted by those
                    who were living in the bloom of youth &amp; manhood. Yet those old men gave
                    of their stock of bread, butter, and whatever they had, and were threatened with
                    violent entrance into their house, and <orig reg="seizure">siezure</orig> of all
                    they had because the steps of age were slow. Oh! Pa I did not think that human
                    nature could partake so much of the nature of the beast. I did not think that
                    man could be so lost of all feelings of humanity, as to trample upon humble old
                    age, for oh! these two men were humble, humbled nearly to earth by the stem, and
                    heavy hand of time. I thank you my parents, and I praise my maker, &amp; I
                    give him thanks that within my heart I still carry a tender, and sympathetic
                    feeling which is always awakened for the old man, and my fellow beings in
                    misfortune. Pa I do not think I could do a cruel act towards any of my fellow
                    creatures though he were my bitterest enemy. In following our army when I have
                    seen a poor horse lying down starving by degrees, and <hi rend="underline"
                    >knew</hi> he would die, so much have I been moved to pity, that when I could I
                    would shoot him through the heart to end his misery. But I must go on with the
                    history. After we crossed into the <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> the detail
                    to catch horses was called in, and we made our way back to the Potomac. We
                    passed through Emitsburg, <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> first, and to our
                    surprise were loudly cheered for it is very near the <abbr expan="Pennsylvania"
                        >Pa.</abbr> line. We marched on passing through a good many little towns in
                        <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> among them Woodsborough, Liberty, New
                    London, New Market, Barnsville, etc. but through all of these we passed at night
                    for we marched the whole night Saturday night, passing Barnsville the last town
                    a little after sunrise, and then towards the river. We had been at most of the
                    places named while we were in <abbr expan="Maryland">Md.</abbr> before, and at
                    New Market a man put his head out of the window, and calling loudly to Miss
                    Mollie exclaimed "Here are these Rebels again". Miss Mollie answered from across
                    the street <hi rend="underline">she</hi> was <hi rend="underline">looking</hi>
                    at them. The place is loyal to the southern Cause, and the citizens told us we
                    would have something to do to cross, but we still went on, and on coming near
                    the river, Stuart as a feint, made an attack on the yankees higher up the river,
                    and sent his lead horses lower down to cross while he was fighting the yankees
                    above. From his attacking them at that point they thought he intended to cross
                    the river there but he had no such idea, and while he was engaging them with on
                    or two pieces of artillery he was preparing to cross about 1 mile below. But
                    there was a <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> of yankees also at the very
                    place he intended to cross for they were determined to catch us if possible.
                    Stuart then ordered up a piece and opened on them. Our Sharpshooters pitched
                    into them at the same time and drive the whole <abbr expan="Regiment"
                    >Regt.</abbr> hurriedly down the river. We were then ordered to cross hastily,
                    and such running to and fro I have seldom seen. We all made a rush for the
                    river, yet in regular order, the <abbr expan="Regiments">Regts.</abbr> in front
                    first, and succeeded in getting every one and every thing over but one of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl.</abbr> Stuart's couriers, I think was cut off. We had
                    just got all over when we could see from this side 2 large columns of yankees
                    who had just got up from Coolville. Had they have got there in time we would
                    probably have lost 1/2 at least of our command in the attempt to cross. After
                    all was safe in <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> we halted a short time to give
                    our horses a little hay to eat and then proceeded on to within a mile of
                    Leesburg.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
