<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4044"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F4044">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Iowa Michigan Royster to his
                    Mother, June 29, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county iowa michigan royster to his mother, june 29 1863</title>
        <author>Royster, Iowa Michigan</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4044</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501595</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Iowa Michigan Royster to his Mother, June 29, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county iowa michigan royster to his mother, june 29 1863</title>
            <author>Iowa Michigan Royster</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Royster Family Papers, #4183,
                            Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel
                            Hill.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-29">1863-06-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties,
                        Family, Home Front, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Patriotism,
                        Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4044T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>After describing personal matters about his engagement and life in camp, Iowa
                    Royster of North Carolina tells his mother of the plundering of Chambersburg,
                    Pa. and Lee's orders regarding the punishment for such behavior. Royster also
                    describes the fear and submission he sees among the people in the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-29">June 29th 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Ma:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I suppose you saw in the "Progress" newspaper a notice of my appointment to this
                    regiment. It was quite unexpected. I had made a request to <abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> Nicholson of this <abbr expan="regiment">reg't</abbr> to
                    recommend me to the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> but he did not expect any
                    good result. When I read the appointment in the newspaper I was under arrest in
                    my old company. In a day or two came a note from <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr> Barbour of the 37th asking <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Baker
                    to send me to him as I had been appointed in his regiment. <abbr expan="Colonel"
                        >Col.</abbr> Baker released me from arrest and sent me on with many
                    expressions of goodwill, and wishes for my future success. The occasion of my
                    arrest was this. <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Baker gave an order that the
                    1st sergeants should call out the men and make them clear out the camp - cut
                    down the trees and pull up the brush. It was Sunday and I was acting as 1st
                    Sergeant of <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> E. I refused to obey the order. I
                    wouldn't make the men work on the Sabbath, and I was order to go to my tent and
                    consider myself under arrest. It was less than a week before I hear of my
                    appointment. The <abbr expan="regiment">reg't</abbr> had two fights with the
                    Yankees while was under arrest. I didn't have to fight. They had taken my arms
                    from me and sent me back to the wagon train. So it was a good thing at last.</p>

                <p>On my way to join my <abbr expan="regiment">reg't</abbr>, I came by Winchester
                    and saw Kate. She had <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> a letter from you
                    dated in <abbr expan="January">Jan.</abbr> and was preparing to answer it. She
                    and I are engaged. Tell my Papa that I don't know how much her father is worth.
                        <pb n="2"/>Don't know whether he is worth anything or not- couldn't come
                    within ten thousand dollars of the amount to save my life. All of his good
                    instructions lost. Well, "a fool will have his own way." Quick courtship wasn't
                    it? A week's acquaintance last September and two days in June. I congratulate
                    myself on my promptness. Great quality in a soldier. When I left Winchester Kate
                    gave me a bundle of provisions, a paper of candy, raisins, etc., some
                    hankerchiefs, trimmed my hat, and did a great many things to captivate me.</p>

                <p>I sold my horse for 350 dollars and my saddle for fifty. So I have 400 cash with
                    me. I wish I could get a chance to send it to Raleigh and settle Mr. Lovejoy's
                    account. I am so extravagant that I am afraid I shall spend all my money here
                    and have none, or if I get knocked over by a Minnie I would not like for the
                    Yankees to get my Confederate.</p>

                <p>I am the only officer present in my company. The men are very clever. There is
                    not one among them who swears or uses any profane language. There are about
                    twenty four. When the <abbr expan="company">co.</abbr> started from N. C. it
                    numbered 126. At Sharpsburg last September only five. The <abbr expan="Captain"
                        >Capt.</abbr> went back a few days ago on business expecting to join us in a
                    few days. I fear that the Yankees have got him. He is a member of the Baptist
                    Church. When the company was first made up, the captain, the three lieutenants
                    and one private were all preachers. Every regiment in the brigade has a chaplin;
                    I heard a sermon yesterday. In this brigade there are the 18th, 7th, 33rd, and
                    87th and 28th <abbr expan="regiments">reg'ts</abbr>. I find a great many old
                    acquaintances among them, and on the whole have <pb n="3"/>quite a pleasant
                    time. Everybody told me that my feet would be blistered, but I have been
                    marching nearly a week and have experienced no inconvenience, though several men
                    have fallen by the road. There is no straggling. All are compelled to keep up.
                    Those who are too weak or sick ride in ambulances or wagons. Lee has fully
                    double the number of men he had at Sharpsburg. Our regiment for instance had
                    only fifty at Sharpsburg, there about two hundred and seventy five now. The
                    other regiments are the same way.</p>

                <p>Yesterday and the day before our soldiers plundered far and wide - taking butter,
                    milk, apple-butter, fruit, chickens, pigs and horses and everything they could
                    lay their hands on. The people are frightened out of their senses. "take
                    anything you want but don't hurt us" is their cry. They are afraid to protest
                    against anything. It is the most beautiful country you ever saw, the neatest
                    farms, fine houses, good fences. The whole country is covered with the finest
                    crops of wheat, such wheat as is not seen in our country.</p>

                <p>Yesterday however, <abbr expan="General">Genl'</abbr> Lee sent an order around
                    that all stealing and plundering should be punished in each case with <hi
                        rend="underline">death</hi>, that officers should be held accountable for
                    the execution of his orders, that he made war upon armed men - not upon women
                    and children. The plundering will be stopped now. I never saw people so
                    submissive and badly scared as these people in my life. It must be conscience.
                    They know how their soldiers have desolated Virginia and they fear that <pb
                        n="4"/>ours will retaliate. But I can't bear it. I hate to take anything
                    when it is given from fear. Quartermasters and Commissaries and Surgeons are
                    empowered to impress everything necessary for the use of the army. But men are
                    not allowed to have anything but what they buy.</p>

                <p>I heard but don't know how true it is that nine of our soldiers were shot
                    yesterday for taking jewelry from off the persons of the women. The articles of
                    war make a death punishment for stealing, and in an enemy's country a regimental
                    court-martial has the power to inflict this punishment. <abbr expan="General"
                        >Gen.</abbr> Lee seems determined to stop all marauding. I don't know what
                    place we shall attack, most seem to think Harrisburg. For my part I want to stay
                    here until the war is over, and take their towns and beat their armies and live
                    on their people. Lee's men have unbounded confidence in him. The Yankees are in
                    great perplexity - don't know what point to re-inforce - don't know whether Lee
                    will attack Harrisburg, Pittsburg, Baltimore, or Washington. I want to take them
                    all. It is glorious. All the fences that are burnt now are Yankee fences.
                    They'll be willing for us to stay out of the Union hereafter. We've come back to
                    the Union, but not as they expected. Write soon. Direct to <abbr
                        expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> Iowa Royster, 37th N.C.G. Lane's Brigade,
                    Pender's Division, Hill's Corps.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
