<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4051"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4051">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Thomas F. Boatwright to his Wife,
                    June 15, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county thomas f boatwright to his wife, june 15 1863</title>
        <author>Boatwright, Thomas F. </author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4051</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501602</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Thomas F. Boatwright to his Wife, June 15, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county thomas f boatwright to his wife, june 15 1863</title>
            <author>Thomas F. Boatwright</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Thomas F. Boatwright Papers, #73,
                            Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel
                            Hill.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-15">1863-06-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4051T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Thomas Boatwright writes about his march into Pennsylvania and his impressions of
                    the area in a letter to his wife.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-15">June 15/63</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Chambersburg Pennsylvania <lb/> Cumberland Co Pa</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Darling wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am glad I have the privilege of writing again after undergoing so many
                    hardships: we have been across the Potomac river for ten days laid in Maryland
                    for <unclear>six</unclear> and from <unclear>Minuto</unclear> to this state in
                    which we have been marching for two day now 30 or 40 miles north of Maryland we
                    are on the turnpike road that leads to Harrisburg the capital which is about 50
                    miles off we have passed through two town in this state Middleburg to
                    Greencastle and while passing through all <unclear>doors' man</unclear> shut and
                    the people thought that we came to murder and rob but no so for the orders from
                    General Lee is not to touch a thing that belongs to private individuals that
                    what is needed for <unclear>our</unclear> comfort must be taken by proper
                    authorities which I think is all right Maryland men seem very cautious to be let
                    loose if <pb n="2"/> they <unclear>were</unclear> all would be burned out of
                    homes in this country but not so. We have captured hundreds of horses and
                    hundreds of cattle and immense quantities of flour and various other articles
                    such as are useful to us. Now I come to speak of the country I never have seen
                    finer crops of wheat in my life but <unclear>no</unclear> their crops seem to
                    look so <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. The people do not know that the war is going in this
                    part of the country that is judging from <orig reg="appearances"
                    >appearinces</orig> I have often heard that this state was <orig reg="thickly"
                        >thickely</orig> settled it is so for I never saw buildings as close
                    together in all of my life a hundred acres of land is as much as any one owns. I
                    have not seen the first <abbr expan="secessionist">secess</abbr> since I entered
                    this state all strong unionists here. Our money is not good here though they are
                    forced to take it in some <pb n="3"/> places. such as paying for
                        <unclear>government</unclear> stores that is those we buy but most of them
                    are <unclear>taking</unclear> I have been a little unwell for several days from
                    cold maybe not so much so as to disable me from marching! I do not know where we
                    are going only say that we are marching northward where bound know not. I have
                    purchased two dresses for you and a pair of shoes that I will send you as soon
                    as a way is <unclear>
                        <orig reg="offered">ofered</orig>
                    </unclear>. <del hand="h1">All</del> will I am at the <orig reg="wagon"
                    >waggon</orig> come up here to help the boy <unclear>attend</unclear> looking we
                    are laying still today resting and gathering stores and <orig reg="wagons"
                        >waggons</orig> are gone out after things <unclear>now</unclear> we get
                    coffee here and <pb n="4"/> sugar whiskey and candy cigars nuts of different
                    kind all I obtained.</p>

                <p>We E as <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> hardly today I must stop writing we have tore up the
                    railroad in this county we only have our Corps here <orig reg="Ewell's"
                    >Ewels</orig> three <abbr expan="Divisions">Div</abbr><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> we are 60
                    miles from the Potomac. near the heart of this state all of the <orig
                        reg="militia">malitia</orig> are gathered at the capital of this state
                    Harrisburg.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all and Oh may the Lord bless you my dear and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to
                    meet again in the pray of good officer and loving</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>Thomas F. Boatwright</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
