<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4054"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4054">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Richard Henry Watkins to Mary
                    Watkins, October 15, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county richard henry watkins to mary watkins, october 15 1862</title>
        <author>Watkins, Richard Henry</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4054</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501605</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Richard Henry Watkins to Mary Watkins, October 15,
                            1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county richard henry watkins to mary watkins, october 15 1862</title>
            <author>Richard Henry Watkins</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Richard Henry Watkins Papers,
                            Mss1 W3272a, Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Virginia.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-15">1862-10-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Desertion/Leave, Family, Military Authority, Military
                        Strategy, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4054T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Richard Watkins' letter to his wife Mary gives an account of his participation in
                    General Stuart's raid into Pennsylvania in October 1862. The letter also has an
                    interesting description of General Stonewall Jackson.</p>
            </div1>

        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-15">Oct 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> -62</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Lee Town</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Precious Mary</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>On last Thursday the day on which <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Berkeley left
                    us <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Stuart and I and a whole
                    <unclear>parcel</unclear> of fellows <add hand="h1" place="inline">about 1800 in
                        all</add> concluded that as times were getting dull on this side of the
                    river we would ride over and see what the people were <orig reg="doing"
                    >doin</orig> on the other side. Started about 10 o'clock in the morning in the
                    direction of Winchester and then turning to the right we reached the Potomac
                    about midnight and encamped <add hand="h1" place="inline">near Hedgesville above
                            W<hi rend="super">ms</hi>port</add>: a thick cloud of dust enveloped us
                    the whole of that day &amp; we saw nothing worthy of note. <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">Raining next morning &amp;</add> at daybreak <del
                        hand="h1">next morning</del> we crossed the river <unclear>drove</unclear>
                    in the enemy's pickett taking six prisoners and passing rapidly through a
                    portion of Maryland entered Pennsylvania about midday and then what a sudden
                    change in the appearance of things all the inhabitants astonished, startled,
                    terrified first cheering us for Union troops then suddenly turning pale,
                    quaking, trembling with fright. One poor woman was so enthusiastic in the cause
                    of the Union that she snatched up her babe and ran through a hard rain to meet
                    us nearly a half a mile in order to hurrah for the Union. You can imagine what a
                    change came over the spirit of her dream when our boys laughed at her and told
                    her that we were live rebels. The order was soon given to detail men to catch
                    horses and I wish that you could have witnessed the scene which followed it. Our
                    large body continued to move rapidly on towards Mercersburg and over every field
                    &amp; in every direction men could be seen chasing horses each one trying to
                    take the most. They would meet wagons in the road take every horse &amp;
                    leave the poor wagoner either swearing with <unclear>rage</unclear> or mute with
                    astonishment. Citizens on horses &amp; in buggies were dismounted &amp;
                    turned loose afoot. Any threat or exhibition of <unclear>rage</unclear> was only
                    laughed at. Every trooper seemed to be in the best humor imaginable and it was
                    really the greatest <orig reg="frolic">frolick</orig> that I ever witnessed. At
                    Mercersburg we halted, fed our horses bountifully from the corn fields of the
                    good old Dutchmen and talked familiarly with such citizens as had the courage to
                    approach us. At this place <orig reg="occurred">occured</orig> the only thing
                    which I sincerely <pb n="2"/> regret about the trip. Some of the men broke open
                    a store and rifled it of a great many goods mainly though such things as they
                    needed badly such as shoes hats &amp;c. I regret exceedingly that this <orig
                        reg="occurred">occured</orig> indeed I doubt the propriety and the policy of
                    even taking horses but this we were ordered to do by our General when there was
                    no authority &amp; certainly no order for the other. The doctrine of
                    retaliation is to me odious and I took nothing not even to the value of a pin
                    while in the state. But to the trip -- from Mercersburg we continued our march
                    to Chambersburg, a large and wealthy town which I reckon contains from fifteen
                    to twenty thousand inhabitants at least and is one of the most beautiful places
                    that I ever saw. Reached Chambersburg about sunset and the home guard
                    threatening to oppose us <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Stuart sent in a flag
                    of truce and informed them that if they made the least resistance he would shell
                    the town. They at once gave him permission to enter. There we encamped for the
                    night just outside of the town, and seeing a large straw stack I did not unfold
                    my blankets but burrowed under the stack and slept all night quite comfortably
                    although my books &amp; overcoat were saturated with water, and nearly all
                    of my clothes wet from the constant rain. The next morning Saturday we were
                    aroused and started again. Took a most meandering route from Chambersburg to
                    Emmetsville <abbr expan="Maryland">M.d</abbr> gathering several hundred horses
                    as we went. When we touched the Maryland line near Emmetsville the order was
                    given that nothing was to be seized under the penalty of death. As soon as we
                    entered the town the citizens discovered that we were Stuarts Cavalry they began
                    to cheer and I have never seen a more cordial &amp; enthusiastic reception
                    than we there received. Such a contrast with what we had witnessed in
                    Pennsylvania; and Emmetsville <unclear>too</unclear> only a half mile from the
                    line but filled to overflowing with secessionists. From Emmetsville we continued
                    our journey through <abbr expan="Maryland">M.d.</abbr> &amp; entirely around
                        M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Clellans army, first approaching near Hagerstown
                    then through Woodville near Frederick, through Liberty near Baltimore, through
                    New Market &amp; then to Barnesville near the Potomac and thence to the
                    river opposite Leesburg <pb n="3"/>We reached the river about 10 or 11 o'clock
                    Sunday morning, having marched eighty five miles in 28 hours without dismounting
                    a single time from our horses (the whole of Saturday &amp; Saturday night
                    &amp; Sunday morning till eleven o'clock). On approaching the river we found
                    that the enemy was in possession of the ford with infantry artillery &amp;
                    cavalry. The moment seemed to be a critical one indeed, but <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Stuart remained perfectly composed and by a
                    rapid manuevering of the trooops &amp; a tolerably sharp skirmish he
                    succeeded in crossing us all over, without the loss of a single man. Just as the
                    rear of our column reached the Virginia shore quite a large force of the enemy
                    appeared on the opposite hills. But all were over &amp; safe. That night we
                    encamped at Leesburg, and next morning as <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    Stuart rode by the whole column gave him three rousing cheers and we came on at
                    our leisure to camp. This morning I am perfectly well, fully refreshed.</p>

                <p>Oct 17-- Whilst writing the above news reached us that the enemy were advancing
                    in large force and of course we were ordered to horse. They came and drove our
                    pickett from <unclear>Charlestown</unclear> and occupied it. Our regiment was
                    ordered on a scout to ascertain their force if possible and went almost to
                    Harpers Ferry before getting the information returning to Camp about Midnight.
                    By daybreak yesterday we were aroused by <unclear>videttes</unclear> stating
                    that the enemy were also advancing from Shepherdstown &amp; were almost upon
                    us. We were soon on our horses and other regiments of our brigade coming up were
                    drawn up in line of battle to receive them. Their cavalry came in sight
                    &amp; halted. I was sent out in chase of some videttes to watch their
                    movements. Purnall Dickinson rode boldly out into a clear field very near their
                    picketts &amp; commenced firing at them. Other videttes soon found him and
                    the firing was kept up for some time. This checked the enemys movements, but
                    about eleven o'clock we were relieved by a portion of the 9th V<hi rend="super"
                        >a</hi> and as I called in my videttes and started off, several thousand of
                    the enemy came pouring out of the woods formed in the line of battle &amp;
                    halted about that time our regiment was ordered to the rear of our cavalry to
                    feed our horses having been on duty 24 hours <pb n="4"/>Whilst there <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee (<abbr expan="Robert">Robt</abbr> E) <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Jackson &amp; <abbr expan="General"
                    >Genl</abbr> Stuart rode by together going over to take a view of the enemy.
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Jackson is entirely different in
                    appearance from what I expected. He is about my size, perhaps not quite so tall,
                    with darker hair &amp; whiskers and entirely genteel in his appearance
                    though <orig reg="plainly">planely</orig> dressed. Nothing rough or uncouth
                    about him. The enemy remained in position until the afternoon when suddenly from
                    some cause unknown to me they became panic stricken and beat a hasty retreat
                    across the river. We pursued their cavalry &amp; artillery with cavalry
                    &amp; artillery and skirmished with them until we forced them entirely
                    across then posted our pickett and returned to this our old camp.</p>

                <p>This morning I was delighted at the reception of another letter from you dated
                        <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 24<hi rend="super">th</hi> &amp;
                        <abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>. I am so sorry to
                    hear that you have been sick. Oh how I wish that I could be with you. Will apply
                    for a furlough as soon as <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Berkeley gets back I
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> have one. If you see him tell him to make haste and come in
                    the mean time if your sickness returns write me and I will come anyhow. Am very
                    glad to hear that you have short hair in <unclear>afine</unclear> that you look
                    now just as you did when at school at Ms Ballantines, I want to hurry home
                    before it grows out again I thank you so much for writing before Archer Haskins
                    returned &amp; s<del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I await his return impatiently in order
                    that I may get another letter. My poor horse John Wesley broke down just as we
                    crossed the Potomac on our way from Pennsylvania but fortunately Magruder is in
                    tolerably good order and I am riding him again. My little bay at home is worth
                    two hundred &amp; fifty or 300 dollars <unclear>according</unclear> to his
                    condition. If he can be sold at that it would be well for
                    <unclear>paps</unclear> to sell him. Has mother sold her
                    <unclear>folio</unclear>? Please ask her or <unclear>Conv</unclear> Purnall to
                    have mine sold at the same time &amp; also my wheat I do not get any papers
                    and cannot watch the market at all. Please write me about my tobacco &amp;
                    corn crop of the present year and write me a great about yourself, especially
                    about my Mary, my darling precious one. Write about her, her little
                        <unclear>shelter</unclear> &amp; all. Write about your thoughts
                    &amp; dreams &amp; acts by day &amp; night. Write write.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I wish to all the best for <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <abbr expan="Your">Yr</abbr> own R</salute>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
