<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6028"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6028">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Ellen
                    Howe, October 19, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to ellen howe, october 19 1862</title>
        <author>Russell, Lauramann Howe</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagle</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagle</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F6028</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501607</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Ellen Howe, October 19,
                            1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to ellen howe, october 19 1862</title>
            <author>Lauramann Russell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Lauramann Howe Russell Papers,
                            Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke
                            University, Durham, North Carolina</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>The date as written by Lauramann Howe Russell appears to be "October
                                19, 1860, but the content of this letter suggests that it was
                                probably written in 1862. Russell wrote a portion of the last
                                paragraph and the closing in the top margin of the second page. He
                                wrote the postscript on the top margin of the first page. We have
                                not included other letters in this collection written from
                                Williamsport, Maryland, Harpers Ferry, (West) Virginia, and
                                Alexandria, Virginia.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-19">1862-10-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F6028T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to his daughter Ellen, Lauramann Howe Russell lists his patients
                    and their wounds. He also describes the kind ladies, paved streets, brick
                    sidewalks, and hospital building of Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-10-19"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 19<hi rend="super">th</hi><orig reg="1862">1860</orig><lb/> Three o'clock A.M.</date>
                        <name type="place"> Chambersburg Franklin <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Daughter Ellen</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In your mother's letter of the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> she tells me that you are sick. she did not
                    tell me how long you had been so. but among other things said that you were
                    comfortable and furthermore that the worst of it was over. I was sorry to hear
                    that my Ellen was sick but it was a great comfort to be told in the same letter
                    that you were getting along well. I am sitting up with the wounded men of my
                    ward. and will write a few lines to interest you while you are laying in bed or
                    setting up in a chair as the case may be, but I hope you may be about the room
                    and still better if possible. My health is very good with the exception of a
                    headache that I had yesterday and the day before but it is now nearly over---My
                    patients are doing very well, there is nineteen of them, three <del hand="h1">of
                        them</del> very badly wounded, <unclear/> one was shot in the shoulder and
                    the ball is somewhere in him now his arm is <orig reg="infected">affected</orig>
                    the whole <orig reg="length">leangth</orig> and it has been lanced above the
                    elbow for the second time it discharges very freely and is very <orig
                        reg="painful">painfull</orig>. the <orig reg="man's">mans</orig> brother was
                    here from <unclear>Ind'</unclear> the other day to see him and <orig
                        reg="stayed">staid</orig> about a week <abbr expan="Number">No</abbr> two is
                    shot in the leg near the body, the wound is not very painful but he has a
                    difficulty on his lungs which I think he will hardly survive.--<abbr
                        expan="Number">No</abbr> three is wounded in the leg just above the knee,
                    the bone was fractured, it is very<pb n="2"/>
                    <orig reg="painful">painfull</orig> and I should not be surprised if in a week
                    or two his leg was amputated. All of the rest are quite comfortable and are able
                    the most of them to <orig reg="get">ge</orig> about the room, and some of them
                        <orig reg="get">ge</orig> out of doors, but of the <orig reg="nineteen"
                        >ninteen</orig> in my ward seventeen are shot in the legs. I had <orig
                        reg="twenty-two">twenty two</orig> three went away the other day they were
                    also shot in the legs. I have two men to help me do the work, and I am what they
                    call in Hospitals <hi rend="underline">Ward Master</hi>.</p>

                <p>A young man in another part of the house had his leg cut off yesterday I saw the
                        <orig reg="operation">opperation</orig> it was the third case of the kind
                    that I have seen since the great battle of <abbr expan="Wednesday">Wednes</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> which I shall
                    remember as long as I live.-- The people of Chambersburg are very kind to our
                    wounded Soldiers they bring in a great many nice things such as grapes which
                    grow in abundance and are very sweet. Jellies of various kinds chicken broth,
                    milk toast, dry toast and many other things which it is unnecessary to mention.
                    The names of some of the ladies that are so kind to our soldiers are Mrs
                    McCellan, Nixon, Brown, Wright, Armstrong, McDowell, Wollace, Burnett &amp;
                    Reed. Chambersburg is a very pretty town of about four thousand inhabitant the
                    streets are paved and the <orig reg="sidewalks">side walks</orig> brick</p>

                <p>The building that I am in was built for a <orig reg="College">Colledge</orig> and
                    used as such <orig reg="until">untill</orig> about the time that I came here I
                    think they will use it all winter for this purpose, and I think that I shall
                    stay here as long as they will let me if it is the remainder of my time with
                    Government.-- I hope this letter will Find you running about the yard. I have
                        <orig reg="thought">though</orig> of you many times since knowing that you
                    were sick I trust you are better by this time. write when you get well enough
                    but not <orig reg="too">to</orig> soon. I shall enclose a ten cent piece for you
                    to get something with love to all.--</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>From your Father</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <abbr expan="Lauramann">L</abbr>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="Number">No</abbr>
                        <unclear>two</unclear> in my ward that I <orig reg="speak">speek</orig> of
                        in this letter died Sunday <abbr expan="about">abt</abbr> Four o'clock</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
