<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6031"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6031">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Serena E. Russell,
     November 28, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to serena e russell, november 28 1862</title>
        <author>Russell, Lauramann Howe</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6031</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501610</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Serena E. Russell, November 28, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to serena e russell, november 28 1862</title>
            <author>Lauramann Howe Russell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Lauramann Howe Russell Papers, Special Collections
       Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We have not included other letters in this collection written from Williamsport, Maryland,
        Harpers Ferry, (West) Virginia, and Alexandria, Virginia.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-28">1862-11-28</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church Religion, Home Front, Hospitals, Arts/Leisure</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6031T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to his daughter Serena, Lauramann Howe Russell recounts his "dull"
     Thanksgiving day at the hospital. He also mentions entertainments at Sabbath School in
     Chambersburg and the requests of children for pine laurel rings.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-28"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 28<hi rend="super">th</hi>/62</date>
      <name type="place">Academy Hospital<lb/> Chambersburg <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn<hi
       rend="super">a</hi></abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Daughter</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It is the evening after Thanksgiving and I suppose you are <orig reg="either">eather</orig>
     finishing up the holiday or at home with the rest of the folks having a good time with Ellen
     and Charles I have told mother about the time we had at this hospital and you will hear all
     about it.</p>

    <p>I got a letter today from uncle Eli there was one also from Charley <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
     <del hand="h1">and</del> Henry and Aunt Elisa. you will see that I had four letters beside
     uncle Eli's &amp; Aunt Elisa's Photographs I was glad to get them for it seemed some like
     seeing them in person I shall expect your picture <orig reg="sometime">some time</orig> and
     Ellens too.<pb n="2"/></p>

    <p>The little girls come into the hospital and sing to the soldiers <orig reg="sometimes">some
      times</orig> and it makes me think of the class of little girls that used to sing with me you
     will recollect about it I presume. they sing many of the things that we used. I <orig
      reg="don't">dont</orig> think that they sing as well for perhaps they have not had the <orig
      reg="music">Musice</orig> to learn only by wrote.</p>

    <p>I had rather of a dull Thanksgiving the dinner was all that was good or lively and that did
     not last long I had my usual work to do of pulling off old bandages and putting on new ones
     making flax seed poulticeses <orig reg="etc.">&amp;C.</orig>
     <orig reg="etc.">&amp;C.</orig> I thought of <orig reg="what">whot</orig> Charles said in
     his letter about being at home and having a good time. I wonder if mother had a chicken if so
     did Frank eat any of it. I hope he and all the<pb n="3"/> of you are well Charles Otis told me
     in his letter that he and his brother Henry were coming up to grandmothers to spend
     Thanksgiving I hope you had a good time with them if you were up there <del hand="h1">with
     them</del></p>

    <p>The Sabbath Schools had their Anniversary at the German Reform Church last evening. I made
     some <orig reg="inquiries">enquiries</orig> about the entertainment during the meeting and
     understood that it consisted in singing <orig reg="speaking">speeking</orig>
     <orig reg="pieces">peaces</orig> answering questions from the bible. the last mentioned
     performance is something new in the way of entertainment I was told that one little girl I
     think it was that answered more than one hundred questions and a little boy that could tell the
     Chapter <orig reg="and">an</orig> verse of any passage that might be read. I think there are
     not many little boys that can do that he must have <orig reg="studied">studdied</orig> the
     scriptures much of his time during life<pb n="4"/></p>

    <p>Enclosed you will find a ring which I think will fit some of your fingers it is one that I
     made from pine laurel that come from Manassas. I think that it is quite <del hand="h1">a</del>
     pretty some of the little girls that come to the hospital ask me to make them some but I cannot
     get time. I did make Ellen Bell McCellan- a little girl about two years old, a little ring and
     put in her middle name she was pleased with it. but it will not do to make any more for them
     For all the little girls in town will want one. I <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> write more
     this time. I hope this will find you in good health.</p>

    <p>Write soon as you can find it convenient and as <orig reg="much">mauch</orig> sooner as you
     have a mind to</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your Father</salute>
     <signed>Lauraman</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">
      <name type="recipient">to Serena E. Russell</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
