<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6509"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6509">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Her "Sister in Faith,"
     August 17, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to her sister in faith, august 17 1864</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6509</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501637</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Her "Sister in Faith," August 17, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to her sister in faith, august 17 1864</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>5 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-08-17">1864-08-17</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front, Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6509T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter, Eliza Stouffer discusses the recent deaths of close friends and her mother
     and the displacement of families due to the burning of Chambersburg.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
   

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-08-17">August 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear sister in faith</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>after a long silence, or delay, first wishing unto you, much love, grace peace and mercy from
     God our Heavenly Father, who sees fit to give &amp; bestow according to our need, may he
      <orig reg="strengthen">strenghen</orig> &amp; console you, in all your trials &amp;
      <orig reg="temptations">temtations</orig> which no doubt you have to share with all the
     children of God. But a great consolation there is in his word, when he says that the hairs of
     our heads are all numbered and that not one of them shall fall to the ground without his
     notice. Is it not a wonder to us, that he should be so mindful of us poor creatures, and should
     it not <orig reg="strengthen">strenghen</orig> our faith, so that we could more fully trust in
     him.</p>

    <p>Dear sister I often have to think back of the times we spent together, how quiet and secure I
     felt when with you, and how soon after, we had to be made afraid of the <orig reg="enemies"
      >enimies</orig> of our own Country. I often have to study why it is so, Is God not ruler over
     all, Is he not on the throne, has he not power over all, and can turn nations &amp;
     Kindred, all power is given him in Heaven &amp; earth, for he <orig reg="overcame">over
      came</orig> the world, There is still a<pb n="2"/> consolation left me, In this, that I
     believe it is not unknown to him, and would rather be ruled by him, than fall alone in the
     unmerciful hands of the wicked world. I believe too, that we observe a scourging, and have
     perhaps grown too cold &amp; careless and that God through <del hand="h1">his</del> mercy
     may have left this come upon us, to draw us nearer to him, &amp; wean us off more from the
     world &amp; the things of the world, when we see how soon we may be deprived of <orig
      reg="everything">every thing</orig>, we here <orig reg="possess">passes</orig>, as we have
     many examples in our town. People that had <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig> that
      the<orig reg="they"/> could wish for, or make themselves comfortable, were deprived of <del
      hand="h1">every</del> all in one hours time, many had only 10 to 15 minutes time given them to
     leave their houses, and then forbid many, to take <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> out
     some saved a few clothes, others none at all, but what they had on their backs, some had their
     clothing &amp; money packed up, and were not allowed to take them out one woman asked
     permission to save one silk dress, had it on her arms they took it from her &amp; tore it
     all to shreds, others again were more merciful, &amp; helped the women to carry out things
     some appeared to be very much affected that they had come to this, one in <orig
      reg="particular">perticular</orig> I was told <orig reg="of">off</orig>, that shed tears
     &amp; would not help to burn. They took him &amp; hand cuffed him, he told some<pb
      n="3"/> of the women that his wife lived in Baltimore, gave them his name &amp; address to
     write to his wife &amp; tell her why he was hand cuffed, did not Know but what they would
     Kill him, and he Knew it would be a consolation for her to Know that it was because he would
     not burn private property others were so affected when they saw the distress of some families,
     one in <orig reg="particular">perticular</orig> I was told that a woman handed her sick child
     out of the window to <orig reg="another">a nother</orig> one <orig reg="until">untill</orig>
     she would get some <orig reg="necessary">nesessary</orig> thing, he came and asked her, madam
     can I do <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> for you, she said no, you have done me all the
     harm you can do, you cant do any worse, he took the child, &amp; said This child does not
     feel revengeful, it has a smile on its countinance &amp; he wept, your friends Isaac
     Snivelys were also burned out he was not at home at the time, she came out to our house with a
     few dresses on her arms, &amp; her <orig reg="Brother-in- 
 law">Brotherinlaw</orig> with a
     Blanket &amp; one quilt that they had saved many have not so much of their own as to lay
     their heads upon, <orig reg="they">The</orig> had their Pickets stationed all around town and
     on the hill above town had their cannon planted, in case should they be attacked, some think
     they did not get all accomplished, that they intended to do they had two pickets at the gate
     house near our mill &amp; inquired about the place and if there were any stores here talked
     very boasting said they would like to get a shot at some <orig reg="yankee">yankey</orig> to
     get a <orig reg="yankee">yankey</orig> suit, and just then<pb n="4"/> some of our soldiers came
     round the corner, &amp; took them prisoners, a great many People think if that had not
     happened our place would have shared the same fate, the next stationed pickets saw this
     &amp; galloped off to town &amp; told them the <orig reg="yankees">yankeys</orig> were
     not more than three quarters of a mile off, that they think hastened them off. they then went
     back, and went through Loudon, set fire to the stores there, and also to a mill near by, but
     the Citizens still put it out. they were the next farm to my Brothers, but none came there. I
     was there at the time my mother was laying at the point of death at the same time we were all
     there us sisters, an exciting time it was for all of us, each one felt for their families at
     home but could not get home well, and did not like to leave our mother, we never left her Know
      <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> about it. she was sick between three &amp; four
     weeks something like <orig reg="inflammation">inflamation</orig> of the liver suffered very
     much But was strong in faith &amp; love and wished for her end. she was buried on sunday
     the seventh of August arrived to the age of 77 years 10 months &amp; 24 days, had a small
     funeral the excitement was so great. very few horses at home, we could not sent word to <orig
      reg="Waynesboro">Wanesboro</orig>, two days after Henry Ryders brother wife was buried she was
     sick only a short time with<pb n="5"/> Billious fever leaves one child. also Emanuel Millers
     widow near Waynesboro was buried near the same time I understood she was taken up in the church
     again shortly before, felt very good to her. I think you must have Known her-</p>

    <p>I also <orig reg="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></orig> a letter from sister Rebekah
     Frantz which stated that Henry Frantz wife has also died I so often <orig reg="wondered"
      >wandered</orig> how she was and <orig reg="whether">wether</orig> she was rightly given up. I
     also <orig reg="heard">head</orig> through Hetty Ryder that sister Mattie Swartly had also
     died. how many changes there are often in a short time, that young sister Landis at <orig
      reg="Shippensburg">Shippenburg</orig> also died right in harvest she was taken up in baptism
     when I was with you. She was strong in faith &amp; hope, to the end hope you are well, also
     your Brother, hope he is better too we are just midling well our eldest son Amos has been lying
     sick with a fever now about 3 weeks is better is clear of fever again is weak yet has not much
     appetite yet. hope if it is the Lords will he may be again restored my love to you, and
     enquiring friends write when ever <orig reg="convenient">convainent</orig> as I would be glad
     to hear from you and Brother there. The <orig reg="Brethren">Brothren</orig> &amp; sisters
     are well as far as I Know at this time. Mary Crosgrove is about the same, still helpless <orig
      reg="otherwise">other wise</orig> does not suffer much at this time, is still at Stoners</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
