<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6502"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6502">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller,
     November 26, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, november 26 1862</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6502</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501630</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller, November 26, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, november 26 1862</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-26">1862-11-26</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Church/Religious Activity</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6502T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to Catherine and Amos Miller, Eliza Stouffer describes the physical state of
     those at home, a visit from Daniel Dash's family, and the importance of maintaining religious
     faith.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
 
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-26">Nov 26<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg, Pa.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Children</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>After a long silence on my part, <orig reg="although">altho</orig> not through forgetfulness
     as my mind has been often with you and would much rather speak to you, face to face then write,
     but must at this time be content and thankful, for this <orig reg="privilege"
     >previledge</orig>, We are all pretty well, with a few small ailments, Papa I think is in a
     better way now than he has been for over a month, he could not get any thing to relieve him of
     diarrhea, since Sunday he has taken <del hand="h1">taken</del> spirits of turpentine and it
     made a change directly, so that we Think he will soon be quite well again Amos has a sore <orig
      reg="carbuncle">carbencle</orig> on his Knee, so that, he walks quite lame, did not grind last
     night, &amp; Emma has a sore finger something like fellon. Our men are thrashing with the
     separater, The girls are washing, I just finished soap boiling had a big job of it. got nice
     soap, (I feel pretty tired) Brother Martin <pb n="2"/>Hoover stopped with us, on monday took
     dinner here, said you were all well, but Mother Miller, was not so well, hope she is well again
     said he enjoyed his visit very much felt strenghened in Spirit, Our Neighbours and friends are
     well as far as I Know, Abners too, he was just in, while I am writing, On Sunday John Frys were
     here, we went with them to Joseph Ryders' Lizzie is quite well again, but looks pale her baby
     is growing some, has not much suck for it, must feed it, In the evening <abbr expan="Daniel"
      >Danl</abbr> Dashes family from <orig reg="Cincinnati">Cincinatie</orig> were here, they have
     three children, had only the youngest one along, a little girl named Sallie, eight years old,
     he looks well, and by all accounts is doing well Elizabeth Dash was also along, she said Molly
     Laufman was very poorly, I thought I would go up to see her as soon as I get time, Phillip
     Hoover was here on saturday evening for a few chickens, he is well, and looks hardy, yesterday
     some of the Cumberland County men passed here (Several hundred) to Gettysburg<pb n="3"/> our
     men said Phillip, was not along they were all from the lower end of Cumberland Co It is pretty
     quiet now, about the rebels coming over here, last week, every few days there were new reports
     of their coming, Uncle Daniel &amp; Jacob Lehman were down at <orig reg="Shippensburg"
      >Shippenburg</orig> last Sunday the meeting was there, this Sunday coming it is at our
     Schoolhouse, now I have written all that I can think of that might interest, and perhaps more,</p>

    <p>will close but yet say a few words more concerning our eternal welfare which is of far more
     value than all these passing events, Yet when I look to myself I have very little to say, and
     feel that I need to be <orig reg="admonished">admonishd</orig> myself, rather than to admonish
     others, and all the encouragement, I have for myself &amp; others is to be given up
     rightly, and to be humble and nothing in our own estimation, So that Gods Spirit may work and
     dictate for us<pb n="4"/> poor short sighted creatures, Oh that we might be given up as tools
     in the Lords hands, and not choose for ourselves, For we must so often see that ours ways are
     not his ways,</p>

    <p>and we must acknowledge, when all goes according to the desires of the flesh that the Inner
     man is weakened and the soul suffers loss, Oh when we look at the reality of our being here and
     the uncertainty of things belonging to this life should we not be willing to forsake our all,
     and alone cling to him who is mighty &amp; powerful, to save to the uttermost if we put our
     trust in him, and why should we not, when there is no other to save from utter distruction,</p>

    <p>No more at present, ever remaining your Mother</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>My love to you all Let us ever remember each other at the throne of grace</salute>
     <signed/>
     <seg type="postscript">
      <name type="recipient">A &amp; C Miller</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
