<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6503"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6503">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller,
     January 13, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, january 13 1863</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6503</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501631</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Catherine and Amos Miller, January 13, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to catherine and amos miller, january 13 1863</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-01-13">1863-01-13</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Church/Religious Activity</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6503T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter Eliza R. Stouffer describes the health of family and friends, and discusses
     her belief that one should trust in religion and God.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-01-13">January 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg, Pa.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Children</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I seat myself to pen you an answer to your letter, Casie, we made out it was your own hand
     write which we were glad to see. yet it was more than I expected you could do, which surely
     shows an <orig reg="improvement">improvment</orig> in your health, for which we should truly
     feel thankful as you say for such great blessings, We are also all well. Papa's health is a
     good deal better than it had been seems to be pretty well relieved from his long standing cold,
     thinks the syrup I made him has done him a great deal of good, we intend going up to see Mother
     this week yet if the weather is not too bad. Our Barometer gives good satisfaction so far, are
     all pleased with it, I do not Know why the letters do not reach you in due time Emma wrote one
     on friday evening took it in on saturday morning before day light, the Post master <pb n="2"
     />said it would go in the first train, thinking Jackson would get it, when at Market Papa had
     also send one to me before I left which should have been there on Tuesday or Wednesday, we
     generally get yours the same day they are put in, when you write again name the No-of your Box
     perhaps that is the cause, for they think it is not here, When you see any of Davids tell them
     if they would like to have our <unclear>helacipede</unclear> and would set a day, when they
     would be at the station to receive it. we would send it any time,-</p>

    <p>Our neighbors and friends are generally well, with few exceptions Molly Laufman is much the
     same, also <unclear>Giny</unclear> Abannon, sister Leah is better was in town the day I came
     home, Mary Stoner is better we were there after meeting, the Dr calls it Neuralgia, it is
     nearly all in the eyes it was only in one the day before we <pb n="3"/>were there it generally
     comes in the evening, Lizzie, Abners wife <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> up intends staying a
     few days,</p>

    <p>About the babys <orig reg="breast">breats</orig> feeding is something I never saw myself, but
     have heard of such cases before, I think the little book called the Ladies Companion says
     something about it. I would not think that it could be <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>
     very serious, and think greasing them a little to soften them would be good. should it get bad,
     The Dr advice would then be best, and if you have not suck enough I think too, the bottle would
     be best as you certainly must be weak, and it would be a <orig reg="benefit">benifit</orig> to
     you, to gain strength faster with this will close, and commit you, and all, to the mercy of
     God, and his tender care, which he has again shown so bountiful, toward us, &amp; you, Let
     us strive to adore him, and appreciate his goodness, and his love <pb n="4"/>May the good Lord,
     bless us with Thankful hearts, and willing hearts to be led by his spirit is my wish and desire
     for us all if I know myself, My love to you all also to Davids I did not write to them yet
     since I came home, If spared will write when I get back from Loudon</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>from your Mother</salute>
     <signed/>
     <seg type="postscript">Write when ever convenient hope you can read this as it was <orig
       reg="written">writen</orig> in a hurry <name type="recipient">A &amp; C Miller</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
