<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8040"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8040">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: William Seibert to Simon Cameron,
                    May 14, 1858</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county william seibert to simon cameron, may 14 1858</title>
        <author>Seibert, William</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8040</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501678</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: William Seibert to Simon Cameron, May 14, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county william seibert to simon cameron, may 14 1858</title>
            <author>William Seibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Seibert to Simon Cameron,
                            14 May 1858, Simon Cameron Papers, Dauphin County Historical Society,
                            Reel 3</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Historical Society of Dauphin County, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-05-14">1858-05-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8040T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Seibert offers a land deal to Cameron.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-05-14">May 14th--1858</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><abbr expan="Honorable">Honr</abbr> Simon Cameron<lb/>Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>It is with some difficulty that I presume to address you- but your known and
                    established character as a truly benevolent man, is as well known as that you
                    are Senator at Washington from the state of Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>I, too, have tried in a smaller way to benefit my fellow beings by acts of
                    kindness--and <hi rend="underline">now</hi> many of them have left me to get
                    through as well as I can- This has placed me in a position that is anything but
                    agreeable in a pecuniary view- Yet light is dawning in the distance, if I can
                    find a <hi rend="underline">friend</hi> who will stand by me for a short time,
                    as the following<pb n="2"/>facts will I think fully show.</p>
                <p>I have a brother who has been operating in Western Country, he took the place a
                    draft of which I send you - some two or three years ago. at twenty eight
                    thousand dollars- all of which is paid except about four thousand dollars. This
                    must be <hi rend="underline">now</hi> paid before he can get <hi
                        rend="underline">the deed</hi>- In June 1856 he <orig reg="tried"
                    >tryed</orig> it at public sale as you will see--Section <abbr expan="Number"
                        >No.</abbr> 1 3 acres 16 P. he sold for 160 dollars per acre, <abbr
                        expan="Section Number">Sect No.</abbr> 2 he had bid up to 150 per acre, and
                    withdrew it--he took the land at 200- per acre <abbr expan="although"
                    >altho</abbr> it did not stand him the one fourth of that amount - yet he
                    thought it was going too low and stopped the sale. The square opposite <abbr
                        expan="Number">No.</abbr> 36 and not marked, belongs to an other person and
                    he asks 1000. dollars per acre for it.</p>
                <pb n="3"/>
                <p>besides this my <orig reg="brother's">brothers</orig> friends advised him to <hi
                        rend="underline">hold on</hi>, he would get a good price for it- if he kept
                    it a few years longer - he took this advice, and now see, he would have done
                    better to have made then a clean and sure profit -and placed himself in a
                    position to meet panic times-- That <abbr expan="Brother">Br</abbr> P.W. Seibert
                    is as noble a speciman of humanity as can be found- he now proposes to me to
                    give me the one half of the whole if I can raise the 4000 dollars for eighteen
                    months, that we will go on to Lafayette directly after harvest- lay out the 140
                    acres. a little different from the plan before- sell on one tenth <hi
                        rend="underline">cash</hi>- <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on balance. with one tenth
                    additional of the principal yearly, for 4 years by giving these terms, he think
                    we can sell the 140 acres yet unsold at 150 per acre - making 21,000<pb n="4"
                    />ten <orig reg="percent">per cent</orig> on this would be 2,100. And
                        <unclear>put</unclear> on balance 18,900 1 year -<unclear>1134</unclear>
                    then at the end of the first year ten <orig reg="percent">per cent</orig> on
                    18,900 would be 1890/5124 making the amount payable. To cover draw back, the
                    Judgement on the balance might be sold -and would be at a sacrifice <orig
                        reg="until">untill</orig> the 4,000 borrowed would be paid--to release the
                    property.</p>
                <p>But here you will ask what security can you give me--that you will secure the
                    4000- dollars-now required. <abbr expan="Brother">Br</abbr> has the property now
                    in his possession draws the rent for it and he would willingly give the
                    Judgement on his interest in the place, and as soon as the 4000 was paid, and
                    deed recorded, it would be perfectly safe or I propose giving you a mortgage or
                    Judgement on 920 acres of land in Stark County Indiana unimproved part of it my
                    brother bought 3 or 4 years ago &amp; <unclear>handed</unclear> at 4 dollars
                    per acre- he says it is now worth 20 dollars per acre- or will be as soon as the
                    Pittsburg-Fort Wayne and Chicago<pb n="5"/>Railroad is completed- which is now
                    done as far as the land for <unclear>burden carry</unclear>. The above Railroad
                    runs through the land- The land is in one body and lays in this form [drawing
                    here] The dotted part is timber the balance <unclear>price</unclear>- The whole
                    lies in section 16 and 21 in Township 34 North Range 1 West Stark County Indiana
                    one mile from a new Town called Groverstown on the Railroad- Should you favor me
                    in this matter- you will be perfectly secure- and confer an obligation- that
                    will be remembered while life shall last- Where <abbr expan="Brother">Br</abbr>
                    went into this matter Hezikah Easton was his firm and fast friend- but adversity
                    overtook Easton and now his name would not go for 40 dollars- let alone 4,000.</p>
                <pb n="6"/>
                <p>The deed for the Land 920 acres, is in the Clerk's office of Stark <abbr
                        expan="County">Co</abbr> Indiana- I will write on and have it mailed to me-
                    and should you incline to favor me either directly or indirectly I will forward
                    the deed to Washington - to have the Mortgage or Judgement written.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours with Respect</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> Seibert</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">N. B. There is no <orig reg="lien">lein</orig> in any
                        form against the 920 acres and the deed for the whole is direct from the
                        State of Indiana the 240 acres <abbr expan="Brother">Br</abbr> paid 4 per
                        acre for, the State made him the deed as the claimant had not received his
                            deed--<abbr expan="William Seibert">WmS</abbr></seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
