<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8504"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8504">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: S. G. Lane to Edward McPherson,
                    October 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county s g lane to edward mcpherson, october 1860</title>
        <author>Lane, S. G.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8504</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501686</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: S. G. Lane to Edward McPherson, October 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county s g lane to edward mcpherson, october 1860</title>
            <author>S. G. Lane</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: S. G. Lane to Edward McPherson,
                            October 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-10">1860-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, National Government, State Government, Women,
                        Unionism/Secession</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8504T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Samuel G. Lane forwards to McPherson a letter written by his cousin, S. L.
                    Hayman. In the letter Hayman expresses gratitude toward McPherson and comments
                    on North Carolina politics and his place as a "Yankee" in southern society.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-10-06"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 6th 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Raleigh</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>D<hi rend="super">r</hi> Sam G Lane!<lb/>Dear Cousin!</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been <hi rend="underline">intending</hi> to write to you ever since I left
                    Pennsylvania, but have been prevented by sickness and <unclear>close </unclear>
                    confinement to the store -- I <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> your letter
                    last week &amp; thank you truly for the courtesy and kindness of feeling it
                    manifested you are not mistaken in regard to my feelings toward my friends
                        <unclear>of</unclear> the good old Keystone" and a letter from home is
                    indeed green spot in the cheerless <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> deserts of North Carolina.</p>

                <p>Immediately on receipt of yours I wrote - at considerable length - to Fitz Hugh
                    stating every instance of my conclusion with <pb n="2"/>McPherson and asking as
                    a personal favor his reconsideration of the matter. I have not since heard from
                    Fitz. H. but from previous knowledge of the man I fear he will not be likely to
                    change his position if he has taken it against <abbr expan="McPherson"
                    >McP-----</abbr> Feeling as I do under great obligation to <abbr
                        expan="McPherson">McP.</abbr> I should be very sorry to be made innocently
                    the cause of anything sending to injure him -- please explain this to him that
                    he may not think me ungrateful for his many acts of kindness towards me. had <hi
                        rend="underline">I</hi> any influence in Franklin <abbr expan="County"
                    >Co.</abbr> I should certainly give it in his favor.</p>

                <p>Political excitement is running high and all our banks have refused to discount
                    till after the election. Great financial troubles <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <pb n="3"/>of Lincoln's election. Breckenridge will most likely carry this state
                    though Bell will run him very close. Douglas will not poll a large vote as his
                    supporters are very few &amp; weak-- I have been frequently <hi
                        rend="underline">questioned</hi> about my political views, and have
                    expressed myself far more strongly in favor of the northern institutions than
                    when in <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penna</abbr>. There is far more freedom of
                        <hi rend="underline">sentiment</hi> here than I supposed and I know several
                    persons who take the <hi rend="underline">N. Y. Tribune and read Helper</hi>,
                    though a <hi rend="underline">violent</hi> republican would not be tolerated and
                    voting for Lincoln would be considered a <hi rend="underline">capital</hi>
                    offence. Should <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> Carolina, Alabama, &amp;
                    Mississippi secede and an attempt be made to enforce Lincoln's administration,
                        <abbr expan="North">N.</abbr> Carolina will certainly join the 'southern
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>under</unclear> no other <pb n="4"/>circumstances.</p>

                <p>I am not very much pleased with Raleigh. <orig reg="It">it</orig> is a remarkably
                    slow &amp; <unclear>aristocratic</unclear> place, been confined to the store
                    from 6 A.M. to 11 P.M. I have seen very little of society - and - though <hi
                        rend="underline">noticed</hi> by several persons of position I shall mingle
                    very little in it as I am still so much of a <hi rend="underline">Yankee</hi> to
                    submit to <hi rend="underline">patronage</hi>. I do not think under present
                    circumstances it <hi rend="underline">would</hi> do to trouble McPherson though
                    I should like very much to have a letter from him to Branch. I feel I may not be
                    able to <unclear>retain</unclear>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> situation long, as I have been very sick nearly ever since my
                    arrival and am too weak to attend to business as it should be done. Please do
                    not mention that Miss <unclear>Wirginan</unclear> promised to express <pb n="5"
                    />her influence with some of her merchant friends of <abbr expan="Baltimore"
                    >Bal</abbr> in my favor, so shall I have slight prospect there. A few years ago
                    I would have been too proud to use such means but now I am only so glad to
                    accept of <hi rend="underline">anything</hi> likely to <unclear>secure</unclear>
                    me a good situation. Ah Well! <orig reg="What">what</orig> vile uses may we come
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/></p>

                <p>I have heard lately from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; Anna, but not one word from
                    any one at Mount <unclear>Al</unclear>. Excuse the haste with which this is
                    evidently written my time is completely taken up. I am obliged to write as now
                    at the store -- subject to constant interrupting. Write to me again shortly. I
                    shall <hi rend="underline">always</hi> be glad to hear from you. With love to
                        <pb n="6"/>cousin Kate. The Dr. &amp; Kate <unclear>Hay</unclear></p>



                <closer>
                    <salute>In haste, Affectionately <abbr expan="Your">Yr</abbr> Cousin</salute>
                    <signed>B. Lane Hayman<lb/>Care P.F. Pescud <unclear>Druggery</unclear>,
                        Raleigh, N.C.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dear Sir:<lb/> I send you <unclear>Sam</unclear> H's
                        answer to my letter, that you may see I fulfilled my promise, &amp; that
                        the young man is grateful for your kindness. I congratulate you upon the
                        result of the election, and am proud that Franklin did her duty to her
                        favorite. Of course "The Times" takes much credit to herself for inflating
                        your "<hi rend="underline">balloon</hi>," and launching it into the open
                        skies. The only compensation I ask is a seat in the <unclear>ca</unclear> (I
                        don't mean the Lincoln <abbr expan="Cabinet">Cab.</abbr>)<lb/>
                        <abbr expan="Respectfully">Resp.</abbr> Yours, <lb/>S. G. Lane <name
                            type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Edward">Ed.</abbr> McPherson</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
