<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8503"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8503">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: S. L. Russell to Edward McPherson,
                    July 31, 1858</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county s l russell to edward mcpherson, july 31 1858</title>
        <author>Russell, S. L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8503</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501685</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: S. L. Russell to Edward McPherson, July 31, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county s l russell to edward mcpherson, july 31 1858</title>
            <author>S. L. Russell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: S. L. Russell to Edward
                            McPherson, 31 July 1858, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers,
                            Box 47</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-07-31">1858-07-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, State Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8503T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Russell extends an invitation to McPherson to visit and offers up commentary on
                    the upcoming election in which McPherson is running. Russell appears confident
                    that McPherson will win.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-07-31">July 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1858</date>
                        <name type="place">M.Connellsburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Having left home on tuesday last to attend to some business in Franklin <abbr
                        expan="County">Co.</abbr> I did not review your letter until yesterday
                    afternoon-- it having been forwarded to me here by Mrs <abbr expan="Russell"
                    >R.</abbr></p>

                <p>I regret to learn that you have almost given up the idea of visiting Bedford
                    during the present season unless in the event of your winning the nomination for
                    Congress. I think however, that that event is likely to occur and that I will
                    have the pleasure to meet you there. The much felt vacancy in the kitchen
                    department has been filled and <hi rend="underline">we</hi> have got to
                    housekeeping and will be much gratified to have you dine or take a cup of tea
                    with us. John Stevens I think or rather hope will go to Bedford next week. Why
                    cannot you come up with him? Since our return home the health of Mrs. <abbr
                        expan="Russell">R</abbr> and myself has been very good.
                    <unclear>The</unclear> trip was of great benefit to both of us. It was a
                    delightful trip.</p>

                <p>I am told here that the Fulton <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> conference will go
                    for you which with the votes of them from Adams will give you six votes on the
                    first ballot and if those six will stand firm through a few ballots I believe
                    that you will get enough from Bedford or Juniata to nominate you. If the
                    Conferees from Bedford find that they cannot have Jordan nominated -- and I do
                    not think that they will be <pb n="2"/>long in ascertaining that -- they will I
                    feel confident vote for you. The <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> Convention for
                    Bedford <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> does not meet until next week but I take
                    it for granted that the conferees will be <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> for Jordan as I do
                    not think that Mr. King or his friends have made any exertion whatever.</p>

                <p>Since my return home I have ever so much engaged in my office and in preparing
                    for housekeeping that I have paid but little attention to politics. The contest
                    this fall is going to be a warm one particularly in those districts where
                    Lecompton Democrats are re-nominated.</p>

                <p>The nomination of John M. Read appears to give satisfaction <orig
                        reg="everywhere">every where</orig> and I have but little doubt of his
                    election.</p>

                <p>Remember me to your mother, Aunt Maria &amp; Uncle Sam. I had a letter from
                    Uncle a few days ago and will write to him after I get home.</p>

                <p>When I was in <abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> York Mr Mehaffy &amp; Cousin
                    Elizabeth called to see us and we intended to return their visit the next day
                    but there came on a storm of rain which prevented our getting out before we left
                    the city.</p>

                <p>Let me hear from you again soon &amp; if I can aid you in any way command my
                    services.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Truly<lb/>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>S. L. Russell</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">E. McPherson, Esq.</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
