<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8513"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8513">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: James Johnston to Edward McPherson,
                    March 21, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county james johnston to edward mcpherson, march 21 1859</title>
        <author>Johnston, James</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8513</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501695</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: James Johnston to Edward McPherson, March 21, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county james johnston to edward mcpherson, march 21 1859</title>
            <author>James Johnston</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: James Johnston to Edward
                            McPherson, Edward McPherson Papers, Library of Congress.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-03-21">1859-03-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Economy, Family, Home Front, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8513T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>James Johnston remembers Edward McPherson's parents and talks of the value of
                    friendships. Johnston also compliments McPherson's pamphlets and advises him on
                    the importance of constituents.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
       

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-03-21">March 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1859</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Ned,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I would have answered your letter of the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> instant
                    immediately, but for a bad cold and sore throat, which made me somewhat
                    depressed in spirits, and afforded me a reasonable excuse for laziness, and
                    indulgence in my propensity towards somnolency. "Blessed be the man, who wanted
                    sleep for it covers me all over like a blanket" says Sancho, and so say I, for
                    really the pleasant part of my life is passed in that state of oblivion. If I
                    had only a pair of round, white arms about my neck to assist my
                    <unclear>dreams</unclear> in taking a pleasant direction, it would be a great
                    gratification. Circumstances forbid <del hand="h1">at last</del> this pleasure
                    to me, but not to you. Let me recommend the prescription of dewy lips, and white
                    arms to you. They will lift your depression of spirits, and will fill that void
                    in your domestic affections, which has been made by the onward march of time,
                    and the inevitable decrees of the fates.</p>

                <p>I remember your father and mother, for I had the pleasure of an introduction to
                    Both. You and your father resembled one another, while there was a likeness
                    between your mother and your brother William. I sympathize with you in the loss
                    of your parents. I have no doubt that you were a pet of your mother, for I
                    remember the anxiety she manifested when you were lying sick in Harrisburg.
                    There is nothing in this world equal in affection and fidelity to a good mother.
                    Our fathers discard us; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> betray and desert us; our brothers and
                    sisters abuse and cheat us; our children prove bad and ungrateful, and yet <orig
                        reg="through">thro'</orig> all the vicissitude of life a good mother clings
                    to us with all the tenacity of a loving woman and all the fidelity of a bold,
                    brave man. The loss of mothers <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> be well
                    supplied and <add hand="h1" place="inline">yet</add> perhaps, it could be better
                    for young persons, if they were separated from their mothers at an early age,
                    and would never see them until permanently established in life.</p>

                <p>So far from forgetting you am I that I cherish your remembrace with feelings of
                    admiration and kindness. I do not wish to forget or alienate friends like you,
                    for in passing <orig reg="through">thro'</orig> this world I begin <pb n="2"/>
                    more and more deeply the necessities of love and friendship. They support us
                    under adversity, and save us from the evil influences of the world. Many of my
                    old friends are dead, and I am not inclined to forget the few, who remain. I
                    believe that there is sympathy between you and me, and I am more inclined to
                    cultivate it than to allow it to fall into nothing. I am not doing <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig> of much importance, and have not for some
                    time. I tried <orig reg="through">thro'</orig> a friend to get a situation in
                    the <orig reg="Cincinnati">Cincinnatti</orig>, or St. Louis press, but he tried
                    in vain, for all situations are filled. I am not very anxious to leave <abbr
                        expan="Pennsylvania">Penna</abbr>, but I owe some money, and I am
                    excessively anxious to pay my debts. I will help upon the farm during the Spring
                    &amp; Summer, and in the fall will, perhaps, try my hand at teaching a
                    school. This will be a new business to me, and I detest the idea of it, but <hi
                        rend="underline">necessitas non habet legem</hi>. I mention these things,
                    because you inquire what I am doing. I am doing no harm, and am doing no good.
                    My existence for some time past has been that of indifference and nonchalance.
                    My vessel is high &amp; dry in a sand-bank, &amp; I lack the levers to
                    put her afloat. </p>

                <p>I received your pamphlets, and read them with pleasure. The one <del hand="h1"
                        >one</del> on Individual liberty <del hand="h1">was</del> very good. It <del
                        hand="h1">was</del> is well written and displays more erudition than I
                    thought you possessed. I trust you will continue your literary <orig
                        reg="labors">labours</orig>, for I sincerely believe that you are able to
                    attain to some eminence in the Republic of Letters. I congratulate you on your
                    election to Congress, and trust you will be able to maintain you position <orig
                        reg="through">thro</orig> a long course of years. Your habits will protect
                    you against the <unclear>temptations</unclear> of the Capital, and your
                    political knowledge <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> fail to gain you an
                    enviable notoriety. Attend closely to your own constituents, and <orig
                        reg="nevermind">never mind</orig> devoting yourself to the whole Union.</p>

                <p>I am very fond of <orig reg="traveling">travelling</orig> and would like to see
                    you; but I assure you that the <hi rend="underline">res pecunia</hi> totally
                    forbids me to pay any kind of visits. Pardon me for not answering your letter
                    the instant it was received, as I ought to have done, &amp; believe me</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Sincere Friend</salute>
                    <signed>James Johnston</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
