<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8542"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8542">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: H. G. McPherson to E., May 3, 1858</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county h g mcpherson to e , may 3 1858</title>
        <author>McPherson, H. G.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8542</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501724</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: H. G. McPherson to E., May 3, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county h g mcpherson to e , may 3 1858</title>
            <author>H. G. McPherson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: H. G. McPherson to E., 3 May
                            1858, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1858</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-05-03">1858-05-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8542T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>H. G. McPherson writes to her niece, E., of her removal to Mrs. T.'s former home
                    in Gettysburg and of her son Edward's devotion to her. She also mentions drastic
                    changes in the town of Gettysburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
        

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-05-03">May 3<hi rend="super">rd</hi>--</date>
                        <name type="place">Gettysburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p><orig reg="Many">many</orig> thanks to you my dear friend for your kind letter of
                    condolence. It is the first I have received from any absent one except my dear
                    children, and other immediate relatives. I have thought much about you since my
                    removal to this part of the town where I have enjoyed so many happy hours in
                    intercourse with loved friends, and to a house so well suited in every respect
                    to my present situation, I am delighted with my new home and you may well
                    imagine me most comfortably placed in it, surrounded with the same plain <orig
                        reg="old-fashioned">old fashioned</orig> furniture of former years,
                    similarily arranged as at the old home down street. I feel quite contented
                    &amp; should be ungrateful if I was not, I have throughout all my trials of
                    affliction &amp; ill health for the last three years been mercifully and
                    kindly dealt with and now when permitted to step into this sweet little snug
                    home I feel doubly <add hand="h1" place="inline">so</add>, to my Heavenly Father
                    who has under all the circumstances provided so liberally for me. I wish you
                    could see how <orig reg="cozily">cosily</orig> I am fixed in your once happy
                    home, I have chosen your favorite seat in your little back parlor in the recess
                    by the window looking out on the alley, where you so frequently gave me the
                    kindest &amp; most cordial grettings. I like the house exceedingly &amp;
                    have never felt disposed to murmur or complain of the change. I am assured all
                    has been directed for the best. <orig reg="Of">of</orig> course it was painful
                    to resign <pb n="2"/> the long loved home, of 47 years standing, but I felt <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">it</add> a duty and was willing to submit to all
                    the melancholy changes, in my situation without the <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">least</add> repining: it is very sad indeed to realize that I
                    have <add hand="h1" place="inline">lost</add> so excellent a husband, yet I want
                    to feel cheerful and to remember he is not lost, but only gone before. I wish so
                    much you would come to Gettysburg &amp; make me a visit and if you will, I
                    shall promise if I <add hand="h1" place="inline">am</add> well enough to return
                    it in due time. I feel very anxious to see York once more in my life. &amp;
                    have often regretted the many years of absence from it. Edward remains with me,
                    he proves to be a most precious son to me, he is devotedly attentive &amp;
                    affectionate in all his feelings toward me he has taken his fathers place in
                    contributing to my comforts and home pleasures, he is so pleasant &amp;
                    cheerful that the domestic circle is very agreeable I do wish so much you would
                    come up, I have so many things to talk about, confidential talks, such as we
                    formerly enjoyed in bygone days: I want you to participate the pleasure of this
                    sweet little home. I like the <orig reg="neigborhood">neighbourhood</orig> very
                    much <orig reg="everybody">every body</orig> is so kind &amp; plain just
                    suited to my taste, we visit wearing our sun bonnets, without carrying card
                    cases &amp; remaining but a few minutes. I never can fall into those
                    ridiculous customs. There is so much style &amp; fashion here now among some
                    people <del hand="h1">here</del>
                    <del hand="h1">now</del>, it is scarcely like <abbr expan="Gettysburg">G-</abbr>
                    I am surprised to observe, how much the people &amp; things have <orig
                        reg="degenerated">degerated</orig>, in the past six or eight years.</p>

                <p>Our dear <orig reg="church">Church</orig>, is in a very lamentable &amp;
                    distracted state at present. I cannot go into detail now, there is so much to
                    communicate, I am too weak to write long letters, I have <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">been</add> obliged for two years to deputize <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">
                        <abbr expan="Edward">Edw</abbr>
                    </add> to attend to my correspondence he intended replying to your kind letter a
                    few days ago, but he went to Baltimore on business, &amp; I thought it would
                    be too long to wait for his return. <orig reg="So">so</orig> I concluded I would
                        <pb n="3"/> attempt some sort of a letter myself -- Mr
                    <unclear>Kouck's</unclear> family are very estimable, we all are on the most
                    sociable cordial terms, we often talk of <add hand="h1" place="inline">you</add>
                    &amp; I am sure if they knew I was writing to you they would desire to be
                    remembered to you, poor old <add hand="h1" place="inline">lady</add> is in
                    feeble health, she suffers from spinal disease. but is cheerful &amp;
                    stepping about the house. O! do my dear Mrs. T-- come up right soon we shall all
                    be so glad to meet you again give my love to my sister, &amp; say to her I
                    shall be glad to have her come with you, you can come so nicely together
                    &amp; <add hand="h1" place="inline">spend</add> a week or two with us. I
                    think it will be charming I have not seen Anna, since I received your letter but
                    have <orig reg="inquired">enquired</orig> for her, she is quite well &amp;
                    very happy in the height of enjoyment with her young friends. <orig reg="Please"
                        >please</orig> excuse this poor dull epistle.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>very truly yours</salute>
                    <signed>H. G. McPherson</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">remember me kindly to the Missess Durkee. Mrs. McGreary
                        is very well &amp; would desire her love too. she frequently speaks of
                        them with affection. she is truly a sweet lovely woman, she is like a
                        daughter in her treatment toward me. I love her very much indeed she has
                        three sweet little girls, they often run up to see "Aunty Phersy" as they
                        call me.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
