<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8543"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8543">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, February
                    16, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, february 16 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8543</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501725</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, February 16, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, february 16 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 16
                            February 1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-02-16">1859-02-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>

            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8543T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. writes of Cousin C's illness, but mostly discusses Edward McPherson's mother's
                    recent death. She also mentions the marriage of Lizzie Law and the declining
                    health of Jane Boggs.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
         
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-02-16"><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 16<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>Many thanks Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr> for your letter received in due
                    time &amp; which should have been replied to before this, but your Cousin C
                    -- is still <orig reg="upstairs">up stairs</orig> &amp; of course, I have
                    many more interruptions than usual &amp; my time more fully occupied. She is
                    better in some respects, but continues very weak, &amp; has for some days
                    suffered much from nervous depression. She is however better <orig reg="today"
                        >to day</orig> &amp; has been sewing a little. Your letter, while it
                    saddened our hearts so much, was very satisfactory, for you told me nearly all I
                    wanted to ask you respecting our dear Aunt, who had been so continually
                    connected with us, all our lives, &amp; with whom our <orig
                        reg="intercourse">inter course</orig> has always been so sweet &amp;
                    pleasant. I wrote to Kate as <orig reg="soon as">soonas</orig> she returned to
                    Hagerstown &amp; she replied to me <pb n="2"/> in a long &amp;
                    interesting letter just after I heard from <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >you</add> But one thing has grieved us -- neither of you have said whether your
                    Mother thought or spoke of us during those last sad hours. You know it is very
                    gratifying to be remembered at such a time, while you can make all allowances
                    for such an omission under the circumstances. I thought it probable you both
                    might have forgotten to mention it. Truly, I cannot conceive of a more painful,
                    trying situation for you to be placed in, than you were, the evening of your
                    arrival in Gettysburg. I wonder it did not make you both sick.-- I am thankful
                    however it passed without any ill effects &amp; that you were comforted by
                    the sympathy of so many attached friends as your dear Mother had, few have so
                    large a circle, for she made them wherever she went &amp; retained them to
                    the last. She was greatly admired in her youth, &amp; I think, was equally
                    as much so in later years, though in a different way. However pleasant &amp;
                    gratifying this may be, it is a <pb n="3"/> small matter compared to the
                    satisfaction of knowing, that she bore the image of Christ, having been "made
                    meet through his blood, for the inheritance of the saints in light," &amp;
                    removed from the church militant to the church triumphant where I trust, strong
                    &amp; divine grace she will be permitted to welcome her dear children. "One
                    thing is needful" My dear <abbr expan="Edward">Ed.</abbr> &amp; God is
                    teaching you this lesson by these sad dispensations nothing else will avail in
                    the last, trying hour. We all approve of your plan to continue at housekeeping -
                    it is just what I thought you would do -- you will be more comfortable than
                    boarding, having such a trusty, faithful person as Tresy. By the time you
                    receive this, Lizzie Law will in all probability have taken the most important
                    step of her life. You have never spoken of it to me. What do you think about it?
                    I wish I could feel entirely satisfied in relation to it, however, she is so
                    entirely confident of happiness herself, that no one else need disturb
                    themselves. She is so very dear to us, that we cannot help <pb n="4"/> feeling a
                    more than common anxiety when her happiness for life is concerned. I have had
                    much this winter to keep me anxious about some of my friends -- Aunt Robinson
                    has been very delicate for some weeks past &amp; a letter from <abbr
                        expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> yesterday, tells me that my much loved young
                    cousin Jane Bogg, is declining very rapidly -- her health has been delicate for
                    more than two years, but for the last month, it has become evident that she will
                    not be much longer with us. But she is ripening for Heaven &amp; this is our
                    comfort. I am very glad your Aunt Polly can be with you, you would be so
                    desolate. Your cousin C- desires me to say (in which we all join), that she
                    wants you to come to see us as soon as you can. We had a letter from Mittie a
                    short time ago, she is very much pleased with Chicago. My love to your Aunt -
                    &amp; much love also to Mrs. McCreery &amp; say how much I would like to
                    see her. I see Mr. Van Wycke is still with you. I cannot realize that there is
                    now but yourself to receive a message of love -- O how sad-- Do write us soon
                    &amp; accept our united love--</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever yours</salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
