<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8550"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8550">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, October 1,
                    1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, october 1 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8550</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501732</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, October 1, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, october 1 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 1 October
                            1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-10-01">1859-10-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualty, Family, Home Front,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8550T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. expresses concern about the Presbyterian church in Gettysburg due to the
                    disruptive presence of Mr. Van Wycke and defends Christianity. In addition, E.
                    urges Edward McPherson to get married.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
          

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-10-01"><abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 1<hi rend="super"
                                >st</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Thorndale</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edw<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr>-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your last letter a few days ago. It was my intention last week to
                    write an apology for the rather trifling letter I had sent you, for so it seemed
                    to me, after reading yours, but for a week past I have been suffering with a
                    boil <del hand="h1">i</del>on my head, behind the left ear &amp; did not, of
                    course, feel very comfortable. Miss Ellen's remedies have proved <orig
                        reg="effective">effectual</orig>, &amp; I hope it will entirely
                    disappear in a day or two. I am really heart sick at the state of things in your
                    church, yet, cannot but hope, that the great Head of the Church will overrule
                    even all these discouraging &amp; disheartening circumstances <pb n="2"/>for
                    his own Glory, for the ultimate peace &amp; spiritual welfare of that
                    portion of his vineyard. I grieve over it the more, because of the pernicious
                    influence it must exert, over the young, &amp; those who are not professors
                    of religion, yourself especially, but it must be remembered that the
                    inconsistencies &amp; unholy tempers of professed Christians, <del hand="h1"
                        >is</del> are not to be charged to religion, but either to their entire want
                    of it, or <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add> a lamentable declension, into
                    which they have fallen. Yet it is to these, the world will look in forming their
                    judgement, forgetting, the one only perfect example set forth to us in the
                    Gospel, who will judge us, not by what others have done or failed to do, but by
                    that law, which requires us to "repent &amp; believe" each for himself. I do
                    believe that one of the greatest stumbling blocks in the way of the salvation of
                    men is, the inconsistencies of professing Christians, &amp; it is this
                    thought that affects my heart so deeply, &amp; I should sink in utter
                    depair, were it not for the blessed truth that the "Lord reigns" &amp; will
                        <orig reg="fulfill">fulfil</orig> all his glorious promises concerning his
                    Church, <pb n="3"/>against which, all the powers of Earth &amp; Hell cannot
                    eventually prevail. I trust you know many, who by their walk &amp;
                    conversation, recommend the Religion of the Lord Jesus to you -- you must not
                    expect them to be perfect, but wherever you see a habitual aim to live as
                    becomes the gospel, follow them, <del hand="h1">in as</del> so far as they
                    follow Christ &amp; manifest his spirit.</p>

                <p>My letters from home this week say, it is not probable now, that we shall leave
                    Frederick this winter, the house will be completed but, <del hand="h1">has</del>
                    plastering not dry enough to render it safe for us to venture in. I regret it
                    chiefly because we will not have you with us as we hoped. And I do think it will
                    be crying shame if you do not pay us a visit before going to Washington-- You
                    never <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> away so long before. I was thinking last
                    week you might ride over here to see me during my visit &amp; even yet, the
                    ladies will be very happy to see you &amp; for fear you may be <hi
                        rend="underline">bashful</hi>, we propose that you bring with you that
                    mysterious <hi rend="underline">one</hi>, who knows them better than you do, to
                    introduce you -- perhaps it may be an old acquaintance of mine <pb n="4"/>and
                    then I shall be doubly pleased. I expect to leave here next Monday week for
                        <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> &amp; go with the wedding party as
                    far as the Junction-- then <abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> Mr Peck &amp;
                    myself go on to Baltimore &amp; they proceed to Niagara Falls. I almost envy
                    them that delightful trip, at this glorious season of the year. I hope when you
                    go under such interesting circumstances, you will choose the Fall or Spring
                    &amp; take me to matronize the party. I want to go now <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">more</add> than before. It gratifies me much to hear of the
                        <orig reg="favorable">favourable</orig> opinions given of your address All
                    here felt just so about it, but we could not express it in such flattering
                    language. Now do lay politics aside for a day at least, &amp; ride over
                    here; I want to see you &amp; introduce you to my Thorndale friends. But I
                    must stop or I shall tire you out, although I have not taken up all the points
                    in your last letter -- yet I must make one assertion before closing, that
                    bachelorism is your <hi rend="underline">sin</hi> &amp; not your misfortune,
                    for you lords of the Creation are <hi rend="underline">prime movers</hi> in the
                    affair, while we poor maidens dare only wait &amp; <hi rend="underline">wait
                        to be asked</hi>. My love to all friends-</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">The <orig reg="borders">boarders</orig> will all leave
                        early next week &amp; we will have a quiet house -- I forgot to tell
                        you, Nannie had gone to Louisiana.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
