<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8564"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8564">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                    June 21, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, june 21 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8564</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501746</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, June 21, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, june 21 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                            21 June 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-06-21">1860-06-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals,
                        National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8564T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In writing to her brother, Edward McPherson, Kate Scott talks of the health and
                    travel of friends and family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-06-21">June 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 18/60</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I imagine you are wondering what - has become of me. I have been silent so long.
                    I can plead no excuse but my old and bad habit of Procrastination, I can get
                    very few letters written, I seem to be always busy through the day and in the
                    evening am out or have company, and I determined as it is a rainy evening I
                    would devote it to letter writing. We are still in confusion with our building
                    but- hope soon to be over the worst. We have had a very uncomfortable time and
                    also very incon <pb n="2"/>venient but I think we will be repaid when it is done
                    it will add so much to our comfort and convenience. I see by the papers Congress
                    will soon adjourn, you will then be at leisure and must come to see us. I see
                    you are moving about a little making speeches already <hi rend="underline">if it
                        were</hi> only for <hi rend="underline">the Union Party</hi> it <hi
                        rend="underline">would</hi> be <hi rend="underline">all right</hi>. I cannot
                    be a Republican. Mary Emma was here yesterday looking remarkably well, as she
                    grows older she grows handsomer, <del hand="h1">There ever</del> a fine thing
                    isnt it. she had a charming trip both to <abbr expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi></abbr> and Pittsburg. They expect the bride and
                    groom next week I must try and get to see them. I wish you could see them in
                    Washington. Jinnie will not be home until they come from the Virginia Springs,
                    Nannie <add hand="h1" place="inline">Findley</add> is going to make her a visit
                    next week-- They have poor Mary <unclear>Shunk's</unclear> baby at January <pb
                        n="3"/> and are all perfectly devoted to it and would like to keep it but
                    Mrs <unclear>Shunk</unclear> claims it and will take it home on Saturday. I am
                    told it is like its Mother -- Poor Mary, her end was a sad one. Mary Alvey came
                    home two weeks ago, very much broken in health, she was very sick at her
                    Father's and Dr thinks if she had remained another week she would have died. she
                    looks dreadfully and was too unwell to travel but- would come home, he thinks
                    her symptoms are more favorable now. I wrote to Lizzie before she left <abbr
                        expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> but have not heard from her. I am afraid she
                    did not get the letter. I will write her a few lines <orig reg="tonight">to
                        night</orig>-- she promised to write me when she heard from Lizzie but she
                    has not done it--. I begged her to come to see us this summer but I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig>- know what her plans are. Write soon and let me know
                    when you will come to see us. Dr has <pb n="4"/> been complaining very much with
                    a pain in his back but is better <orig reg="today">to day</orig> I hope it- is
                    nothing serious. The children are well and grow very fast. Lillie is devoted to
                    school and learns very fast she reads quite well-- I must close and write a few
                    lines to Lizzie, write soon</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>Kate --</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Dr says if you have a copy of Sumner's speech please send
                        it to him he would like to see it, Mr <unclear>Heandy</unclear> is very
                        anxious to see it also.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
