<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8566"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8566">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                    August 21, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, august 21 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8566</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501748</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, August 21, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, august 21 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                            21 August 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-08-21">1860-08-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Family, Home Front, National Government, Patriotism, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8566T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Edward McPherson's sister, Kate Scott, mentions her preference for Democratic
                    candidates, complains of slow workmen, and shares news of friends and family.
                    She also notes that Edward's attention to politics is diverting his attentions
                    away from his friends and family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
          

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-08-21">August 21<hi rend="super">st</hi>/60</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> a paper from you this eve which informs me
                    of your <orig reg="whereabouts">where abouts</orig>. I had not heard of your
                    return to <abbr expan="Gettysburg">G--.</abbr> since your trip to <abbr
                        expan="New">N</abbr> York. We all regretted very much you could not make us
                    a visit hope you will very soon. You are so absorbed in politics you seem not to
                    have time for your friends. this ought-- not to be, there are so few of us left
                    and we ought to see more of each other. I had a long letter from sister from
                        <unclear>Altona</unclear> but do not know where she is now. I wanted her to
                    come here but, I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know whether she will or not we
                    are not fixed yet in our back building but -- could get- along. the workmen here
                    do try one's patience too much. I hardly know what to do <pb n="2"/>sometimes. I
                    get out of <orig reg="humor">humour</orig> with them might all have been done
                    long since, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> by the paper <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>
                    you are highly complimented and will likely be the Candidate again. I cannot
                    think you are on the right side. I am strong for Bell and Everett have just been
                    reading Crittendon's speech which pleases me mightily. We had a visit-- <del
                        hand="h1"/> Saturday from -- Professor Reynolds your old Teacher. he is
                    looking remarkably well and in fine spirits, he thinks I have changed very
                    little, he tells me he has quite a family <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> 8 children, he called
                    in yesterday and for sometime with Dr in the Office and talked <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    many things, he seems to be very much pleased with your course, he says there
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> three young men he feels very proud <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Robert
                    Clarkson, William Paxton and you. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I was so sorry to hear of
                    Miss Maria McClellen's death, she will be such a loss <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> her
                    sister and brothers. I sometimes think <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> going over to <abbr
                        expan="Gettysburg">G--.</abbr> for a day or two this fall <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    can't know yet. I still have a yearning after <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> place. I see you
                    have the gas in operation <pb n="3"/> You must feel quite grand.</p>

                <p>How long will you be in <abbr expan="Gettysburg">G--.</abbr> now. You are <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>kind</unclear> of passage. I now know where to find you. I enclose this
                    note you wished me to sign. the glasses arrived safely and are <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    and look very well. The children are very well. Lillie and Mae are tired of
                    vacation and wish school would commence. The William's have not got home yet.
                    Mary <hi rend="underline">Emma and</hi> her <hi rend="underline">Father
                    went</hi> to the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Springs, Nannie Findley went with them and
                    Cousin Nancy went to Jinnie's, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> all be home soon. It is late and
                    I will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to stop. Write soon again. Love to all for <del
                        hand="h1"/></p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>Kate ---</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
