<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8560"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8560">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                    February 20, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, february 20 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8560</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501742</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, February 20, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, february 20 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                            20 February 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-02-20">1860-02-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home
                        Front, Medicine/Hospitals, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8560T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kate Scott writes to her brother, Edward McPherson, concerning local news of
                    friends and family, including weddings, death, insanity, and travel.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
        

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-02-20"><abbr expan="February">Feb</abbr> 20<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi>/60.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am afraid you have been looking for a letter from me and have been disappointed
                    for some time. My intentions are the best -- in the world but I have a way of
                    putting off letter writing and it is wrong I know for I often neglect my friends
                    longer than I am aware of. We are all well and getting along in the usual way. I
                    spent a week with <hi rend="underline">Mary Emma</hi> lately, she was so lonely
                    she came in for me and could take no denial, so I got ready in a hurry and took
                    Norman and Lillie with me. I spent the time very pleasantly though at this
                    season the country is <pb n="2"/>lonely. Mr. Bailey from Pittsburg made them a
                    very unexpected visit while I was there. his son <unclear>McDonell</unclear> is
                    to be married about the first of June to Miss <unclear>Dalyele</unclear> and he
                    is anxious for them all to go over to the wedding. I think they will if nothing
                    serious in the meantime. Cousin Nancy is still with Jinnie who has a daughter
                    two weeks old, name Annie McDonell. You heard I suppose of the death of Mary
                        <unclear>Shunk</unclear>, her case was a most distressing one. She died a
                        <unclear>maniac</unclear>, leaving a daughter three weeks old, the only
                    child her friends are all in the deepest affliction, she was brought home and
                    interred beside her mother. Nannie is with Mr. L. now and has charge of the
                    babe. Have you heard <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from sister lately? I
                    feel anxious to know whether she has gone to Old Point yet. Mr.
                    <unclear>M</unclear> said in his last letter two or three weeks ago, they hoped
                    to <pb n="3"/>get off very soon, he sent me a check for a hundred dollars which
                    with the eighty he sent me last winter would <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >be</add> what was due up to first of May, but he has either made a mistake or
                    forgotten he has the money, at <unclear>1</unclear> percent-- I will mention it
                    to him when I write, I would have written before this but did not know whether
                    they had left the city or not. Do you know <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig>
                    of the Gettysburg Rail Road now? We hear rather doubtful talk here about it, Dr
                    was advised by a friend if he possibly could to sell the land but I imagine that
                    would be impossible if they are not doing any business. I hope it is not the
                    case for I would hate very much to lose the money -- let me know when you write
                    what you think. It is right hard to know what to do with money, <orig
                        reg="everything">every thing</orig> is rather uncertain. I suppose you were
                    greatly pleased at the election of a Speaker <pb n="4"/> we were all mighty glad
                    to see your statement in the Sun. We could not understand how you could do as
                    you were represented to have done. Mary Louisa <unclear>Schmebley</unclear> is
                    in town. She has been spending the winter in Montgomery <abbr expan="County"
                    >Co.</abbr> and was in Washington. Was at the House and saw you but you did not
                    see her. I hope you are not too much engaged to write me soon--. I have written
                    this very hurriedly after being at Prayer meeting and it now late. I <orig
                        reg="received">recieved</orig> a paper from you <orig reg="tonight">to
                    night</orig>, but have not had time to read it yet-- will do so in the morning.
                    Dr is well and very busy. We have had two snow storms within the last week and
                    he has been going in the sleigh for a few days; do write soon. Dr. joins with me
                    in love.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours <hi rend="underline">truly</hi></salute>
                    <signed>Kate [Scott]</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
