<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8562"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8562">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                    April 20, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, april 20 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8562</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501744</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, April 20, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, april 20 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                            20 April 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-04-20">1860-04-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8562T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kate Scott informs her brother, Edward McPherson, about local news of family and
                    friends, including weddings, travel, and the children.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
      
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-04-20">April 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>/60</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother.</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> your letter in due time and was glad to
                    hear you had got through your business in Gettysburg so satisfactorily, it makes
                    me sad to know our things are so scattered through the town and that we no
                    longer have a home there. I suppose I may look for the mirrors soon. I do hope
                    they will carry safely, wouldn't it be too bad if they should be broken. I would
                    be too much provoked, I think they were cheap enough I would like to see your
                    rooms and <pb n="2"/> am glad you are so snugly fixed. I suppose you did not get
                    back to the meeting of Presbytery. Mr Brown and Mr Marshall intended going over
                    on <del hand="h1">Monday</del> Tuesday but it rained so hard all day they did
                    not get off. Mr B--. left on Wednesday in the cars for Chambersburg and thought
                    he might go down in the stage, but I rather think he went on to <abbr
                        expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>
                    <orig reg="where">were</orig> he is at present. I heard from sister a week ago,
                    they will soon be in <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt--</abbr> now and to go through
                    the sad scene of parting, I think it is dreadful. I hardly know how Lizzie can
                    bear it. I think she is very delicate, she complains very much. I do not think I
                    will be down to meet them, it does not suit me very much to leave home. Lizzie
                    thinks she will be in Washington about a month which will be very pleasant for
                    you all. I would love to be with you. <del hand="h1">Mary</del> All from <pb
                        n="3"/>Rose Hill were here on Tuesday, they are getting ready for Pittsburg
                    the middle of next month. 7th of June is the wedding day. It will be a great
                    affair, they will travel and call at- Rose Hill on their return. Jinnie is
                    better now but has had a mighty hard time. Dr Lindsley from Washington is her
                    attending Physician now. Dr made a visit- to Carroll <hi rend="super">Co.</hi>
                    week befor last he had a very pleasant visit. took all his friends by <orig
                        reg="suprise">surprize</orig>. Mary Boyle is at home and looking very sick.
                    They are very anxious for me to go down this summer and take all the children
                    but that is too much of an undertaking for me. Write soon, I suppose you will go
                    to Baltimore to meet the folks, I think if I remember right it will be your
                    first meeting with Captain Howe. I would like to see him. The children are all
                    well, Lillie goes to school, in the <orig reg="neighborhood"
                    >neighbourhood</orig> and is <pb n="4"/>very much pleased. I think she will
                    learn readily, she seems to be very apt-- Norman is so lonely without her he
                    hardly knows what to do with himself if Andrew is with you yet- give my love to
                    him and tell him I hope he will give us a call this summer. we have a
                    disagreeable job on hand which I wish was done, we expect to raise our back
                    building and enlarge the dining room it will be a delightful improvement but an
                    inconvenience while it is being done, we hope to do it next month if the weather
                    is good, write soon,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>truly your affectionate</salute>
                    <signed>sister K ---</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
