<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FD1014"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="FD1014"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Diary of Charles Edward Lippitt (1863)</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county diary of charles edward lippitt 1863</title>
        <author>Lippitt, Charles Edward</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name/> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Desi Hopkins, Virginia Center for Digital History</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 8.4 kilobytes</num>
      </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">FD1014</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
<p>copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500352</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Diary of Charles Edward Lippitt</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county diary of charles edward lippitt</title>
            <author>Charles Edward Lippitt</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent> pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 

            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Charles Edward Lippitt Diary and Medical Record Book, #3157, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill.</idno> 
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt> 
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1863-06-26" to="1863-06-30">1863-06-26; 1863-06-30</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>Home Front, Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
        </respStmt> 
        <item>Proofread.</item> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="FD1014T">

<front id="d2">
<div1 id="FD1014bio" type="bio">
<head>Biography
<!-- <ref>FD1014bio</ref> -->
</head>
<p>Charles E. Lippitt served with the 57th Virginia regiment and this segment of his diary includes a description of his regiment's movement through Franklin County, Pennsylvania.</p> 
</div1> 
</front>

<body id="d4">


<div1 id="FD10141863" type="part" n="1863">
<head>1863
<!-- <ref>FD10141863</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1863-06" id="d6">
<head>June 1863 
<!-- <ref>Home Front, Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Women</ref> -->  
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-26" id="d7">
<head>Friday, June 26, 1863</head>
<p>Ordered to march at 4 but as it rained all night &amp; was still inclement did not get off till between 5 &amp; 6. Marched about 3 miles and made a wearisome halt in the rain for Hill to pass through Hagerstown. We followed him, passing through Middleburg <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr>, &amp; camping 1 mile from Greencastle. The march was a most tedious one, rainy all day and the roads very muddy. The country is a fine one, well cultivated and the crop looking well, better than with us. There seems to have been plenty of rain here.</p>

<p>There was some waving of hankerchiefs in Martinsburg &amp; Williams Port, but even more in Hagerstown. Here the men are sullen and the women obsequious, bowing even at a distance as if to conciliate. All seem afraid we will injure them knowing how well they deserve it, but Lee has issued orders forbidding any one taking or injuring private property excepting the <abbr expan="Commissary supplies">C. S's</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="Quartermasters">Q. M's</abbr> &amp;c</p>

<p><abbr expan="Generals">Genls</abbr> Lee, Longstreet &amp; Pendleton passed us today.</p>

<p>Our march today was about 15 miles. The Dutch farmers say Take de horses take de cattle take eberyting put don't purn de parn don't purn de house &amp; don't hurt de wife &amp; leetle one.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-27" id="d8">
<head>Saturday, June 27, 1863</head>
<p>Orders more sensible today, to march at 6 1/2 <abbr expan="o'clock">o'clk</abbr>. Passed through Greencastle in Franklin <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> where the people all looked very serious, most of the houses closed, but the inhabitants were visible. Fine country well cultivated. An old farmer said he could not blame our army for taking horses &amp;c for he had heard the Yankees boast of what they had taken from the Southern people.</p>

<p>A fine day for marching, but only made about 15 miles passed through Marion a village 4 miles from Greencastle &amp; through Chambersburg, a thriving town of perhaps 7 or 8,000 inhabitants, camping 3 miles beyond the latter place. Stores closed but streets and windows filled with men and women, the latter very common looking, not to compare with our Southern females. <abbr expan="Quartermaster">Q. M.</abbr> &amp; Commissary supplies pressed in <abbr expan="Chambersburg">C.</abbr> The men caught some <orig reg="fowl">fowles</orig> on the road, but were made to offer to pay for them. I am glad to see the men are allowed to walk through wheat fields &amp;c, instead of confining them to the muddy roads. Some of the women were very impudent. A few of our men exchanged hats with citizens in a very quiet manner. 'Tis said one murder was committed by a souther soldier, but as the parties were drunk I did not <orig reg="hear">here</orig> what was done with the men. 'Tis also said that some of our men have been bush-whacked, this should not be allowed. Met several droves of horses going South.</p>

<p>I did not mention that a deserter was shot in Garnett's Brig on the 25th upon halting for the night. The <orig reg="offense">offence</orig> was committed some time ago.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-28" id="d9">
<head>Sunday, June 28, 1863</head>
<p>Orders to clean guns wash clothes &amp;c. Some of our officers attempted to go into town to buy some articles, but Lee's orders prohibited it. No one is allowed to purchase but Chiefs of Departments and they only for the use of the Army.</p>

<p>Heard today that Grant had made another attack upon Vicksburg been repulsed with great loss &amp; was recrossing the Big Black in retreat.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-29" id="d10">
<head>Monday, June 29, 1863</head>
<p>Orders to march at 8 <unclear>wh</unclear> were countermanded, remained quiet <orig reg="until">till</orig> 3 when we took up line of march retracing our steps through Chambersburg where the people seemed quite delighted at our <hi rend="underline">retreat</hi> saying we were running from McClellan. One damsel vented her spleen upon me by a horrid grimace, <abbr expan="it was">'twas</abbr> quite amusing. We camped about 2 miles south of town in a fine grove.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-30" id="d11">
<head>Tuesday, June 30, 1863</head>
<p>A detail made from <abbr expan="regiment">reg't</abbr> to tear up Rail Road. Various rumors viz Beauregard on the march to join us. The rest of Lee's Army in motion. Ewell retracing his steps &amp; turning off towards Gettysburg. 1000 Yankee militia captured near Carlisle paroled &amp; every man stripped of his shoes &amp;c &amp;c. Our <abbr expan="Quartermasters">Q. M's</abbr> have pressed a number of horses, the horses are fond in all sorts of out of the way places, even covered up in straw ricks, &amp;c. They are taken &amp; if the owner is found he receives pay for him from $80 to $100. Showery for the last two days. Our mail came and left today.</p>
</div3>

</div2>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI.2>