<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FD1007"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
 
<TEI.2 id="FD1007">  
<teiHeader type="migrated">  
 
    <fileDesc>  
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Diary of Samuel Cormany (1863)</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county diary of samuel cormany 1863</title>
        <author>Cormany, Samuel</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>  
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>  
          <name>Valley Staff</name>  
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>  
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>  
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>  
 
      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 17 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>  
      <publicationStmt>  
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>  
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>  
 
        <idno type="VCDH">FD1007</idno>  
 
        <!--
<availability>  
<p>Publicly accessible </p>  
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>  
<p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>  
</availability>
-->  
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>  
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500348</idno>
      </publicationStmt>  
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow:  Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>  
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>   
 
      <sourceDesc>   
        <biblFull>  
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Samuel Cormany Diary</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">samuel cormany diary</title>
            <author>Samuel Cormany</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>  
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>  
          <extent>5 pages</extent>  
          <publicationStmt>  
            <publisher/>  
            <pubPlace/>  
            <date value=""/>  
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: James C. Mohr, editor, and Robert E. Winslow III, assistant editor, The Cormany Diaries: A Northern Family in the Civil War (Pittsburgh: University of Pittsburgh Press, 1982)</idno>  
          </publicationStmt>  
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Valley of the Shadow:  Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
          </seriesStmt>  
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>  
        </biblFull>  
      </sourceDesc>  
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Published Source</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>  
 
    <profileDesc>  
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1863-06-30" to="1863-07-06">1863-06-30 - 1863-07-06</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>  
      <textClass>  
        <keywords>  
          <term>
Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Family, 
Home front, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women
</term>  
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>  
      </textClass>  
    </profileDesc>  
 
    <revisionDesc>  
      <change>  
        <date value="2003-03">March 2003</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>  
        <item>Proofread for typographical errors; corrections made.</item>  
      </change>  
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>  
  </teiHeader>  
 
<text id="FD1007T"> 
 
<front id="d2"> 
<div1 id="FD1007bio" type="bio"> 
<head>Biography
<!-- <ref>FD1007bio</ref> -->
</head> 
<p>Samuel Cormany enlisted in the Union Army not long after moving to Chambersburg from Canada with his wife, Rachel.  His diary provides a graphic account of a soldier's participation in the battle of Gettysburg.  Samuel survived the war, and afterwards he and his wife moved to Missouri to live on a farm.</p> 
</div1> 
</front> 
 
<body id="d4"> 

 
<div1 id="FD10071863" type="part" n="1863"> 
<head>1863
<!-- <ref>FD10071863</ref> -->
</head> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1863-06" id="d6"> 
<head>June 1863
 <!-- <ref>Patriotism, Women, Troop Movement</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-06-30" id="d7"> 
<head>June 30, 1863</head> 
<p>Tuesday. We moved out early to within a few miles of Westminster
and drew up in line for battle--our advance moved on--and the <abbr
expan="Regiment">Reg't</abbr> supported--met little resistance in
taking the City--Took 8 prisoners.</p> 
 
<p>The Regiment halted close to the City--We got some eatables-- The
people were ecstatic to see our troops driving out and following up
the "Johnies." They did all in their power for us--The <abbr
expan="Rebels">Rebs</abbr> had acted awful meanly--Took everything
like hats, boots, shoes, clothing &amp;c--The streets and fence
corners were strewn with their discarded old ones. Some of them, yes
many, were almost able to join in the march, being so full of
lice<ref n="1" target="scormany1">[1]</ref>--Soon we were called on to
muster for pay--still near town--and at noon took up the march
Manchester--I never saw more cherries, ripe and ripening, and better
crops then are to be seen hereabouts--<abbr
expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> Barnes &amp; I got a fine supper at
Mr. Bingamins--Fine ladies about. Exultant on our arrival, and almost
worshipped us as their protectors- i.e., our soldiers--For the night
we picketed and laid ready--I stood Post two hours--</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
 
<div2 type="section" n="1863-07" id="d8"> 
<head>July 1863
<!-- <ref>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Home front,
Family</ref> --> 
</head> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-01" id="d9"> 
<head>July 1, 1863</head> 
<p>Wednesday. I had a fine chicken breakfast--and a feast of other
good things. Took up march for Hanover. Very fine rich country--and
such fine water--Settlers are Old Style People. Many <orig
reg="Dunkers">Dunkerds</orig>. We were given any amount to eat all
along the way--The <abbr expan="Rebels">Rebs</abbr> who had passed
this way acted very meanly--All around--demanding setters to pay
money to exempt horses from  being taken and barns and houses from
being burned--One old  man said he paid $100 to exempt 2 horses--
another paid $23 to save  his horse--Still another--$100 to save his
barn. We found this hideous thing to be quite common<ref n="2"
target="scormany2">[2]</ref>--We struck Hanover at dark. Found N.C.
R. R. badly torn up<ref n="3" target="scormany3">[3]</ref>--During the
day we heard heavy <orig reg="cannonading">canonading</orig>--and
later musketry firing--in the direction of Gettysburg. Rumor was,
"Theres a Battle on at Gettysburg" and was not hard to believe--Some
of our Cavalry had fought desperately here today, early--Charging
into the enemy's rear and flanks-- Killed some 30 <abbr
expan="rebels">rebs</abbr> and hustled large forces on their way. So
they had to abandon their dead and some of their wounded<ref n="4"
target="scormany4">[4]</ref>--We lay on arms in a field for the
night--we were well fed, but awfully tired and sleepy--A shower of
rain failed to awaken me--I was lying in a furrow, an old furrow. I
partially awakened in the night feeling coolish on my lower side--but
didn't fully awake. In the morning I discovered that water had run
down the furrow--and I had "dam'd" it somewhat and so was pretty wet
from below, while my poncho had kept me dry from the top--</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-02" id="d10"> 
<head>July 2, 1863</head> 
<p>Thursday. More or less Picket firing all night--We were aroused
early, and inspection showed a lot of our horses too lame and used up
for good action--So first, our good mounts were formed for moving
out, and were soon off--with the Brigade and took <abbr
expan="Rebel">Reb.</abbr> <abbr expan="General">Genl.</abbr> <orig
reg="Stuart">Steward</orig> by surprise on the Deardorf Farm--on
right and rear of the army line--where <orig
reg="Stuart">Steward</orig> was expected to at least annoy the rear
of <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> <orig reg="Meade">Mead</orig>--
But our boys charged him--and after severe fighting dealt him an
inglorious defeat and later in the day came in and lay on arms in the
rear of <orig reg="Meades">Meads</orig> right--While our mounted men
were paying attention to <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> <orig
reg="Stuart">Steward</orig>, we fellows had our horses cared for and
were marched down to the right of the main line--to occupy a gap and
do Sharpshooting--at long range, with our Carbines--we soon attracted
attention, and later an occasional shell fell conspicuously close--
but far enough to the rear of us so we suffered no serious harm.
Towards noon firing became more general and in almost all directions-
-and we were ordered to our horses--and joined our returned heroes,
and lay in readiness for any emergency--The general battle <orig
reg="increased">increaced</orig> in energy--and occasional
fierceness--and by 2 P.M. the <orig
reg="cannonading">canonading</orig> was most terrific and continued
til 5 P.M. and was interspersed with musketry--and Charge--yells and
everything that goes to making up the indescribable battle of the
best men on Earth, seemingly in the Fight to the Finish--At dark, our
<abbr expan="Cavalry Brigade">Cav Brig</abbr>--2nd <abbr
expan="Brigade">Brig</abbr> 2" <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr>--was
moved to the left--many wounded came in--Taken as a whole from all
one can see from one point--it seems as <abbr
expan="though">tho</abbr> our men--The Union Army--is rather
overpowered and worsted<ref n="5" target="scormany5">[5]</ref>--Lay on
arms to rest-- Little chance to feed and eat.</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-03" id="d11"> 
<head>July 3,1863</head> 
<p>Friday. <orig reg="Cannonading">Canonading</orig> commenced early-
-and battle was on again in full intensity at 10 <abbr
expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> we were ordered to the Front and Center,
but immediately removed to the right of the Center--had some
skirmishing. Pretty lively--Our squadron almost ran into a Rebel
Battery with a Brigade of Cavalry maneuvering in the woods. They
didn't want to see us, but moved left-ward and we held the woods all
P-M.--All seemed rather quiet for several hours--From 1 1/2 til 4
P.M- there was the heaviest <orig reg="cannonading">canonading</orig>
I ever have heard--One constant roar with rising and falling
inflections<ref n="6" target="scormany6">[6]</ref>--</p>

<p>Our Boys opened 54 guns at the same  time on the Rebel lines and
works from a little conical hill, <orig
reg="Cemetery">Cemetary</orig> Ridge. We were picketing in the rear
and on the right of it--Many shells came our way--some really quite
near--But it is wonderful how few really made our acquaintance.</p>  
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-04" id="d12"> 
<head>July 4, 1863</head> 
<p> Saturday. The great battle closed and quieted with the closing
day--Some firing at various points--</p> 
 
<p>Our <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> layed on arms with Pickets
out--on the ground where we had put in most of the day--Rather
expecting attack momentarily--Rained furiously during the night--We
had fed, eaten, and were standing "to horse" when about 6 <abbr
expan="o'clock">ock</abbr> NEWS CAME--"The <abbr
expan="Rebels">Rebs</abbr> are falling back!" and "Our Forces are
following them" and our <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> went out
towards Hunterstown reconnoitering. We found some confederates who
had straggled, or were foraging, not knowing yet what had happened
and was taking place--Of course, our Boys took them in--Making a
little detour I captured two. <abbr expan="Sergeant">Sergt.</abbr>
Major J. T. Richardson and Private Cox 9th <abbr expan="Virginia
Cavalry">Va Cav</abbr>--disarming them and bringing them in--I
guarded them--while the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> gathered
in some others--P.M. Captain Hughes came along and paroled them--and
we were ordered to camp near Hanover--where we first lay on arriving
near Gettysburg-- Evening awfully muddy and disagreeable--I saw much
of the destructiveness of the Johnies today--</p> 
</div3> 
 
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-05" id="d13"> 
<head>July 5, 1863</head> 
<p> Sunday. Rained awfully during the night. I got very wet--</p> 
 
<p> Early we took up the march for Chambersburg<ref n="7"
target="scormany7">[7]</ref>--Crossing the battlefield--<orig
reg="Cemetery">Cemitary</orig> Hill--The Great Wheat Field Farm,
Seminary ridge--and other places where dead men, horses, smashed
artillery, were strewn in utter confusion, the Blue and The Grey
mixed--Their bodies so bloated--distorted--discolored on account of
decomposition having set in--that they were utterly unrecognizable,
save by clothing, or things in their pockets--The scene simply
beggars description--Reaching the west side of the Field of Carnage--
we virtually charged most of the way for 10 miles--to Cashtown--
Frequently in sight of the Rebel rear guard--taking in prisoners--in
bunches--We captured some 1,500 wounded men, and 300 stragglers--we
went as far as Goodyears Springs, where we rested <unclear></unclear>
for the night. (I had to guard a <abbr expan="Rebel">Reb</abbr> all
night.)</p> 
</div3> 
   
<div3 type="entry" n="1863-07-06" id="d14"> 
<head>July 6, 1863</head> 
<p>Monday. Had a good breakfast. Turned my prisoner over to others We
took up the march--via Fayeteville for Quincy-- I told <abbr
expan="Corporal">Corp.</abbr> Metz I intended going on--To
Chambersburg--To see wife and Baby--and would report in the morning
again. He understood and I slipped away--and was soon making time for
home--I got a fine "10 oclock piece" at Heintzelmans--on approaching
Chambersburg I was assured there were still squads of <abbr
expan="rebels">rebs</abbr> about town--Near town I was met by town
folk inquiring about the battle. I was the first "blue coat" they had
seen--and the first to bring direct news of the Enemy's defeat--as
communications had been cut. As I struck the edge of town, I was told
"The Rebel rear-guard had just left the Diamond." So I ventured out
2nd Street and ventured to strike Main near where Darling and Pussy
lodged--and behold They were at the door--had been watching the <abbr
expan="Rebel">Reb</abbr> Rear leaving town--and Oh! The surprise and
delight thus to meet after the awful battle they had been listening
to for passing days--My horse was very soon stabled. My Cavalry
outfit covered with hay--and myself in my <orig
reg="citizens">citazens</orig> clothes--So should any final "rear"
come along, I would not be discovered--To attempt to describe my joy
and feelings at meeting and greeting my dear little family must prove
a failure--We spent the P.M and evening very sweetly and pleasantly,
but only we had a few too many inquiring callers.</p> 
</div3> 
</div2> 
</div1> 
 
</body> 
 
<back id="d15"> 
<div1 id="FD1007notes" type="notes"> 
<head>Notes
<!-- <ref>FD1007note</ref> -->
</head> 

<note n="1" place="end" id="scormany1"><seg type="note-symbol">{1}</seg><p> Many sources agree that the people of
Maryland and Pennsylvania were repelled by the appearance of the
ragged, unkempt, and poorly supplied Confederates.</p></note> 
 
<note n="2" place="end" id="scormany2"><seg type="note-symbol">{2}</seg><p> See Rachel's diary for numerous
references to this same practice in and around
Chambersburg.</p></note> 
 
<note n="3" place="end" id="scormany3"><seg type="note-symbol">{3}</seg><p> The Northern Central Railroad, which ran
north from Baltimore to York, Pa., included a spur line through
Hanover to Gettysburg.</p></note> 
 
<note n="4" place="end" id="scormany4"><seg type="note-symbol">{4}</seg><p> Stuart's main cavalry force had made a
long loop below, around, and now almost back through the Union army.
Just as he was about to reunite with the main Confederate army, Union
cavalry under Brig. Gen. Judson Kilpatrick engaged his troops and
forced them to make another long circular detour, during which they
were again attacked, and Stuart himself was nearly captured. This
forced Lee to suffer a last critical day without the bulk of his
cavalry.</p></note> 
 
<note n="5" place="end" id="scormany5"><seg type="note-symbol">{5}</seg><p> Cormany fought most of the second day at
Gettysburg beside infantry forces on the right wing of the Union
position. Two Confederate brigades had temporarily reached the top of
Cemetery Hill, and Southern troops were entrenched for renewed attack
at the base of Culp's Hill. The Confederates very nearly turned the
Union right flank, but Confederate commanders, deprived of cavalry
reconnaissance never fully realized how much they had weakened the
Union line in Cormany's area. Consequently, though battered, even
beaten, Union defenders remained at the end of the day basically
where their commanders had placed them. Glenn Tucker, <hi
rend="italic">High Tide at Gettysburg: The Campaign in
Pennsylvania</hi> (Indianapolis, 1958), pp. 282-306. Samuel's name
appears on the Pennsylvania monument at Gettysburg.</p></note> 
 
<note n="6" place="end" id="scormany6"><seg type="note-symbol">{6}</seg><p> The Battle of Gettysburg reached a climax
on July 3, when a Confederate effort to break the center of the Union
line failed disastrously. That effort, which featured the massive
infantry offensive known as Pickett's Charge, began with what still
remains the largest artillery duel ever waged in North America. The
sound of that duel, reverberating through the valleys of south
central Pennsylvania and northern Maryland and back and forth among
layered air inversions, was said to have been audible 140 miles away.
Jack McLaughlin, <hi rend="italic">Gettysburg: The Long
Encampment</hi> (New York, 1963), p. 136. Later, Union field
gunners played a crucial role in repelling the infantry offensive and
inflicted heavy casualties on the retreating Confederates after their
attack had been turned.</p></note> 
 
<note n="7" place="end" id="scormany7"><seg type="note-symbol">{7}</seg><p> When Lee decided to retreat, he divided
his forces into two main columns. The first headed west through
Cashtown, Greenwood, and Fayetteville to Chambersburg, where they
would turn south down the Cumberland Valley. The other proceeded
directly southwest from Gettysburg toward Hagerstown. The 16th
Pennsylvania pursued the first of those columns in the direction of
their own home town. </p></note> 

</div1> 
</back> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>
