<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.09.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/03/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-18">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Political "Situation."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Southern people have been taught by oppression and tyranny, an important
                        lesson to watch, work and trust no party, but they like to know what others
                        think about the situation of political affairs. We don't know what to think
                        sometimes--things change so rapidly now-a-days, but the following from the
                        Baltimore Gazette seems to come about to the point:</p>
                    <p>"In national affairs a crisis has been reached which threatens to culminate
                        in the total overthrow of either the extreme or the more conservative wing
                        of the dominant party, and which may result in the restoration of the
                        Constitution, or the deposition of the President and another and a madder
                        epoch of revolution and anarchy. The Radical party has in the recent
                        elections the strongest incentives to action, for it cannot venture to carry
                        out its scheme for the removal of the President unless it can show that it
                        can still carry with it, as it has done heretofore, a large majority of the
                        people. It is in a situation where it can ill-afford to manifest any sign of
                        weakness, and it has doubtless done its best. The result is that about
                        fifteen thousand voters in Maine, who went with it only twelve months ago,
                        have declined to adhere to its fortunes now. We cannot, therefore, regard
                        the fact, especially when considered in connection with other indications,
                        in any other light than as evidence of a reaction against the Radical
                        revolutionary movement. If this be so, the same influences which have been
                        at work in California, in Montana and in Maine must also have been quietly
                        operating in Ohio and Pennsylvania, and will be productive of similar
                        results. Elections are held in those States shortly, and we shall then know
                        with certainty whether we are justified in the hope that the power of the
                        Radicals has culminated and is on the wane. If the Ohio and Pennsylvania
                        elections are of the same character as that which has just been held in
                        Maine, Mr. Johnson will be master of the situation, and may even, in his way
                        and time, save the Constitution and civil liberty."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian agrees with an excerpt from the Baltimore Gazette that
                    argues that the conservative and radical wings of the Republican party have come
                    to a critical juncture in disagreement. If elections continue to trend
                    conservative, President Johnson may claim victory in the end and "save the
                    Constitution and civil liberty."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Facts For Colored Folks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There has been a comparatively large immigration of Northern people to the
                        Valley; they have invested their money here and more are coming. They all
                        wish to come South and <emph rend="italic">prefer the Valley because the
                            number of colored people is so small in proportion to the whites</emph>.
                        The prejudice, of the working white man North, against the negro is intense
                        and he is the man who will settle up the South. He, or his friends, fought
                        for <emph rend="italic">free white labor</emph> and they won. The first
                        question a white immigrant from the North asks, is: "You aint bothered with
                        the niggers here, are you?" Finding we, in the Valley, are not, he buys land
                        and settles. These facts should teach colored folks something. They should
                        study over them and make themselves the best laboring class in the world;
                        they should stick to their old friends and avoid voting and politics.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial advises the Freedmen to labor and avoid politics since white
                    men in the North are more racist than those in the South. Many northern
                    immigrants settle in the Valley because of its low black population, and don't
                    want to be "bothered" by the race.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "opium eating" is prevalent in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Travel is reportedly dull, with only 400 travellers in the mountains.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The peach crop in the Valley is "immense" and "much money has been made out
                    of it. Every farmer should put out a good orchard."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Increase in Property Values</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gives an example in the "general advance in Staunton" of property
                    values. Twenty years ago, a man bought 2 1/2 acres of land near town. He made
                    $3,000 off it and recently sold it in lots for $4,500.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Badly Needed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors advocate building a sidewalk to Thornrose Cemetery. "It is a
                    disgrace not to have one and a great inconvenience. The Street Commissioners
                    will die some of these days, and they should prepare a walk for the mourning
                    people who desire to follow them decently."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marching</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A veteran of the Stonewall Brigade claims to have marched 36,243 1/8 miles
                    during the war, and often passed sleeping in camp "Uncle Bob's Soldier" of
                    Longstreet's Corps who bragged about his exploits the week before. The ordinance
                    train of Jackson's corps allegedly travelled 15,000 miles in two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Construction on the Manassas Gap Railroad is reportedly progressing
                    rapidly. Cars should run to Mount Jackson by Christmas, Harrisonburg by May, and
                    Staunton by September, 1868.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Staunton's Quota For Washington College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn>Plunket</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following "recruits" from Staunton will be sent to "Uncle Bob" at
                    Washington College this session: Plunket O'Ferrall, S. B. Mason, W. B.
                    McChesney, Benjamin Crawford, Jr., Edward Echols and Francisco.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Statten</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bovey</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammock</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kertcoff</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freed</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evers</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holt</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grim</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallholm</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stern</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A successful camp meeting was held at Mt. Crawford. Only "a little
                    misbehavior on the part of some young men who were excited on the 'spiritual
                    question'" marred the event. A list of ministers present is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.18.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Land Sales and New Settlers in Virginia</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig reports that an "imposing" amount of land has been
                    quietly sold in Virginia. Most of the purchasers are from northern states.
                    "Shrewd capitalists from the North and from abroad have explored the State,
                    searched out the finest lands, and examined carefully into such as have the
                    advantage of water power and contain coal and mineral deposits. The process of
                    colonization and of individual settlement thus quietly going on is but the
                    beginning of that tide which, in a few years, will sweep over the State,
                    bringing an influx of capital and immigration that will place Virginia in the
                    front rank of American States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
