<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.12.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/13/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-04">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.04.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The True Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Who shall line for us the picture of a true, good woman--the pride and the
                        paragon of her own sex, and the ambition of the other; of the woman young,
                        beautiful, healthful--well-informed, but not pedantic, who can talk well,
                        listen well, sing well, play well, walk well and dress well; who is neither
                        flirt nor pride; who knows neither too much nor too little; whose lips are
                        innocent of slang, and whose heart is pure from evil thought; who is
                        polished in manners, and affectionate in disposition; beloved of the old,
                        the darling of the young; shy, modest, retiring; and commanding all the
                        world's homage, without demanding the homage of anybody?</p>
                    <p>It must not be considered that the youthfulness of such a woman is absolutely
                        necessary to her loveliness. Youth is a great blessing and a great charm;
                        but, age is also a blessing--do we not wish to grow old? and a great
                        adornment if it be combined with goodness. The beauty of the mind grows with
                        the revolving years, and makes a woman of seventy, with mind and manners and
                        innate gentleness, more beautiful than sweet seventeen can be, if the mind
                        and the manners are wanting, and the tenderness that should be in every
                        womanly heart is displaced by a masculine tone of thought, behavior or
                        conversation.</p>
                    <p>Though all the women are not such as every man at the poetical period of life
                        has pictured in his imagination, there are thousands in every country who
                        resemble the ideal, if not in accomplishments and education--for these are
                        not within the reach of everyone--yet by outward grace of person, and inward
                        purity of soul. All the flowers that bloom in the fair garden of humanity
                        are not of equal delicacy and brilliancy; for nature, that has room for the
                        magnolia, the lily, has room also for the violet, the bluebell, and the
                        daisy, and loves her humblest children as well as her proudest.</p>
                    <p>Nothing in the world--at least to the male eye--equals in pleasantness the
                        face and form of a bashful and virtuous woman, looking up to a man for
                        support and guidance, and giving him her true affection in return. Nothing,
                        on the other hand, is more disagreeable than the bold virago, womanly in
                        form but not in spirit, who would storm the citadel of your politeness to
                        extort your homage <emph rend="italic">viret armis</emph>, and who, by every
                        movement of her features and glance of her eyes, even if she do not utter a
                        syllable, betrays that she is puffed up with conceit and selfishness, and is
                        too ignorant to distinguish between a churl and a gentleman, or to accept
                        the place that properly belongs to her in the social system.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article describes the "perfect" woman. She who "accepts the place that
                    properly belongs to her in the social system," not those who are "womanly in
                    form but not in spirit" are the best.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Situation, Vol. 3, No. 1, of the Valley Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Two years ago the first number of the Valley Virginian was issued. It entered
                        upon its career in times most trying to our people. They had hardly realized
                        that a mighty Revolution was at an end; that our "cause was lost," and that
                        a new race for life--a struggle against fate, had commenced. The Virginian
                        has gone with its people during these two years of "trial and tribulation."
                        It has, with a peculiar pride, noted their heroic struggles, their wonderful
                        energy, and, from week to week, chronicled the almost marvelous recuperation
                        of the Great Valley. It has had its days of gloom and despondency, as its
                        readers have, and it was no easy task to carry a cheerful face and a hearty
                        "God send you speed," to them every week. Still it has grown with them and
                        prospered as they prospered.</p>
                    <p>In looking back over the two years struggle, we would do injustice to our
                        feelings, did we not express our thanks to a people who have sustained us so
                        generously, and, proudly point them to a subscription list increased from
                        600 to 1400, to the paper improved, enlarged and reduced in price--an
                        established Institution of the Valley of Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Questions of great interest to our people will soon be forced upon their
                        attention. The Valley Virginian, in the future as in the past, Independent
                        in all things, "will be devoted to what it considers the best interests of
                        the Valley and of Virginia." Its synopsis of the proceedings of Congress,
                        the "Hunnicut Convention" and other important news will be as full as
                        required, so as not to destroy the usual variety of the paper. We ask but a
                        continuance of the support that has made the Virginian what it is. We will
                        spare no effort to keep it so and improve it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors look back on two years at the Valley Virginian, the political
                    events it has documented as well as the expansion and growth of the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Scallawags</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This item from the Dispatch suggests that Federal patronage alone is
                    prompting some southern whites to support the rights of African Americans. "If
                    the patronage should be withdrawn, these loyal vagabonds would soon cease to
                    clamor for negro suffrage."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Appointments of Committee for the Seventh Magisterial District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>I. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>U. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trevoy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Theophilus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburn</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herring</ln>
                        <fn>Bethuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>Courtney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rollar</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neff</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echard</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farrow</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoon</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Peter F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the names of men selected by the Conservative Voters of
                    Augusta to serve as vote organizers for the Seventh Magisterial District. Kenton
                    Harper, Superintendent of the District, orders them to organize the voters of
                    each neighborhood by tens, each organizer being responsible for getting his ten
                    men to the polls. The organizers will also register any voters who have not yet
                    done so. "No white man of common intelligence, with the proper instincts of his
                    race, can fail to appreciate the fearful magnitude of the impending crisis. If
                    we neglect the peaceful means in our power to defeat the iniquity meditated
                    against us, history affords no adequate example of the horrors to which we, as a
                    people, will be subjected. Let us be wise then, in time, and exert our utmost
                    energies to avert them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Associate Continues his Talk with the People of Alleghany. The Question of
                    Labor is the One That Most Concerns Us.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The result of the war brings home to our doors a question which Europe has
                        not been able to solve satisfactorily, after the lapse of ages--the question
                        of free labor.</p>
                    <p>Slavery is abolished. The negro is free. Our large farms remain, and they
                        must be worked. It can only be done by the importation of foreign, or by
                        making a respectable laborer of the negro. We are for Cuffee. We were raised
                        with him, owned him, respect him. He was true to us in war, and we shall be
                        true to him in peace. What he wants in a state of freedom or slavery is
                        plenty of friend, Bagby's "bacon and greens," and not a "yankee school-marm"
                        with "catechism" and "psalms," and hymns, and spiritual songs, and
                        "wooden-bacon hams," served up with the "right of suffrage." He, to be sure,
                        has become a little spoiled lately, by his associations, but he will soon
                        learn to keep better company, and be a "wiser and better man." Bear with his
                        follies and his fooleries yet a little longer. He sought neither freedom or
                        suffrage. His greatness has been thrust upon him. He'll survive it, and,
                        like water, seek his level, and his "old master's home" again. We must be
                        patient with him until the yankee gets tired of insulting us, by making a
                        fool of him, and look after his welfare. By so doing we will ultimately take
                        care of our own interest. "The bottom rail cannot remain on top." He must
                        resume the "banjo" and the "hoe" and we must try and make him a happy,
                        contented and prosperous laborer. How is it to be done? Let us forget the
                        elections for the moment, and look at the question from a stand-point worthy
                        of Virginians and of men. We know that it is no blind instinct that attaches
                        the idea of respectability to the possession of a home and of property, of a
                            <emph rend="italic">locus standi</emph> in the community, promotes the
                        feeling of self-respect and establishes a standard of conduct which conduces
                        to and gives a claim to outward respect. We must, therefore, sell him, at a
                        mere song, or give him ten or twenty acres of land on the skirts of our
                        farms. The possession of a home will fix him to the spot, destroy the
                        gregariousness of his nature, keep him from towns, and make him proud and
                        industrious. Having a home we must give him work, see that he does it, and
                        above all, that we pay him a fair price for it. Of the 4,000,000 of French
                        peasant proprietors they possess only an average of eight and a half acres
                        each, and of them Mr. Mills says, "The situation of the peasant proprietors
                        is propitious to every elevating influence and to every moral virtue,"
                        whilst of the poor Irish tenant, who has no moral status, because he has no
                        moral stimulus, he says--"almost alone among mankind, the Irish cottier is
                        in a condition that he can scarcely be better or worse off by any act of his
                        own. If he was industrious or prudent, nobody but his landlord would gain;
                        if he is lazy or intemperate, it is at his landlord's expense. A situation
                        more devoid of motives to either labor or self-command, imagination itself
                        cannot conceive." We improve, by our plan, Sambo's condition over either the
                        French peasant or the Irish cottier. We make his work profitable to himself
                        and to us. make him a quiet and useful citizen and not a drone and a curse.
                        Answer the question: "What is to become of and what will we do with the
                        negro, and increase the value of the landed property of Virginia without
                        detriment to Sambo or his former master, who had the misfortune to be born
                        white?" We shall be glad to hear from any one who has thoughtfully and
                        honestly considered the subject.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the Covington Times argues that African Americans are the
                    best solution to the labor problem. Blacks want material comfort and prosperity,
                    not political rights, the author insists. If southern land owners would only
                    ensure that their tenants can make a decent living, then radicalism will be
                    rejected and both races will live in harmony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smart</ln>
                        <fn>M. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. B. Smart and Miss Sallie Ast, both of Staunton, were married on December
                    3rd by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getty</ln>
                        <fn>Vernon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Vernon Getty, of Georgetown, D. C., and Miss Eliza Stevenson, oldest
                    daughter of R. W. Stevenson of Staunton, were married in Staunton at Trinity
                    Church on November 27th by the Rev. James A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Porterfield</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. J. Foster, of Richmond, and Miss Rebecca Porterfield Taylor, daughter of
                    Edwin M. Taylor, were married at the home of the bride's father on November 28th
                    by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bramham</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farish</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Charles S. Peyton, of Staunton, married Miss Sallie E. Bramham, of
                    Albemarle, on November 21st by the Rev. W. P. Farish.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca L. Watts, wife of Major John B. Watts of Staunton, died at the
                    residence of her father, John Seawright, on November 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>510 guests stayed at the American Hotel, Staunton, during the month of
                    November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Majesty of the Law Vindicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosell</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Mayor imprisoned for ten days James Rosell, a Freedman, for stating
                    publicly that "a negro couldn't get the same justice before the Mayor that a
                    white man could and who ever said he could was a d---d liar." The remark
                    occurred after the Mayor had tried a Freedman for larceny which was not denied.
                    Upon hearing of Rosell's remarks, the Mayor returned to the court and had him
                    arrested. Rosell also had to post security bond in real estate and two hundred
                    for twelve months of good behavior. "The offender is a mail carrier and a son of
                    a respectable freedman, Phillip Rosell, late a Delegate to the Convention in
                    Richmond, who afterwards approved of the Mayor's action. Let this be admonition
                    to all, white or colored, that they must obey the law and respect its proper
                    administration."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
