<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.03.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/09/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-20">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.20.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>To the Parents and the Public of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The undersigned have been appointed by the "Educational Association of
                        Virginia," a committee to address you on their behalf, "urging you to be a
                        more hearty co-operation with teachers, in matters of instruction,
                        discipline, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>The benefits which would be secured to education, and the aid which would be
                        afforded teachers by such co-operation would be very great; as all who have
                        any experience on the subject must be aware of the obstacles at the very
                        threshold of education, arising from the want of proper family management.
                        If, therefore, they can be removed much good will be attained. Since the
                        teacher is properly to be regarded as the parents agent, to assist in the
                        training of his children, it appears obvious, that parents may be best
                        induced to this important concurrence, by pointing them to the fundamental
                        principles to be observed in the education of youth.</p>
                    <p>In its broad, comprehensive sense, education embraces the physical, moral and
                        intellectual instruction of a child, from infancy to manhood. Any system is
                        imperfect which does not combine them all, and that is best which, while it
                        thoroughly developes them, abases the coarse, animal affections of human
                        nature, and exalts the higher faculties and feelings. A child has everything
                        to learn, and is more readily taught by having before it good examples to
                        imitate, than by simple precepts. He should, therefore, as far as
                        circumstances will permit, be encouraged to associate with his parents; for
                        his heart must be affected, his feelings moved, as well as his mind
                        expanded. He may be taught that it is criminal to steal, and sinful to lie,
                        and yet be unable to apply this knowledge to the government of himself; and
                        it will therefore, be of no value to him, unless the principles is confirmed
                        into a habit.</p>
                    <p>Obedience is the first requisite in family training. It should be made
                        sincere and perfect, and proceed as much from affection as a conviction of
                        necessity. To accomplish this, great prudence, and the exercise of much
                        patience, are necessary. By firmness mixed with kindness, the child will
                        learn, by repeated experience, that he is not to follow his impulse, and
                        that self-control, which even an infant can understand, is necessary to his
                        comfort. Neither violence nor harshness should ever be used; and the parent
                        must bear constantly in mind, that to govern his child, he must show him
                        that he can control himself. One of the most common errors in the management
                        of children is irregularity of behavior to-wards them. They are skillful, as
                        pertinacious in their attempts to gratify their self-will; at one time
                        trying to evade authority, at another to oppose it. If they once succeed,
                        they are encouraged to persevere, and it is necessary for the parent to meet
                        the first attempt with firmness, and not permit himself to be baffled,
                        either by evasion or resistance. Although a child may not yield to threats,
                        and may defy punishment, he cannot resist patient kindness and gentle
                        admonition.</p>
                    <p>The love of truth is equal in importance to habitual obedience. Every
                        encouragement, even to the pardoning of offences, should be given to its
                        cultivation. The first impulse of the mind in children is always to speak
                        the truth rather than falsehood, unless some evil motive arise to sway them
                        to untruth. They should be accustomed to hear the truth always spoken.
                        Confession of error, with a detestation of falsehood, dishonesty and
                        equivocation, should be sedulously inculcated. A strict adherence to
                        promises made to them is of the utmost importance, as well as the removal of
                        all temptation to misconduct.</p>
                    <p>The influence of christianity forms the essential element of moral character;
                        as its principles are the only sufficient basis of virtue or happiness.
                        Hence, the parent's most sacred duty to his child is to impress the
                        sentiments of our holy religion early upon his mind, by personal explanation
                        and systematic instruction. As the intellect expands, its sacred truths will
                        be comprehended and felt, and its motives and principles be strengthened and
                        confirmed by practice and habit.</p>
                    <p>An essential part of the education of youth is to teach them to serve
                        themselves, and to impress upon them the fact that nothing good can be
                        acquired in this world without labor; and that the very necessaries and
                        comforts of life must be procured by earnest and regular exertion. They
                        should also be taught to know that after having been reared and educated by
                        their parents, they should not expect to provide further for them, and that
                        their future subsistence and advancement must depend upon themselves.
                        Parents sometimes commit the mistake of allowing their children, after
                        having reached the period of life when they ought to be engaged in making a
                        livelihood, to rely upon them for support. This encourages them in injurious
                        idleness, and destroys that spirit of self-dependence, which is necessary
                        for their advancement in life, and causes them to appear so unreasonable as
                        to depend upon them after having arrived at an age when they should think
                        and act for themselves.</p>
                    <p>The choice of a profession is not of so much consequence as the manner in
                        which it is pursued. If habits of self-control and self-denial have been
                        acquired during the season of education, the great object has been
                        accomplished. Diligence and integrity in any useful pursuit of life will be
                        sure to secure prosperity and fame, and success will result from engaging in
                        that business in which the generality of mankind are interested.</p>
                    <p>Such being the correct view of education, the support and cooperation which
                        faithful teachers should receive from parents can be easily inferred by the
                        good sense of each one. We only ask especial attention, in concluding, to
                        the following suggestions, which our experience has shown to be of prime
                        importance.</p>
                    <p>1. The parent, after committing his child teaching of another, should
                        continue to manifest an affection-interest in his improvement, by constant
                        inquiry and encouragement.</p>
                    <p>2. The supplying of young persons while absent from their homes, with
                        needless money, and the permission to contract debts, are to be reprobated,
                        as tempting to a sinful prodigality and multiplying the dangers of
                        contracting habits of vice.</p>
                    <p>3. The proper authority of teachers must be firmly sustained by parents.</p>
                    <p>4. Every young person should be informed by his parents that he must give
                        diligence to profit by his studies, or else must be compelled to make
                        himself useful to society by actual labor in some humbler sphere.</p>
                    <p>And last, an unworthy parent cannot reasonably expect the teacher, against
                        the current of his wrong example, to form his son into a worthy man.</p>
                    <p>R. E. Lee, John B. Minor, R. L. Dabney, Committee.<lb/> March 8, 1867.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Committee appointed by the "Educational Association of Virginia" publish
                    a letter providing guidelines for the proper rearing of children. They
                    especially encourage parents to support and work with teachers to impart a
                    proper education upon their children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that throughout the South, "it is estimated that about a
                    million of the poor blacks have disappeared during the last four years. The
                    deaths are far more numerous than the births." In Virginia the population has
                    decreased by 49,000 according to a report by General Howard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that a good wife "should be like a snail, to keep within
                    her own house; but she should not be like a snail to carry all she has upon her
                    back." "She should be like an echo, to speak when spoken to; but she should not
                    be like an echo, always to have the last word." "She should be like a town
                    clock, always to keep time and regularity; but she should not be like a town
                    clock, speak so loud that all the town may hear."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There were 435 arrivals at Staunton's American Hotel last month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Duties Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The History of the world has been badly written, if there was ever a people
                        placed in the "situation" which now "be-devils" the honest masses of the
                        South. Still, there are proud recollections of the past and grand hopes in
                        the future of such a people, which it is well for us to remember. While
                        History makes no mention of a people in our condition, it records no
                        instance where a race has accomplished so much or developed so high an order
                        of talent. Since Raleigh crossed the Seas, with his brave "cavaliers," and
                        Spottswood discovered our magnificent Valley; since a Washington, the
                        grandest "Rebel" of recorded time, gained our Independence; since Jefferson,
                        Madison and a host of other great minds, gave form and substance to
                        Constitutional Liberty, this people have controlled a Continent--and their
                        descendants only ceased to do so, when overpowered by brute force. Shall we
                        disgrace this glorious record, by inactivity, or shall we master the
                        "situation"?</p>
                    <p>It is all very fine to talk about "Italy" and "Hungary" and what they did by
                        remaining "passive" under oppression, but our "passive" men seem to forget
                        that the people of Italy and Hungary were all of <emph rend="italic">one
                            race</emph>, and that but for the assistance of France and Prussia,
                        these countries would now be under the rule of Austria. We have no friendly
                        or <emph rend="italic">interested</emph> neighbors to help us out of a bad
                        scrape, but we have four millions of negroes to control.</p>
                    <p>Is it possible to teach the Southern people a little practical selfishness?
                        Is the terrible experience of four years, of the bloodiest and most cruel
                        war recorded in history, to leave us the same people we were; to leave us,
                        or rather what is left of us, the same helpless people we have always been?
                        This is the question for us to decide and the only question. The example of
                        Italy and Hungary will do for "Honor" gentlemen, of the "inaction" order, to
                        talk about and grow eloquent over, but recollect, neither of these countries
                        had four millions of a different race; a race, it is true, that proved
                        faithful during the war, but still a race that may be used by our enemies,
                        and theirs, to enslave us.</p>
                    <p>It is now certain, as the Virginian proclaimed at first, that the provisions
                        of the "Military Bill" will be carried out, and negro suffrage enforced. A
                        General issues his orders from "H'd Quarters, District No. 1, Richmond"--a
                        place formerly known as the Capitol of Virginia. He does his work like a
                        gentleman and a soldier, <emph rend="italic">but he will do it</emph>,
                        bitter as it may be to him and to us. In fact our "head is in the Lion's
                        mouth," and it won't do to twist his tail too much, neither will it do any
                        better to let it stay there and refuse the friendly aid of the negro vote,
                        to get it out. If we remain "inactive," Botts &amp; Co. may succeed in
                        "twisting his tail," to our great disadvantage.</p>
                    <p>It is true that our people have been so busily engaged, since the surrender,
                        in making "bread and meat," that they have had no time to attend to the
                        education and interests of the Freedmen, and that business has gone into the
                        hands of our enemies. But even now our duty is plain; we must take more
                        interest in this class; we must show them we are their best friends, and it
                        is a sacred duty every man owes to his family, to explain this question to
                        them. It won't do to say you "won't vote beside a nigger," for if you do
                        not, and fail to make him vote rightly and intelligently, you are neglecting
                        a duty and deserve to be punished, (as you surely will be,) for it.</p>
                    <p>Our duty is so plain a one, that it seems idle to repeat it, and we would not
                        but for the deplorable apathy and indifference (natural we know) of our
                        people. <emph rend="italic">We must take charge and control the negro
                            population</emph>, and every white man that has a vote must vote and
                        instruct every colored man in his duty. The great hero of this century and
                        of the war, Stonewall Jackson, did not deem it beneath his dignity, but
                        considered it a sacred duty, to instruct the negroes, even before the war.
                        Are we so proud and foolish that we can not "profit by his example?" Or will
                        we lay supinely on our backs, in "masterly inactivity," and see this vast
                        element of strength wielded against us, by the vilest and lowest creatures
                        on "God's green earth." We will not insult the intelligence of our people by
                        admitting such a thing, but we feel it our duty to urge upon them the
                        necessity of going to work at once, and controlling this element. There is
                        no time to be lost, and it would be a poor compliment to a people who held a
                        world at bay, with a "skirmish line," for four years, to say they cannot now
                        control four millions of a race, that "skirmish line" at the same time, held
                        in subjection.</p>
                    <p>The "silver lining" to the "cloud" of our troubles is to make an element of
                        strength out of that with which our enemies expected to destroy us, and it
                        is our duty, to black and white, to do it. We have it from the best
                        authority that "Gen. Lee" is heartily in favor of a Convention. He thinks we
                        should make every effort to avert our ruin; that it is idle to talk of
                        resistance or "inactivity." He acknowledges that the pill is a bitter one,
                        but says he can suffer nothing more than APPOMATTOX! It is "bitter"--a hard
                        duty to perform, but remember the words of our "best and bravest" and let
                        every man do his part in the trying times now upon us. Providence always
                        assists those who help themselves.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial asserts that the South is unique among conquered nations
                    because it is a region that is home to two distinct races. All white Southerners
                    must now "instruct" and "control" black Southerners in order to ensure that
                    African American suffrage will not transform the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>One of the Effects</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since the passage of the Military Bill, several gentlemen of our town have
                        received letters from Northern capitalists and farmers, desiring to invest
                        in the South and especially in our Valley. So it is no use to despond, for
                        even this harsh measure, may, and we think will, prove beneficial to us
                        materially, by the confidence it will inspire in northern men and capital
                        heretofore afraid to venture South. The tide of immigration and capital is
                        certain to turn towards the general climate of the South soon, in spite of
                        radical meanness. Then our day of triumph will come. Stick together, work,
                        teach your children trades, develope and encourage home enterprises, and our
                        future is a bright one.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article argues that the one positive effect of the Military
                    Reconstruction Bill is the increased willingness of northerners to invest in the
                    South. Immigration from the North is also picking up, ensuring a prosperous
                    future for the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Courage</head>
                <origin>Winchester Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is nothing so discouraging in our present condition as the feeling of
                        despair which seems to have taken possession of many of our people. Involved
                        in thick darkness, they would cut the cable of the "anchor of the soul" and
                        become the sport of the tempest. Is despair a remedy for any evil or the
                        only refuge of a brave people? On the contrary, is it not practical
                        infidelity and the sum of all evils.</p>
                    <p>Has God forgotten to be gracious, or given up his power to dispose of what
                        man proposes? The Radicals are very ingenious, and in a worldly point of
                        view, very powerful; but one word from the omnipotent disposer of events
                        will crush them to atoms. Other nations have been worse off than the people
                        of the South and afterwards regained power and prosperity. Other parties
                        have rioted in all the excesses of corruption, bigotry, injustice and infamy
                        as the Radical faction now does and have fallen into disgrace and so it will
                        be again.</p>
                    <p>There are agencies at work that will surely accomplish their speedy
                        destruction, and the rumbling of the chariot wheels of the great arbiter of
                        human destiny may be heard in the distance. With due respect for the
                        opinions of despairing patriots, we must be permitted to doubt the
                        omnipotence and perpetuity of the Radical party.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Winchester Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Winchester Times urges southerners not to despair at the power of the
                    radicals, since it will eventually be broken. With optimism, the South may
                    recover from their predicament.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Encouraging</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lord Macauley's maxim that man's desire to improve himself will help him
                    overcome any difficulty should give hope to the South. Exertions to regain
                    prosperity will counterbalance "profuse expenditure, heavy taxation, absurd
                    commercial restrictions, corrupt tribunals, disastrous wars, seditions,
                    prosecutions, conflagrations and inundations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "our Irish friends" celebrated St. Patrick's Day
                    last Sunday, March 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the game of marbles is "flourishing on the streets
                    and alleys of Staunton."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.20.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Burial of Our Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By Col. Theodore O'Hara, of Kentucky</p>
                    <p>The muffled drum's sad roll shall beat,<lb/> The soldier's last tattoo;<lb/>
                        No more on life's parade shall meet,<lb/> The brave and daring few.<lb/> On
                        Fame's eternal camping ground,<lb/> Their silent tents are spread,<lb/> And
                        glory guards the solemn round,<lb/> The bivouac of the dead.</p>
                    <p>No answer of the foe's advance,<lb/> Now swells upon the wind;<lb/> No
                        troubled thought at midnight haunts,<lb/> Of loved ones left behind;<lb/> No
                        vision of the morrow's strife,<lb/> The warrior's dream alarms--<lb/> No
                        braying horn or scream of fife,<lb/> At dawn shall come to arms.</p>
                    <p>Their shivered swords are red with rust,<lb/> Their plumed heads are
                        bowed,<lb/> Their haughty banners, trailed in dust,<lb/> Is now their
                        martial shroud.<lb/> And plenteous funeral tears have washed,<lb/> Their red
                        stains from each brow,<lb/> And their proud forms, in battle gashed,<lb/>
                        Are free from anguish now.</p>
                    <p>The neighing steed, the flashing blade,<lb/> The trumpet's stirring
                        blast--<lb/> The charge, the dreadful cannonade,<lb/> The din and shout are
                        past;<lb/> Nor war's wild note, nor glory's peal,<lb/> Shall thrill with
                        fierce delight,<lb/> Those breasts that never more shall feel,<lb/> The
                        rapture of the flight.</p>
                    <p>Like the dread Northern hurricane,<lb/> That sweeps his broad plateau;<lb/>
                        Flushed with the triumph yet to gain,<lb/> Came down the sorried foe.<lb/>
                        Our heroes felt the shock, and leapt,<lb/> To meet them on the plain;<lb/>
                        And long the pitying sky hath wept,<lb/> Above our gallant slain.</p>
                    <p>Sons of our consecrated ground,<lb/> Ye must not slumber there;<lb/> Where
                        stranger steps and tongues resound,<lb/> Along the heedless air;<lb/> Your
                        own proud land's heroic soil,<lb/> Shall be your fitter grave;<lb/> She
                        claims from war her richest spoil--<lb/> The ashes of her brave!</p>
                    <p>So 'neath their parent turf they rest,<lb/> far from the gory field!<lb/>
                        Borne to a Spartan mother's breast,<lb/> On many a bloody shield;<lb/> The
                        sunshine of her native sky,<lb/> Smiles sadly on them here,<lb/> And kindred
                        hearts and eyes watch by,<lb/> The heroes' sepulchre.</p>
                    <p>Rest on, embalmed and sainted dead!<lb/> Dear as the bloody grave;<lb/> No
                        impious footsteps here shall tread,<lb/> The herbage of your grave;<lb/> Nor
                        shall your glory be forgot,<lb/> While fame her record keeps,<lb/> Or honor
                        points the hallowed spot,<lb/> Where valor proudly sleeps.</p>
                    <p>Yon marble minstrel's voiceless tone,<lb/> In deathless song shall tell,<lb/>
                        When many a vanished age hath flown,<lb/> The story how ye fell;<lb/> Nor
                        wreck, nor change, nor winter's blight,<lb/> Nor Time's remorseless
                        doom,<lb/> Shall dim the ray of holy light,<lb/> That gilds your glorious
                        tomb.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem honors the Confederate dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
