<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.12.18">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/14/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-18">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Conservative Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The proceedings of the CONSERVATIVE CONVENTION, including the speeches of
                        Hon. A. H. Stuart and R. M. T. Hunter, are published in another column. It
                        was a significant gathering of the Conservative wisdom and influence and
                        spirit of the Old Dominion well worthy of her past glorious history. It
                        means that the descendants of the men who made illustrious the Virginia of
                        other days, and sternly resolved that the goodly heritage shall not pass to
                        the spoiler without at least one more manly struggle: it shows that there is
                        life in the old land yet.</p>
                    <p>The number of delegates in attendance reached near one thousand. Almost every
                        single county in the State was represented. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >personnel</emph> of the delegations was of the highest type; the wisest
                        and best men of the whole State, such as the people are wont to look to, and
                        to rely upon in times of real importance; no mere gathering of politicians
                        to advance the comparatively petty interests of party, but the men whose
                        hands and hearts comprehended the true interests and welfare of the whole
                        Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>The very organization of the Convention illustrated its character. The
                        selection for its presiding officers of such men as A. H. H. Stuart, R. M.
                        T. Hunter, S. McD. Moore, T. S. Bocock, Flournoy, Newton and others, men
                        known to the entire country, as statesmen and patriots, was significant of
                        solemnly earnest work. And the deportment of the whole body throughout its
                        entire proceedings was most remarkable--in such a large number--for its
                        dignity and courtesy and genteel demeanor, all indicative of a true
                        appreciation of the high and important duty, and the critical character of
                        the occasion for which they had assembled. No vainglorious or empty
                        haranguing--such as too often marks voluntary popular gatherings--no
                        [unclear] aimless declaration was for an instant tolerated. And although
                        there was felt and manifested a deep yearning to hear the eloquent and sage
                        counsels of their old leaders present, still that feeling was repressed and
                        all remained satisfied with the wisdom of the significant speech of ex-Gov.
                        Letcher, who in answer to earnest calls simply said:--<emph rend="italic">"A
                            still tongue marks a wise head."</emph></p>
                    <p>The resolutions passed were short and pertinent but positive and sufficient.
                        They manifest the skills and cool spirit of men who know their rights and
                        knowing dare maintain them. They are at the same time just to all and
                        responsive to all the obligations of good citizenship. The address--when
                        prepared by the very able Committee appointed for that purpose--will
                        doubtless be distinguished by the same characteristics. The organization
                        adopted is the same that was inaugurated in Augusta county and is now faring
                        so well here. It will ensure the registration and voting of every
                        conservative citizen of Virginia at the next election, and permit no more
                        fatal derelictions of a solemn and patriotic duty.</p>
                    <p>The assemblage and action of such a Convention can but come to great
                        good--both in its effects upon our own people, and upon those just and
                        patriotic people in the North who are now striving in our interests, and in
                        the interests of a common humanity against the mad, frenzied and murderous
                        spirit of revenge and hate which would crush us while helpless to the earth.
                        Let us all then take hope and courage, and press on calmly and firmly <emph
                            rend="italic">keeping the "touch of the elbow,"</emph> and make this one
                        more manly effort in the cause of sheer justice and right, and to enhance
                        the common glory of our now common country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises the action of the Convention of Conservative white voters
                    which met in Richmond. They characterized it as a last "manly" effort against
                    Republican policies, and praised the adoption of the district system of
                    organization which is sure to turn out and register voters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Conservative Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Conservative Convention assembled in the New Richmond Theatre on the 11th
                        inst., and organized by electing the following permanent officers of the
                        Convention:<lb/> President--Hon. A. H. H. Stuart.<lb/> Vice Presidents--Hon.
                        R. M. T. Hunter, Hon. S. McD. Moore, Hon. T. S. Bocock, Hon. R. S. Preston,
                        Hon. T. S. Flournoy, Gen. J. L. Kemper, C. W. Newton, Esq., Hon. W. H.
                        Macfarland, Col. Geo. W. Bolling, Wood Bouldin, Esq.<lb/> Secretaries--Henry
                        K. Ellyson, W. R. Coleman, James McDonald, and J. Bell Bigger.</p>
                    <p>The President, on being conducted to the chair by Messrs. Funsten and Turner,
                        said:</p>
                    <p>Gentlemen of the convention: I thank you for the honor you have done me in
                        calling me to preside over a convention which embodies so large a share of
                        the virtue, intelligence, and patriotism of Virginia.</p>
                    <p>We have assembled, gentlemen, under circumstances of peculiar interest and
                        solemnity. This is no convention to advance the interests of a mere party.
                        Thank Heaven, if the late fearful conflict has done no other good, it has
                        effaced all old party lines and subdued all old party animosities. We come
                        together not as Whigs or Democrats, but as Virginians, earnestly devoted to
                        the promotion of the interests and honor of our common mother.</p>
                    <p>Nor have we come together in any factious spirit or with any aggressive
                        purpose.</p>
                    <p>Whatever opinions individual members of this Convention may have entertained
                        in the past as to the right of a State to withdraw from the Union, I think I
                        may safely affirm that they have been abandoned as impracticable. The
                        questions arising out of those opinions have been referred to the
                        arbitrament of arms, and having been decided adversely, all now feel that
                        they are bound in honor, as well as impelled by interest, to stand by the
                        award.</p>
                    <p>The people of Virginia now desire repose, and they earnestly seek a
                        restoration of their constitutional relations to the Union as the best means
                        of affording it. They feel, too, that the material interests of all parts of
                        our widely extended country are impaired, and our liberties imperiled by the
                        longer continuance of the present unhappy strifes, and we seek a restoration
                        of the Union as the most efficient remedy for all the evils of which we
                        complain.</p>
                    <p>When the war ceased we were told that if we annulled our ordinances of
                        secession, and repudiated the Confederate debt, and perfected the
                        emancipation of our slaves by adopting the constitutional amendment, who
                        would be restored to our constitutional rights. To these conditions we
                        promptly acceded, because they involved no sacrifice of our self-respect and
                        were attended by no national degradation. We have faithfully fulfilled all
                        these conditions, and yet our rights are withheld. May we not, under these
                        circumstances, appeal to the justice and good faith of the North for the
                        redemption of the promises thus made to us?</p>
                    <p>Looking to events which have happened in other Southern States, the people of
                        Virginia have been led to fear that a policy is to be inaugurated here which
                        tends, if it be not designed, to subvert our whole social fabric and to
                        bring the land of Washington, Henry, Jefferson, Madison and Marshall under
                        the dominion of an alien and inferior race. We should be false to all the
                        instincts of humanity--false to the blood which courses through our
                        veins--false to every obligation of duty to ourselves, our kindred, and our
                        country, if we did not earnestly protest against and seek to arrest so
                        fearful a calamity.</p>
                    <p>We hope our fears may be unfounded. We hope we may be spared this attempted
                        degradation. But it is the part of prudence to guard against all
                        contingencies. It is for this purpose that we have met to take counsel
                        together to-day. We wish with one united voice in appeal to the patriotic
                        people of the North to come to our relief and stay the hands of those who
                        would oppress and degrade us.</p>
                    <p>We desire further to perfect our organization, so that all who desire that
                        this shall continue to be a white man's government may be able to act in
                        concert, and by one vigorous and united effort save ourselves from ruin and
                        disgrace. We prefer military rule to the despotism of an ignorant rabble.
                        And we wish to declare with earnestness and emphasis, that, come what may,
                        we and those we represent can never agree that this shall be any other than
                        a white man's government. Our rights may be wrested from us by violence, but
                        we will never agree that our proud old mother shall be presented in the
                        attitude of consenting to her own degradation.</p>
                    <p>THE SECOND DAY'S PROCEEDINGS</p>
                    <p>Convention called to order by the President, and alter prayer by Rev. Mr.
                        Peterkin, the business committee made their report which was adopted
                        unanimously.</p>
                    <p>They reported a plan of general organization of the Conservative voters of
                        the State, and advised that a committee of five be appointed to prepare and
                        publish an address on behalf of the people of Virginia, to the people of the
                        United States.</p>
                    <p>COMMITTEE ON ADDRESS</p>
                    <p>The following are the committee appointed by the President: Wm. C. Rives, R.
                        M. T. Hunter, John Janny, James Marshall and T. R. Tucker.</p>
                    <p>Several other important matters were referred to the committee.</p>
                    <p>Among them an address to the Senate and House of Representatives of the
                        United States; another address to the Senate and House of Representatives in
                        Congress assembled.</p>
                    <p>A resolution proposing a committee to confer with General Schofield, upon the
                        propriety of disarming the negroes of the Commonwealth and suppressing
                        military drills among them.</p>
                    <p>A resolution to the effect that this is a White man's government, and that it
                        is the mission of the Conservative party, North and South, to preserve it as
                        such.</p>
                    <p>A resolution that it is expedient for the convention to memorialize Congress
                        on the subject of our grievances, and also to address the people of the
                        Northern, Western, and Eastern States on the same subject.</p>
                    <p>A resolution by Mr. Turner, of Richmond, that an address to the people of
                        Virginia be prepared by the committee and reported to the convention, and
                        also a plan of organization for the State at large.</p>
                    <p>All of which the committee have had under consideration; but from the extent
                        and magnitude of the topics presented, and the shortness of time, which
                        could be employed in maturing such measures as they suggest, (farther than
                        they are embraced in the former part of this report) the committee recommend
                        that these several matters be referred to the Central Executive Committee,
                        should one be appointed, to be properly disposed of.</p>
                    <p>All which the committee respectfully submitted.</p>
                    <p>The Convention adopted the following Declaration of Principles.</p>
                    <p>1. This Convention doth recognize that by the result of the late war, slavery
                        has been abolished; and doth declare that it is not the purpose or desire of
                        the people of Virginia to reduce or subject again to slavery the people
                        emancipated by the events of the war; and by the amendment to the
                        Constitution of the United States.</p>
                    <p>2. This Convention doth declare that Virginia of right should be restored to
                        her federal relations with the Government of the United States; and that it
                        is not in the contemplation of the people of Virginia to violate or impair
                        her obligations to the Federal Union, but to perform them in good faith.</p>
                    <p>3. This Convention doth solemnly declare and assert that the people of
                        Virginia are entitled to all the rights and freedom and all the guarantees
                        there-for provided by the Constitution of the United States, and they insist
                        on the same as unquestionable; and the Constitution, which all are sworn to
                        support, does not justify the governing of Virginia by any power not
                        delegated by it, nor ought she, under it, to be controlled by the Federal
                        Government, except in strict accordance with its terms and limitations.</p>
                    <p>4. This Convention doth declare, in the language of a resolution adopted by a
                        public meeting held at the Cooper Institute, in the city of New York, that
                        the policy which continues to subject the people of ten States of the Union
                        to an irresponsible government, carried on by military power, is
                        inconsistent with the express provisions of the Constitution of the United
                        States, and is subversive to the fundamental ideas of our Government and of
                        civil liberty; and the object of which this great wrong has been persisted
                        in is now being disclosed to the people and to the world, to wit; to subject
                        the white people of those States to the absolute supremacy, in their local
                        governments and in their representation in the Senate and the House of
                        Representatives, of the black race, just emerged from personal servitude, is
                        abhorrent to the civilization of mankind, and involves us and the people of
                        the Northern States in the consequences of surrendering one-third of the
                        Senate and one-quarter of the House of Representatives, which are to
                        legislate over us, to the dominion of an organized class of emancipated
                        slaves, who are without any of the training, habits or traditions of
                        self-government.</p>
                    <p>5. This Convention, for the people of Virginia, doth declare that they
                        disclaim all hostility to the black population; that they sincerely desire
                        to see them advance in intelligence and material prosperity, and are willing
                        to extend to them a liberal and generous protection; but that, while in the
                        opinion of this Convention any Constitution of Virginia ought to make all
                        men equal before the law, and should protect the liberty and property of
                        all, yet this Convention doth distinctly declare that the Governments of the
                        States and of the Union were formed by white men, to their control, and that
                        suffrage should be still so regulated by the States as to continue the
                        Federal and State systems under the control and direction of the white race.</p>
                    <p>6. That in the opinion of this Convention the people of Virginia will
                        sincerely co-operate with all men throughout the Union, of whatever name or
                        party, who will labor to restore the Constitutional Union of the States, and
                        to continue its Government and those of the States under the control of the
                        white race.</p>
                    <p>On motion of John T. Anderson, of Botetourt, it was resolved that the
                        executive committee, when appointed by the Chair, take speedy means to test
                        the validity of the reconstruction acts before the Supreme Court.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Avlett and the mover of the resolution advocated its passage.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Hon. John B. Baldwin, the Chair was given time to appoint the
                        committee of thirty three, as provided by the report of the committee above
                        mentioned.</p>
                    <p>Hon. Samuel McDowell Moore stated, that as the Convention had done all the
                        good it could, and if it remained longer in session might do harm, he moved
                        to adjournment <emph rend="italic">sine die</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The motion was agreed to, and thus closed the ablest, the wisest and most
                        prudent convention we ever saw assembled in Virginia.</p>
                    <p>MR. HUNTER'S SPEECH.</p>
                    <p>There were loud calls for Hon. R. M. T. Hunter, when, after some hesitation,
                        he advanced to the front of the stage, and was received with rounds of
                        applause.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Hunter said: He could claim the merit of impartiality for the counsels
                        which he was about to give his countrymen, as he had no interest in the
                        proceedings of this or any political body except those which every citizen
                        has in the good government of the country to which he belongs. He had a
                        sentiment however which was stronger than any interest could be; and that
                        was for the promotion of the welfare and preservation of the honor of his
                        native State, which was dearer to him now in her misfortunes than in the
                        palmy days of her prosperity. He had no political aspirations, and if he
                        had, there was no possible public career before him. He said this not by way
                        of regret or complaint, for whilst he held that no man had a right to throw
                        away any opportunities of usefulness which had been bestowed upon him, yet
                        if they were taken from him he might turn aside to domestic pursuits, which
                        were far more congenial to his tastes than the stormy career of public life.
                        He had, however, a difficulty in offering counsels to which he had never
                        experienced before. He had been a member heretofore of public meetings which
                        had the welfare and honor of Virginia under consideration. But then, there
                        were always some general principles of justice or considerations of
                        expediency upon which he could reason and form some theory, which, whether
                        right or wrong, was satisfactory to himself at least. Now, he was not to
                        consider the questions before us in that point of view, but he was to
                        ascertain, if possible, what would be allowed to us by those who controlled
                        us, and to choose amongst these things what would be best for Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Even in this limited view of the question he was at a loss as to what was
                        before us. If he were to take the recent elections as a test of the feeling
                        of the North, he could hope that the cup of universal negro suffrage would
                        pass from us; but if he must take the reconstruction act as the ultimate and
                        final decree of Congress which must rule us at least for the next two years,
                        then he had only to choose between military government or the control of the
                        colored race. Between these alternatives he had no hesitation in saying that
                        he preferred the military control. Under military government he was
                        controlled by men of his own race; educated men who acted under the
                        responsibilities of their commission and in some degree under the control of
                        a President who we know to be disposed to do us justice, and accord to us,
                        as far as he could, our constitutional rights. If we were to be placed under
                        the control of the black race, in the country between the Potomac and the
                        Rio Grande, it was not difficult to divine the results. We had the
                        experience of Hayti and Jamaica before us. There was no doubt but that it
                        would result in the formation of a black man's party, which would persecute
                        the white man in all possible modes. In Hayti they were suddenly emancipated
                        as in this country, and without adverting to the scenes of atrocity which
                        occurred when they had the control of public affairs, it is enough to say
                        that the result was to destroy all the elements of material prosperity and
                        moral progress. A black man's party was formed and the whites were
                        persecuted until most of them were driven from the country, and he had the
                        authority of an intelligent observer, who has recently been amongst them,
                        that they not only exclude all white men from office, but deny them the
                        privilege of holding real estate. The black men themselves only work by
                        compulsion, and the culture of sugar, of which they made 120,000,000 of
                        pounds in 1789 has disappeared, so of cotton, and so would it have been of
                        coffee if it were not that trees planted long ago still continue to bear. In
                        Jamaica we have the same history as was compatible with the control of the
                        English Government. The same hostility to the white men. The same
                        independence in agricultural production.</p>
                    <p>Could any body doubt but that we should see similar [unclear] the Southern
                        States if the whole country between the Potomac and the Rio Grande should be
                        submitted to the rule of the colored race? The Radical party seemed to think
                        that they would thus secure the support of the whole Southern country so
                        long as the black man should rule. They would find themselves mistaken in
                        this after the first election. The blacks would form not a Radical, but a
                        black man's party, and we know, from the history of party warfare, that all
                        parties would bid for them. They would set for the benefit of themselves,
                        and not for this or that party of the whites, and can there be conceived
                        anything more demoralizing than a party constituting, in the language of one
                        of the resolutions, one-third of the Senate, and a fourth of the House of
                        Representatives who would thus hold the balance of power between the two
                        parties of the white race, and act only for their own good. As Free Lancers
                        in the field, they would determine all disputed questions in reference only
                        to their own interests. He said this in no feeling of hostility to the
                        colored race, but in accordance only with the history of the past. On the
                        contrary, he felt kindly toward the colored race, but thought their welfare
                        was to be promoted in a mode which was contrary, perhaps, to their own view.
                        But there were dangers ahead of them in their present course to which, they
                        had not adverted, and which had been carefully concealed from them. Suppose
                        they could assume the control of the Southern States for the present, how
                        long would it last? Would the white race in the North long endure a state of
                        things in which the blacks, though a minority, would control, by holding the
                        balance of power in all contested political questions? Would they consent to
                        see the material resources and productions of the South wasted and perhaps
                        destroyed which used to yield them so large a harvest of wealth? Would they
                        contribute to the result which was to restore the cultivated field to the
                        wilderness and jungle, and leave the wild beasts and the alligator to reign
                        supreme over those plains and bottoms, which heretofore had been the seats
                        of a refined civilization, and of a production whose profits extended North
                        as well as South? Would they stand by contentedly and see the moral,
                        material and social elements of strength and happiness wasted and almost
                        destroyed to maintain the supremacy of the colored race, which would seem to
                        be the present policy.</p>
                    <p>Every consideration of self-respect and national interest would forbid it.
                        The extreme western limit of agricultural settlement east of Rocky mountains
                        has already been attained. It cannot be long before the tide of agricultural
                        immigration must soon tend Southward. The colored race will not be allowed
                        to hold these immense resources in abeyance. This country belongs to the
                        white man, and they will claim its control. To subject the white race in
                        Virginia to the government of the black race, when it is superior in
                        numbers, wealth and intelligence, would be to commit one of the highest of
                        all sins, a sin against nature. Would any party in loyal States permit the
                        blacks to give the power of the government to a minority amongst themselves
                        when they had only to call into action their own strength to avert? Was
                        there ever a race superior in numbers, wealth and intelligence to those who
                        governed them who tamely submitted to be so ruled?</p>
                    <p>I throw out these considerations not merely to encourage my own fellow
                        citizens and brethren, but for the black race itself, whom I have kindly
                        feelings. I was not only reared amongst them and feel the kindly ties of
                        early associations, but I acknowledge the obligation which rests upon us to
                        give them all the opportunities of progress and development which we can
                        afford them in justice to ourselves. That the reaction will come, I have no
                        doubt, but I fear it will come in a mode which I should regret as a friend
                        to civilization and humanity, and to the black race itself. And suppose for
                        the sake of a brief period of control which is given them, not for their own
                        sakes, but to secure the supremacy of the Radical party they should thus get
                        up a contest between the races and incur the hostility of the whites, what
                        will become of them when the reaction comes? I shudder to think of the
                        result. If the Radicals appeal to the black race to sustain them, will not
                        the other party invoke the aid of the whites, who are so much more powerful
                        in all the natural elements of strength in the country in which they may be
                        brought into competition. I speak not only in the interests of the white,
                        but also of the black race when I protest against my system of laws which
                        seeks to place the weaker and inferior race in control over that which is
                        superior in wealth, numbers and intelligence. After all, the citizens of any
                        community have more interest in its good government than in the question of
                        who shall direct it. I will not offer the advice, because it will not be
                        received in the spirit in which it is offered, but far better would it be
                        for the blacks to leave the government of the country where they found it.
                        If they do not provoke the hostility of the white race, they will be treated
                        not only with justice but generosity. If they are made equal in the eye of
                        the law and protected in all their rights, would they not be in a far better
                        position to leave the government to the whites, who are best fitted for it?
                        I am sure I speak not only my own feelings, but those also of the white
                        citizens of Virginia, when I say that at present we would tolerate no
                        government which did not respect not only their freedom, but their just
                        rights of person and property.</p>
                    <p>But Mr. President it may be that they will heed no advice which I can give
                        them. The Radical party which now controls Congress may retain that for two
                        years yet to come, and they may force on us a state of things contrary not
                        only to justice, but sound policy. There will be nothing left to us then but
                        patient endurance until the reaction comes. That it will come I do not doubt
                        for a moment, and if it should bring consequences to the black race which we
                        shall all deplore, we shall not be responsible for it. Mr. President, I know
                        what I recommend when I counsel patient endurance and manly fortitude to the
                        people of Virginia, if this state of things should occur. It will be best
                        for our beloved State that it should be so. The present generation has
                        suffered, still suffers, and perhaps may continue, for some time to come, to
                        suffer. He's what is the life time of one generation in the existence of a
                        State. Virginia will revile and fulfill a destiny as bright probably as the
                        most ardent son ever wished for her. Trials, difficulties and sufferings
                        constitute the discipline by which individuals and States are trained to
                        moral and heroic excellence. What individual ever attempted greatness who
                        was reared in the lap of ease and luxury, and was not trained for some part
                        of his life in the school of adversity? What nation has achieved excellence
                        in greatness which was not disciplined in the same school? England had what
                        is called its rebellion, a period of some cruelty and much suffering, and
                        yet from that rebellion sprung some of those acts which are the proudest
                        moments of the liberty of the subjects, and more than all the resolution in
                        which were laid broad and deep the foundations of British freedom and
                        prosperity.</p>
                    <p>The revolution of France was far more terrible. The wisest men trembled for
                        her future, and yet from that revolution sprang that equality of all men
                        before the law and the throwing open all the roles of life to the free and
                        equal competition of all which gave a new impulse to the energy of the
                        nation and placed it at the head of the European powers. Who shall say that
                        the present period may not prove a new seed of progress and a new germ of
                        growth in the career of Virginia. I think I already see its effects in the
                        rising generation. The times are teaching them habits of self-denial and
                        self-reliance, which contributes so much to give strength of character and
                        self-respect. The feeling of patriotism is intensified by the present
                        condition of the good Commonwealth, and every true son feels a redoubled
                        desire to redeem her from her present depression and to reconstruct her
                        morally and nationally. Mr. President, they will do it! The young men of
                        Virginia will do it. Let them meet their present difficulties with manly
                        fortitude, a noble constancy. The State has been dismembered, it is true,
                        but she is still a great State, large in territory and abounding in
                        resources. I speak in no language of compliment, when I say that I believe
                        we have the people who will develop these resources. To speak the language
                        of flattery in these times would be vain and wicked. But the past justifies
                        my confidence in my fellow citizens; they have been equal to all emergencies
                        in the past, they will meet the difficulties of the present in a proper
                        spirit. We are poor, very poor, it is true, but our hands, I trust, will be
                        endured with a patient fortitude and manly constancy.</p>
                    <p>There is wealth in the earth--let us plough, dig and mine for it. There is
                        wealth in our falling waters and running streams. They will turn the mill
                        and build up manufactories. There is wealth, too--stores of wealth--in our
                        black diamonds; they will make the steam which drives the car, propels the
                        boat and turns the wheel. We have streams to bear away the fleets of
                        commerce as far as the tide may flow and we have forests to build those
                        fleets. It is for the people of Virginia to say whether we have not the men
                        to develop those resources. I believe that we have. I have confidence in my
                        fellow-citizens. I believe that there is great and glorious destiny yet in
                        store for Virginia. I have given, I think, a reason for the faith that is in
                        me. But, Mr. President, I confess that I, too, have my moments of
                        despondency. When I think of what Virginia has been, of all that she has
                        done for the Union, her sister States and for mankind, and then reflect upon
                        her present condition, I may say, in the eloquent words of another, that
                        thoughts, feelings and emotions crowd upon my mind which I cannot altogether
                        repress, and yet which in humble submission to divine Providence I dare not
                        express. But I thank God that this is not my permanent state of mind. I do
                        not despair. The present hours of darkness and despondency will soon pass
                        away, and Virginia, if not exactly her old self, will be a great State
                        again. The time must come when she will hitch on to the Federal train as
                        great as any in her constitution of freight and passengers, and who shall
                        say that the trumpet of leadership may not be placed once more in her hands.
                        Mr. President, every man has some times a belief for which he cannot exactly
                        account and which seems to come to him more from intuition than reason.
                        Such, perhaps is in fact the foundation of my faith in the future greatness
                        and prosperity of Virginia. I believe, sir, that the seed of Anglo-American
                        civilization was first sown on the silent banks of the James for some divine
                        purpose. It is now nearly three centuries since the Anglo-Saxon came, the
                        master builder of forms of government, with his compass and square to lay
                        the foundations of the immense social fabric which we now see around us,
                        embracing almost every variety of climate and race which are known upon
                        earth. From that seed sprang the "Old Dominion," the mother of States and of
                        statesmen. The "Mother of States," for every State south of the isothermal
                        line of the northern line is numerously stored with the descendants of
                        Virginia sires. Kentucky was her eldest daughter, and under her great
                        pioneer, George Roger Clarke, acquired the territories which now comprises
                        most of the Northeastern States, already the seat of empire freely bestowed
                        by Virginia upon the Confederacy for purposes of peace and harmony. The
                        mother of statesmen, all acknowledge her to have been. It was she who gave
                        to the Revolution the leader of its armies and to the Union the man more
                        than any other who may be considered its founder and the preserver of it in
                        infancy. It was she who gave the author of the Declaration of Independence,
                        and the long line of Virginia Presidents under whose guidance the beginnings
                        of empire were laid which are the most painful steps in a nation's progress.
                        Her great mission seems to have been to promote individual liberty as far as
                        was consistent with the existence of democratic republican government. We
                        appeal to history to sustain the assertion that whenever the Federal
                        Government was under the influence of Virginia principles the people were
                        harmonious, prosperous and happy, and so soon as that government departed
                        from those principles trials and discontent have arisen. The old state of
                        things has passed away; concentration and consolidation are now the order of
                        the day. Time will make up the issue between the old state of things and the
                        new; history will record that issue, and impartial posterity will pronounce
                        the verdict. I will not undertake to predict what it will be, but as a
                        Virginian, I do not fear the result.</p>
                    <p>Mr. president, I hope for better things, but still I will look to the future
                        in its worst aspect. Suppose that a temporary supremacy of the black race
                        should be forced upon us. We must meet it with a manly fortitude, a patient
                        endurance; we must do nothing inconsistent with our self respect or wound
                        the honor of our people, which to nations is the pearl of great price.
                        Patiently we will bide our time until the reaction comes, as assuredly it
                        must. The interests of the North will not endure the waste of so much of the
                        sources of its wealth and prosperity, and may I not hope that its feelings
                        will also forbid our subjection to such domination. Such a state of things
                        cannot last. We could not even be threatened with such a danger if the
                        passions and bitterness of the contest had not obscured the judgement of
                        those who now govern. These passions must subside before long, and the
                        volcano will burn out. For this I trust not only to natural causes, but to
                        Providence, which will not permit the destiny of such a State to be marred
                        or leave its tale "half untold."</p>
                    <p>In conclusion, fellow citizens, as Lord Elder and amongst the best of his
                        utterances, "I submit the cause of my country to that Great Being, who can
                        say to the madness of the people as he can say to the raging waves of the
                        ocean--Hither shall thou come, no further."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the proceedings of the Conservative Convention that met in
                    Richmond which included resolutions and addresses by Alexander H. H. Stuart and
                    R. M. T. Hunter. Both men stressed that the government of Virginia is a "white
                    man's government" and that conservative voters must unite to ensure that it
                    stays that way. They also touched on national politics and race relations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Professor A. J. Turner plans to give a concert of vocal and instrumental
                    music at the chapel of the Deaf, Dumb and Blind Institute. "We attended the
                    concert given by Prof. T. on last year at the Institution which was so far
                    superior to anything of the kind that we have visited."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Churches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Episcopal:--West Main Street, Rev. J. A. Latane, pastor. Sunday services, 10
                        A. M. and 8 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Roman Catholic:--Augusta Street, Father J. A. Weed. Sunday services, 10 1/2
                        A. M., 3 1/2 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Baptist:--West Main Street, Rev. Geo. B. Taylor, Pastor. Sunday services, 11
                        A. M. and 6 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Presbyterian:--Frederick Street, Rev. Wm. E. Baker, Pastor. Sunday services,
                        11 A. M. and 7 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Lutheran:--Main St., Rev. J. I. Miller, Pastor. Sunday services, 11 A. M. and
                        7 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Methodist:--Lewis Street, Rev. John L. Clarke, Pastor. Sunday services, 11 A.
                        M. and 7 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Colored.</p>
                    <p>African Methodist Episcopal:--West Main Street, Rev. Jacklin Strange, Pastor.
                        Sunday services, 11 A. M. and 7 P. M.</p>
                    <p>Methodist:--North New Street, Rev. E. Lawson, Pastor. Sunday services, 11 A.
                        M. and 7 P. M.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strange</ln>
                        <fn>Jacklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the addresses, pastors and hours of service of all of
                    Staunton's churches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Kinnie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David E. Sibert, of Bridgewater, and Miss Kinnie H. Sibert, of Mt. Solon,
                    were married on December 10th by the Rev. G. Stevenson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Edward I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Addie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward I. Evans, of Winchester, and Miss Addie M. Lushbaugh, of Staunton,
                    were married on December 12th by the Rev. J. L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooke</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodge</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George P. Baker, of Staunton, and Miss Mattie L. Cooke, formerly of
                    Staunton, were married in Richmond on December 12th by the Rev. M. D. Hodge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
