<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.07.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-10">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.10.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Valedictory Delivered at the D. D. and B. Institution, June 27th, 1867.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints the valedictory address given at the commencement ceremony
                    of Staunton's Deaf, Dumb and Blind Institution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper brands Radical Republicans hypocrites for their "war cry" of
                    "extermination of the Indians, while they whine like spaniels over the wrongs of
                    the negro."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Conquerors and the Conquered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Earl of Chatham proclaimed in the British Parliament, very near a century
                        ago, "that three million Anglo-Saxon Americans, fighting for their
                        independence and rights, as free born men, once over-powered and conquered
                        and held down by military force, would be sufficient, when wielded by
                        despotic power, to crush the liberties of the rest of the British empire."</p>
                    <p>His profound observation is likely to be soon confirmed in the history of the
                        American Republic. The stronger section of the Union, wielding the whole
                        power of the common government, succeeded in crushing, by arms, the
                        aspirations of the weaker section for independence and self-government. In
                        order to carry out their arduous undertaking, the Northern people(for the
                        time only, as they fondly supposed,) consented to surrender their liberties
                        into the keeping of the government at Washington.</p>
                    <p>The war has closed--the North has conquered, the South lies prostrate and
                        helpless at the feet of the government. The Radical party, which assumes to
                        be the government, is fast drawing full power of the State and people toward
                        the Central Despotism, which despotism it is determined at all hazards to
                        control in its own interests. This despotic action became restive and
                        alarmed the shadow of the despotism which held the South in subjection to
                        the North; the signs of the times indicates only that a huge majority of the
                        citizens of the Northern States will be [unclear] approaching general
                        election [unclear] the party in power. But the people of the original free
                        States will bestow the officials of the Electoral College and in the hall of
                        Congress, with the overwhelming powers which they have confided to the
                        Central Despotism, for the purpose of crushing the liberties of the South.
                        The vote of fourteen Southern States; for Kentucky and Maryland will
                        inevitably meet the fate of their Southern Sisters, which they hoped to
                        avoid by "loyalty" to "the old flag," together with the minority vote of the
                        North, which will likely be cast for the Radicals, will give that
                        unscrupulous party another four years leave of power, and less time than
                        that will suffice for their reckless boldness and energy to complete their
                        scheme of despotism for the whole country.</p>
                    <p>We may be considered visionary in these prognostications, but no careful and
                        candid observer of the times can doubt that this is the programme. By
                        disfranchisement of the whites and enfranchisement of the negroes, the
                        Radicals expect to use the whole influence of the South to consolidate and
                        perpetuate the power of their party, in spite of the protests of the North;
                        or in other words to use the conquered to subdue the conquerors.</p>
                    <p>In an able article, that sterling journal the National Intelligencer, well
                        and truly says: "The programme is plainly developed. There is not space in a
                        single article to comment on it; but it is but simply this; The Radical
                        party managers, foreseeing their loss of political power in the Northern
                        States, are preparing to make up their losses by the means of a military
                        despotism in the South. Fearing the influence of the Border States, they
                        have determined to reduce Kentucky and Maryland, to begin with, to the same
                        status as the ten Southern States hitherto subjected to Radical military
                        control. Having by fraud and violence, by the outrageous disfranchisement of
                        white voters, and the fraudulent manipulation of the negro vote, secured to
                        themselves the political power of the twelve, and with Tennessee, thirteen
                        States, they would be ready to deal [section unclear]. [Section unclear]from
                        New York and Pennsylvania and Indiana, and other Northern States will be
                        subjected to precisely the same process as that already applied to Kentucky,
                        and soon to be applied to Maryland.</p>
                    <p>Thus military despotism, with all its attendant frauds and outrages, will be
                        extended over State after State throughout the whole Union. This is what is
                        in store for the deluded and betrayed people of the loyal Northern and
                        Western States. Their loyalty and their rights under the Constitution are to
                        be measured only by their allegiance to the Radical revolutionary
                    cabal."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that the Radical Republicans are using their control
                    of Congress and the military to impose a military despotism upon the country.
                    Since they cannot hold power legitimately, they will use the powers and rights
                    surrendered to them during the war to perpetuate their rule.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper mocks the Republican's outrage at a comment attributed to Miss
                    Annie Surratt which compared the shooting of Lincoln to the "shooting of any
                    poor nigger in the army." "Is not a 'nigger' a 'man and brother,' and is it not
                    self-evident that 'all men are born free and equal?'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Situation in Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have before us a private letter post marked Spring Hill, June 29th, from
                        an officer, distinguished and trusted by our people during the war, now
                        devoting himself to practical "reconstruction" on his farm in Tennessee. It
                        furnishes, in his peculiar way, points of so great interest that we feel it
                        our duty to take the liberty of giving them to the public. he says: "The
                        darkeys here are doing remarkably well, in spite of the most persistent
                        efforts on the part of fanatics and Radicals to make them troublesome. They
                        are getting up 'Loyal Leagues,' and all sorts of abominations, to place them
                        in opposition to their old owners, but so far, without success. The blacks
                        join the processions and seem much flattered by the speeches &amp;c.;
                        sing patriotic songs, and roar at the jokes but have been industrious and
                        obedient thus far. I have tried to catch a cunning old horse, who would eat
                        the ear of corn, but, on sight of the bridle, would suddenly recollect some
                        good grass in another part of the field." This is decidedly the best
                        illustration of the "negro question" we have seen, and the Radicals will
                        appreciate it, when they "show the bridle."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from a letter from a Tennessee farmer argues that African
                    Americans are only half-hearted about following the Radicals. Their
                    participation in clubs and rallies is a result of manipulation, and so far they
                    have really remained "obedient."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Who are to Blame?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Examiner puts the blame for the people's want of interest in registering,
                        in the right places. But then the people should find new leaders, and
                        recollect that the great revolution left their old ones five hundred miles
                        behind the age. It says:</p>
                    <p>"But the general and deplorable apathy which prevails in this State is due,
                        we are ashamed to say, to the unpardonable interests of those leaders to
                        whom the masses have heretofore looked for instruction. Eloquent men, where
                        voices have again and again aroused the people upon ordinary political
                        occasions, have been silent at this crisis in the fate of the white race in
                        Virginia, and yet, if the State is wrested from us by this trick of
                        registration, these gentlemen will be the heaviest sufferers from the very
                        calamity which they might have averted.</p>
                    <p>There is no section of the State where the people would not turn out <emph
                            rend="italic">en masse</emph> if they were properly aroused. In a county
                        near this city, where the blacks greatly outnumbered the whites, a talented
                        and eloquent gentleman delivered an address to the people in one of the
                        magisterial districts, where it was believed the blacks would have
                        outnumbered the whites in registration, two or three to one. In that
                        district the registration has since taken place, and, to the surprise of
                        all, the white has equalled the black population. And this is in a district
                        where there were many more blacks than whites!</p>
                    <p>We mean in this to show, that by the lightest effort of the thirty or forty
                        thousand majority which we have in the State might readily be induced to
                        register and vote. A single speech in each magisterial district will do the
                        work, and if there are not workers enough in the State to do it, we deserve
                        to be defeated."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that white men must be encouraged to register to
                    vote. If an effort is made in this direction, whites will be assured of
                    outnumbering blacks at the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Triumphs of Radicalism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Military Commissions and their murdered victim,--a corrupt judiciary, packed
                        juries, perjured witnesses and suborners of perjury in high places of power.
                        A press, licentious and subsidized on the one hand, and gagged and
                        suppressed on the other. A country, once governed by a Constitution and
                        laws, now given over to the reckless and despotic will of the mob which
                        happens to be in power. A Union declared by its founder to be "perpetual,"
                        and for the preservation of which millions of lives and treasure were given,
                        deliberately, by solemn legislative enactment, dissolved for partisan ends.
                        A country, which a wise and conciliatory policy would long since have
                        restored to peace and prosperity, still, through the malignity of party,
                        "rent with evil feuds." A constitution, once the pride and hope of mankind,
                        torn and trampled contemptuously under the foot of party. Four millions,
                        happy, well fed and contented laborers, elevated to liberty, suffrage and
                        pauperism. A military supremacy, which rivals and puts to shame the
                        "tottering and effete Despotisms" of the old world. A national debt, in
                        comparison with which, both as to its vast proportions and the rapidity of
                        its accumulation, all other national debts sink to insignificance. A
                        grinding and unequal taxation which the people cannot and will not
                        stand--and probable repudiation, bankruptcy and national dishonor.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper lists the "accomplishments" of the Radical Republican government
                    ranging from a corrupt judiciary and censored press to high debt and high taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Freedmen and their Contracts</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that "the political agitations and league
                    organizations are beginning to work fearful mischief in the rural districts," as
                    Freedmen are increasingly breaking their work contracts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that "our Valley exchanges denounce Dr. Brown, colored,
                    as an incendiary radical in his teachings."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John K. Forrer of Augusta's Mossy Creek Iron Works is growing grapes on his
                    estate and plans to establish a vineyard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>70 to 150 tourists headed west to the Springs in the last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that butter, eggs, and other dairy products are in short
                    supply in Staunton due to harvest time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. John B. Baldwin was elected president of the County Fair Committee and
                    Prof. Jed Hotchkiss Secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Dr. Brown, "colored, who has lately been speaking
                    through the Valley," formed a Union League in Harrisonburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Manganese</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Shelton and Company are working vigorously on the manganese mines at Back
                    Creek, Augusta County. "They have lately opened several large and profitable
                    mines."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A delegation from Augusta left to attend a White Sulphur Springs Railroad
                    Convention. "Our reporter will be there. Take care of him Major Woodward, and
                    everybody else."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Good News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The largest oat crop in ten years is reportedly being grown in the Valley.
                    Corn and all the other crops are also doing well. "Truly we have no reason to
                    grumble or give way to despair."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>University Graduates From Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>DeWitt C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The following students from Augusta obtained University degrees: DeWitt C.
                    Gallaher of Waynseboro in Latin, Greek and Moral Philosophy; Charles Gallaher,
                    of Waynesboro, in French; S. Travers Phillips, of Staunton, in Spanish and
                    Chemistry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Cruise Through a Model Mill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A newspaper correspondent declares John J. Cupp's mill at Mt. Solon a model
                    to be envied. "His beautiful and docile spring twirls 3 pair of burrs and one
                    country stone at the rate of 120 revolutions per minute."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Fourth--Firemen's Excursion to Goshen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Early Dawn," as Stonewall Jackson used to say, in his orders for moving,
                        found the Augusta Fire Company, their invited guests, and numbers of ladies
                        and gentlemen of Staunton, at the Depot ready for an excursion to Goshen.
                        The "old familiar voice" of the Stonewall Band welcomed the crowd and gave
                        promise of the enjoyment before us. The Committee of Arrangements, headed by
                        the indefatigable and indispensable, John M. Harly, had made ample
                        preparations for the accommodation of all, and the train was soon speeding
                        its way westward, the cheers of the "boys," at everything and everybody on
                        the road, enlivening the way and making one think of the troop trains of
                        other days. At Swoope's Depot a slight accident occurred, which was soon
                        remedied by our pleasant Conductor, Capt. B. G. Warthen. The thirty minutes
                        stay there gave several lazy, nosyly married men, who got up too late for
                        breakfast in Staunton, an opportunity to enjoy a good breakfast at the
                        hospitable table of Mrs. Jacob Dull, over which streak of luck they bragged
                        all day. At nine the train arrived at Goshen, where the party was welcomed
                        by Mr. H. A. Goodloe, Proprietor, and soon every one was made comfortable
                        and felt at home. Some went fishing, others rolled ten-pins, while the
                        majority tripped the "light fantastic toe" to the music of Coleman's String
                        Band. A number of ladies and gentlemen, from the neighborhood, joined the
                        party, and showed it every attention. In the evening, after repeated calls,
                        Y. Howe Peyton, Esq., delivered a spirited and telling address. He was
                        followed by other gentlemen, after which the party took the cars and
                        returned to Staunton, by 8 o'clock, P. M.</p>
                    <p>Taking it, all in all, this excursion was successful beyond the anticipations
                        of the most sanguine. Nothing occurred to disturb the enjoyment of any one
                        present and the best order was observed by all. The party are under many
                        obligations to Mr. Goodloe for his untiring exertions to render the day
                        pleasant. His house was open, his table supplied with everything desirable
                        and his servants all attention. To fully appreciate an excursion of this
                        kind, where every one feels at home and everybody is agreeable, a person
                        must be a part of it. No detailed account can give anything like an idea of
                        it. Staunton may well be proud of her Fire Companies, her Stonewall Band,
                        and the representative ladies who honored the excursionists with their
                        presence. May an hundred more glorious Fourths find that joyous party
                        assembled at "Goshen on the [unclear]."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harly</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warthen</ln>
                        <fn>B. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goodloe</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article describes a Fourth of July excursion to Goshen led by the
                    Augusta Fire Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Closing Soiree of the Masonic Female Seminary of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The bad weather kept many from enjoying the excellent performers at the
                    closing exercises of the Masonic Female Seminary. The school, started by the
                    Grand Lodge of Virginia, has "made a favorable beginning."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Corporation Court--July Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harland</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosby</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mays</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Pat</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Denny</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Ed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glenn</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>J. I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolen</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayo</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornley</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Corporation Court met for the July term, Mayor Trout presiding. George
                    Harland, Staunton's jailor, was granted $28.25 for care of the prisoners. The
                    Grand Jury indicted the following: Mosby, Mays, and Jackson, "colored, for
                    disturbing public worship;" Pat Moore, E. Denny, and John Randolph, "colored,
                    for petit larceny;" Ed Taylor, "colored, for assault and battery." The case of
                    W. W. Glenn vs. J. I. A. Trotter and M. G. Harman were postponed until next
                    term. Mrs. B. Bolen was indicted for selling liquor and keeping a livery stable
                    without a license. True bills were found against the following: Thornly, Nelson,
                    and Rodney, "colored, for petit larceny;" Lydia Reed for keeping a house of ill
                    fame; and Tom Harris, "colored, for committing a rape on two colored children
                    aged 7 and 9 years." The trial was set for February. Ellen Mayo and Lydia
                    Jackson were sent to jail for 60 days for petit larceny. Erasmus Denny,
                    "colored," was found guilty and bound out "on motion of his mother." John
                    Randolph, "colored," was sent to jail for 30 days. Henry Thornley, "colored,"
                    was discharged, as was Pat Moore, "rag man." Ed Taylor, "colored," was also
                    discharged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>Leonidas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Leonidas Points and Miss Belle Gordon, of Madison County, were
                    married at the Wesleyan Female Institute on July 4th by the Rev. J. L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartley</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layton</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. B. Bartley and Miss Jane Layton, both of Augusta, were married at the
                    Virginia Hotel on June 19th by the Rev. J. L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander H. H. Stuart, Jr., son of the Hon. Alexander H. H. Stuart, died
                    in Staunton of typhoid fever. He was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
