<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.09.04">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/02/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-04">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Registration returns for all but eight Virginia counties have been received
                    showing 110,000 whites and 90,000 blacks. Four of the counties not yet reporting
                    are expected to have large white majorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Mossy Creek Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are gratified to hear that it is the intention of the good people of North
                        West Augusta to rebuild this institution, which was, for so many years, the
                        pride and ornament of their section. It was a matter of general regret when,
                        during the war, by some accident, the noble building which they had erected
                        at so much expense, took fire and was burned to the ground, leaving only an
                        unsightly pile of ruins instead of a thorough temple of learning; and we are
                        sure that it will be a matter of general gratification if a good and
                        substantial building shall again be reared upon the site of the former Mossy
                        Creek Academy, and a school be again started that shall attain the
                        popularity of the one formerly taught there.</p>
                    <p>We remember with pleasure the days we spent there as a school boy, but a
                        feeling of sadness is mingled with it, when we think of the many noble boys
                        who were there with us that afterwards fell in defence of their native land,
                        in the very prime of their manhood. We could give a long roll call of honor
                        for it. Many of the hands that planted the trees which flourish upon that
                        neglected hill are now mingled with the clods of the Valley. More than 20 of
                        those that were there during the single session of 1854 and '55 now rest in
                        soldier's graves. Rebuild this institution then, we say, if for no other
                        purpose, as a monument to the memory of its fallen braves, and rear up other
                        generations under the shade of the trees they planted to emulate their
                        heroic virtues; put a tablet in its wall; on which their names shall be
                        inscribed, and, with an abiding faith in the judgement of posterity, write
                        upon that tablet the inscription the old man of S. W. Virginia placed upon
                        the grave of his only son and child: "If to die for liberty was right,
                        remember him, if wrong forget him."</p>
                    <p>We need all the old land-marks we can hold on to, for we are drifting wide
                        from our former moorings, and there are none that will serve us a better
                        purpose, in our time of sorest need, than our institutions of higher
                        learning. The demagogue, who would bring the intelligence of society down to
                        the level of the intellect of a half-civilized African (we strongly suspect
                        merely for the selfish purpose that he may get the vote of the negro,) may
                        declaim against such institutions, and demand that everybody shall be taxed
                        to support <emph rend="italic">free</emph> schools for the benefit of
                        everybody--in other words to establish a system that has no freedom in it,
                        and which attempts to educate by lowering the standard of education. We have
                        all heard of these things lately, but we put it to the honest, substantial
                        people who live near, and who built up Mossy Creek Academy, to know if they
                        want any freer or any better system of education than that which they have
                        had, and we would like to know if any one that desired to share its benefits
                        has been debarred the privilege. We do not want foundries where boys shall
                        all be put into the same mould and come out all alike--variety is the spice
                        of life; and we conclude by urging the people of Mossy Creek, and all the
                        rest of our people, to rebuild their schools and set them on the same
                        foundations they had before, and as they have manhood enough not to be
                        ashamed of themselves, let them transmit the same sort to their
                    posterity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds plans to rebuild Mossy Creek Academy which burned down
                    during the war. Its reinstitution will serve as a memorial to the alumni who
                    fought and died during the war, and serve as an example of past civilization,
                    before public schools and the education of African Americans lowered academic
                    standards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Educate the Daughters of our Dead.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brane</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Society for the Liberal Education of Southern Female Children issues an
                    appeal to heads of female schools to admit as many daughters of Confederate dead
                    for free or reduced charges. "Every young daughter of the South, rescued from
                    ignorance, and suitably trained for a life of usefulness, will prove, by God's
                    blessing, a polished stone of that temple which we hope soon to see rising from
                    the present ruin." Society membership costs $5 annually.Interested persons may
                    contact the President, Mrs. William H. Brane, or Corresponding Secretary Mrs.
                    Hugh Lee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial asserts that with the removal of Phil Sheridan from command
                    of the 5th Military District, and Sickles and Stanton from their positions,
                    President Johnson has shown that "there is a point beyond which patience ceases
                    to be a virtue." The Radicals now "seem to have awakened to the fact that they
                    have a foeman worthy of their steel, and are girding on their armor for the
                    death struggle--for power and plunder."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Rich Harvest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that record harvests throughout the United States show
                    that "we are growing more peaceful. We are becoming more wealthy as a nation."
                    Wheat, cotton, tobacco, sugar, rice, fruits and cereals are all yielding bumper
                    crops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Situation as Viewed by a True Virginia Gentleman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A gentleman form South-side Virginia argues that southern whites should not
                    attack reconstruction head-on, but instead fight small battles while complying
                    with as much as possible. Reconstruction must be shown to be a failure of
                    ideology, not of implementation, so Congress is not tempted to try the
                    "experiment" again. The writer fears that black Virginians will not "exercise
                    their new privilege with wisdom or discretion; but that they will array
                    themselves against the whites, from a belief that their interests are at
                    variance with the interests of the whites." This misconception must be cleared
                    up.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>1,502 visitors stayed at the American Hotel during the month of August.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Flour Inspector</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer, Augusta Flour Inspector, inspected 4,150 barrels of flour in
                    Staunton between July 15th and September 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum will discuss the question, "Is it expedient for
                    Virginia to adopt the free school system at this time?" General Echols will
                    argue in the affirmative and Jed Hotchkiss in the negative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walton</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walton</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. C. Walton and Miss Catherine H. Walton, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 30th by the Rev. J. L. Clarke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. L. Grove, aged 27 years, died at the Staunton residence of his mother on
                    August 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas R. Blackburn, aged 73 years, died at the Staunton residence of Capt.
                    J. C. Marquis on August 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.04.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Answer To That Time I Wore the Rebel Grey.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By Lizzie</p>
                    <p>Why sit with thoughts so dark and sad,<lb/> This bright and glorious Summer's
                        day?<lb/> Were I a man, I would be glad,<lb/><emph rend="italic">To think I
                            ever wore the grey</emph>.</p>
                    <p>If she is false, the one you woo'd,<lb/> Now that a cloud is on your
                        way,<lb/> She was not fair enough or good,<lb/> To claim the one who wore
                        they grey.</p>
                    <p>And well you say she cannot be,<lb/> More faire, though clothed in garments
                        gay,<lb/> Than when you fought with Robert Lee,<lb/> And proudly wore the
                        faded grey.</p>
                    <p>But judge not all by one you knew,<lb/> And let the world act as it may,<lb/>
                        For in each heart that's brave or true,<lb/><emph rend="italic">A love yet
                            lingers for the grey</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Yes bitterness is in our heart,<lb/> And never can be done away,<lb/> From us
                        by force, our rights they part,<lb/> Except the one to love the grey.</p>
                    <p>Then proudly rise and take your crutch,<lb/> And feel no king with princely
                        sway,<lb/> The right to pride, has half so much,<lb/> As he who wore the
                        rebel grey.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Appomattox C. H., Aug. 17th, 1867.</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this poem, "Lizzie" encourages the author of "That Time I Wore the Rebel
                    Grey," to be optimistic, proud of his Confederate service, and not to mourn over
                    a lost love.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
