<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.03.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/09/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-03-27">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.27.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Hope For the South</head>
                <origin>N. Y. World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The N. Y. World asserts that the South should retain hope despite the
                    political climate for several reasons. First, their warm climate gives them a
                    comparative advantage over Northern agriculture. Second, cotton is in demand all
                    over the world. Third, the destruction of slavery means that land owners no
                    longer need to pay for all aspects of their workers' upkeep.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>110 visitors arrived at the American Hotel last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Future</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The despondency and doubt that now oppress our people are, naturally, the
                        consequence of "hope deferred which maketh the heart sick." But then there
                        can be too much even of a good thing and certainly we have had enough of
                        this. The schemes of our enemies and their oppressions are devilish, but a
                        brave, cheerful spirit, a determination to work out of our troubles, and
                        conquer in the end, will soon change the face of affairs. It is actually
                        sinful for men, with brains to conceive and hands to execute, to be
                        grumbling and growling over what can not be helped. It is a duty to look
                        upon the bright side; to meet the situation and play our part in the great
                        future, as worthy sons of a glorious ancestry.</p>
                    <p>Look for the moment at the past of this people, and prepare to meet the
                        future as becomes the descendants of such a race. What race so grand in the
                        conception of its ideas; so bold and daring in executing them? Witness Sir
                        Walter Raleigh crossing the Atlantic in a frail bark, (a feat that puts to
                        shame the late boasted Yacht match of the upstart Bennett and other
                        yankees.) Witness Spottswood and his hardy 'Knights of the Golden Horse
                        Shoe,' penetrating the vast wilderness of West Augusta; witness Washington,
                        the boy engineer, making his way, foot sore and weary, over trackless
                        mountains, and see the grand climax of his career at Yorktown; pointing a
                        world to Freedom! Witness Virginia giving away vast territories, for the
                        common good, with as little thought of self, as the "Lord of the Manor,"
                        gives his tenants a holiday. Remember the self-sacrificing devotion of
                        Virginia to a Union that now seeks to crush her, in her hour of desolation.
                        Remember the wonderful amount of talent this one State has produced and
                        developed. Think of the late war for Justice and Right, the heroism and
                        endurance of our soldiers; the patriotic devotion of our women. Look back;
                        raise yourselves if you can, to the grand stand-point of the intellectual
                        strength and manhood of the Fathers of the Republic. Dwell proudly on what
                        has been accomplished. Think of how little this race has done for
                        itself--how much for others. Then come down to the stern facts of the
                        present, and prepare to play your parts like men, in the grand future still
                        in store for us.</p>
                    <p>That age has passed away, but we must retain its noble, generous spirit. Our
                        peculiar institutions, our ancient forms of law and every sacred right are
                        subject to the will of a conqueror. There is no dishonor on the proud name
                        handed down to us, by an ancestry that gave Freedom and a name to the powers
                        which now control the Government of the United States. We fought a good
                        fight, but an over-ruling Providence decreed we should be oppressed for a
                        time. Still there is a way out of our troubles, it is to <emph rend="italic"
                            >work</emph>; to use every means the enemies of the country have given
                        us to defeat them. Look the future squarely in the face. This is a
                        consolidated Government now, materialism reigns supreme; new ideas, new
                        forms of government take the place of the old, and the world moves with
                        railroad speed and calls it "progress." We must move and play our parts well
                        in this new game of life, or we are surely lost. Be up and doing, and our
                        future no man can conceive or venture to predict!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article encourages white Virginians to act as their Anglo-Saxon
                    ancestors did by persevering and overcoming obstacles in times of trouble.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Constitution Overthrown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It would be well for our people to ponder over the following remarkable
                        admissions of the N. Y. Times, the leading Republican paper North. It is
                        rather rough but still it is true. The Times says:</p>
                    <p>"Everything done by Congress to suppress the rebellion, says our
                        correspondent, is found in the Constitution, and <emph rend="italic">more
                            would have been found if necessary</emph>. Unquestionably! But this is
                        only a roundabout way of saying that <emph rend="italic">the will of
                            Congress</emph> became the supreme law of the land, and the provisions
                        and prohibitions of the Constitution vanished in its presence. Congress did
                        whatever it deemed necessary to be done--and it continues to do so down to
                        the present hour. The reconstruction bill of the last session was, in nearly
                        every one of its provisions, a clear and flagrant violation of the
                        Constitution as intended by its framers, as interpreted by the Supreme
                        Court, as maintained by every department of the Government hitherto, and as
                        expressed in its clear and explicit language. Yet that bill is the law of
                        the land, and as such will be enforced,--because it embodies the will of the
                        nation, which has become a 'higher law' than the Constitution, and as such
                        will control, not only its construction, but its application to the
                        practical government of the country.</p>
                    <p>"We may just as well look this matter in the face. It is quite useless to
                        ignore the plain and palpable fact that the rebellion and the war have <emph
                            rend="italic">revolutionized</emph> our Government. We are not now
                        living under the Constitution of 1799, but under an unwritten Constitution
                        which represents the national will as embodied in the action of Congress.
                        The limitations of the old Constitution have ceased to have binding force.
                        Congress exercises power never conferred upon it, and denies to States
                        rights expressly reserved to them by the Constitution. And it does so with
                        perfect impunity because there is no authority to overrule or reverse its
                        action. The President is powerless, because two-thirds of Congress is
                        against him. The Supreme Court is powerless, because the case cannot come up
                        for its action, and even if it should, the Court has no means of enforcing
                        its decrees. The people are without remedy, because ten States are not
                        allowed any voice in the matter, and the remainder sustain the usurped
                        authority. We are living under a <emph rend="italic">de facto</emph>
                        government, a government resting on force and on the will of the people who
                        wield it--but an <emph rend="italic">actual</emph> government
                    nevertheless."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial encourages readers to take note that the New York Times
                    considers reconstruction legislation to be in violation of the Constitution and
                    evidence of rule by the whim of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Confiscation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints several negative responses from journals in the North to
                    Thaddeus Stevens proposed plan of confiscation of the property of
                    ex-Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Prices Then and Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article discusses the change in prices since the beginning of last
                    year. The price of breadstuffs has increased 32%, while dairy, beef and pork
                    have fallen 20%. Grocery prices have fallen 10%.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>"Alas! For the Rarity of Christian Charity."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial chastises as unchristian the position taken in the
                    Philadelphia Evening Bulletin that northerners should not send economic aid to
                    the South if they continue to insist on electing ex-Confederates to office. In
                    the eyes of the editors, such a stance amounts to proposing "that the suffering
                    poor of the South be left to starve to death, on account of their political
                    opinions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Flour</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer, Flour Inspector, inspected in Staunton 7,500 barrels of flour
                    from August 1st, 1866 to March 21st, 1867. "Right good for a 'burn-out,'
                    Sheridanized district."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last Friday "a lot of idle boys, Freedmen, &amp;c., among whom we were
                    surprised to see some respectable young men, collected near Bickle's corner and
                    amused (or disgraced) themselves snow-balling people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Our Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors argue that "building the recently chartered Shenandoah River R.
                    R." is a "much better idea" than focusing on the South's political misfortunes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "colored Baptist Congregation at the Natural Bridge" are planning to
                    erect a church. "They have been liberally aided by the white people of the
                    neighborhood. This is right and laudable."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>County Court--March Term</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>T. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Sam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pannel</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The County Court met, J. Marshall McCue presiding. David Hanger, charged
                    with felony, was tried and acquitted. The Grand Jury, led by foreman T. E.
                    Montgomery, issued the following indictments: Reuben Hill, Sam Jackson, Martin
                    Hill, "colored," Frank Harris, David Hanger and Joseph Newman for petit larceny;
                    Daniel Pannel and Calvin Davis for assault and battery. M. D. McCormick and
                    Jacob H. Marshall were appointed road surveyors. James W. Baldwin qualified as
                    Deputy Clerk. George W. Sutler renewed his bond as Notary Public. "In view of
                    the condition of the roads and the backwardness of the farming operations, the
                    Court deemed it proper to adjourn."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Akers</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>Frances</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin Akers and Mrs. Frances Wiseman, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 21st at the County Clerk's Office by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulvy</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ingles</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. L. Berry and Miss Nancy J. Hulvy, both of Augusta, were married on
                    January 3rd by the Rev. Mr. Ingles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weddell</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. E. Weddell, of the "Okolona News," and Miss Alice White, of Okolona
                    Mississippi were married on March 6th by the Rev. Kerr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Martha Risk, aged 59 years, died in Staunton on March 21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew H. Brady, aged 56 years, died in Salem on February 28th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>Charlie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charlie Paris, infant son of J. R. and Lucy J. Paris, died on March 21st.
                    He was 23 months, 9 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Johnny Hilbert, infant son of J. W. and Kate Hilbert, died in Staunton on
                    March 23rd. He was 27 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.03.27.04" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Soldier's Last Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the "Valley Virginian."</p>
                    <p>Lines written on the death of Major Pettigrew, of Georgia, who was wounded
                        and taken prisoner at the battle of Fredericksburg, December, 1862, and
                        carried to Washington, D. C., where he died, and was buried, January 7,
                        1863, with Masonic honors.</p>
                    <p>Speak low, the heroes' breath is faint,<lb/> His conflict's almost o'er;<lb/>
                        A few more hours with much restraint,<lb/> A few more sighs without
                        complaint,<lb/> And he will be no more.</p>
                    <p>This form now bowed and writhed in pain,<lb/> Once in the battle stood;<lb/>
                        And met and gave the steady aim,<lb/> Saw comrades die and feel the
                        pain,<lb/> Amid the leaden flood.</p>
                    <p>The cannon's roar, the bugle's blast,<lb/> The battle's fierce display;<lb/>
                        The death-shots falling thick and fast,<lb/> The bleeding wounded hurried
                        past,<lb/> From break to close of day.</p>
                    <p>With order stern, "fixed bayonets; charge!<lb/> That battery take away!"<lb/>
                        The fierce repulse, and counter charge,<lb/> "The enemy's forces are too
                        large,"<lb/> Ne'er filled him with dismay.</p>
                    <p>But make the charge, this fight the last,<lb/> He here on earth can
                        make;<lb/> And death's cold sweat is coming fast,<lb/> And faces strange are
                        moving past,<lb/> Will this his courage shake?</p>
                    <p>Ah, no, e'en now 'though human aid<lb/> Is useless, and his soul<lb/> Must
                        stand before the God who made<lb/> It for His glory, undismayed<lb/> He
                        whispers, "Christ's my whole."</p>
                    <p>His head is raised, his eyes grow bright,<lb/> A voice he seems to hear;<lb/>
                        And soon the blissful heavenly light<lb/> Dispels the shades, the gloom of
                        night,<lb/> "Come! Soldier, do not fear."</p>
                    <p>His voice is hushed, that form is still,<lb/> And now lies cold in
                        death;<lb/> Ne'er more will fight 'gainst wrong and ill,<lb/> The life an
                        enemy must kill,<lb/> Has conquered with expiring breath.</p>
                    <p>A****<lb/><emph rend="italic">Washington, D. C., Oct. 20, 1866.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This poem submitted to the Valley Virginian was written to honor the death
                    of Major Pettigrew of Georgia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Effect of the Military Bill on Radicalism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This excerpt from the National Intelligencer argues that the Military
                    Reconstruction Bill, "forced on the South" by the Radical Republicans, will
                    bring about their undoing. Other issues such as tariffs and taxation will divide
                    the party, and the Radicals will loose power as it becomes obvious that
                    Reconstruction is only a ploy designed by them to hold onto it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
