<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.04.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>8/12/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-04-24">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.24.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginia soldiers have made 358 applications for artificial limbs, and 300
                    have been granted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The State of "Great Moral Ideas."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article claims to destroy the myth of Massachusetts' moral
                    superiority. "In spite of her churches and her lectures, her seminaries of
                    learning and her sumptuary laws, Massachusetts is today more irreligious, more
                    conceited, more fanatical, worse governed and has more of vice and crime and
                    pauperism within her border than any other State in the Union containing the
                    same number of inhabitants."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Result of Inaction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Did it ever strike the advocates of "inaction" that its natural result would
                        be ten thousand times harder on the soldiers who fought for the South; the
                        widows and orphans of her dead, than ever the vilest radical ever proposed
                        in the Military bill? The result of "passive endurance" would be to put all
                        of this class under the iron rule of such men as Brownlow and the radical
                        negroes, a fate which even our enemies give us a chance to escape, by
                        action. We cannot believe that the honest, but deceived advocates of this
                        policy ever looked at the question in its true light, and we think it their
                        duty to give the view a careful consideration.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article asserts that those who counsel inaction in the face of
                    Reconstruction would betray the Confederate dead and the Confederate veterans by
                    opening Virginia to rule by blacks and radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Jews</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends Jews from Manhattan insurance companies who refuse to do
                    business with them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>"Pious Drinking and Moral Swearing."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An informant in the capital asserts that Congress is full of "ingenious
                    rascality and trickery." Congressional Temperance Societies and revivals are
                    actually "pious Drinking" and "Moral Swearing Societies."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asserts that the only way to ensure a successful convention is to
                    see that Hunnicut, Botts and their allies do not have power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Word to the Colored People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our issue of August 8th, 1866, we talked to the colored people as follows,
                        for which we were called "foolish" by some of the "over wise." Now that
                        suffrage has been given the colored people, we repeat the advice given them,
                        and again urge upon all classes the necessity of harmony, in order to defeat
                        the devilish schemes of the radicals for our destruction. And most earnestly
                        do we appeal to the intelligent whites to allow no foolish prejudice to keep
                        them from impressing the truths given below, upon the colored people.</p>
                    <p>In a few words we will try to state the case to the colored people. You are
                        here, a part of the great body of the Southern society, and you have several
                        questions to ask yourselves. 1st. Who are you and how did you get here? 2d.
                        Who brought you here and sold you, and who has taken care of you since? 3d.
                        What is your true policy for the future? In answer to the first question you
                        know you are black, a negro, and that your forefathers were brought by force
                        from Africa, a land of darkness and barbarism. To the 2d, we can answer that
                        the immaculate and freedom loving Yankees, of New England, kidnapped you and
                        brought you here, sold you to Southern men, and then set up a howl about the
                        "brutality of Southern slavery," after these same Southern States forced
                        them to abolish the "slave trade" in 1808, sorely against their will--for it
                        was very profitable. These Southern people took your forefathers, ignorant
                        and naked, and by their kindness, patience, judgement and love for you,
                        brought you to your present state of civilization, which no other portion of
                        your race has reached. In return you gave them your labor, and that you
                        loved them was shown by your noble conduct during the war. Circumstances
                        beyond your control freed you from the restraints heretofore put upon you,
                        and an all-wise Providence allowed this same Yankee, who sold you into
                        slavery, to free you--<emph rend="italic">not for the love of you, but to
                            gratify his infernal hatred to the Southern whites--your friends</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Such is the true state of the case? you have accepted the freedom forced upon
                        you by Radical Yankee hatred of Southern men and no one blamed you for it,
                        any more than they would blame a school boy for taking holiday, when the
                        teacher is "barred out." And what are you to do? Ah! there's the rub--your
                        dispositions and education prompt you to do right; prompt you to cultivate
                        friendly feelings with your best friends, our people, but foolish people
                        among us, and designing Yankees, tell you to carry out the same spite a
                        Radical Yankee will always have. They urge you to believe that we are no
                        longer friends and they are--and the promptings of vanity make some of you
                        agree with these poor creatures--Now look matters square in the face. You
                        are here forever unless you die out like the Indians, as the Yankees
                        predict. How to do your part for society is the question. It is to trust
                        your white people; to be prompt and energetic; to comply with all contracts;
                        to work and study, and make up your minds that only by hard work and by
                        trusting to the kind and affectionate feelings of those who raised you, can
                        you exist on this Continent. Do this; show yourselves worthy of the position
                        you are placed in, as you heretofore showed you could be trusted and your
                        future is clear before you--always recollecting the great fact, the position
                        of the honored dead and respected of your class exemplifies, that "you must
                        respect yourselves to be respected." Listen not to fools or worse, who tell
                        you about social "equality" and all that, for that's your ruin and
                        extermination. Be honest, be faithful; make yourselves <emph rend="italic"
                            >necessary</emph> to the community and the devilish schemes of the
                        Radical Yankee to ruin the Country, through you, will be thwarted and your
                        race saved.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Faced with African American suffrage, the paper prints advice that all
                    white southerners should give to black southerners. Blacks must view southern
                    whites, not northern radicals, as friends, and should work toward harmony with
                    them by giving up ideas of "social equality" and instead focusing on hard work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The "Convention."</head>
                <origin>Richmond Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For two days past the African Church has been the scene of a grotesque,
                        although melancholy <emph rend="italic">traveste</emph> of the convention
                        which the great political parties of Virginia were, in better times, in the
                        habit of holding in that building. Where RANDOLPH, MADISON, MONROE, LEIGH,
                        and UPSHUR were once heard with wrapt attention, HUNNICUT bawled like a
                        harpooned gorilla, and CONWAY croaked like a gorged cormorant.</p>
                    <p>All who attended the convention assure us that the black "delegates" were, in
                        deportment, intelligence and refinement, very superior to their white
                        allies. The graduates of the corn field were immeasurably ahead of the
                        products of the "town meetings" and "common schools." The impression general
                        among the outsiders was, that taking the delegates as specimens, black
                        missionaries should be sent to Massachusetts. It was conceded by all parties
                        that at the great "mongrel convention" in Philadelphia, FRED DOUGLASS was
                        the master spirit.--<emph rend="italic">Richmond Times</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Times ridicules the blacks and their white supporters for
                    their participation in the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>A Disgusted Delegate</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The true sentiments of the Union men of Augusta, as expressed through one of
                        their number, and who had manliness enough to repudiate the Hunnicut
                        faction, The Richmond Whig, of the 20th inst., has the following statement
                        of E. L. Houff, with resolutions.</p>
                    <p>"We have been called on by Mr. E. L. Houff, a delegate from Augusta to the
                        African Church pow-wow, at whose request we publish the subjoined preamble
                        and resolutions which were offered by him in that body and were unanimously
                        and contemptuously voted "under the table." Mr. H., who seems to be sensible
                        and well-meaning person, is satisfied that he was entirely out of place in
                        any such body, and that the convention was got up and controlled by corrupt
                        and designing (white) men for their own selfish ends. He will take care, in
                        the future, not to be caught in any such company. The following is the paper
                        which was submitted by Mr. H, and which expresses his own sentiments and, as
                        he assures us, those of the "Union men" of Augusta":</p>
                    <p>"WHEREAS, The State of Virginia, as well as the whole of the Southern States,
                        saw fit to secede from the General Government of the United States; and as
                        the result of the secession involved the country in four years' war, the
                        most terrible that has ever waged on this Continent; and, as the States thus
                        seceded are at this time held by the United States Government as conquered
                        provinces; therefore be it</p>
                    <p>"1. <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we, a portion of the citizens
                        of Virginia in convention assembled for the purpose of bringing back our
                        State to the faith of our fathers, while differing with the advocates of
                        secession from the commencement of the political strife to the present time,
                        yet we recognize them as friends and fellow citizens of a common country;
                        and as all classes should work harmoniously together for the purpose of
                        building up our dilapidated country and perpetuating the interest of our
                        beloved State, we hereby ask the Congress of the United States, in the name
                        of the loyal citizens of Virginia, and in behalf of our misguided friends,
                        that no portion of their property be confiscated on account of the part
                        taken by them in the late rebellion.</p>
                    <p>"2. <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That, as Union men, we are desirous
                        of fostering harmony in our beloved land, and intend to uphold the Union
                        party and perpetuate its success by all legitimate means.</p>
                    <p>"3. <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we abide by the laws made by
                        Congress to govern the State of Virginia, and we deem it our duty to uphold
                        the Union now and forever one and inseparable.</p>
                    <p>"4. <emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we, the Union men of Virginia,
                        throw to the breeze our banner with this inscription: <emph rend="italic"
                            >The Union, the Constitution, and the Enforcement of the
                    Laws</emph>."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig reports that E. L. Houff, speaking for Augusta's
                    Unionists, expressed displeasure at the Convention which was run by "corrupt and
                    designing white men for their own selfish ends." A resolution he presented
                    against confiscation of land, or harsh treatment of ex-Confederates failed to
                    pass.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Who Are Disqualified</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Schofield has clarified rules for voter registration. Any one
                    forced into Confederate service through the draft will not be disqualified.
                    "This will reduce the number of persons disqualified to vote or hold office to a
                    very small margin. The disqualified will be confined altogether to those who
                    volunteered in the early part of the war, few of whom are now living. The
                    survivors are principally of the conscript class, save perhaps a few officers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum decided by a 13 to 12 vote that the revolution of 1776
                    was a mistake.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahone</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>James L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branch</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>N. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Express Company organized and elected the following officers:
                    Col. M. G. Harman, President; Gen. William Mahone, John Wood, Jr., James L. A.
                    Trotter, Thomas Branch, and N. M. Lee, Directors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Circus is coming to Staunton, and the paper warns readers not to come
                    to town "or you might be tempted to attend, leaving you minus at least two
                    dollars and giving the yankees something to gloat over when they get North."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Babies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a "baby epidemic rages fearfully in Staunton and
                    vicinity." The area is averaging six births a week in a proportion of five boys
                    to one girl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Joseph E. Johnson has written a letter correcting many of the errors
                    found in Dr. Dabney's life of Stonewall Jackson. The "expose" was so forceful,
                    the article suggests, that Dabney would be best served by burning the remaining
                    copies of the book.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that in Staunton there are "13 dwelling houses in the
                    process of erection, besides several just finished, also a Saw Mill, Plaster and
                    Grist Mill, a School House, for the Freedmen, 50x30, showing a spirit of
                    enterprise which our people may well be proud of."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Colored Benevolent Association in Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Senator</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Senator Trout presented a bill incorporating the Augusta Benevolent
                    Association of Colored Persons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors lament that benefit concerts and organizations for aid to the
                    South "lose a screw or go by the board for want of patriotism on the part of all
                    engaged. There is a lurking spirit of gain which prompts some people to take
                    advantage of even the poorest."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. Arnall, the Depot Agent, reports that 4,456 bushels of corn, and 565
                    barrels of flour were shipped by the Central Railroad during the week ending
                    April 22nd. Most of the corn was sent to Richmond, and the rest to South
                    Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>How They Are Deceived</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. D. Caldwell, a visitor to the Valley from Montour, Pa., was looking to
                    buy a "large tract of land" and went away "much pleased with the country and the
                    people." He reported that many "respectable people" in the North were frightened
                    to come South by "radical reports of danger from 'Rebels.'' 'All respectable
                    people from the North will be well treated. So come along with your greenbacks!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Wilson and Mrs. M. E. Wilson, both of Augusta, were married on March
                    4th by the Rev. Mr. Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>W. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownlee</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. C. Miller and Miss Mary S. Brownlee, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 4th by the Rev. Mr. Pinkerton, at the same time as the Wilsons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanrahan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Hanrahan, aged 55 years, died in the Staunton residence of W. H.
                    Tams on April 21st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mrs. Maria Slanker, aged 70 years, died in her Staunton residence on April
                    11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Julia Grove, aged 13 years, 7 months, and 25 days, died in Staunton on
                    April 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.04.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
