<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.12.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/15/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-12-25">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our Christmas Greeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We extend to our numerous subscribers and friends the compliments of the
                        season and cordially wish them a merry Christmas and a happy New Year.</p>
                    <p>Though our sky is still darkened by angry clouds the light that beams from
                        the Northern and Western horizons shows that these clouds are drifting off,
                        and gives abundant promise that this long day of travail and sorrow shall
                        give place to a morrow of rest and joy. The Christmas and New Year of 1867
                        furnish to us more cheerful reflections than did those of 1866, and with
                        well filled store houses and cheering prospects we are sure that the people
                        of the Great Valley of Virginia can heartily enjoy the festivities of this
                        cheering season. Let none be forgotten in the circle of joy, let him that
                        hath abundance give to him that lacketh. So that all may be in the proper
                        frame to be joyous and thankful at the return of this ever welcome time of
                        holiday.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper extends a Christmas greeting to its readers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Destitution in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Norfolk Journal, in speaking of the destitution in the south, says truly:</p>
                    <p>The rigors of winter are upon us and the pinchings of want, heretofore so
                        generally unfelt throughout our land, are more or less experienced by almost
                        every class.</p>
                    <p>There are very few families whose worldly condition has not undergone a sad
                        and unaccustomed change. From comparative affluence and ease many have been
                        reduced to the necessity of struggling against the physical forces opposed
                        to them, and are learning that dire lesson of accommodating themselves to
                        circumstances and the altered condition of things. The transition from
                        comparative plenty to a state bordering closely on the confines of want is a
                        severe ordeal. Distress may be said, in its various degrees, to be
                        universal.</p>
                    <p>A large portion of the negro population will be sufferers. Many of them in
                        their miserable hovels no doubt miss the big log fires to which they were
                        accustomed in their snug and comfortable plantation cabins, and do not
                        receive that kind and gratuitous care in sickness which was bestowed upon
                        them when they were regarded as of the family.</p>
                    <p>Pinching want drives them to commit depredations, which, in a state of
                        servitude, were rare because necessity did not force them to pilfer.</p>
                    <p>Fences stand but little chance in this inclement season, and share the fate
                        of unpenned as well as penned hogs, and the hen-rosts. Instead of having
                        made some provision for winter, they have lost much time and spent much of
                        their earnings in following upon the heels of political emissaries who have
                        deluded them into taking a false position in reference to their former
                        masters, against whom they have arrayed themselves in political hostility.
                        They must remember that the Freedmen's Bureau cannot last forever, and that
                        they, like the white man, in order to escape want and misery, must obey the
                        law common to both, and devote themselves to labor and industry.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This selection from the Norfolk Journal describes widespread poverty
                    throughout the South. The Freedmen are especially impoverished, which can lead
                    to crime, the article asserts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eagle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt C. Davis and Miss Elizabeth J. Scott, both of New Hope, were married
                    on December 7th by the Rev. J. J. Eagle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lackey</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burruss</ln>
                        <fn>Willie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George W. Lackey and Miss Willie M. Burruss were married on December
                    11th at Variety Springs by the Rev. George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. William T. Crawford and Miss Elizabeth J. Williams were married at
                    Variety Springs on December 11th by the Rev. George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harsha</ln>
                        <fn>Seymore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFall</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neal</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Seymore Harsha, of Grant County, West Virginia, and Miss Jennie E. M.
                    McFall, of Augusta County, were married at Parnassus on December 5th by A. A. P.
                    Neal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>Narcissus V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDonald</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Isaac Newton Vines and Miss Narcissus V. Hite, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Greenville on December 12th by the Rev. W. A. McDonald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. James R. Yates and Miss Nannie Steele, both of Augusta, were married at
                    the residence of the bride near Greenville on December 10th by the Rev. William
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.12.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
