<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.07.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-17">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.17.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To a people situated as we are this heading can have but one attraction--they
                        want to know the worst. We publish, to-day, the supplement to the old
                        Military Bill, a forced construction of that bill, by the Congress now in
                        session. It virtually deposes the President, and he is powerless, or thinks
                        he is. It gives to Military Commanders South dictatorial powers, and not
                        only endorses all their acts but gives them, subject only to General Grant,
                        powers never before granted to men in this much glorified Republic, whose
                        corner stone was the "consent of the governed." This is hard; it is hard for
                        a people, once proud, prosperous and free, to submit to this harsh decision
                        of the conqueror but, then, it really gives the District Commanders no more
                        power than they have heretofore exercised, and it would ill become a people
                        who have suffered so much for <emph rend="italic">the right</emph>, to give
                        up in despair or doubts its final triumph. Every new order to the South only
                        goes to show the weakness of the party in power North, while the bounteous
                        provisions a merciful God has vouchsafed to us, for our material comfort,
                        shows that He, who doeth all things well, has not given us over, forever, to
                        our enemies.</p>
                    <p>We should recollect that, with all our trials, we are blessed above many
                        people on this earth, and that there are indications which bid us be of
                        "good cheer," for the end is not yet. Some of the Southern leaders are
                        blindly running into the Radical party for safety from imagined evils to
                        come, or rather they are trying to rush in; others are laying back, waiting
                        for "something to turn up," but none of them truly represent the great mass.
                        The people are at work, they have generally registered and obeyed orders to
                        the letter, and, when the time comes for action, at the elections, the
                        country will be surprised at the result. This hard struggle for existence;
                        this terrible fight against fate, has had one good effect. It has kept our
                        people from all the political complications--ready to act as circumstances
                        may dictate in the future.</p>
                    <p>Let the people continue to work for their material advancement, regardless of
                        the ravings of madmen North or the whining crys of the weak at home: let
                        them obey orders, and frown down parties in the South--always remembering
                        that material prosperity brings political strength; and that causes are at
                        work, which will surely, so surely as God is Just, bring them the "reward"
                        promised for works faithfully performed and suffering patiently endured.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial comments on the new Military Bill which allegedly gives
                    District Commanders despotic power over the South. The paper encourages readers
                    to have hope, and to work for material prosperity despite the difficult
                    political situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The "Valley Virginian" Enlarged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors of the Valley Virginian announce that the paper has been
                    expanded in size and reduced in cost. It will add more selection to enhance the
                    "literary character" of the paper. "The 'Virginian,' born amidst the poverty and
                    desolation of its people, determined 'to keep pace with their giant strides in
                    the material development of the great Valley.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The wheat crop is expected to bring in 200,000,000 bushels, "about a barrel
                    and a third of flour for every inhabitant," making it the largest ever.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Congressional--The New Reconstruction Bill So-Called</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a copy of the new Reconstruction Bill outlining the powers
                    of the military district commanders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Over 900 visitors arrived at Staunton hotels in the past two days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Hams are in demand in Staunton and going for 1 shilling a pound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Baseball is reportedly very popular in the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Internal Revenue Service collected $150,216.08 in the district
                    including Staunton for the year ending in June. "Our fore-fathers fought against
                    taxation without representation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Northern men, especially from Pennsylvania, travel through the Valley daily
                    looking to buy homes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Registration in Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The voter registration totals to date are as follows: Staunton 1st
                    District, 380 whites, 184 blacks; Staunton 2nd District, 466 whites, 258 blacks;
                    Middlebrook, 401 whites, 123 blacks; Greenville, 123 whites, 123 blacks;
                    Waynesboro, 470 whites, 221 blacks. At Greensville and Waynesboro 23 whites and
                    no blacks were rejected. This brings the county total to 2423 whites and 1015
                    blacks, a white majority of 1015. Four districts are still to report which are
                    expected to augment the white majority.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Census</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper calls for a census "not only to prevent registration frauds, but
                    to show us where we are, in population." The editors suggest that the chief of
                    police and his deputies could take it at minimal cost. "We want an alphabetical
                    list of all the white and black male adults in the town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
