<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.09.11">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/03/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-11">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">11</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.11.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.11.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Lyceum discussed the question, "Is the establishment of the
                    Free School system at present advisable in Virginia?" It was decided in the
                    negative. The next topic for conversation will be, "Is it expedient for churches
                    to enact rules to prohibit dancing?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The official registration returns from the State of Virginia have been
                    received. The total number of registered voters is 216,000 with a ratio of 11
                    whites for every 9 blacks. Delegates to the Convention will be selected between
                    the 10th and 15th of October.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The "Reaction North."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have heard a heap of talk about a "reaction North" and what it will do for
                        us, according to the non-action men South. We do see signs of a "reaction"
                        North and West, but we can't see how it is to benefit us in our present
                        condition, unless we conform our State Constitutions to the requirements of
                        the Military Bills. That parties North and West are changing front and that
                        new issues are springing up, which will sweep away old parties we believe;
                        and we hope to see in this change for the 'Land We Love'--the Sunny South,
                        but we cannot see any relief from compliance with the Military Bills, odious
                        as they are, or any reason to change our opinion as to the plain road we
                        "prisoners of war" have to travel.</p>
                    <p>"Don't halloo before you are out of the woods" is a good old saying and one
                        that should be acted upon by our, Southern, people, in regard to all
                        apparent evidences of "reaction" North, especially the "ten thousand
                        Democratic," or anti-Chinese, anti-mixed suffrage, "Conservative," majority
                        in California. <emph rend="italic">The Military Bills are certain to be
                            enforced by the present Congress, regardless of what is done by the
                            people of California or any body North</emph>, and we should act so as
                        to control our coming State Convention and, through it, our local
                        governments--the great object.</p>
                    <p>The Radicals in California lost that State, from local causes entirely
                        disconnected with our fate. They nominated Gorman, a corrupt and unpopular
                        man, for Governor; the other parties united and beat them, by their
                        divisions, and by using the "Chinese suffrage" question against them. Just
                        so far as this election shows a protest against "mixed suffrage," it is
                        gratifying to know that the "blue veins" will tell and sweep all minor
                        issues aside, but these changes must not be taken for love for the "Rebel,"
                        so-called, or as sympathy for his fate. We must swallow the "bitter pill;"
                        must "reconstruct under the Military Bills," or another howl will be raised
                        North and we will lose all.</p>
                    <p>Recollect that the Radicals, our worst enemies, wish us to vote down
                        reconstruction under these bills; they formed them so as to induce us to do
                        so and have <emph rend="italic">obstructed</emph> their fair execution for
                        the same purpose. It was Stonewall Jackson's successful rule "to do exactly
                        what the enemy desired him not to do," and, be assured, the acceptance of
                        these bills by us, will be used as a "trump card," by the opposition to
                        Radicalism to carry the North against it. In short the duty of practical,
                        true Southern men is to act as if they had no friends North, and
                        "reconstruct" as speedily as possible, tying their faith to no party or set
                        of men at present. We can easily settle many questions when we have a voice
                        in the "Halls of the Nation," as the yankees like to call it, and become, as
                        we surely will, the balance of power on this Continent. Until work,
                        emigration and material prosperity gives us that power, let us beware of
                        undue elation over local victories in the North and West, and attend
                        strictly to the work before us as a people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial argues that despite a few setbacks for the Radicals in
                    Northern elections, southerners should still plan to comply with the provisions
                    of the Military Bill and reconstruct on that basis. Waiting for a reaction in
                    the North against the radicals can only make matters worse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Great Preacher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Munsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Munsey preached to a congregation of 2000 at the Methodist Church
                    in Staunton. The subject of his sermon was "Be sure your sin will find you out."
                    The editors praise his performance and declare that Munsey is to preaching what
                    Jackson was to military leadership. "He takes you by storm, enthuses and
                    enthralls you! For one hour and twenty minutes, Sunday, he held his immense
                    congregation entranced, not one thinking of the time or looking at his watch."
                    Like the hero Jackson, Munsey is an "inspired Christian."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns African Americans that defeat for the radicals in northern
                    states such as Kentucky, California, and Connecticut "is simply opposition to
                    negro or mixed suffrage. We advise them to think about it well before they throw
                    themselves into the troublesome sea of political strife. The end is not yet--and
                    the whites will rule this continent."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Proper View</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New Orleans Crescent expresses our views fully in the following extract:</p>
                    <p>"Because the Southern people are in duress, it is no reason that they imitate
                        the impotent fury of wild beasts which wear out their teeth in gnawing at
                        the bars of their cage, and in biting the iron rods with which their keepers
                        stir them up. The badgered bull, charging at a red rag, is about as
                        reasonable and graceful as those Southern politicians who, in rhetoric rage,
                        tear to pieces the orders and the opinions of Sickles, Pope or Sheridan.
                        This is not the way to avoid the stroke of the conquering power, or to heal
                        the wounds which it has already inflicted. The district commanders are
                        simply the viceroys of that power. To pursue an uncompromising opposition to
                        them, and at the same time to propose allegiance to the government whose
                        will, enacted into law, they are carrying out, is palpable inconsistency.
                        Those who take glory to themselves for such an opposition, would gain credit
                        for candor and courage at least, if not for prudence and wisdom, by openly
                        advocating resistance to the federal authority, and endeavoring to re-open
                        the war against the North. In the last analysis, that is its meaning, if it
                        has any rational meaning whatever. To think of its reaching such a
                        development, in actual circumstances, is, of course, preposterous. But it
                        serves as a pretext for keeping up at the North the radical cry of
                        disloyalty and rebellion among Southerners. And thus it is that Southern
                        impracticables and marplots play into the hands of the most virulent and
                        desperate enemies of the South."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors endorse the argument made in this excerpt from the New Orleans
                    Crescent that counsels southerners not to openly defy Federal authority. Only
                    through compliance with the Military Bill will southern States be speedily
                    readmitted to the Union with their rights intact.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.11.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our General Agent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Houston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Major Houston Hall, of the famous 62d Virginia Regiment, has been named
                    general travelling agent for the Valley Virginian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Town Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmonson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper declares that "Staunton is growing more rapidly than any interior
                    town in the State. On every side new buildings are going up and others are
                    projected to meet the wants of our growing population." E. L. Edmonson is
                    planning to build 13 Concrete or Pebble houses on 1/4 acre lots carved out of
                    his property on Coalter Street above Col. M. G. Harman's.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"One by One."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Every day we are called upon to follow some of our aged and respected
                        citizens to the grave. They grow old and feeble in good works; we see them
                        less frequently on our Streets and grow accustomed to their absence. In this
                        terrible struggle against fate--this daily fight with poverty--we scarcely
                        take time to ask "how is the old man," until we are startled by the
                        announcement that he is no more. How many, who loved and respected
                        him--thought of Thomas R. Blackburn, aged 74 years, who departed from among
                        us on the 20th ult.! His was a life of usefulness, a life of labor, and our
                        Western Lunatic Asylum stands a Monument to his genius as an Architect and
                        his worth as a man. Truly his contemporaries can say, and thank God: "The
                        playmates of youth, the fellow laborers of manhood, die away, and take the
                        road before us. Old age is like some quiet chamber, in which, disconnected
                        from the visible world, we can prepare in silence for the world that is
                        after."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This obituary for Thomas R. Blackburn, architect of the Western Lunatic
                    Asylum, calls attention to all the "aged and respected citizens" of Staunton who
                    are often forgotten or ignored in life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Town Council--September Session</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The September Session of the Town Council met, Mayor Trout presiding. Only
                    William H. Wilson was absent. The Superintendent of the Water Works reported
                    that water depth at the Spring stood 18 1/2 inches above the supply pipe, and
                    that work done for individuals amounted to $99.20, and for the town, $3.50.
                    Recommendations for improvements were received from the Street Commissioners,
                    and the following appropriations were made: $350 to pave between the Valley Bank
                    and Miss Sallie Ryan's lot on Frederick Street; $150 to improve the pavement on
                    Main Street in front of Rev. G. B. Taylor's house, after he removes or changes
                    his porch; $800 for pavement on the north side of Frederick Street between John
                    B. Scherer's and Green Street, and Green Street and Beverly; $800 for a sidewalk
                    on New Street between the Presbyterian Church and the late David Point's in
                    Gallow's Town. In all, $1,600 was appropriated. A petition to improve the street
                    running between John Gregory's on Augusta and Market was referred to the
                    commission. The Commissioners were asked to estimate the cost of improving
                    Market Street between James M. Lilley's lot and 9th Street. William A. Burke was
                    not allowed an account for curbing Frederick Street. The Water Committee was
                    asked to report on the feasibility of replacing the four inch water pipe running
                    between the Episcopal Church and Morris corner with a six inch pipe. The
                    Overseer of the Poor was ordered to work with the Superintendent of the
                    Freedman's bureau on "removing a number of Freedmen, who have come into town
                    since the surrender and are liable to become a charge on the same, to the places
                    where they last resided, in accordance with Gen. Schofield's last order." Fifty
                    dollars were appropriated to the Street Commissioners for incidental expenses.
                    The Mayor and recorder were ordered to sell the Market House to the highest
                    bidder. The license fee to manufacture and sell malt liquor was set at $25 per
                    year. The accounts for the month amounting to $330.08 were allowed. A $5 account
                    presented by the Water Committee for hack hire to and from the town spring was
                    not allowed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>Lucretia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James R. Fisher, of Augusta County, and Miss Lucretia Shaver, of Woodstock,
                    were married on August 28th by the Rev. J. P. Hyde.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel M. Woodward, Sr., aged 77 years, died in Staunton on September 4th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Departed this life on the 4th inst., Samuel M. Woodward, in the 77 year of
                        his age.</p>
                    <p>In the loss of this most excellent man and sincere christian, this community
                        is called to mourn the death of one of its oldest and most esteemed
                        citizens. Mr. Woodward was, for many years, Stewart of the Western Lunatic
                        Asylum in this place, and performed the duties of his responsible office
                        with great fidelity and success. His efficiency aided no little the other
                        accomplished officers, in securing for this noble Institution its high
                        character. Long will his cordial and cheerful manner be remembered--by not
                        only the patients, but their friends and visitors.</p>
                    <p>Few men in this community enjoyed a larger acquaintance in this country than
                        Mr. Woodward, and none possessed the esteem of the people more than himself.
                        His urbane manners; spotless integrity and christian deportment, secured for
                        him the cordial friendship of all who enjoyed his acquaintance. His illness
                        was long and distressing, but his resignation and fortitude never forsook
                        him, and a simple, childlike trust in the love of God, characterized the
                        evening hours of his life. The usually large number of friends which
                        constituted the extended funeral cortege, bore gratifying testimony to the
                        high esteem in which he was held in this county. He has gone to the rest
                        prepared for him and is happy; and this whole community offer their cordial
                        sympathy to his bereaved family.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper publishes an obituary for Samuel M. Woodward which praises his
                    contributions to the Western Lunatic Asylum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.09.11.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
