<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1867/va.au.vv.1867.07.03">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/25/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1867-07-03">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.03.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>A Point Well Put</head>
                <origin>Lewisburg Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This item attacks the northern historian Swinton for planning to write
                    about Stonewall Jackson and Robert E. Lee. The article suggests yankees should
                    stick to writing about their own generals, soldiers, and campaigns, and leave
                    southerners to learn about their heroes, living and dead, from other
                    southerners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Louisville Courier reports that many citizens of Tennessee are fleeing
                    the state to avoid radical rule, and more are expected to desert should Brownlow
                    be re-elected. "Do not such facts speak volumes against the Radical party? None
                    should vote the radical ticket in this State who do not wish to see our people
                    subjected to the oppression and tyranny beneath which the citizens of Tennessee
                    and Missouri are groaning."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that so far registration totals for the state as a whole
                    show a majority of black voters. "Let no white man fail to register, as he ought
                    to, or let him acknowledge the negro as the superior race."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Professor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Lyceum met on Monday night to hear a lecture by Professor Miller on the
                    "Power of Memory." "The lecture was listened to with great attention, by an
                    appreciative and select audience." The next topic for discussion will be, "Is it
                    expedient for Virginia to adopt a free school system?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"The Mother of States"--How to Make Her a State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Ever since Virginia was settled she has held a proud and pre-eminent position
                        on this Continent. There is an interest attached to Virginia and Virginians
                        which no other State or people enjoy. It was Virginia who gave a "Father to
                        his Country" and a Henry to the great Revolution. Her Jefferson wrote the
                        Declaration of Independence and developed the true principles of Republican
                        Government in her Bill of Rights. She furnished the line of Presidents,
                        Soldiers and Statesmen who made the United States what it was before the
                        wars. She was the "back bone" of the Confederacy during the war, and the
                        talent and genius of her sons have given laws to other States. In her
                        princely generosity she has given away an empire and peopled it with her
                        children. Alas! that some should have returned to stab her in her desolation
                        and distress, while others aided her enemies, in the Halls of Legislation
                        and at home. Still, with all her faults and absence of selfishness, or
                        rather suicidal domestic and foreign policy, she stands to day--despoiled,
                        robbed, divided as she is--the first State and people on this Continent,
                        socially and morally, with her material wealth but half developed, and her
                        future full of promise. We have already alluded to the influences that have
                        heretofore forced her children away from her, and made her the "Mother of
                        States." This is a proud title, but bought at too dear a cost. These causes
                        no longer exist, and our planters and farmers have but to take hold of the
                        work before them, with energy guided by their known common sense, to make
                        Virginia not only the "Mother of States," but <emph rend="italic">the
                        State</emph> of the Continent. They must no longer force their sons to seek,
                        in new and hostile States, the position their talents and energies justify
                        them in claiming at home. They must divide up their farms before a "Butler"
                        or a "Stevens" does it for them. As the "boy" becomes of age give them a
                        hundred or two hundred acres on the "old place"; build him a house, stock
                        the farm and help him along. This "boy" may have led men during the war and
                        hates to be living on the "old man," or working on "board wages." He wants a
                        little place and a wife of his own; he wishes to be independent and rely on
                        himself. If you start him, he will soon show that a "little farm well
                        tilled," for one's self, can be made as profitable as the whole place, under
                        present management, He will be a good citizen, a worker, and a comfort to
                        you in your old age--and he will build up our old State, instead of the
                        'Great West.'</p>
                    <p>And don't stop with providing for your own "boys." Look around in the towns
                        and villages, and on other farms. You will find honest, industrious, but
                        poor, young men, marked all over with noble scars, received in defence of
                        your big landed possessions; others with a wife and little ones, living from
                        hand to mouth, on the meagre and uncertain wages of trade. Take them by the
                        hand, sell them a little place at low rates and on ample time. Give them the
                        aid of your credit and advice, and in a few years they will work you out of
                        your troubles, increase the value of your still large estates, and form the
                        most intelligent and prosperous body of small farmers the world ever saw.
                        This requires exertion, and a seeming expense, on part of land owners now,
                        but the consciousness of duties well done and the actual enhancement of the
                        values of what remains, will more than repay you for all you do. Don't say
                        "you can't;" don't look over your thousand acres and selfishly hug to your
                        heart the delusion that you are 'a wealthy man,' and must keep up a big
                        show, but learn wisdom from your empty pockets, and be men worthy of
                        Virginia's past renown and her mighty future.</p>
                    <p>We have, more than once, spoken earnestly about the causes that led to the
                        war, and the triumph of the Northern or free labor idea, over the Southern
                        system. That system had much influence in forcing our young men to leave
                        home, but it is crushed out, forever, and we must adapt ourselves to "the
                        situation" as it stands now. "Free labor" fought for this magnificent
                        country and it is coming to settle here, and that sooner than we expect. The
                        petty political troubles and excitement, of to-day, will soon be over and,
                        then, such a tide of immigration as will pour into the South was never
                        before seen in the world. We look upon it as certain and hail its coming
                        joyfully, for it will adapt itself to our social life, and settle the negro
                        question, while the effervescing froth, at Washington, is bubbling over it.
                        Every indication North, and in Europe, goes to prove what we say. They are
                        coming to make their homes here. Democrat, Radical, Yankee Soldier, German,
                        Irish, all will soon be upon us, and it behooves us to be prepared for this
                        new invasion, by preparing our children, and our young men, to meet the
                        "Spirit of the Age" on equal terms. We must mould this mass to our purposes,
                        as we can, if the property holders of the South will act up to the
                        requirements of the occasion.</p>
                    <p>In this connection we would suggest a "Land Owner's Association," composed of
                        the property holders, farmers and planters of the State, or of the Valley.
                        Let it be regularly organized and have for officers the best practical
                        talent available. Let each member contribute so much land, to be sold at
                        reasonable rates, and make it the duty of the officers to settle good men,
                        natives and foreigners, upon it. Then let the Association send agents to
                        Europe, not Humbugs or Speculators, but men like J. B. Scherer, of Staunton,
                        who has earned the confidence and respect of our people by 27 years of
                        honest effort among us. His native State, Baden, cultivates the vine, wheat,
                        oats, korn or speltz, (a grain similar to our wheat, but having three grains
                        to each hull and producing from 40 to 50 bushels to the acre. It makes the
                        finest flour, and only requires an additional "rolling mill" to roll it
                        out,) fruit of all kinds, tobacco and fine stock. The climate is somewhat
                        similar to ours, but not so favorable. Mr. Scherer could influence the right
                        kind of people to immigrate, and we know he is identified with us, by every
                        tie that binds man to a country. M. Blout, John Shutterly, Christian
                        Staubousch and numbers of others, who are part and parcel of us, could be
                        used by such an Association in the same way. Honest, intelligent foreigners,
                        like them, can be found in every County in the State. But our article is
                        long enough for to-day. Think over what we suggest and give the public the
                        benefit of your thoughts through our paper. This question is the one of the
                        greatest moment now, and every man should give his mite of thought, as well
                        as of land, to aid the common cause.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blout</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shutterly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubousch</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This editorial advocates formation of a Land Owner's Association formed to
                    pool and sell unused land to worthy small proprietors. Large land-owners need to
                    cultivate small farmers in order for Virginia to regain her place as one of the
                    most prosperous states in the Union. Confederate veterans and European
                    immigrants recruited by Staunton's leading German citizens are the best small
                    farmers with which to begin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>What are We to Do?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian continues to endorse the Charlottesville Chronicle's
                    call for a non-partisan "Convention of Patriots," but they cannot condone
                    denouncing the Democratic Party. The Virginian thinks the Convention should make
                    it clear that southerners accept the military bill, and then move on to regain
                    power in a re-formed Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Valley farmers are now harvesting the best wheat and rye crop ever grown in
                    the Valley. Oats, corn, and other crops are also doing well. "Our future begins
                    to look bright, in spite of the Radicals."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Charley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The "glorious Fourth" of July will be celebrated by the local Fire Company,
                    with only Goshen Depot abstaining. "If you want to do the clean thing,
                    'loyally,' go along. Charley Arnall sells the tickets and the Stonewall Band
                    makes the music."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although the terms for southern readmission into the Union are "merciless"
                    the paper insinuates that Radical Senators Wade, Sumner, Stevens, and Butler
                    hope the South will reject them so that Reconstruction can be prolonged.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Trip Through the Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have frequently noticed the desire Pennsylvanian people had to locate in
                        our Valley, and our readers will recollect the party we reported under the
                        head of the "Rebel Valley." Mr. B. Y. Hamsher, editor of the Chambersburg,
                        Pa., Valley Spirit, was one of the party, and in his paper, of the 26th
                        ult., gives an interesting account of his trip, and promises his readers
                        "some general observation of the country &amp;c." We hail this as a good
                        omen for the future of our Valley, and will look for the article with
                        interest, knowing that all that is needed to secure us capital and labor, is
                        a truthful representation of our county, and people, to the North. Mr.
                        Hamsher fell into an error about the battle of New Market.--Stonewall
                        Jackson was killed before it took place. Breckenridge, Imboden and the
                        Cadets, of V. M. I., whipped the "boys who fites mit Seagle." Speaking of
                        their stay in Staunton, he mentions the American Hotel and Col. O'Ferrall,
                        in the most complementary manner, and continues:</p>
                    <p>"Staunton is a handsome, thriving town, of some six thousand inhabitants,
                        surrounded by a succession of high hills, which completely overlook the
                        place, giving it a most romantic and picturesque appearance. There are many
                        fine buildings in the town and we noticed many evidences of energy and
                        business activity among the inhabitants. It is located on the Virginia
                        Central Railroad, running to Richmond, which makes it a trading point of
                        considerable importance. The State Lunatic Asylum and Deaf, Dumb and Blind
                        Institution are both located here, and are said to be the finest
                        institutions of the kind in the country. There are about six hundreds
                        inmates in both institutions at the present time. The buildings immediately
                        adjoin the town, are large and elegant structures with spacious and
                        handsomely ornamented grounds attached. Augusta County is one of the
                        largest, as well as one of the richest counties in the State. The land is
                        somewhat more rolling than that of the counties through which we had passed,
                        but equally as good, if not superior.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Ferrall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reprints some of the impressions of Augusta B. Y. Hamsher printed
                    in the Chambersburg, Pa., Valley Spirit after a trip down the Valley. The
                    editors assert that this is a good omen, and will help attract northern labor
                    and capital to the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Losses of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginia sustained 500 million dollars in losses, including slaves, during
                    the war, according to a correspondent of the New York Herald. This includes 15
                    million in cash loaned to the Confederate government, including four million
                    from the school fund.The state also lost one-third of its territory through the
                    formation of West Virginia. At least 50,000 soldiers from Virginia died during
                    the war. "It will thus be perceived that the Old Dominion suffered her share in
                    the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>What are We To Do?</head>
                <origin>Charlottesville Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Chronicle, after showing there is no excuse for the policy of the Radical
                        party, says:</p>
                    <p>There is absolutely no sentiment of <emph rend="italic">justice</emph> left
                        at all where the whites of the South are concerned; the <emph rend="italic"
                            >forms</emph> of fair dealing are not even observed. As witness the
                        giving over the South to the <emph rend="italic">control</emph> of the
                        negroes, when a Northern community will not tolerate even a handful of the
                        same race; as witness the obstacles thrown in the way of registration in
                        Richmond for the purpose of intimidating the whites; as witness the
                        remarkable excitement about a July session of Congress in order to amend
                        again, or begin anew, the scheme of reconstruction in the South--at a moment
                        when we were quietly and laboriously carrying out in good faith the harshest
                        conditions ever imposed on a decent people. Add the cry of confiscation, and
                        the well-understood purpose that if any Southern State complies with the
                        terms of the Reconstruction bill, that compliance will not be availing,
                        unless the blacks of the South are at the same moment given the control of
                        State affairs.</p>
                    <p>We do not mention these things to make any fresh complaints of them. We
                        comprehend the situation. We know that the Republican Party have determined
                        to break down all opposition at the South--and to make it contribute to the
                        strength of the Republican Party.</p>
                    <p>From this conviction there is a practical thing which the South might do that
                        would improve its treatment. One cause of the violent course of the
                        Republicans towards the South is the constant irritation kept up at the
                        North by the Democratic party. The Northern Democratic press, for the
                        campaigning purposes, keeps up a perpetual hot fire against the
                        Republicans--advises the South to resist negro suffrage and the
                        Reconstruction bill, calls on us to become <emph rend="italic"
                        >martyrs</emph>, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c. President Johnson gives
                        countenance to this party, and by some ill advised interference, from time
                        to time, stirs up from his wakeful naps the Radical monster. There is in
                        short a regular war of bitter words going on all the time between the two
                        Northern parties, and the Southern whites are identified in the Northern
                        mind with the Northern Democracy, who pretend to champion our cause. What is
                        the consequence? The lash falls incessantly, and at intervals the screw is
                        given another turn. The idea is we must keep these Southern Democrats well
                        under the foot, or they will rally and co-operate with their Northern
                        allies. That is the train of thought.</p>
                    <p>We therefore do repeat what we have already frequently called attention to;
                        that the first step, for the Southern people to take, is to disclaim all
                        connection with the Northern Democracy. We have not one particle more
                        respect for the Northern Democracy than we have for the Republicans. They
                        got us into troubles, and basely abandoned us. And they are doing us
                        infinite injury now by obstructing the settlement of reconstruction. They
                        use us merely as so much political capital, and are no true friends. But
                        whether friend or foe, they have no power--and are a perpetual nuisance.</p>
                    <p>We have got to make terms with the Republican party--they are the Government;
                        and will be for a good many years.</p>
                    <p>Now let us, in public meetings, lay it down that we do not intend to act with
                        the Northern Democracy.</p>
                    <p>We shall now make our position clear by adding that we (individually) are not
                        going to the Republicans. A great many people are; a great many respectable
                        people who act chiefly from considerations of <emph rend="italic"
                        >policy</emph> are; <emph rend="italic">we are not</emph>. If the
                        Republicans will treat us properly, we will, in the Federal elections, vote
                        for the best man they put up; but we shall not join the party.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Policy</emph> suggests that the Southern people go over
                        to the Republican Party in a body--that all of us call ourselves
                        Republicans. But we do not see how any conscientious man can describe
                        himself by a name which is not true; we do not see how any Southern man can
                        put on the livery of the Republican party without losing his self respect.</p>
                    <p>But the thing is going to be done by a great many; people do not reason
                        nicely; oaths, names, emblems are barriers of straw where a powerful
                        inducement draws a man on to break through them--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Charlottesville Chronicle</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial from the Charlottesville Chronicle argues that the Radical
                    Republicans are treating the South unjustly and hypocritically. Unfortunately,
                    Northern Democrats are making the situation worse by agitating and giving the
                    Republicans even more reason to deal harshly with the South. The article
                    advocates making terms with the Republicans without giving them support.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Editorial Correspondence of the Rockingham Register</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton, June 20, 1867.</p>
                    <p>We may as well admit the fact, that our good neighbors of this attractive
                        mountain "city" are greatly in advance of us "fogies" in Harrisonburg, with
                        all our enterprise, all our industry, all our activity of movement. A few
                        days most pleasantly spent here looking around, as "a snapper up of
                        unconsidered trifles," have satisfied us that we must quicken our momentum
                        if we would not be left behind Staunton in the race for material prosperity.
                        The beneficial effects of a railroad upon the fortunes of an interior town
                        are here seen. The business men, the merchants, the tradesmen, the
                        shop-keepers, have all the airs and manners which attach to important
                        centres of trade and commerce. Whilst, however, our neighbors of Staunton
                        are ahead of us in population, enterprize and in some other elements of
                        material prosperity, yet it is undeniably that a very large amount of their
                        business success is mainly attributed to their intimate connection with us.
                        The upper part of the great county of Rockingham has been pouring her
                        exuberant resources directly into the laps of the enterprizing business men
                        of Staunton. The business done at the railroad depot in Rockingham flour,
                        corn, bacon, butter, etc., is very great indeed. With the completion of
                            <emph rend="italic">our</emph> railroad (no longer a matter of doubt and
                        uncertainty,) this tide of material life will flow into Harrisonburg, and
                        we, too, shall grow rapidly and steadily. To show how Staunton is growing,
                        even as "a way station" on a railroad, (not as the terminus of a great line
                        of railway as our own modest town is destined soon to be,) we may mention
                        that she is spreading her arms in all direction. West of Staunton, there is
                        a very marked air of improvement every where to be seen along the lines of
                        the railroad. There are sixteen or eighteen new dwellings of recent erection
                        between "the city" and Pointsville, an unpretending little village just
                        beyond the limits of the corporation, whilst there are thirty-four new
                        houses now going up in town. Many strangers are seeking localities near
                        Staunton for the purpose of pitching their tents in this beautiful portion
                        of our lovely Valley.</p>
                    <p>A strange interest, too, attaches to this interior "city" because of those
                        great State Institutions, the Asylums for the Deaf &amp; Dumb, and
                        Insane, which are located here. The Insane Asylum is well and favorably
                        known throughout the United States as one of the best institutions of the
                        kind extant, whilst its twin-sister, the Asylum for the Deaf &amp; Dumb,
                        is equally well and favorably recognized throughout the country. In the
                        Asylum for the unfortunate Insane, three hundred and twenty or thirty
                        patients, all of whom are receiving every possible attention which the
                        highest skill, intelligence, and humane sympathy can give. Dr. Stribling, so
                        well known as a gentleman every way fitted for the arduous and delicate
                        duties of his position, still fills the place of Superintendent of this
                        Asylum, aided in his onerous responsibilities by two gentlemen of enlarged
                        intelligence, experience and skill in their professions, Drs. Hamilton
                        &amp; Berkeley. As we stood upon the observatory which surmounts the
                        main building within the grounds occupied by this institution, looking out
                        upon the splendid country which stretches away in every direction, our heart
                        involuntarily thanked God for this heaven-born asylum, for the unfortunate
                        of our State whose minds have been wrecked upon the troubled ocean of life.
                        What, thought we, was the desolation of our beautiful Valley and the
                        destruction of its material interests, compared with the overthrow and wreck
                        of the human mind? Whilst a visit to the Asylum engenders painful sympathies
                        for the unfortunates within its influences, yet all retire with the
                        conviction that the State cannot too liberally support this magnificent
                        charity which has done and is still doing so much to minister to the relief
                        of minds diseased.</p>
                    <p>The Wesleyan Female Institute, in charge of our former townsman, Professor W.
                        A. Harris, deserves cordial recognition at the hands of the friends of an
                        elevated course of education for the gentler sex. The examinations of his
                        pupils have been in progress, and his bright-eyed scholars have shown very
                        commendable progress and proficiency in their various studies.</p>
                    <p>We should like to draw a pen and ink sketch of some of the more prominent
                        public men of Staunton; but a want of time or a want of capability
                        admonishes us to desist for the present.<lb/> W.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A Rockingham correspondent describes the progress and growth Staunton is
                    experiencing as a result of trade, industry and the railroad. He also discusses
                    favorably its state institutions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that "first class harvest hands" are making $2 a day in
                    Augusta, and demand is heavy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Greenville, in Augusta County, is planning to start a brass band.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. H. H. Harris, of Amelia County, has been called to Horeb Church in
                    Augusta County near Weyer's Cave.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Teachers Association of Virginia is meeting in Lynchburg and "the
                    schools of Staunton should be well represented."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The first of many Union prayer meetings was held in Staunton at the
                    Presbyterian Church on Sunday. "We hope they may be well attended and be
                    productive of much good."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Concerts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Methodist Church held two concerts recently. "Both showed what native
                    talent can do, and we hope that such exhibitions will always be encouraged by
                    our people."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Cemeteries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Ladies Cemetery Association received $28.50 from Miss M. E. Jordan of
                    Alleghany. "This is doing well, for one young lady, but there is room for others
                    to do the same. By the way, couldn't our Street Commissioners haul the dirt from
                    the streets to the old Cemetery and the Ladies Cemetery? It would be a great
                    help and add to the attractiveness of the town."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Concert at the D. D. and B. Institution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The blind students at the Deaf, Dumb and Blind Institute gave a concert on
                    Wednesday under the direction of Prof. Turner. The concert was held in the
                    chapel, which was packed to overflowing. The programme consisted of vocal and
                    instrumental music "which was rendered in such exquisite style as to cause a
                    sensation of wonder and admiration among the entire audience. Prof. Turner, with
                    an energy and talent that is commendable, has worked wonders with the musical
                    talent of the Institution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Fashionable Wedding--Beautiful Stauntonian Present</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Paris correspondent of the Baltimore Gazette reports that the
                    "beautiful Miss Carter Thompson, of Staunton," was present at the wedding of
                    Miss Helen Carroll, of Maryland, and Mr. C. Oliver O'Donnell, of Baltimore. The
                    ceremony was held in L'Eglise de la Madeleine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Freedman's Bureau--A Superfluous Concern</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A correspondent of the New York "Herald" writing from Staunton avers that the
                        Freedman's Bureau in this place has "little or nothing to do in the
                        distribution of charity rations. There is no destitution in Virginia. In
                        every part of the State her people have been and are sending off
                        contributions of corn and bacon to the cotton States. How can this be done,
                        considering the ravages of the war, in Virginia? Simply enough. Her people
                        since the war, especially the whites, have worked and are working for large
                        supplies of corn, wheat, rye, potatoes, beans and bacon. Their generous soil
                        has rewarded them. Last year they had a prodigious corn crop, of which they
                        have still a surplus on hand beyond all their immediate wants; and if
                        Congress will only definitely say what we are to do, and all that is wanted,
                        these people declare, 'we will do it because,' they argue, 'we see that the
                        constitutional system in this country is at an end, and we are ready for
                        anything that will give us the repose of an established government.'"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A New York Herald Correspondent in Staunton reports that the Freedman's
                    Bureau there is handing out very few charity rations. In fact, the area is
                    exporting surplus produce to the South, since the people, "especially the
                    whites," have worked hard at rebuilding their farms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Closing of Weslyan Female School</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Payne</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitzer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Anna D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walton</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMullan</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitzen</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds Prof. Harris for a successful completion of the school
                    year at Staunton's Wesleyan Female School, and the high achievement of its
                    pupils on exams. "Considering the condition of this school when he took charge,
                    its success has been wonderful since, and its prospects are now very bright." A
                    new course in Physiology and Hygiene was singled out for praise. A list was
                    published of the graduates of the schools of Natural Philosophy, Chemistry,
                    English Literature, Latin, and French.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that travel is increasing. There were 1,875 visitors to
                    Staunton hotels during the month of June.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Registration in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The current voter registration totals in Staunton are as follows: 1st
                    District, 380 whites and 184 blacks; 2nd District, 466 whites and 258 blacks,
                    leaving a white majority of 301.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Commencement Exercises of Belle Haven Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>A. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Ednorah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a notice of commencement exercises at the Belle Haven
                    Institute in Alexandria. Miss A. V. Mason of Staunton was awarded a medal in
                    music. Miss Ednorah Mason of Staunton was awarded a Certificate of Graduation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Commencement at the Va. Female Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Despite rain and muddy streets, Augusta's citizens enjoyed the commencement
                    exercises of the Virginia Female Institute. The ceremony began with piano music
                    accompanied by Prof. Ide on violin. A chorus performed by the entire class was
                    next, followed by several other vocal and instrumental pieces. Some of the
                    pieces were composed by Ide. Miss A. Cowan of Rockingham delivered the
                    valedictory address. The Rev. A. M. Randolph closed with an address on the
                    "Duties of Woman." "Long may the present corps of teachers continue in their
                    sphere of usefulness, and may this Institution be a 'beacon of light' for its
                    daughters in their paths through life, and prepare them for the enjoyment of
                    another to come."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argabright</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knicely</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funkhouser</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Argabright of Augusta and Miss M. J. Knicely of Rockingham were
                    married on June 6th by the Rev. Joseph Funkhouser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Effie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Pelter and Miss Effie G. Brown, both of Augusta, were married on June
                    15th by the Rev. W. Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1867.07.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
