<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.11.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-11-16">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.16.01">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and a story entitled "How a Woman Had Her Own
                Way."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Triumph of Right!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository details the final election results for Abraham Lincoln's
                    victory over McClellan. Lincoln received 213 electoral votes and 384,000 popular
                    votes. McClellan received 21 electoral votes from Kentucky, Delaware, and New
                    Jersey and 33,000 popular votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cheating By Rule</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'No mere informality in the manner of carrying out, or executing, any of
                    the provision of this act shall invalidate any election held under the same or
                    authorize the returns to be rejected or set aside.' In the face of all these
                    provisions of the law under which the return judges act, and which they are
                    sworn to execute faithfully, the Democratic return judges have pretended to give
                    certificates of election to F. M. Kimmell for Judge, and A. H. Coffroth for
                    Congress, in the face of an undisputed record defeating them both!"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The desperation of the defeated Democrats in this Congressional and Judicial
                        district fitly emblems their hostility to law and order, and shows with what
                        tenacity they cling to the spoils of office. After failing in their studied
                        efforts to disfranchise our gallant soldiers, they next resolved to defy the
                        law and defame them out of their votes; and to that end the Democratic
                        return judges have been manipulated by crafty and reckless politicians and
                        driven to open, insolent disregard of the laws they were sworn to execute.</p>
                    <p>The plain English of the complications in our congressional and judicial
                        districts is that the Democratic candidates for Judge and Congress were
                        defeated at the polls by the army vote; and not relishing defeat they, or
                        their friends, resolved that they wouldn't be defeated if enough of votes
                        could be crowded out to elect them. Just how they were to be crowded out,
                        they did not seem much to care, only so that apparent majorities should come
                        to their side. To this end, Mr. O. N. Shannon, Prothonotary of Bedford
                        county--the same who withdrew his subscription to the soldier bounty
                        fund--took the lead, and manifested his appreciation of his solemn oath of
                        office, and his respect for the integrity of our elections, by usurping the
                        sanctions of a court in a contested election, and rejected such returns as
                        did not suit his views. We say he rejected such as suited him, because he
                        had no right--not even the shadow of a right to reject any; and all his
                        proceedings were extra-judicial to use a charitable phrase, and villainous
                        and fraudulent to apply the honest Saxon. <emph rend="italic">His</emph>
                        duties as Prothonotary, touching election returns are thus clearly defined
                        by the law:</p>
                    <p>Section 1--It shall be the duty of the Prothonotary of the county, to whom
                        such returns shall be made, <emph rend="italic">to deliver to the return
                            Judges of the same county, a copy, certified under his hand and seal of
                            the return of votes so transmitted to him by the Judges of the
                        election</emph>, as aforesaid or as officially certified by the Secretary of
                        the Commonwealth, as aforesaid, by said Prothonotary."</p>
                    <p>Instead of obeying the instructions "to deliver to the return judges" the
                        returns, Mr. Shannon imagined himself to be judge and jury to determine just
                        what votes should be allowed in the count and what should not ; and of
                        course, he only rejected such votes as did not benefit his particular
                        ticket. To consummate a fraud upon the people, upon the soldiers, and upon
                        Judge Klug and Gen. Koontz, Mr. Shannon deliberately defied the law,
                        disregarded his oath of office, and has clouded himself with infamy. But he
                        was not alone in his insolent disregard of sworn duty. The return judges of
                        the Democratic faith in Fulton, Bedford, Adams and Franklin seem to have
                        been trained to aid in the fraud; and with one accord they seem to have been
                        impressed with the necessity of rejecting enough votes to elect their
                        candidates. How far they, in this doing, disregarded the law, let the law
                        itself explain. <emph rend="italic">Their</emph> duty touching election
                        returns are thus defined:</p>
                    <p>"<emph rend="italic">The return Judges, so met shall include in their
                            enumeration, the rates so returned, and thereupon shall proceed, in all
                            respects, in the like manner as is prescribed by law, in cases where all
                            the votes shall have been given at the usual place of election."</emph></p>
                    <p>And lest some fool or scoundrel should not understand the law, or pretend not
                        to understand it, its provisions go so far as to expressly forbid that they
                        shall assume to determine the legality of any votes brought before them. It
                        says in section 79:</p>
                    <p>"The clerks hereupon shall in the presence of the judges, make out returns in
                        the manner here-inafter directed, which shall be signed by all the Judges
                        present, and attested by said clerks and "it shall not be lawful for said
                        Judges or clerks; and <emph rend="italic">it shall not be lawful for said
                            Judges or clerks, in casting up the votes which shall appear to have
                            been given</emph>, as shown by the certificates under the 76th and 77th
                        sections of this act to <emph rend="italic">omit or reject any part
                        thereof</emph>, except where in the opinion of said Judges, such certificate
                        is so defective, <emph rend="italic">as to prevent the same from being
                            understood, and computed in adding together the number of votes, in
                            which case it shall be the duty of said clerks to make out a true and
                            exact copy of said paper or certificate; to be signed by said
                        Judges</emph>, and attested by said clerks, and attached to and transmitted
                        with said return to the Secretary of the Commonwealth &amp; c."</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by the foregoing section of the law that neither the
                        Prothonotary nor the return judges have any right whatever to determine the
                        legality of the votes returned. They are sword to receive, compute and
                        certify them, and "It shall <emph rend="italic">not</emph> be lawful for
                        them <emph rend="italic">to omit or reject any part thereof!</emph>" It is
                        to pretended in these cases that any part of the vote returned could not be
                        "understood." The trouble was that it was too easily understood, and for
                        that reason it was rejected. It was understood that it defeated two
                        Democratic candidates, and to defraud those honestly elected, and with that
                        view only could men thus deliberately cast aside their oath of office and
                        usurp the functions of the courts. They are forbidden even to reject for any
                        sort of informality. If the votes lack all the formalities of the law, they
                        must nevertheless be returned by the Prothonotary and counted and certified
                        by the judges. Such is the language of the law, as follows:</p>
                    <p>"No mere informality in the manner of carrying out, or executing, any of the
                        provision of this act shall invalidate any election held under the same or
                            <emph rend="italic">authorize the returns to be rejected or set
                        aside."</emph></p>
                    <p>In the face of all these provisions of the law under which the return judges
                        act, and which they are sworn to execute faithfully, the Democratic return
                        judges have pretended to give certificates of election to F.M. Kimmell for
                        Judge, and A.H. Coffroth for Congress, in the face of an undisputed record
                        defeating them both. That Gen. Coffroth will take any sort of a certificate
                        and imagine himself a Congressman until his vain dreams are dispelled when
                        Gen. Koontz takes his seat, is natural enough and will surprise no one; but
                        can F.M. Kimmel accept a certificate in plain violation of law, and assume
                        the functions of an office thereby which charges him with the execution of
                        the laws? Coffroth has nothing to lose--neither reputation nor honors, but
                        Judge Kimmell has been Judge and retired with credit, and he cannot now, in
                        the face of the law, accept so sacred a trust merely because a few mad
                        political partizans have been false to their oaths and faithless to justice.
                        No one knows better than himself that return judges have no right to reject
                        any returns whatever, and that the whole power to determine questions of
                        illegal voting belongs to the courts; and for him to claim the advantage of
                        an insolent wrong--a palpable infraction of the laws of the State, and a
                        shameless disregard of the oaths of the return judges, would make our
                        judicial tribunal but a mockery of justice and of law.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Koontz has a regular certificate of election; will be proclaimed elected
                        by the Governor, and will be called in the House and sworn. Attempts to
                        defraud him by a bogus certificate given Gen. Coffroth will be entirely
                        futile; but should Judge Kimmell accept the brief and blotted honors
                        presented to him by men who seem insensible to duty or shame, a contest
                        before the legislature must ensue and Judge King would be in the false
                        position of a contestant, while he is entitled by every declaration of the
                        law to his commission on the return. It matters not, so far as the
                        correctness of our position goes, whether the legal votes would elect Judge
                        Kimmell or not. Not knowing anything about it, we do not assume to determine
                        that question; but <emph rend="italic">prima facie</emph> Judge King is
                        elected, and the law declares in the most unequivocal language that he shall
                        be so returned, and that Judge Kimmell shall be contestant if they be any
                        contest. We shall see what we shall see, with abiding faith that all will
                        end well.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Criticizes the election judges who discarded army votes to obtain
                    Democratic victories for Kimmell for judge and Coffroth for Congress. The
                    Repository believes Governor Curtin will proclaim Koontz's election over
                    Kimmell. The paper prepares to criticize Coffroth if he accepts the illegal
                    victory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes the Harrisburg Telegraph for suggesting that Simon Cameron, the
                    chairman of the Union State Committee, intentionally refrained from campaigning
                    in the October elections to reserve his efforts for Lincoln's election in
                    November. The Repository argues that "None but a perfectly original blockhead
                    would decide to lose a State in October in order to gain it in November, and
                    Gen. Cameron is not of that sort."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository criticizes the decision by the election judges to discard
                    election tickets with G. Morrison Coates's name misspelled "C. Morrison Coates."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository demands that the Valley Spirit print the correct election
                    results noting that the Democrats only elected one-third of the congressmen and
                    slightly more than one-third of the legislators.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Franklin County Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository prints the official election results for King and Coffroth,
                    for Lincoln and McClellan as well as a history of the two parties since 1854.
                    The faintness of the article makes the list of results illegible, but a summary
                    reveals that the full vote provided Lincoln about 200 to 250 majority in the
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Reference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository notes that the recent elections gave the U. S. Congress a
                    two-thirds Union majority making the abolition of slavery by Constitutional
                    amendment doubtless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It betrays a singular hallucination on the subject of negro equality,
                    apparently inspired by the apprehension that some ambitious sable statesman may
                    one day write more learnedly on law than have some white men in the past. Don't
                    borrow trouble on that point, friend Jeremiah. The African like all other races,
                    will be simply good for what he is worth-- no more, no less--and he cannot be
                    perpetually degraded or elevated beyond that point."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository ridicules Jeremiah Black for his fears about the advancement
                    of black men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Declares the commencement of the draft, at the office of Capt. Eyster, for
                    the district including Adams, Bedford, Franklin, Fulton, and Somerset counties.
                    The article notes the surplus and deficiencies of each county for the 700,000
                    and 500,000 calls. Franklin County has 44 surplus and 6 deficiencies for the
                    700,000 call and 27 surplus and 62 deficiencies for the 500,000. Franklin has a
                    surplus on the first call in all sub-districts except three: Southampton,
                    Hamilton, and Warren. Each district is entitled to credit for its surplus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Border Protection</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Outrages upon persons and property other than were justified by the usages
                    of war, or ever incident to the movement of a large army, were rare; but in
                    1864, when the rebel cause is sinking into the depths of despair, we find a part
                    of the same army of Lee make it a record of vandalism unparalleled in the
                    history of modern warfare."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the increase in guerilla bands raiding towns with the increased
                    demoralization of the rebel troops. The Repository urges localities along the
                    border to organize companies of 50-100 men to protect their homes and property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.16.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Rebel Movements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On Thursday Major Gilmore with perhaps twenty men, was in Shepperdstown.
                    He robbed the stores and individuals in the most approved rebel style, and we
                    learn, killed one man named Snyder for want of promptness in delivering up his
                    pocketbook."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Chambersburg was thrown into a fever of excitement on Saturday night last, by
                        the apparently well authenticated rumor that Maj. Gilmore with fifty of his
                        rebel command had crossed the Potomac at Shepperdstown on Saturday. Gen.
                        Couch made prompt disposition of his forces to meet any movement of the
                        enemy by throwing his men forward to the border to cover the more exposed
                        points; and as the troops left this point for the border our people were
                        apprehensive that a small raiding party might reach our town. Considerable
                        uneasiness prevailed during the night; but with Sunday morning came
                        assurances of safety, and the venerable village assumed its serenity again.
                        We submit whether it is not worthy of reflection on the part of every
                        able-bodied citizen, whether a rumor of fifty or even five hundred rebels
                        advancing, upon this point, <emph rend="italic">should</emph> create alarm
                        and confusion? If there were no military forces here at all, the people of
                        Chambersburg <emph rend="italic">could</emph> readily defend themselves
                        against small raids, and they <emph rend="italic">would</emph> do so if they
                        had but organization. Let us have organization at once, not only here, but
                        throughout the entire county, and raiding and all danger of raids will be at
                        an end.</p>
                    <p>The fact which led to the fluster here on Saturday night were about as
                        follows: On Thursday Major Gilmore with perhaps twenty men, was in
                        Shepperdstown. He robbed the stores and individuals in the most approved
                        rebel style, and we learn, killed one man named Snyder for want of
                        promptness in delivering up his pocketbook. After glutting his appetite in
                        the way of free-booting, the command dispersed, and a portion of the party
                        crossed the river and scattered through the country in citizens dress,
                        doubtless to look out good points for plunder. That a portion of them are in
                        this county there is no reasonable doubt, as three of them were arrested on
                        the cars on Saturday last near Newville. The mean robbery, arson and murder
                        if necessary to carry out their plans, and every citizen should be on the
                        alert to compass their arrest. No stranger should be allowed to loiter in
                        any part of the county without being required to give a satisfactory account
                        of his business, and failing to do that, he should be allowed the privilege
                        of explaining his business to the nearest military commander. The common
                        safety demands that suspicious characters should not be tolerated at all in
                        any part of the border, and if honest and innocent men suffer some
                        inconvenience at times, they can well afford it in view of the perils
                        against which we have to guard. Let every citizen be vigilant, and fully
                        prepared for rebel prowlers, and in their vigilance and preparation will be
                        their entire safety.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes Chambersburg's panic at the rumor of a rebel company, led by
                    Major Gilmore, crossing the Potomac at Shepperdstown on November 12. The
                    Repository argues that the organization of a company to protect the area would
                    increase feelings of safety.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrested As Spies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the arrest of three men as rebel spies. The men claimed to be rebel
                    deserters. The Repository doubts their word because they passed several military
                    outposts--including the one at Chambersburg--without surrendering themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bank of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mull</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the decision to change the Bank of Chambersburg to a national
                    institution, "The First National Bank of Chambersburg." Armstrong was appointed
                    auditor to determine the value of the stock for those holders who wish to sell.
                    Messersmith remains the cashier. The financial officers--Messersmith, Mull , and
                    Taylor--were given gifts of $1,000, $500, and $500 respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Called To St. Louis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. S. J. Niccolls, pastor of the Presbyterian Church in
                    Chambersburg, was called to lead the Second Presbyterian Church of St. Louis.
                    The Chambersburg congregation appointed Sharpe and Reed as representatives at
                    the meeting at the Presbytery in Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the promotion to captain and assignment as Quartermaster to Maj.
                    Gen. Foster at Hilton Head of James R. Gilmore, chief of the Telegraph Corps in
                    North Carolina. The Repository printed numerous letters sent by Gilmore in the
                    last fourteen months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Serenade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the serenading of General Couch and Colonel Stumbaugh by the
                    Union men of Chambersburg. Stumbaugh and McClure gave speeches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Officers Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the election of John A. Wright as president of the Connellsville
                    and Southern Pennsylvania Railroad and McClure as a director. The Repository
                    reports that a survey of the proposed route pends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Presented</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the presentation of a silver communion service by the First
                    Presbyterian Church of Pittsburgh to the Chambersburg Presbyterian Church. The
                    Chambersburg church's service was destroyed in the fire on July 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the number of votes counted from the box in Lurgan Township
                    exceeded the number of names on the poll lists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carper</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the restoration of the post office at Keeffer's Store and the
                    appointment of William Carper as postmaster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Speech From The President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a speech given by Lincoln on the war's demonstration that a people's
                    government could sustain a national election in the midst of a great civil war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Cavalry Fight in the Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a cavalry fight in the Shenandoah Valley including rebel defeat,
                    the pursuit to Front Royal, and the participation of Gens. Torbert and Sheridan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Movements on the Border</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Warns citizens to be watchful for a small band of rebels that reportedly
                    crossed the Potomac and scattered in civilian dress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Prompt Measures for Defense</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a meeting of citizens of Chambersburg to organize and arm in
                    protection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>McClellan Resigns His Commission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the War Department received McClellan's resignation of his
                    commission. The editors of the Repository believe that the government will not
                    accept the resignation, but will instead assign him to duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Reported Capture of Augusta, Ga.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the rumor of Sherman's capture of Augusta, Georgia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes war news including the defeat of Gen. Hood with considerable
                    losses in his first attempt to cross the Tennessee River, the capture of the
                    pirate ship Florida by the Wachusett off the coast of San Salvador, Ewell's
                    command of the rebels in the Shenandoah Valley, the destitution of the rebel
                    army, and Gen. Pleasanton's congratulations of his troops for their defeat of
                    Price in Missouri.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the accidental poisoning of Gen. Sheridan and several staff
                    officers in Winchester. A corrosive substance had been mixed with their food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf>M. D.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Tirzah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 3, by Rev. West, J. Mackey, M. D., State Acting Asst. Surgeon,
                    U. S. General Hospital, Summit House, West Philadelphia, married T. Gamble, of
                    the Dry Run vicinity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kobler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohler</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 3, at the home of S. Lobler Esq., in Guilford Township, by Rev.
                    S. McHenry, W. Bittner married L. Kohler, both of the Marion vicinity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKelvy</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKelvy</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKelvy</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 13, at Laclode, Illinois, David, son of George and Sarah
                    McKelvey, of Path Valley, Franklin County, died at the age of 17 years, 6
                    months, and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.16.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
