<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.10.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-05">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sherman's Rebuke To Hood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"When Gen. Sherman made Treason feel the iron heel of the conqueror by
                    ordering all rebel citizens out of his lines, so as to prevent an organization
                    of rebel spies by the people who live on her bounty, Gen. Hood denounced the
                    order as 'studied and ungenerous cruelty.' To this Gen. Sherman replied in the
                    following pungent letter. It would be well for Northern men who are always
                    complaining of Union armies and officers, to read what the Hero of Atlanta
                    says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints Sherman's response to the rebel General Hood's outrage over
                    Sherman's expulsion of rebels from his lines. Sherman defends his order as
                    insuring the safety of the women and children of Atlanta. He points out that
                    rebels made similar orders or faced civilian casualties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Richmond Examiner On The Political Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'It is useless to vote war if your last armies are destroyed; useless to
                    vote peace if your armies are marching on flushed with victory to a splendid
                    conquest.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an article of the Richmond Examiner linking the election results
                    with the progress of the rebel army and the Union army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Are The Germans Wrong In Wanting Our Bonds?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I have received six per cent. in gold, which averaged 100 per cent, in
                    currency, making 12 percent. income. Now, today, my bond is salable [sic] in the
                    New York market at 10 per cent. premium. Put these together, and to-day I have
                    22 per cent. for one year's use of my money."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository describes Germans as excellent savers of money. Germans'
                    buying of U. S. Securities, indicates the soundness of the investment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Hon. Alexander King</head>
                <origin>The Somerset Herald and Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Herald and Whig praise Alexander King's execution of his duties in
                    court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following remarkable statement comes from a correspondent of the
                    Press in the field in front of Petersburg. It is vouched for as true by the
                    writer, and he refers to the Union soldiers for proof of the truth of what he
                    says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a report describing soldiers' responses to the candidates for
                    president. The rebel soldiers on the front line gave three cheers for the
                    nomination of McClellan while the Union soldiers responded with their own cheers
                    for Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Among other news items, is the note that a number of men--Johnson, R. J.
                    Breckinridge, Tod, E. Everett, D. S. Dickinson, L. Trmaine, B. F. Butler, B. H.
                    Brewster, W. M. Hiester, D. Dougherty, U. S. Grant--who opposed Lincoln in 1860,
                    now support Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and legal notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository responds to a Valley Spirit article that notes prosperity
                    under Democratic administrations. The Repository argues that Democratic U. S.
                    Senators led the movement for secession destroying peace and undermining
                    prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists notable Democrats who moved from opposing Lincoln to supporting him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Responds to a Valley Spirit article in support of J. McDowell Sharpe by
                    praising A. K. McClure. The Valley Spirit article celebrates Sharpe's efforts in
                    the legislature to get compensation for the Franklin County sufferers. The
                    Repository reminds readers of McClure's efforts while a private citizen to get
                    compensation for the destruction of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the dropping prices caused by the hopeful outlook of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calls attention to the Valley Spirit praise of McClure's efforts to get
                    compensation from the legislature for the destruction in Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Old Keystone State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report that Pennsylvania sent sixteen regiments to Grant's army
                    as well as approximately 20,000 volunteers to the old regiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the recent decision to exempt any man who paid the $300 exemption for
                    any previous draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gen. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note McClellan's hypocritical demand for frugal government
                    while retaining his commission in the army without rendering any service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Democrats of Fulton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the abuse committed by Democrats upon the enrolling officers for
                    Licking Creek Township and Bethel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors reference a letter from a Franklin County soldier at the
                    hospital at Cumberland. The soldiers in the hospital unanimously support
                    Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Maj. Harry White</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the exchange of former senator Maj. Harry White, of the 67th
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports news from Harrisburg including the promptness of Pennsylvania in
                    furnishing troops, the sixteen regiments organized by Governor Curtin, and
                    electioneering for the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes war news including the victory of General Sully over 5,000
                    Indians on September 21, Longstreet in command of the Shenandoah Valley, rumors
                    Georgia's re-admission to the Union, the break up of General Early's army, and
                    the movement of generals Ord and Birney on Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Last Speech of Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Then, I ask, what excuse has the South for the scheme which they have
                    concocted to wind up the Union? The slavery question is a mere excuse. The
                    election of Lincoln is but a pretext. The present Secession movement is the
                    result of an enormous conspiracy which was matured a year ago."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints the last speech of Douglas in support of war should
                    the South secede from the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gen. Sherman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I assert that my military plans make it necessary for the inhabitants to
                    go away, and I can only renew my offer of services to make their exodus, in any
                    direction, as easy and comfortable as possible--You cannot qualify war in
                    harsher terms than I will."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints Sherman's response to complaints of the removal of
                    Atlanta's inhabitants. Sherman discusses the necessity of the order to his
                    military strategy to end the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Hear The Rebel Vice President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a speech in 1861 by Alexander Stephens, the Vice President of the
                    Confederacy, reminding Southern leaders of all the benefits of the Union and
                    federal government and asking what wrongs the Union committed against the
                    Southern states that justify secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Burglary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a burglary at the warehouse of Wunderlich &amp; Nead. The
                    thieves used a false key and blew the safe to steal three U. S. bonds for $500
                    each.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamman</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Philip Hamman reopened his law practice at the office of
                    Mrs. Bard, formerly occupied by Reilly &amp; Sharpe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Liberal Contribution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Acknowledges the contribution of $151 from the citizens of Dry Run and
                    Spring Run to the citizens of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 22, in the Lutheran Parsonage, Upper Strasburg, S. Gelwix
                    married K. Snyder, the eldest daughter of Rev. Snyder, both of Upper Strasburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 21, Mrs. Cross died at about 98 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>List Of Causes For Trial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phreaner</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crook</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zellers</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rule</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philippi</ln>
                        <fn>Mathias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashway</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennock</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennock</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trindle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritch</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holby</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cramer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoap</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hock</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brough</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>W. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreager</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prothonotary</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of causes for trial for the October term. The cases for the first week
                    are as follows: T. Carlisle, surviving partner of Robison &amp; Carlisle vs.
                    B. Phreaner's Administrators; J. and S. Ely vs. F. Funk; E. Kuhn vs. W. Crook's
                    Executors; S. Bowman vs. W. Bowman; M. Zellers vs. J. Rule; M. Philippi vs. J.
                    Ashway; S. &amp; M. Pennock &amp; Co. vs W. Reber; E. Trindle and S.
                    Doyle vs. M. Clarke; J. Tritch vs. J. Price. The cases for the second week are
                    as follows: H. Holby vs T. Fletcher, J. Cramer, J. Gelwicks and others; S. Baker
                    vs S. Bitner Administrator of P. Kyner; W. Bush vs. J. Shoap; C. Hock vs. A.
                    Adams et al.; J. Kennedy's Executors vs. P. Bough, et al.; W. Rodgers vs. W.
                    Keyser; A. Lochbaum vs. Dr. Lambert and J. Huber; R. Morrison vs. H. Kreager,
                    for the use of Administrators of J. Miller; G. Gaff's use vs. J. Tritle; J.
                    Snyder and wife vs. W. Christ; A. Hess vs. D. Reisher. K. Taylor, the
                    prothonotary, publishes the list.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.05.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
