<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/01/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-06-29">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gambling Operation Defeated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Couch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A ring of stock gamblers, including a man who identified himself as Joseph
                    H. Miller, attempted to produce a panic and cause the price of Cumberland Coal
                    Company stock to plummet so they could buy it up. The scheme entailed convincing
                    the public, via the newspapers, that rebel forces had invaded Cumberland Valley,
                    but Mr. Gilmore, the telegraph operator in Chambersburg, was suspicious of the
                    dispatches he was supposed to be sending. Instead of sending them along to the
                    Associated Press in New York and the Philadelphia Inquirer, he passed them along
                    to Major General Couch, who confirmed that it was a hoax.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the 21st Cavalry</head>
                <origin>Camp one mile from Chickahominy River, June 8th, 1864.</origin>
                <commentary>"The 21st in Battle--A Brilliant Charge--Col. Boyd Wounded--The Regiment
                    Complimented--Nine Killed and Forty-nine Wounded"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. H. R.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Water</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2d Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>News from the front, where the 21st Cavalry had to fight as Infantry (a
                    "cruel test," for they had never been drilled even an hour in infantry
                    movements). There is also an account of the wounding of Col. Boyd, who was
                    "sitting down cheering his men and smoking his pipe" when a sharpshooter got
                    him. 2d Lieut. R. Water of Co. E was struck upon the side of the neck with a
                    shell and instantly killed, one of nine men to die. A total of forty-nine were
                    wounded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"The Richmond Whig, contemplating the scarcity of provisions in the rebel
                    capital, proposes to expel the Irish and German women, who are running from
                    place to place where charity is dispensed, 'just as hogs in the fall of the year
                    run from one apple tree to another.' The New York Post suggests that they be
                    exchanged for an equal number of rebel women, who are now crowding the boarding
                    houses of New York, and twenty thousand of whom are known to the police."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The "Political Intelligence" column appears on this page, along with an
                account of Lincoln's recent visit with General Grant and summaries of financial,
                personal, and war news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"Do not venture into a sick room if you are in a violent perspiration: for
                    the moment your body becomes cold it is in a state likely to absorb the
                    infection; nor visit a sick person (if the complaint be of a contagious nature)
                    with an empty stomach, nor swallow your saliva. In attending a sick person,
                    place yourself where the air passes from the door or window to the bed of the
                    invalid, not between the invalid and the fire, as the heat of the fire will draw
                    the infections vapor in that direction, and you would run much danger from
                    breathing in it."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Flirtation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"Flirtation, whether seriously or lightly considered, is injurious to a
                    woman as well as unbecoming to her. It is a broad unblushing confession which
                    the individual makes, of her desire to attract the notice of men. No girl ever
                    made a happy union by flirtation, because no man capable of making a woman
                    permanently happy was ever attracted by that which is disgusting to persons of
                    intelligent refinement."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes reviews of Grant's campaign, a transcription of a speech by James T.
                Brady at a mass meeting held in honor of Grant in New York on June 4th, anecdotes,
                and advertisements, with the following headings: Dry &amp; Fancy Goods; Watches
                and Jewelry; Education; Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.03">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Gutta-Percha Roofing;
                Medical; Publications; Tobacco and Segars; Dentistry; Co-partnership Notices;
                Groceries; &amp;c; Hardware, Cutlery, &amp;c; Forwarding Houses; Attorneys
                at Law; Hats, Caps, &amp; Straw Goods; Miscellaneous.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Congressmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Judging the result in these districts by the present indications, the
                    Union men cannot fail to gain at least five Congressmen in his State, and if New
                    York, Ohio and Indiana do as well, the proposed amendment of the constitution
                    abolishing slavery, will not be defeated in the next Congress for want of a
                    two-thirds vote."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An overview of the Pennsylvania Congressmen, and a look toward the next
                    term, as the long session of Congress draws to a close. Franklin County is in
                    the 16th District, represented by Coffroth, who will probably be "run out" by
                    Col. Jordan of Bedford, or Gen. Koontz of Somerset in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Coffroth Speaks a Piece</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Scathing ridicule of Coffroth, the present Representative of the 16th
                    District. For instance: "It is not the fault of Coffroth that Coffroth cannot
                    reason; for his reason is not of his own creation, and it would be unfilial to
                    blame his parents--blasphemous to blame his God. Hence the mantle of charity
                    falls over such mingled nonsense and half-fledged treason as Coffroth utters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>"The Methodist Sunday School Convention"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Of the thirty-nine schools reporting at the Methodist Sunday School
                    Convention for the Carlisle District, the one in Chambersburg is the
                    oldest--dating since 1821, and of the sixty-four in the district, Chambersburg
                    is the largest, with 275 scholars. Rev. F. Dyson was the reporter for the
                    Chambersburg section of the district. There are 1,050 teachers and officers and
                    4,800 scholars in the entire district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes various barbs thrown at the Valley Spirit, more articles
                about Pennsylvanian politics and politicians, and small news items.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Gallant 21st Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt. Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Menear</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stern</ln>
                        <fn>Henry J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheeler</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>Peter H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beitler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hart</ln>
                        <fn>L. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prosser</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Toot</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>N. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peacock</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vondersmith</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vincent</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hack</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2d Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn>D. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meloy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vancamp</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>Emmet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurst</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drum</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clellan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keppley</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>Theo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strunk</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wagoner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmiston</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilfong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Millen</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geiger</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>G. W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strine</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stohr</ln>
                        <fn>Max</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moson</ln>
                        <fn>R. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillies</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Call</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>L. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walters</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shroeder</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heikes</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lott</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bronizer</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krouse</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Clellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gill</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lohr</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>Airwine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markey</ln>
                        <fn>Pat</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowman</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stutzman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bingaman</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huss</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barrack</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Melker</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carr</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minnick</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hickman</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reinohl</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bechtel</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burket</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kepley</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Augline</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rousch</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knight</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholas</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whiteneck</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bollinger</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Cormick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fannycase</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanderaw</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stone</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickell</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Unger</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitz</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neal</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bair</ln>
                        <fn>John K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherzer</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickerson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Filby</ln>
                        <fn>Thaddeus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williamson</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Levy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leat</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Travis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiser</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devers</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A brief history of this new regiment, including a listing, supplied by
                    Sergt. Maj. H. B. Kindig, of those known to be killed and wounded in the recent
                    fighting. Capt. Hullinger's company was detached and sent to the mining region
                    of Pennsylvania "on special duty," but the rest of the companies of the "Gallant
                    21st" soon found themselves in the thick of the fighting at Cold Harbor and then
                    at Petersburg The need for infantry reinforcements was great, and the 21st had
                    to "dismount, turn over their horses and equipments, shoulder muskets and march
                    at once to the front as infantry." In the action of June 2 &amp; 3, Col.
                    William H. Boyd was wounded seriously in the neck. In Company A, Privates E. J.
                    Menear, Henry J. Stern, and William T. Sheeler were wounded; In Company B,
                    Privates Peter H. Mickley and John Beitler were killed, Sergt. L. J. Hart and
                    Privates Charles S. Prosser, William Toot, N. D. Miller, George W. Conrad, and
                    Samuel A. Peacock were wounded; In Company C, Capt. D. B. Vondersmith, Sergt. D.
                    J. Vincent, Corp. James Bush, Privates George Houser and William E. Hack were
                    wounded; In Company E, 2d Lieut. R. Waters and Private John Kayton were killed,
                    Sergt. Buchanan, Corp. G. W. Bowman, Privates George Kline, D. F. Pratt, and
                    John Greenawalt were killed; In Company F, Corp. G. W. Davis and Privates John
                    Meloy and J. W. Vancamp were wounded; In Company G, Private John Smith was
                    killed, Capt. W. H. Phillips, 1st Sergt. Emmet Reynolds, Privates John A. Hurst
                    and William Drum were wounded; In Company H, Sergt. M'Clellan, Privates D.
                    Keppley, Theo Parker, and Frank Strunk were wounded; In Company I, Sergt.
                    Wagoner and Private Parker were killed, Lieut. M. P. Doyle, Corp. H. C.
                    Edmiston, Sergts. Wilfong and John R. M'Millen, Privates M. Geiger and William
                    Kline were wounded; In Company K, Private Henry Oyler was killed, Privates G. W.
                    E. Small and John Clark were wounded; In Company L, Corp. Scott and Privates P.
                    Strine and Jacob Sharer were wounded; In Company M, Privates Max Stohr and Jacob
                    Leer were wounded. In the action of June 17-19, Lieut. Col. R. F. Moson and
                    Major Charles F. Gillies were wounded. In Company A, Capt. H. W. M'Call, Sergt.
                    L. F. Johnson, Corp. Joseph Smith, Privates B. Walters, Charles Shroeder, James
                    Gordon and Daniel Heikes were wounded; In Company B, 1st Lieut. H. G. Lott,
                    Sergt. L. Bronizer, Privates C. Lynn, D. Krouse, and William M'Clellan were
                    wounded; In Company C, Privates J. Kaufman and Samuel Thompson were wounded; In
                    Company E, Corp. A. Howard, Privates D. Burkholder, C. Hollar, John Alexander,
                    William B. Gill, and Marion Baker were wounded; In Company F, Privates Harrison
                    Lohr, William H. Pearson, and Airwine Horner were killed, Privates J. R. Miller,
                    George Palmer, Pat Markey, D. Plowman, Samuel Stutzman, and A. Smith were
                    wounded; In Company G, Private William A. Bingaman was killed; Corp. W. Cooper,
                    Privates E. Wilson, John Huss, H. Barrack, Thomas Wills, Israel Kyle, Henry
                    Melker, and J. C. Lambert were wounded; In Company H, Privates Hugh Carr and
                    William Minnick were killed, Sergt. E. Hickman, Corp. J. K. Lehman, Privates G.
                    H. Reinohl, D. B. Bechtel, John W. Weaver, Burket, J. Lawrence, J. Kepley, W.
                    Augline, and J. Bowman were wounded; In Company I, Privates D. Rousch, John
                    Knight, Charles Nicholas, John Blair, G. W. Whiteneck, A. Bollinger, John
                    Fisher, and Jere Kauffman were wounded; In Company K, Private George Shaffer was
                    killed, Sergt. F. Gamble, Privates John M'Cormick and H. Ruthrauff were wounded;
                    In Company L, Privates Thomas Fannycase, Joseph Wilson, William H. Huber, L.
                    Vanderaw, William Stone, C. W. Bender, Jere Weaver, William Myers, Daniel Henry,
                    S. Stickell, and William H. Unger were wounded; In Company M, Corp. J. H.
                    Kendig, Privates Samuel Norris, Simon Fitz, and Frank Neal were killed, Sergts.
                    E. L. Wright, John Armstrong, John K. Bair, Charles Sherzer, Corps. James
                    Robinson, Thomas Dickerson, Privates Thaddeus Filby, William Wright, James
                    Pennell, Thomas Hays, and Harvey Williamson were wounded. The Herald adds the
                    following names of men killed and wounded in the fighting on the 22nd: David
                    Leat, Milton Stewart, William Travis, and George B. Wiser, all killed, and
                    Lieut. John A. Devers, wounded. Lieut. Levy, commissary of the 21st, and Lieut.
                    Clark, quartermaster in charge of headquarters' commissary wagons, narrowly
                    escaped a shot that killed an "inoffensive mule" when it ricocheted between the
                    two men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>From Libby Prison</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of the outrages of Libby Prison, supplied by Mr. Peter Bowers,
                    of Co. A, 13th Pennsylvania Cavalry, who was imprisoned there for sixty days.
                    The men are nearly starved to death, and subjected to "the strictest vigilance
                    and most revolting brutality." The dead were taken to the "dead room," where
                    they often remained for days, decomposing in full view of those prisoners who
                    were still alive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Refugees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They had, when they started, two two-horse wagons and when three miles
                    from Edinsburg, a party of guerrillas came out from a dense wood on the road,
                    and took the best horse from them. They were then compelled to load up their
                    effects and the small children in one wagon and abandon the other."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Greencastle <emph rend="italic">Pilot</emph> gives an account of a number
                        of Union Refugees from Virginia. It says that owing to the impoverished
                        condition of the country, and impelled by the natural desire to be with
                        their husbands again, four married women (with eighteen children) set out
                        from the vicinity of Hensley's Methodist Church, Rockingham county, Va., on
                        Wednesday, the 8th of June, for Pennsylvania, where they expected to meet
                        their husbands, who had left some months previous for the freer and purer
                        atmosphere of the loyal Stotes [sic].</p>
                    <p>The names of the party are as follows, viz: Mrs. Wesley Hensley, with seven
                        children; Mrs. Rob't Hensley, with five children; Mrs. Matthew Lamb, with
                        six children, and Mrs. Hiram Hensley, making twenty-two persons in all. They
                        had, when they started, two two-horse wagons and when three miles from
                        Edinsburg, a party of guerrillas came out from a dense wood on the road, and
                        took the best horse from them. They were then compelled to load up their
                        effects and the small children in one wagon and abandon the other. The women
                        and large children had to walk all the way from that place, and met with no
                        further interruption on the road. At Martinsburg they readily procured a
                        pass to cross the Potomac. On last Thursday the party, way-worn and
                        foot-sore, reached the vicinity of Greencastle, and were hospitably
                        entertained by Mr. Mickley.</p>
                    <p>Their destitute condition becoming known to our citizens, contributions were
                        at once made, and these women and children sent by railroad to Harrisburg.
                        Their horses and wagon were sent in charge of one of their friends in the
                        same direction.</p>
                    <p>Our readers will remember that some months ago we published a statement that
                        a band of twenty-four men, Union refugees from Rockingham co., Va., had
                        passed over the South Mountain into Adams county, where they were engaged in
                        cutting timber. Here the small pox broke out among the party, and some of
                        them died, and the rest scattered: among those who died was a son of the
                        elder Mrs. Hensly, the husband of the younger woman of that name. The first
                        intelligence they had of this fact they received here, and were distressed
                        very much in consequence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hensley</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Twenty-two Union refugees from Virginia, all women and children, have
                    reached the vicinity of Greencastle, where Mr. Mickley has "hospitably
                    entertained" them. They are Mrs. Wesley Hensley, with seven children; Mrs.
                    Robert Hensley, with five children; Mrs. Matthew Lamb, with six children; and
                    Mrs. Hiram Hensley. Their husbands had preceded them, making up a party of men
                    cutting timber in Adams County, but small pox had broken out among the men. Some
                    had died, included one of the husbands, and the rest had scattered, all of which
                    was news to the women.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Body Found</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pencyl</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waltman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harclerode</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The body of Charles Pencyl, whose disappearance was noticed in early April,
                    was found by George Waltman and his small son, in the woods near Charles
                    Harclerode's in Bedford County. Waltman was at the foot of Dunning's Mountain,
                    looking for his cows when his son spotted a soldier's hat, which led to the
                    discovery of the body, "torn asunder, and scattered" by beasts. Foul play has
                    been ruled out, and it is presumed that he "perished from exposure" on the night
                    of the 29th of March, "when he had lost his way in a heavy snow storm."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Franklin County Rebel Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gen. Sheridan in his official account of his battle with Lee's cavalry
                    near Gordonsville, on the 12th inst., reports among the rebel dead left on the
                    field, 'Col McAllister, commanding a regiment, killed.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Gen. Sheridan in his official account of his battle with Lee's cavalry near
                        Gordonsville, on the 12th inst., reports among the rebel dead left on the
                        field, "Col McAllister, commanding a regiment, killed." This doubtless was
                        Thomas McAllister, formerly of St. Thomas, in this county. He was a native
                        of Juniata, and moved here some time about 1840; was chosen to the
                        legislature in 1846 with Maj. John M. Pomeroy, but was not returned. Soon
                        after he moved to Virginia, turned up as a rebel Colonel, and has at last
                        met the hard fate he invited by his treason. His brother, Col. Robert
                        McAllister, of Juniata, has commanded a New Jersey regiment for two years
                        past, and has twice been in battle when his rebel brother's command was
                        engaged against him.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllister</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllister</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheridan's official account of the battle on the 12th of June reported that
                    Col. McAllister was among the rebel dead, and it is thought that this must be
                    Thomas McAllister, formerly of St. Thomas, who had moved to Virginia and "turned
                    up as a rebel Colonel." While in Franklin County, he was chosen for the
                    legislature in 1846 with Maj. John M. Pomeroy, but was not returned. His
                    brother, Col. Robert McAllister, of Juniata, "has commanded a New Jersey
                    regiment for two years past, and has twice been in battle when his rebel
                    brother's command was engaged against him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shockey</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jno. Shockey, son of Isaac Shockey, Esq., of Franklin County, has died from
                    the effects of a wound sustained in an engagement near Richmond. He was nineteen
                    or twenty years old, and had been in the service for about two years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"The last portion of the Signal Corps encamped near this place started for
                    Harpers Ferry on Monday last under command of Lieut. Kennedy. It numbered about
                    sixty men. Many of the number are from this county, sons of some of our most
                    respectable citizens and are by education and physical development well
                    qualified for the particular branch of the service to which they are attached.
                    This was the last body of troops encamped about this place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Not Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The reported death of John T. Harmony of the 21st Pennsylvania Cavalry has
                    been contradicted. A letter from him states that he escaped unhurt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Vocal and Instrumental Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"Vocal and instrumental concert, by the young Ladies of the Seminary at
                    Franklin Hall, on Thursday evening next at 8 o'clock. Proceeds for the Christian
                    Commission. Tickets 20 cts., to be had at the Bookstores and at the door."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elser</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"In a recent charge upon rebel pickets made by the advance guard of the
                    11th Penna. Cav., Geo. F. Cook had a horse shot dead under him, and John Elser
                    was taking [sic] prisoner. Both of these soldiers are from this place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Mr. David Hollar, residing near Orrstown, had one of his feet entirely cut
                    off by a Reaper on Monday last. Amputation was rendered necessary and
                    successfully performed above the ankle."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"The anniversary of the Mission School"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>"The anniversary of the Mission School (colored) will be held in the
                    Presbyterian Church, on Sabbath afternoon next, at 3 o'clock. Friends of the
                    cause are invited to attend."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peifer</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Henry, of Hamilton township, and Miss Lizzie Peifer, of
                    Chambersburg, were married on June 12, 1864, by the Rev. S. McHenry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Culbertson died in his sleep on June 21, 1864, in Amberson's Valley.
                    He was 81 years, 11 months, and 5 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steppler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steppler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steppler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Steppler, son of Andrew and Mary Steppler, died on June 25, 1864,
                    aged 2 years, 1 month and 11 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca Susan Coble, wife of George Coble, Jr., and second daughter of
                    Robert and Caroline Clugston, of Waynesboro, died on June 21, 1864, aged 26
                    years, 5 months, and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Christian Burkholder died near Fayetteville on June 22, 1864, aged 63
                    years, 6 months, and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crumlick</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Maria Crumlick died in Loudon on June 25, 1864, aged 79 years, 8
                    months, and 25 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregor</ln>
                        <fn>Magdalena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Magdalena Gregor in St. Thomas township on June 18, 1864, aged 100
                    years, 1 month, and 12 days. "She was the maternal ancestor of 9 children, 31
                    grand children, 87 great grand children, and 6 great great grand children,
                    making 133 of a posterity, and representing five generations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page includes "Latest News," much of it about the war, and new
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.06">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Lines of Travel; Pension
                and Bounty Agencies; Medical; Musical; Boots and Shoes; Dye-Colors; Drugs,
                Medicines, &amp;c; Dry &amp; Fancy Goods; Books and Stationery.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.07">
            <pageNote>Entirely advertisements, with the following headings: Clothing; Insurance;
                Justices of the Peace; Coal, Lumber, &amp;c; Liquors; Physicians; Agricultural;
                Trees, Plants, and Vines; Saddlery, Harness, &amp;c; Confectioners; Seeds,
                Medical.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.06.29.08">
            <pageNote>Includes a lengthy article about the wheat crop, which will have about half
                the normal yield in the Southern counties, due mainly to the severity of the past
                winter. There are also advertisements, with the following headings: Wants;
                Financial; Real Estate Sales; Hotels; Military Notices; Legal Notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
