<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.08.31">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-08-31">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>31</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.08.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints Governor Curtin's message to the Pennsylvania legislature. He
                    emphasizes the need for a garrison in Pennsylvania and Maryland because of their
                    proximity to the Confederate states. He believes that the federal government
                    should help provide the protection. Governor Curtin and Governor Bradford wrote
                    a letter to Lincoln requesting the inclusion of garrison men in the quota for
                    volunteers. The Secretary of War refused the request. Curtin recommends that the
                    legislature establish fifteen regiments, to be paid by loan, with the officers
                    chosen by seniority and/or merit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The York (Pa.) True Democrat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes an article from the York True Democrat newspaper. A number of
                    recruits who intended to credit themselves to the townships in which they
                    reside, now positively refuse to do so because those townships declared that the
                    soldiers had no right to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository asserts that "not a single Republican or Union man" in
                    Pennsylvania voted against the amendment providing suffrage to soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Regiment of Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A regiment of Ohio soldiers, whose term of enlistment had expired, paid
                    their respects to President Lincoln before starting for their homes. The men
                    being drawn up in front of the White House, the President addressed them as
                    follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints Abraham Lincoln's address to a Ohio regiment whose
                    term of enlistment expired. Lincoln thanked the soldiers and requested their
                    patience and tolerance in dealing with taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes real estate sales, advertisements, and a poem entitled "Just
                Before the Battle."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.08.31.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. Earley's Mission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The great aim of Earley is evidently to hover on the border of Maryland
                    and Pennsylvania as long as he can with safety; keep both States distracted and
                    alarmed; weary our people of war alike by atrocious robbery and applying the
                    torch of the barbarian; disorganize us with the hope of wholly or partially
                    defeating the coming conscription, and drive the timid and time-serving to
                    voting the Peace ticket at the next election."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The rebel Gen. Earley has now been on the line of the Potomac for sixty days,
                        and from present indications he means to hold the Shenandoah Valley and
                        threaten the Maryland and Pennsylvania border as long as it is in his power
                        to do so. He first reached the river about the 1st of July, and after
                        sending plundering bands under M'Causland, Johnston and Gilmore north as far
                        as Hagerstown, he moved to Frederick, and, after an unimportant engagement,
                        he marched thence upon Washington, but beyond stealing a few thousand horses
                        and cattle and losing perhaps a thousand men, nothing was accomplished. The
                        6th corps met him in the Washington defences, and drove him rapidly across
                        the Potomac and into the valley again. When Gen. Wright abandoned the
                        pursuit, leaving Crooks and Averill alone in Earley's rear, he turned upon
                        their small command and drove them across the Potomac again with some loss
                        of men, but none of material; and from his second line on the Potomac he
                        sent M'Causland to burn and rob Chambersburg. Again he was compelled to
                        retreat hastily up the valley before Sheridan's forces; but when he reached
                        Strasburg he was reinforced by Kershaw's division of infantry and Fitz Lee's
                        division of cavalry, in all about 15,000 men, and he at once assumed the
                        offensive again. That his augmented force did not exceed the force of
                        Sheridan we are fully persuaded; but Sheridan was in an awkward position to
                        offer battle and at the same time protect his line toward Washington. He
                        therefore wisely fell back to Charlestown and Harper's Ferry, where he could
                        give battle with his whole force and has since been ready for Gen. Early,
                        who has preferred roving around almost anywhere but in the immediate
                        vicinity of Sheridan's lines. It is manifest, whatever may be Earley's
                        immediate purpose, that he is not willing to offer battle to Sheridan in his
                        present position. He has thrown his large body of cavalry up the river,
                        amused them on Friday last by shelling Williamsport, and shows a disposition
                        for almost everything else than a square fight.</p>
                    <p>Thus far the two months' campaign of Gen. Earley is barren of substantial
                        military results. It has not affected the siege of Richmond--doubtless its
                        primary and main object. It has not discomfited any portion of the Union
                        army, and does not seem to be aimed at any such result. It has not, counting
                        all its plunder, kept its own men in supplies, and it cannot, as things look
                        now, contemplate an invasion in force of either Maryland or Pennsylvania.
                        What then is Gen. Earley's mission? It is not without purpose well
                        considered and wisely matured object, and since it is <emph rend="italic"
                            >not</emph> to give battle to the opposing army, what are we to
                        understand as the aim of Davis and Lee in thus detaching 30,000 of their
                        best troops to manouvre [sic] on the line of the Potomac, evidently
                        intending to avoid decisive military results?</p>
                    <p>There can be but one rational solution of Gen. Earley's campaign. It has a
                        two-fold purpose, is equally political and military in its aim, and hopes to
                        be compensated rather by the former than the latter. The great aim of Earley
                        is evidently to hover on the border of Maryland and Pennsylvania as long as
                        he can with safety; keep both States distracted and alarmed; weary our
                        people of war alike by atrocious robbery and applying the torch of the
                        barbarian; disorganize us with the hope of wholly or partially defeating the
                        coming conscription, and drive the timid and time-serving to voting the
                        Peace ticket at the next election. This we believe to be the mission of Gen.
                        Earley, and it remains to be seen how far it will succeed. He has evidently
                        been assured that a draft cannot be made in Pennsylvania without riot and
                        revolution, and he is on hand to distract the power of the government as
                        much as possible, and give heart and hope to those who would plunge the
                        North into anarchy; and if he can bear to Richmond the glad tidings that
                        Pennsylvania copperheads have completed his work of defeating the filling up
                        of the ranks of our brave armies, he will return to the capital of Treason
                        the most successful general they has ever started on a campaign.</p>
                    <p>We know how the torch, repeated spoliation and perpetual peril appeal to the
                        selfishness of men; but when refuge from all or either is to be purchased at
                        the price of universal anarchy and the crowning triumph of perjured
                        traitors, the man who yields his devotion to a common country in the hour of
                        personal danger, is faithless to order and government, and faithless to
                        himself, his home and his children. So far from quailing beneath the
                        systematic oppression of the foe, deliberately designed to make us traitors
                        to ourselves and to our country, let it make us more faithful, more earnest,
                        more determined than ever before to resist the power of brutal traitors, and
                        exterminate treason from our once free and prosperous land. While treason
                        has life and power on this continent, there can be no peace, no order, no
                        government; and men of all political persuasion should make common cause to
                        make it die the death of infamy, that it may leave no new champion of
                        treason to rise up and again deluge us with fraternal blood.</p>
                    <p>The remedy is simple, plain and within the power of all. <emph rend="italic"
                            >Our armies must be reinforced!</emph> If Sheridan had but 25,000 more
                        men Earley would be driven back to the capital of crime at once and the
                        border would be speedily and forever free from thieving and destructive
                        incursions. Had Grant 50,000 fresh men just now Richmond would be ours in
                        thirty days; and had Sherman a like number of reinforcements the Flag of the
                        Free would wave in triumph over Atlanta and Mobile before the frosts of
                        Autumn reach us. This and this only is the remedy. It is the only measure of
                        safety to the border, to our armies, to the Republic; and it is to defeat
                        this if possible, that the rebel chief now hovers around us. Let the
                        patriotic men of all parties appreciate the common danger to ourselves and
                        to the government, and stand shoulder to shoulder and heart to heart to
                        re-enforce our gallant armies speedily and amply, and tranquil[l]ity and
                        lasting Peace must be the rich fruits of our efforts. We must choose between
                        this and anarchy; between disorder and desolation on the one hand and a
                        speedy peace and a restored and prosperous Union on the other, and the
                        choice must be made quickly. Let it be made as humanity and patriotism
                        dictate, and the mission of Early will fail as expiring treason surrenders
                        the fairest continent of the world to the beneficence of a great people and
                        Free Government.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses General Early's mission near the Potomac. Because Early's forces
                    made very little progress other than burning down a town, the Repository argues
                    that his true purpose was to keep both Pennsylvania and Maryland "distracted and
                    alarmed" and thus frighten the people into voting for the peace ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the disruption to Union organization caused by fears of invasion and
                    then actual invasion. The Repository urges the Union party to begin organizing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Gen. Wm. H. Koontz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Franklin's district nominated General William H. Koontz was
                    nominated over Colonel Jordan of Bedford as the Union candidate for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Praises the nomination of Alexander King of Bedford as the Union candidate
                    for judge. The Repository predicts widespread support and election victory for
                    King.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors comment on the Harrisburg correspondent's just but severe
                    condemnation of the Pennsylvania legislature. Members appropriated $33 per
                    Chambersburg head, but $275 more than the law allows for themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository informs readers of the urgent need for slippers in all the
                    army hospitals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Senator Wilson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository quotes Senator Wilson's public denial that he "is mixed up
                    with any proposition for an armistice with the rebels."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reports that insurance policies do no cover property damage
                    by a common enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository notes that General Hunter recently dismissed a large number
                    of his officers, including Col. Higgins of the 22nd Pa. Cavalry, Colonel Wynkoop
                    of the 20th, and Colonel Pearce of the 12th. Pearce was dismissed for "'utter
                    worthlessness as an officer.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knight</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors bemoan the destruction of Chambersburg. The act of "vandalism"
                    proves false the South's boast of chivalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>About The Rebel Raid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Never were a more scienced set of highwaymen organized than the command of
                    McCausland. When Gen. Averill surprised them at Moorfield, many of them were
                    besotted with liquor and most of them demoralized by their robberies."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Careful inquiry into the details of the burning of Chambersburg, establishes
                        the fact that in nearly every house systematic robbing was practiced by the
                        rebels. Officers and soldiers seemed to rival each other in thieving. Not
                        only watches, jewelry, silver-ware, and trinkets of every kind were taken
                        from drawers of every place they hoped to find them; but silk dresses and
                        clothing of almost every kind were appropriated by the free-booters and
                        secreted in their pockets and haversacks, or tied to their saddles. Capt.
                        F.W. Smith, son of the present Governor of Virginia, stole a quantity of
                        silver-ware from the residence of Mr. M'Clure, and rode out of town with a
                        pair of silver goblets strapped to his own saddle. When at Hancock, he was
                        evidently ashamed of his theft, and endeavored to escape the odium of
                        robbing by shameless falsehood. A Hancock correspondent informs us that he
                        exhibited Mrs. M'Clure's silver-ware in that place to a lady, and stated
                        that they had been given him by Mrs. M'Clure for helping her out with her
                        clothing--a statement that is wholly false. He took nothing from that house
                        that he did not deliberately steal; but it is most natural that a thief
                        should falsify to hide his villainy. A correspondent writing from Fulton
                        county informs us that every farm house in the cove near the road was robbed
                        of everything the rebels could carry. Some of the farmers lost considerable
                        sums of money, and clothing of all kind were taken--particularly silks and
                        other valuable articles of apparel. Never were a more scienced set of
                        highwaymen organized than the command of McCausland. When Gen. Averill
                        surprised them at Moorfield, many of them were besotted with liquor and most
                        of them demoralized by their robberies. Whnn [sic] called upon to fight,
                        they were so encumbered with their stolen goods and so prostituted by the
                        unbridled license they had enjoyed for a week before, that they made no
                        defence. We learn from an officer who was present that they behaved more
                        like a set of thieves fearing an officer of the law than like soldiers.
                        Their camp which they abandoned when Averill attacked them, was strewn with
                        silks, shawls and countless articles of clothing and other booty, and they
                        made much more effort to get away with their plunder than to fight like
                        trained soldiers. They lost all their artillery, some 400 prisoners, and a
                        number killed and wounded while Averill's loss did not reach twenty in all.
                        When Averill's men swooped down on them in their camp, although the evidence
                        of their robberies was visible on the person of almost every rebel, they
                        cried out--"<emph rend="italic">We wer'nt in Chambersburg!</emph>"--<emph
                            rend="italic">"We didn't burn your houses!</emph> The thieves evidently
                        expected that summary justice would be dispensed by [illegible] prompt
                        butchery; but they were amazed to find that Gen. Averill treated them as
                        prisoners of war.</p>
                    <p>There is a common error prevalent even among our own citizens as to the
                        number of rebels actually in Chambersburg when is [sic] was burned. Most of
                        our people fix the number at from 350 to 600; but we are assured that Mr.
                        Christian Stouffer, who lives on West Market street, on which the main body
                        of M'Causland's command entered, counted 831 who entered Chambersburg by
                        that street, and there were not less than 250 who entered by different other
                        streets. Mr. Stouffer is a perfectly reliable gentleman, and we are fully
                        convinced that there were not less than 1,000 rebels in the town when it was
                        robbed and burned. It must be remembered that the rebel command was
                        scattered over more than half the town--that they entered and fired over 200
                        houses almost simultaneously, and each squad contained from two to five men.
                        While few citizens saw as many as fifty rebels together, they were at work
                        in some twelve or fifteen squares at one time, and their number was not less
                        than 1,000, or almost one-third of the command brought to Chambersburg.</p>
                    <p>Gens. M'Causland and Bradley Johnston took breakfast at Mr. Hencry
                        Greenawalt's, on the Western turnpike, on the morning of the 30th.
                        M'Causland brought his brandy to the table, and drank freely of it while
                        eating. When they rose from the table and were passing out of the house,
                        Johnston noticed a delicate child of Mrs. Greenawalt's, and he remarked that
                        it looked quite pale. M'Causland answered--"Madam, in a few hours, when I
                        get through with Chambersburg the women and children of the town will look
                        paler than your child," and with a fiendish chuckle of satisfaction he
                        proceeded to execute his purpose. When in Chambersburg the rebel soldiers
                        were openly encouraged to get drunk and steal. Gen. Johnston sat on the
                        verandah of the Franklin House, and his soldiers would repeatedly come to
                        him and call his attention to the valuable goods they had stolen. Some would
                        exhibit fancy combs, others jewelry, and others articles of apparel of which
                        they had just robbed citizens, and the General would compliment them or
                        smile approvingly at their dexterity as common thieves. One officer called
                        all the straggling men about Johnston to come up street and get plenty of
                        liquor, as a cellar had been opened in which there was abundance, and they
                        all left to whet their brutal passions with whiskey. In every hotel and
                        eating house they first broke into the bar or cellar to get liquor, and no
                        general officer attempted to restrain them.</p>
                    <p>In our report of the movement made on the morning of the 30th ult. with the
                        artillery here, by which the rebels were retarded from entering the town
                        until day-light, we omitted to state that Capt. M'Gowan, Provost Marshal of
                        this place, was in the immediate command of the few troops here, and that
                        Lieut. Underhill had immediate charge of the battery. They held their ground
                        manfully on the Fair Ground until they were ordered by Gen. Couch to fall
                        back, which was done just in time to save their gun. These officers behaved
                        most gallantly and saved Chambersburg from the horror of being fired in
                        darkness as was evidently the intention of Gen. M'Causland. Several of his
                        officers, who protested against and refused to participate in the burning of
                        the town denounced him to our citizens as an evidence of it his deliberate
                        purpose to fire the town at night which must have resulted in the loss of
                        many lives of women and children.</p>
                    <p>The number of rebels who were in and about Chambersburg has been variously
                        estimated and persistently belittled by unfriendly journals abroad. Gen.
                        Averill who encountered them several times reported their number at 3,000;
                        and Col. Dixon, of St. Thomas, an old officer of the Pennsylvania Reserves,
                        counted M'Causland's forces accurately as it retreated through that place,
                        and it numbered 2,890 men, independent of stragglers scattered through the
                        country. Of this number there were nearly if not quite 1,000 in Chambersburg
                        participating in the burning and robberies, and 2,000 were in line of battle
                        on the hill west of the town, with two batteries completely covering the
                        force detailed to apply the torch.</p>
                    <p>Capt. Smith, who burned "Norland" was evidently anxious to procure the
                        private papers of Mr. M'Clure. He thoroughly ransacked Mrs. M'Clure's
                        Secretary, but found nothing there suited to his taste. The important
                        private correspondence of Mr. M'Clure was in the house, but as it was in a
                        place where a thief would not be likely to search for whiskey, money or
                        jewelry, it escaped vandal hands to perish in the flames. All the political
                        letters of Mr. M'Clure relating to the campaign of 1860, the formation of
                        the Lincoln Cabinet in 1861, and others of more recent date were in his
                        library, but were not found as Smith's proceedings in the library were
                        carefully watched until all left the house. Had Capt. Smith found the
                        correspondence he could have published nothing to make the authors blush,
                        unless Hon. A. H. H. Stuart, of Va., and several others now devoted to
                        treason, would have been shamed by being reminded that as late as 1861 they
                        denounced Jeff Davis and other Southern traitors with an earnestness that
                        would now do credit to a Northern Abolitionist. Had the letters of Mr.
                        Greeley and Mr. Stevens been exhumed by rebel explorations, this consolation
                        would remain, that nobody could read them, not even the authors themselves
                        after they had been written one or more years. Unfortunately for Mr. Lincoln
                        he writes a legible hand, and any rebel who can read "writin'-readin'," as
                        Col. Montgomery would say, might readily decypher his chirography; but as
                        the rebels didn't get them, its no odds, as Toots would say, what was in
                        them. As Capt. Smith, by his admirable thieving qualities, is certainly on
                        the fair way to political promotion in rebeldom, he may regret that he
                        missed this correspondence, as it would have shown him how political
                        campaigns are managed in Pennsylvania. Missing his mark, however, he must
                        learn elsewhere.</p>
                    <p>Two Union soldiers named George Styer, of Howard county, Md., and Adam
                        Alexander, of York county, Pa., members of the independent Patapsco Guards
                        were the last troops in Chambersburg. They were across the Falling Spring on
                        King street when the rebel pickets were advancing from the west on the same
                        street, and fell back leisurely, loading and firing their pieces until they
                        were driven down Main street, from thence down the alley to the depot
                        buildings, and then out to Kennedy's woods, when they retreated to
                        Shippensburg. They halted at the corner of King and Main and loaded their
                        guns when the rebels were not over a square from them. They have been in the
                        service nearly three years, and when told by some citizens, while loading
                        that the rebels were close to them, they answered that they had seen rebels
                        before, and marched off cool[l]y to get a good position for a shot at the
                        "Johnies." These men deserve well for their gallantry.</p>
                    <p>We have entirely reliable information of a consultation had by Gen. Earley
                        and a number of his officers on the Potomac, after the destruction of
                        Chambersburg, in which the policy of Earley's campaign was freely discussed;
                        and it was admitted by all that if Earley's demonstrations on the border
                        failed to raise the siege of Richmond the rebel capital must eventually
                        fall. How or from whom we have this information, it is not proper to say;
                        but the consultation and discussion were heard by the person from whom we
                        have the statement. Gen. Earley and his chief officers were quite
                        disappointed at the fruits of their campaign--it having failed in its great
                        purpose to relieve Richmond.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the rebels robbed almost every house in Chambersburg. Officers
                    and soldiers seemed to compete with each other in thieving. The Repository
                    denies the claim of Smith, the man who burned A. K. McClure's home, that Mrs.
                    McClure gave him the silverware for helping her save her clothing. General
                    Averill surprised robber rebels at Moorfield, but they were too drunk and
                    preoccupied with their spoils to fight. The rebels supposedly shouted to Averill
                    "'We weren't in Chambersburg! We didn't burn your houses!'" The Repository
                    estimates about 1,000 rebel soldiers sacked and burned Chambersburg. The
                    artillery commanded by Capt. McGowan, Provost Marshall of Chambersburg, and
                    Lieut. Underhill prevent the rebels from entering the town before daybreak.
                    George Tyer and Adam Alexander, the last Union soldiers in Chambersburg, kept
                    firing at the rebels as they left.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Suspended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository mentions the suspension of the Mercersburg Journal because
                    of the high price of paper and the rebel invasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Rebuilding</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides suggestions on rebuilding Chambersburg. The editors urge the
                    planting of shade trees and the construction of buildings with good taste. The
                    buildings need not be rebuilt in the exact way. The rebuilding process may
                    create new popular town areas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Distressing Occurrence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the accidental death of William Gelwix, of Capt. Stroud's company.
                    Gelwix accidentally caused his gun to fire while jumping a fence near
                    Chambersburg and was fatally shot in the abdomen. He was the son of D. Gelwix of
                    Strasburg, was about thirty years old, and had been part of the first mustering
                    of Capt. Hullinger's 21st Cavalry in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Streets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reports that the town council decided to widen Main Street
                    by eight feet on each side. The editors believe that the widening of the
                    pavements alongside the streets would "add largely to the comfort and value of
                    the properties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Bible Donation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Torrence</ln>
                        <fn>I. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a letter from Rev. I. H. Torrence to Samuel Seibert, B. F. Nead, W.
                    G. Reed, George Flack, and D. K. Wunderlich. Torrence writes that families who
                    lost Bibles should receive a new one from Rev. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gone To Montana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the move of Jeremiah Cook to Montana. Cook maintained a reputation
                    as "a sound lawyer, and excellent business man and withal one of the cleverest
                    of good fellows."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Recruits</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Guilford Township offers a $300 local bounty in addition to
                    the government bounty, for a total of $592.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>On A Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the visit of Captain David S. Gordon, of the 2nd United States
                    Cavalry, and Captain L. B. Kurtz, of Company G of the 17th Pennsylvania Cavalry,
                    to their homes in Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Democratic Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. M. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reports the Democratic nominations. At their convention in
                    Chambersburg, they nominated General A. H. Coffroth for Congress, F. M. Kimmell
                    for judge, and J. M. McDowell Sharpe for assembly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Discharged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morehead</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merklein</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the honorable discharge of Jacob Butler, William Deatrich, David
                    Morehead, and Thomas Merklein, all of Chambersburg. They return home after
                    serving three years in the 11th Pennsylvania Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Files Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stoner and McClure, the proprietors of the Repository, request readers to
                    submit copies of any issues of the paper, "however old," but especially the
                    first issue of July 8, 1863. The Repository promises to pay liberally.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the official vote of the special election of August 2 for the
                    amendments to the state constitution. Franklin County voted as follows: 1st-For
                    2,513, Against 721; 2nd-For 2,529, Against 722; 3rd-For 2,511, Against 732. The
                    first amendment provided suffrage to soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes war news. While destroying the Weldon Railroad south of Reams'
                    Station, General Hancock's forces successfully repulsed numerous attacks.
                    General Early's forces moved on to Williamsport, retreated to Charlestown, and
                    now moves toward Richmond to aid Lee in recovering the Weldon Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyle</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of David Coyle, of Perry County, at Newville on August
                    22, in his 87th year. He was the father of A. L. Coyle of Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.08.31.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides news of the state legislature in Harrisburg. The correspondent
                    reports on the acts of the extra session, the new military bill, the liberal
                    appropriations to members of the legislature, the "mean" appropriation to the
                    residents of Chambersburg, Governor Curtin's special message, the speaker of the
                    Senate, bounty brokers, and political movements. The militia bill passed, but
                    had no power of enforcement in case "copperhead commissioners should conclude to
                    disregard its provisions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Burning Of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin>Pittsburgh Evening Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary>"The following graphic letter, which we copy from the Pittsburg Evening
                    Chronicle, is from the pen of Rev. S. J. Niccolls, Presbyterian pastor of this
                    place. He has ever actively participated in every measure looking to [order?]
                    defence and was a witness to the sacking and burning of Chambersburg, and speaks
                    advisedly as to the facts he records. The Chronicle, which had previously
                    reflected severely upon the citizens and also upon Gen. Couch for not defending
                    the town, prefaces Mr. Niccoll's letter with a tender of regrets to Gen. Couch
                    'for the injurious strictures concerning his management which were made in the
                    Chronicle under wrong impressions.' We give the letter entire:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S. J. Niccolls"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a letter written by Rev. S. J. Niccolls, of Chambersburg,
                    originally printed in the Pittsburgh Evening Chronicle. Niccolls disputes the
                    Chronicle's accusations that General Couch and the citizens of Chambersburg
                    failed to defend themselves. Niccolls provides a long and detailed description
                    of the rebel invasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeaths</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Anna Yeaths on August 22, in Guilford Township, at 3
                    years, 5 months, and 21 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeaths</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Emma Yeaths on August 19, in Guilford Township, at 3
                    months and 7 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Anna Lowry on August 10, in Guilford Township, at 6
                    months and 25 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of John Grove, Sr., of Guilford Township, on August 13,
                    at 78 years, 5 months, and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Renfrew</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Robert Renfrew near Fayetteville on August 9, at the
                    age of 81 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Henry Miller in Chambersburg on August 8, at 10 years,
                    2 months, and 8 days. Henry Miller was the son of John and Mary Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oyler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Mary Oyler, of Guilford Township, on July 20.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Gracy Allison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>J. Allison</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Gracy Allison Eyster on August 1. Gracy was the infant
                    daughter of J. Allison Eyster and died in Chambersburg at the home of William C.
                    Eyster.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Lizze Jane McDowell on August 21, in Mercersburg, at
                    the age of 21 years. Lizzie was the daughter of John M. McDowell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cromer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Cromer, of Jackson Hall, married Charlotte Detrich, of
                    St. Thomas, on August 18. Rev. Henry performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dine</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aikens</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that David Dine, of Fayetteville, married Margaret Aikens, of
                    Guilford Township, on August 18. Rev. Henry officiated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that William S. Spangler married Hannah J. Peters, both of Guilford
                    Township on August 11. Rev. Barnhart performed the services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litrell</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Margaret Uglow, of Chambersburg, married Archibald Litrell, of
                    Frederick County, Virginia, on August 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Niccolls</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pauli</ln>
                        <fn>Anne E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Charles H. Taylor married Anne E. Pauli, both of Chambersburg,
                    on August 5. Rev. Niccolls performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dizard</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerrin</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Samuel Dizard, of Fayetteville, married Rebecca McFerrin, of
                    New Franklin, on August 23. Rev. Howe performed the services.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Chicago Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the latest news on the Chicago Convention, including Governor
                    Bigler as temporary president, Governor Seymour as president, the probable
                    nomination of General McClellan, and the participation of Vallandigham as the
                    Ohio delegate. The Repository charges the convention with "treason."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Head Quarters Provost Marshal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain, Provost Marshall</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates the announcement of Provost Marshall Eyster that the Board of
                    Enrollment of the Sixteenth District will hold daily sessions at Chambersburg,
                    starting September 12. Eyster requests appearance of people who desire exemption
                    because of age, physical disability, non-residence, two year service. Urges
                    residents to "see that delinquent drafted men are arrested and brought before
                    the Board of Enrollment."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, legal notices, and market
            reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.08.31.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and train schedules.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
