<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.11.02">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-11-02">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Hon. Geo. H. Pendleton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository provides a short biography of Pendleton, the Democratic
                    candidate for vice president, and records his anti-war votes in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and a poem on Gen. Sheridan.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Army Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reports election irregularities with the army vote. Some
                    Democratic judges invalidated a number of soldiers' votes because poll books
                    contained candidates from several counties, a violation of the act passed by the
                    legislature. The editors remind that the act also states that "no mere
                    informality in the manner of carrying on or executing any of the provisions of
                    this act, shall invalidate any election held under the same or authorize the
                    return thereof, to be rejected or set aside."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Southern Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The investment, on their part, is therefore most judicious, and at once
                    disenthrals the Southern counties, develops their slumbering wealth,enhances the
                    value of every acre of land on the border, and must greatly cheapen coal,
                    lumber, and every article wanted from the West."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Commissioners named in the ball incorporating the Connellsville and
                        Southern Pennsylvania Railroad Company, met at Bedford on the 14th ult., to
                        open conscription books and commence the work of organization. Hon. Samuel
                        L. Russell presided at the meeting, and five millions two hundred thousand
                        dollars were subscribed to the capital stock, and five dollars paid in on
                        every subscription. Such an immense subscription made <emph rend="italic"
                            >bona fide</emph>, as it was, at once secures the early construction of
                        this most important artery of trade, and must add fabulous wealth to the
                        Southern tier of counties in this State.</p>
                    <p>The stockholders adjourned to meet in Philadelphia, on the 10th of November,
                        to effect a permanent organization of the company by the election of
                        President and Directors. Thus far we have heard only the name of Col. John
                        A. Wright suggested for the Presidency, and we shall be glad to learn that
                        he has been chosen and accepted the responsible trust. He is one of the most
                        thorough and experienced Railroad men of the country, and with the sternest
                        integrity combines the most comprehensive and practical business qualities.
                        We can think of no man who could give a brighter promise of early success to
                        this vital enterprise.</p>
                    <p>The delay in the approval of the bill by Gov. Curtin, arising from the grave
                        constitutional question earnestly urged by the Baltimore interests in
                        opposition to the resumption by the State of the franchises of the
                        Pittsburgh and Connellsville Company, necessarily postpones active
                        operations on the new road this season; but we are assured that the
                        promptest measures will be taken to put it in readiness for rapid progress
                        next season. We presume that the heavy subscriptions to the capital stock
                        made at Bedford came mainly from those interested in the great internal
                        thoroughfares of the country--the Pennsylvania Central and the Pittsburgh,
                        Fort Wayne and Chicago Railroad, as the construction of the great Southern
                        line is of the utmost importance to them. The Pennsylvania Central is now
                        unequal to its immense and steadily growing trade, and by leading the
                        Southern Pennsylvania to the commercial city of our State by intersecting
                        the Cumberland Valley at or near Chambersburg, its through trade can be well
                        accommodated, and the local trade of the State immensely increased by
                        developing the exhaustless mines and forests of the counties between this
                        and Connellsville. The investment, on their part, is therefore most
                        judicious, and at once disenthrals the Southern counties, develops their
                        slumbering wealth, enhances the value of every acre of land on the border,
                        and must greatly cheapen coal, lumber, and every article wanted from the
                        West. In addition it will make Philadelphia the receptacle of all the wealth
                        of Southern Pennsylvania, and add greatly to the general prosperity of the
                        Commonwealth. This enterprise cannot be too earnestly commended to the
                        people of our county, and we hope to see them co-operate generously in
                        pushing it forward to early completion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the efforts to establish the Connellsville and Southern
                    Pennsylvania Railroad near or through Chambersburg. The Repository notes the
                    economic benefits a railroad would bring the community.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Political Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Such an infringement upon the constitutional rights of the South excites
                    the liveliest indignation of the Spirit, and it makes its last grasp for
                    M'Clellan by an appeal for despairing rebels. It writes 'with sorrow!' Surely it
                    may well mourn, for its kindred journals of rebeldom mourn deeply over the
                    desolation of the Valley, and the defeat of Early. . . they mourn too with the
                    Spirit that Early's defeat insures the enforcement of the draft and the defeat
                    of the Democracy."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository condemns the Valley Spirit's criticism of Gen. Sheridan's
                    scorched earth tactics in the Shenandoah Valley as disloyal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes war news including the Union capture of 24 cannons from General
                    Early; the rebel capture of the steamer Ike Davis near the mouth of the Rio
                    Grande; and the resolution of the governors of Virginia, North Carolina, South
                    Carolina, Georgia, Alabama, and Mississippi "which declare that it is necessary
                    that every male person of suitable age, without regard to color, shall at once
                    be put in the southern armies."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Franklin County Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roath</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>D. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>M. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository prints the combined home vote and official army vote for the
                    Franklin County elections: Congress--Koontz (Union) 3508, Coffroth (Democrat)
                    3457; Judge--King (Union) 3431, Kimmell (Democrat) 3477; Assembly--McClure
                    (Union) 3632, Roath (Union) 3376, Sharpe (Democrat) 3580, Mitchell (Democrat)
                    3298; Commissioner--Davison (Union) 3442, Armstrong (Democrat) 3478;
                    Director--Criswell (Union) 3475, D. J. Skinner (Democrat) 3446; Auditor--M. R.
                    Skinner (Union) 3441, Martin (Democrat) 3466; Coroner--Wertz (Union) 3451,
                    Miller (Democrat) 3459.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alex. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository prints the "correct list" of the members of both branches of
                    the new Pennsylvania legislature, which includes McClure and Sharpe as the
                    representatives for the district of Perry and Franklin. The election brought 18
                    Union and 13 Democrat members the state Senate and 64 Union and 36 Democrat
                    members to the state House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Enormous Frauds In The New York Soldiers' Vote!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the forgery of ballots in the New York elections. The article
                    includes the confession of one of the participants.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports political news including Lincoln's proclamation admitting Nevada
                    into the Union. The article describes a rebel attempt to affect the election. A
                    paroled soldier named Franklin Schwenk, of Company H, 13th Pennsylvania Cavalry,
                    declares that the rebels offered to set him free if he would vote for McClellan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes reminders to readers to support the Union and vote for
                Lincoln.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.02.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Grand Mass Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes a meeting on October 28, at which Hannibal Hamlin, the Vice
                    President, urged support for the Union and the Union presidential and vice
                    presidential candidates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Hero Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ley</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>L. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hebble</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Michael Ley, of Co. G, (under Capt. Kurtz) 17th Pa.
                    Cavalry. He was shot on October 1 while bearing dispatches from Winchester to
                    Gen. Sheridan's headquarters. Capt. Hebble's company helped bury him with
                    military honors in Mercersburg in the Presbyterian Cemetery. He leaves a wife
                    and four children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sad and Fatal Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sweitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of Jacob Sweitz on October 26. He was killed by drunk
                    soldiers who had earlier attempted to gain admission to his house.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Patriotic and Prolific</head>
                <origin>The Carlisle Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reprints a Carlisle Herald article about the Reese family.
                    Hiram Reese recently enlisted his sons, George and Jeremiah. A total of twelve
                    Reese sons have enlisted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Masonic Dedication</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the dedication of the new hall for the Cumberland Valley Lodge,
                    No 315, A. Y. M. in Shippensburg on the 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hock</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Charles Hock died suddenly at his home, Snow Hill, near
                    Quincy, on October 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Advance of Hancock's &amp; Warren's Corps</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the advance of Hancock's and Warren's Corps. The article details
                    the repulse of a rebel attack on Hancock, the capture of 900 prisoners, a
                    gallant affair at Beverly, the rebel attack of a garrison, the defeat of the
                    rebels losing half their forces, the defeat of General Price's army, the capture
                    of 1,500 prisoners and 12 pieces of artillery, and the capture of General
                    Marmaduke and Cabell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>R. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the court martial of Capt. Ward, Co. D, 11th Pa. Cav., at Fortress
                    Monroe, for forging certificates crediting recruits to certain townships and for
                    selling horses belonging to the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foust</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 11, at the home of the bride's father, by Rev. Breidenbaugh, J.
                    Lesher , married M. Foust, both of Antrim Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michael</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carlisle</ln>
                        <fn>Emma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 25, by Rev. Breidenbaugh, at the home of Dr. Michael,
                    Greencastle, W. Wilhelm, of Baltimore, married E. Carlisle, of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breidenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daly</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 25, by Rev. Briedenbaugh at the Lutheran Parsonage, Greencastle,
                    T. Daly married S. Frantz, both of Montgomery Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catron</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 12, in Hannibal Mo., R. Catron, formerly of Waynesboro, aged
                    57 years, 11 months, and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 25, in Quincy Township, Mrs. Middour, wife of J. Middour, died
                    at "an advanced age."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Charlotte</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 21, near Brown's Mill, Mrs. Hassler, wife of A. Hassler, Esq.,
                    aged 36 years and 2 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowry</ln>
                        <fn>Curtis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On 28, in Guilford Township, C. Lowry, died at 54 years, 11 months, and 14
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Ruth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 20, R. Patterson, widow of J. Patterson, of Letterkenny
                    Township, died in about the 80th year of her life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.11.02.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes a poem entitled "The Truant Wife," advertisements, and train
                schedules.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
