<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.10.12">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-12">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository lists the candidates for the Pennsylvania legislature
                    (including Koontz and Coffroth for the 16th district) and predicts that, based
                    on Governor Curtin's victory last year, the Union nominees will win this year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Lincoln And Johnson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors provide biographies of Lincoln and Johnson to urge readers to
                    support the Union ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Army Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors list several reasons for the potentially small number of
                    military votes including the movement of the troops, underage soldiers, and
                    foreign soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository denies the claim made by the Valley Spirit that "President
                    Lincoln offered Gen. McClellan the 'highest command in the army,' the 'best
                    civil position within his gift,' and proposed to 'support McClellan for the
                    Presidency in 1868,' if McClellan would withdraw now."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If the efforts of Mr. M'Clure were prejudicial to the full, it is strange
                    indeed that it was not discovered last winter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository explains the Valley Spirit's change in attitude towards
                    McClure's efforts to get compensation for damages caused by the rebel invasion.
                    The Spirit originally praised him, but now claims his presence in Harrisburg
                    actually caused the vote to go against compensation. The Repository argues that
                    the Spirit attempts to discredit McClure with voters by making false
                    accusations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Charleston Mercury</origin>
                <commentary>"The rebel papers are just beginning to appreciate the fact that
                    vandalism such as the plundering and burning of Chambersburg is a losing game.
                    The Charleston Mercury of a late slate forget that the war is a 'failure,' and
                    say:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors reprint an article from the Charleston Mercury arguing that the
                    burning of Chambersburg encouraged enlistment into the Union forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mentions a trial in Indianapolis that involves a member of the Sons of
                    Liberty, which is supposedly "manipulated" by Vallandigham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Capt. D. B. M'Kibbin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>M'Kibbin</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the parole of McKibbin, formerly Colonel of the 158th
                    Pennsylvania Infantry. McKibbin was captured two months ago and imprisoned at
                    Charleston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>One item (among others) that claims if McClellan is elected the Union would
                    take on the Confederacy's debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes war news including the successful raid on Staunton, Virginia;
                    the destruction of railroad; the capture of 2,400 cattle; and rebel soldiers
                    stripping dead soldiers and collecting debris on the battlefield of the
                    Wilderness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the honorable exemption of Col. L. B. Pierce, of the 12th
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Financial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the next public loan of the United States "is to be on 5-20
                    years 6 per cent. bonds."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Is The War A Failure?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is not proper for me to speak of the number of men in the field, but
                    this I will say, that two-thirds of our men are absent, some sick, some wounded,
                    but most of them absent without leave."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors reprint a speech by Jefferson Davis given at Macon, Georgia.
                    They italicized statements that emphasize the rebel forces' recent failures.
                    Davis claims that if half of the rebel deserters returned to their troops, then
                    the Confederacy would win the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Election!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository predicts election results including Union victories for both
                    branches of the Pennsylvania legislature, General Koontz, and Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Election in Sherman's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that it is "not likely that anything like a full vote has been
                    polled [in the Union forces at Atlanta], as most of the tax receipts were with
                    the Commissioners."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Grant And Sheridan Victorious!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the victories by Grant and Sherman, Birney, and Sheridan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The Repository lists partial returns for the recent election.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Disgraceful Conduct</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Sharpe's harness was cut while he was speaking in the Red School House
                    and stones were thrown at him when he was returning home. Subsequently C. Eyster
                    and W.S. Everett, Esqs., spoke at the same place and their carriage was cut;
                    their horse turned loose; a shawl and the cushions stolen, and stones thrown
                    into the window while they were speaking."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is always disgraceful to disturb or in any way interrupt a political
                        meeting. Speakers may be fools and utter disgraceful sentiments, but there
                        is no law that compels anybody to listen to them; and it is always best to
                        let them alone. There have been in several instances, disgraceful
                        disturbances at political meetings in this county. At the Union meeting at
                        Dry Run Mr. Stewart twice narrowly escaped being hit with stones while he
                        was speaking, and there were slight disturbances at the Democratic meetings
                        at Waynesboro and Greencastle. Mr. Sharpe's harness was cut while he was
                        speaking in the Red School House and stones were thrown at him when he was
                        returning home. Subsequently C. Eyster and W.S. Everett, Esqs., spoke at the
                        same place and their carriage was cut; their horse turned loose; a shawl and
                        the cushions stolen, and stones thrown into the window while they were
                        speaking. Such conduct is disgraceful in the extreme, and all good citizens
                        should resolve to have it arrested regardless of consequences. It is a
                        disgrace to any community to have a meeting interrupted, and all should aid
                        to expose and bring to punishment those who thus violate all decency. If
                        this disorder is not stopped, there is but one remedy for it, and that is to
                        arrest and punish the offenders, and we trust that no man, of any party,
                        will be found ready to excuse or shield the men or boys who are thus
                        disgracing themselves and their communities.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports several "disgraceful disturbances" during campaigning by Stewart,
                    Sharpe, Eyster, and Everett in the district. Opponents threw stones and damaged
                    their carriages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Orphans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that applications for the education and maintenance of soldiers'
                    orphans in Franklin County can be given to Hon. Black. The state will provide
                    for room, boarding, and books. The families must pay for the orphans' transport
                    and provide clothing. The schools will be ready this month.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presbytery Of Carlisle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wightman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaldson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillaudett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Rev. Wightman of Greencastle opened the Presbytery of
                    Carlisle, meeting in Shippensburg on October 4. Donaldson was ordained and
                    arrangements were made for Gillaudett's installation in the church of Dickinson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death Of A Soldier</head>
                <origin>The Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hennicle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hennicle</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Henry Hennicle, son of Henry Hennicle, of the
                    Waynesboro vicinity. Young Hennicle died while in a hospital at Richmond because
                    of starvation. He enlisted under Capt. Walker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lieut. Thomas Myers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the confinement of Chambersburg resident Thomas Myers, of Co. K,
                    107th Pa. Regiment, in Charleston, South Carolina. The rebels captured Myers at
                    Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A List Of Grand And Traverse Jurors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenridge</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bovey</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Divilbiss</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritz</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gift</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hostetter</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brake</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brant</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>Jos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diehl</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gribble</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lenher</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowery</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Christian H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ludwig</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minters</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAleer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the grand jurors: J. Walter, Waynesboro; J. Allen, Montgomery; S.
                    Brackenridge, Green; W. Blair, Southampton; S. Bitner, Lurgan, T. Bovey,
                    Guilford; J. Bear, Warren; I. Craig, Chambersburg; J. Cook, Montgomery; W.
                    Divilbiss, Peters; S. Etter, Green; L. Fritz, Warren; A. Gift, Peters; S.
                    Greenawalt, Chambersburg; R. Horner, Peters; U. Henderson, Guilford; J.
                    Hostetter, Greencastle; S. Laughlin, Lurgan; J. McAllen, Metal; J. Monn, Green;
                    J. Thomas, Warren; N. Wilson, Mercersburg; M. Wingert, Green; J. Wallace, Green.
                    Traverse Jurors: P. Ackerman, Chambersburg; J. Byers, Hamilton; J. Brake,
                    Letterkenny; D. Brant, Fannett; J. Bosserman, Montgomery; H. Byers, Antrim; J.
                    Byers, St. Thomas; J. Carbaugh, Washington; S. Cook, Warren; J. Caufman,
                    Hamilton; L. Deatrich, Antrim; A. Davison, Antrim; C. Diehl, Guilford; L.
                    Deatrich, Antrim; W. Fleagle, Quincy; L. Gribble, Metal; S. Gsell, Montgomery;
                    W. Gillan, Jr., Letterkenny; D. Gelwicks, Letterkenny; A. Kreitzer, Antrim; G.
                    Lenher, Chambersburg; G. Lowery, Quincy; C. Lesher, Antrim; G. Ludwig,
                    Chambersburg; D. Lehman, Green; G. Mitchell, Antrim; A. Metz, Chambersburg; M.
                    Minters, Quincy; J. Mohler, Southampton; A. Miller, Antrim; J. McCune,
                    Mercersburg; J. McAleer, Hamilton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.12.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
