<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.09.07">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-09-07">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.09.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Important Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The legislature has passed a voluminous act providing in detail for taking
                    the soldiers' vote. It provides that all soldiers, who are legal votes at home,
                    shall vote, whether in the State or in the field, and the right of suffrage
                    shall not be effected by the soldier having been credited to any locality, other
                    than his actual residence."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The adoption of the amendment to the constitution conferring the right of
                        s[u]ffrage upon our soldiers in the field, necessitated the enactment of a
                        bill with proper provisions to carry out this important and just feature of
                        our organic law. The legislature has passed a voluminous act providing in
                        detail for taking the soldiers' vote. It provides that all soldiers, who are
                        legal votes at home, shall vote, whether in the State or in the field, and
                        the right of suffrage shall not be effected by the soldier having been
                        credited to any locality, other than his actual residence. The polls shall
                        be opened in the day of election in each company composed wholly, or partly
                        of Pennsylvania soldiers, at the quarters of the company officer, and all
                        members of the company who are within one mile of the officer's quarters,
                        and not prevented by orders or the proximity of the enemy from attending,
                        shall vote at such poll, and at no other place. Soldiers detached, in
                        hospitals or otherwise unavoidably prevented from attending the election at
                        the company poll, shall vote at any other poll most convenient; and where
                        ten or more soldiers are detached they may open a poll of their own at such
                        place as they may select, and certify their returns. The polls shall be
                        opened not earlier than 7 A.M., and remain open at least three hours, and
                        may be kept open until 7 P.M., if the judges find it necessary to poll the
                        full vote. Before opening the poll, the electors present at each place of
                        voting shall elect <emph rend="italic">viva voce</emph> three persons
                        present at the time as judges, and the judges shall select two clerks, who
                        shall constitute the election board, and shall be duly sworn to a faithful
                        discharge of their duties. All elections shall be by ballot, and when doubt
                        exists as to the right of a soldier to vote, the officers shall examine the
                        applicants under oath and determine the right. Separate poll books shall be
                        kept and returned for each county, and they shall name the company regiment
                        and place at which the election is held. Provisions in detail are given for
                        counting and preserving the ballots for each county, so that access can be
                        had to them in case of alleged fraud. Tally-lists shall also be kept for
                        each county.</p>
                    <p>After the votes are counted and the returns made out in conformity with law,
                        a poll-list, tally list and return of each city or county together with the
                        tickets, shall be sealed up and transmitted through the nearest post office
                        or express as soon as possible, to the Prothonotary of the proper county;
                        and the other poll-book, tally-list, returns &amp;c., shall be delivered
                        to the State Commissioner, if he shall call for them within ten days--if
                        not, they shall also be mailed or expressed to the Secretary of the
                        Commonwealth. The return judges of the several counties are required to meet
                        on the second Tuesday of November, to add the vote of the soldiers to the
                        proper returns of the counties, and certify the result in the usual manner
                        as ascertained by the united home and army vote. The Secretary of
                        Commonwealth is required to have an abundant copies of the law, together
                        with necessary portions of the general election laws of the State and all
                        the needed forms to be supplied to the army and the others holding the
                        elections in the field. The Governor is authorized to appoint competent
                        Commissioners not exceeding one for each Pennsylvania regiment, who shall be
                        sworn to discharge their duties faithfully and whose duty shall be to
                        deliver the necessary laws and blanks, and to receive the proper returns.
                        Such Commissioners shall be deemed in the military service, and may vote at
                        any one of the polls they attend. No election of soldiers shall be
                        invalidated by the failure of commissioners or other officers to supply the
                        forms or discharge their duties. When any number of soldiers less than ten
                        shall be members of companies of other States, or for any other legal cause
                        shall be separated from their commands and unable to attend the election at
                        the proper quarters, they may before the day of election deposit their
                        ballots in sealed envelopes, together with a statement of the name and
                        residence of the voter and send it to a qualified elector at home, who shall
                        cast such sealed ballot at home for the soldier, and it shall be opened by
                        the election officers when the returns are counted. The statement of the
                        soldier voting thus by proxy shall be certified to by his commanding
                        officer, some commissioned officer, or by some other creditable witness if
                        an officer is not accessible; and there shall also accompany such ballots an
                        affidavit of the voter stating that he is a qualified voter in the election
                        district in which he proposes to vote; that he has not sent a ballot to any
                        other person; that he will not attempt to vote at any other poll; that he is
                        not a deserter; has not been dismissed [from] the service, and stating also
                        where he is stationed. Officers of election refusing to receive such
                        ballots, when presented in proper form, shall be deemed guilty of
                        misdemeanor and punished by fine and imprisonment. The assessors are
                        required to assess a county tax of ten cents on each non commissioned
                        officer and private in the service, and such soldiers shall be exempt from
                        all other personal taxes while in service. The payment of such tax shall
                        entitle all soldiers, otherwise qualified to the right to vote.</p>
                    <p>The law is quite voluminous but in the main fair in its provisions, and leans
                        as strongly as possible in favor of the soldiers, so as to prevent him from
                        being defrauded out of his vote by legal quibbles. It was passed by the
                        Union men of the legislature--having been opposed by the Democratic
                        legislators because of its ample provisions for giving the right of voting
                        to our gallant soldiers in the field.</p>
                    <p>A supplemental bounty bill was passed at the extra session of the
                        legislature, which gives boroughs, wards and townships full authority to
                        levy bounty tax and collect the same when the county commissioners neglect
                        or refuse to do so. The districts may levy and collect the tax by their
                        authorities or board of election officers; but the bounty so collected shall
                        not exceed $300 for each recruit. The bill is also curative in its
                        provisions, and ratifies all loans created or taxes levied by the action of
                        the people of districts in any way that met the sanction of a majority of
                        the citizens. In such case the constituted authorities or board of election
                        officers are required to carry out in good faith the collection of such
                        taxes. It provides also that persons who have furnished substitutes credited
                        to the proper townships, the principals shall receive the bounty toward the
                        payment of his substitute. No tax exceeding two per cent of the last
                        adjusted valuation of property for county or State putposes [sic] shall be
                        levied in one year. A <emph rend="italic">per capita</emph> or poll tax may
                        be levied by the commissioners, school directors, supervisors or road
                        commissioners, or the proper authorities, not exceeding $5 per head to be
                        applied to bounty purposes; but persons in service, or disabled in service
                        shall be exempt; and the property of widows and minor children, and widowed
                        mothers of soldiers who died in service, is exempt from all taxation under
                        this bill. The act was approved on the 25th of August, 1864.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the passage of a bill which sets the procedures to enact the
                    amendment allowing suffrage to Pennsylvania soldiers. Soldiers would vote in
                    polling places set up at the quarters of the commanding officers. Soldiers
                    prevented from attending the election at the company poll would vote at any poll
                    most convenient. Soldiers unable to vote with a company would vote by proxy by
                    sending their ballots to an elector at home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Retaliation A Rebel Lie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Fair Play"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the rebel excuse that the burning of Chambersburg served as the
                    retaliation for similar Union offences. "Fair Play" notes the great difference
                    between a few straggler Union soldiers causing damage and an official order from
                    rebel officers to burn Chambersburg. He suggests the burning of Warrenton,
                    Virginia, as a "fitting retribution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Special Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints Governor Curtin's report to the Pennsylvania
                    legislature on his efforts to remove Colonel Gibson from the 2nd Pennsylvania
                    Artillery, to secure commissioned surgeons for the 2nd Pennsylvania Artillery,
                    to restore the 187th Pennsylvania Volunteers to provost duty within
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes real estate notices and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.09.07.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas Jefferson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earley</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>John w.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackey</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stotler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saltsman</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Angle</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleagle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tanke[illegible]</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenbery</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository lists the men on the Union County Committee for the year:
                    Chairman--T. J. Nill; North Ward, Chambersburg--A. D. Cauffman, W. Gelwicks;
                    South Ward, Chambersburg--G. J. Balsley, T. J. Earley; Antrim--W. H. Davidson;
                    Fayetteville--J. W. Barr; Greenvillage--Dr. Maclay; Dry Run--Lieut. Mackey;
                    Guilford--A. Stotler; Hamilton--A. McElwain; Letterkenny--W. W. Britton;
                    Loudon--W. Burgess; Lurgan--J. Saltsman; Mercersburg--T. Grove; Welsh Run--Dr.
                    Angle; Metal--J. Flickinger; Orrstown--S. Knisely; Quincy--W. Fleagle;
                    Peters--J. Patton; St. Thomas--J. R. Tankersley [illegible]; Washington--G. W.
                    Walker; Warren--J. H. Thomas; Concord--S. H. Hockenbery; Mt. Rock--T. Fuller;
                    Sulphur Spring--P. Shearer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fill Up Our Brave Armies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt> "<emph rend="italic">Atlanta, the last inland stronghold of Treason in the
                        Cotton States</emph>, has fallen! The victorious legions of the heroic
                    Sherman now rest in that stubbornly defended citadel of crime, after a march and
                    series of battles unexampled in the history of modern warfare. Their noble
                    sacrifices and brilliant achievements hurl back in confusion and shame the
                    driveling cowards who proclaim the war a 'failure,' and give earnest promise of
                    a speedy, honorable and enduring Peace." </excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Loyal men! <emph rend="italic">Atlanta, the last inland stronghold of Treason
                            in the Cotton States</emph>, has fallen! The victorious legions of the
                        heroic Sherman now rest in that stubbornly defended citadel of crime, after
                        a march and series of battles unexampled in the history of modern warfare.
                        Their noble sacrifices and brilliant achievements hurl back in confusion and
                        shame the driveling cowards who proclaim the war a "failure," and give
                        earnest promise of a speedy, honorable and enduring Peace.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">But one vital point of Treason remains</emph>, and that
                        is wasting in strength under the tireless energy and unfaltering courage of
                        the great leader and soldier of the Army of the Potomac. They ask for one
                        hundred thousand men promptly to enable them to consummate their great work
                        and preserve to us and to posterity the blessings of Free Government.</p>
                    <p>Let their shattered ranks be filled, and filled at once. Let every district
                        waste not one day, nor one hour, until its quota is filled. Brave men are
                        not wanting to respond to the call if citizens but do their duty generously
                        in providing for the wants of themselves and their household gods. This is
                        the work of every patriot, of every christian, of every friend of humanity,
                        of order and of government: and let it be done with hearty, ceaseless energy
                        until it is completed; and our gallant armies, whose heroism and victories
                        stand unparalleled in history, will soon return to us honored, and honoring
                        a Nationality that has swept treason to perpetual infamy, and given to the
                        world a beneficent government, an enduring monument of Civil and Religious
                        Liberty!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository urges loyal men to enlist and defeat the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Chicago Nominees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the Democratic nominees for president and vice president as General
                    George B. McClellan and George H. Pendleton. The Repository criticizes McClellan
                    as a weak leader and Pendleton as a strong support of Vallandigham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rebel Press On Chambersburg</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel, Richmond Dispatch, and Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository excerpts articles from three Richmond newspapers which
                    celebrate the burning of Chambersburg as sweet revenge for Union atrocities and
                    support for the Peace movement in the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Threatened Revolution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls attention to the New York Herald's prediction of McClellan's defeat.
                    The Herald, "McClellan's earliest and most devoted military organ," fears that
                    rebel sympathizers will revolt upon the re-election of Lincoln. The Repository
                    urges readers to dismiss the Herald's fears because Union victory appears
                    promising.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Hear Our Noble Chief!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints the Secretary of War's official request for more soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Democratic County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the nominees chosen at the Democratic County Convention: J. McDowell
                    Sharpe for legislature, General A. H. Coffroth for Congress, Kimmell for judge,
                    and John Armstrong for commissioner. The Repository criticizes the candidates
                    for weak and inconsistent support of the war and the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gen. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Where is the Patriot of the West Point oration--the Soldier of the Army of
                    the Potomac? Was the one a lie, and the other a fraud? A faithful people want to
                    know!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules McClellan's acceptance speech for not mentioning support for the
                    Union and praise for the Union army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository argues that Sherman's victory at Atlanta contradicts the
                    Democratic Convention's claim of the Union's "Four years of failure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts Union successes and progress in the war including Union control of
                    large areas formerly under Confederate control.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>General Coffroth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If Judge Kimmell were on the bench we should apply at once for a committee
                    for our friend the General, as he would certainly do that much for a wayward
                    relative; but as he is not, and Judge King hasn't had his hand in very long, we
                    affectionately entreat the General to appeal at once from Philip drunk to Philip
                    sober."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository responds to General Coffroth's comparison of Republicans and
                    Tories. The Repository suggests that Coffroth must be mad or drunk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Every Voter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository responds to the Shippensburg Sentinel's claim of Democratic
                    strength in Capt. Coffey's company. The Repository believes that facing traitors
                    on the battlefield will make the company loyalists at the polls.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Atlanta (rebel) Register</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository calls attention to an article in the Atlanta Register
                    stating that the actions of the Peace Democrats and the rebels benefit each
                    other.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository points out that the Democratic presidential and vice
                    presidential nominees both vote in Ohio, a violation of the rule that running
                    mates must be from different states. The editors deem this much worse than the
                    1860 Republican ticket with two Northerners, Lincoln and Hamlin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository provides details on the Pennsylvania State Guard formed by
                    Governor Curtin. Organizers prefer veteran soldiers not subject to the draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>B.</ln>
                        <fn>P. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates the confidence of a soldier in the Army of the Potomac with the
                    initials P. D. B. of Franklin County in the condition and prospects of the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository informs readers that Rev. B. S. Schneck penned an account of
                    the burning of Chambersburg, soon to be published by Lindsay and Blakiston, in
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Chicago Convention!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the events at the Chicago Convention including the demand for a
                    "humiliating" peace, the declaration of the war as a failure, the demand for the
                    immediate cessation of hostilities, the nomination of General McClellan for
                    president by Vallandigham, and the nomination of Pendleton for vice president.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Rats Deserting The Ship!</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Herald, long the apologist, defender, and organ of Gen.
                    M'Clellan, both as a military and political leader, squarely deserts the sinking
                    Chicago ship and gives notices to M'Clellan himself to stand from under the
                    crash to come upon the craven Peace-mongers who controlled the Democratic
                    National Convention. Hear the Herald of Saturday last, in its editorial leader
                    reviewing the political situation:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository calls attention to the New York Herald's rejection of the
                    Chicago Platform as dictated by Jefferson Davis and the rebels. The Herald
                    demands the substitution of the Chicago platform with McClellan's own.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.09.07.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>About The Draft</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository provides details on the draft, including information on the
                    time, volunteers, exemptions by commutation, substitutes, crediting substitutes,
                    application to strike names, non-reporting conscripts, adjustment of quotas, the
                    one hundred day men, a warning against swindlers, and the collection of
                    bounties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Remember Our Suffering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository urges the people of Franklin County to donate food, bedding,
                    or other needed item to those hurt by the rebel invasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bank Of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Bank of Chambersburg only lost its building in the rebel
                    invasion because "all its notes, securities, specie and other valuables were out
                    of rebel reach." The bank temporarily operates from the house of D. K.
                    Wunderlich.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbett</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmer</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>David J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Mont.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>V. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeHaven</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository provides a detailed report on the Democratic County
                    Convention held in the Public School House on August 30. The article lists the
                    following officers and nominations: J. Armstrong--President; Sibbet and
                    Gilmer--Vice Presidents; A. Burgess and J. Orr--Secretaries. Assembly--Sharpe of
                    Chambersburg; Commissioner--Armstrong of Chambersburg; Director of the
                    Poor--Skinner of Fannett; Auditor--M. Martin of Lurgan; Coroner--Dr. Miller of
                    Antrim. Congressional Conferees--Douglas, G. M. Stenger and DeHaven; Judicial
                    conferees--Duncan, Orr and Croft; legislative conferees--McAllen, Johnston and
                    Shoemaker. Sharpe and W. S. Stenger gave speeches.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Credit To Whom Credit Is Due</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository notes that the citizens of the county should thank K. S.
                    Taylor, Franklin's Prothonotary, and Harry Strickler, Franklin's Register and
                    Recorder, for saving the court house records.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rebel Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the extra train from Hagerstown that came through Chambersburg,
                    carrying 56 rebel prisoners captured by General Averill's forces in the
                    Shenandoah Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Rabid Disloyalist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the "rabid" disloyalty of Eli Smith, from Taneytown, Maryland.
                    Smith declared himself a rebel and expressed regret that the whole town had not
                    burned. Smith was promptly arrested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. James R. Gilmore</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository notes James R. Gilmore's recent visit to Chambersburg. He
                    serves as the chief of the Military Telegraph Corps in North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldiers Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkett</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository relates the news from the Waynesboro Record of the deaths of
                    John Mickely and Emanuel Burkett, of Capt. Kurtz's company. Mickely and Burkett
                    were killed near Martinsburg on August 29 during General Averill's fight with
                    the rebels. Burkett's body remains missing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dr. Wm. C. Lane</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>William C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointment of Dr. William C. Lane, of Upper Strasburg, as
                    surgeon of the Enrolling Board of this district and the appointment of Dr.
                    Samuel G. Lane as Assistant Surgeon General of Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Atlanta Fallen!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the fall of Atlanta including the retreat of General Hood, the
                    death of rebel General Hardee, the actions of the 20th Corps, the surrender of
                    Fort Morgan, the capture of 600 prisoners and 60 guns, the imminent fall of
                    Mobile, General Averill in the Valley, General Early's retreat to Winchester,
                    Sheridan's pressure on the rebels, and Grant's possession of the Weldon
                    Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Veteran 107th</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hattenstein</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that in the battle of September 19, on the Weldon Railroad, the
                    107th captured the battle flag of the 18th North Carolina. The color-bearer
                    Hattenstein, of Company C, captured the flag.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Lt. Col. Geo. Stitzel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzel</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the arrival of Lt. Col. George Stitzel, of the 11th Pa. Cavalry, in
                    Chambersburg on a short leave of absence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>On A Visit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the visit of former townsman Robert Early, now a 1st Lieutenant and
                    Quarter Master of the 136th Regiment Indiana Volunteers, in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Lieut. M. W. Houser</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the arrival of M. W. Houser, of the 57th Regiment Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, at his home in Chambersburg. He was wounded twice in the battles of
                    the Wilderness last May and he rejoined his command when only partially healed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, military notices, and market
            reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.09.07.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
