<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/15/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-07-06">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fourth of July in Chambersburg!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a rumor of rebel invasion of southern Pennsylvania on July 3. The
                    article describes the quick preparation, actions, and evacuations. The following
                    day, the citizens were notified that the invasion was a false alarm and
                    proceeded to celebrate independence day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Were you ever ashamed of the names of some of our battle-fields? Not
                    Northern mudsills, but Southern chivalry, are responsible for such names as
                    these--they are genuine and historical: Bull Run, Snicker's Gap, Slaughter's
                    Mountain, Polecat Station"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes items of war news including the acceptance of black men as
                    substitutes for white men, the efforts by firemen to obtain water for hospitals
                    in City Point from the James River, a smuggler's unsuccessful attempt to fill a
                    dead mule with ammunition and supplies, Sherman capture of about thirty iron
                    works in the Altoona vicinity, the South's names for various battles, the
                    successful efforts of Generals Hunter and Wilson to cut Lee's communications
                    with the south and southwest;, and Grant's control of the situation at
                    Petersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Political Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports political news including the Democrat Chicago Convention's
                    suggestion to form a Western Confederacy, and elections in Nebraska for
                    delegates to frame its constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Financial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes a "Special War Tax" enacted by Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Evaluates and explains the recent movements by Grant and Lee. The author
                    speculates on the weakness of the Confederate army forcing Lee east of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Constitutional Amendments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the pending vote in Pennsylvania to ratify several amendments: the
                    suffrage of soldiers and electors, limiting bills to one subject, and the
                    prevention of the legislature's usurpation of the court's powers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>An Ugly Picture</head>
                <origin>The Village Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a Village Record article commenting on the Valley Spirit's report
                    of Union defeats in Virginia. The Record requests a more truthful report from
                    the Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Washington</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Notwithstanding all this, the blacks rushed on undaunted, and after a
                    terrible struggle, in which some rebel cannon were captured and immediately
                    turned upon their late owners, and with the terrible bayonet dealt out death
                    right and left, sparing none who fell in their way, taking not a single
                    prisoner, they compelled the remainder to flee in utter confusion to the woods
                    in their rear, and held the ground which to-day gives Grant a position where he
                    can at any time lay Petersburg in ashes."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Shadows of War--The Hospitals--Heroism of the Black Troops--The
                        Conscription Bill.</p>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Franklin Repository.</p>
                    <p>Washington City, June 24, 1864.</p>
                    <p>At the present time our city is almost devoid of any sort of attraction
                        interesting enough to call strangers to it, unless it be the numerous
                        hospitals in which at present, are so many thousands of wounded
                        heroes--brave men who have sacrificed all the comforts and pleasures of
                        home, endured untold hardships and privations in periling their lives for
                        their country.</p>
                    <p>In passing through the hospitals and looking on the limbless and sick victims
                        of this accursed rebellion, one's heart is filled with mingled pride and
                        sorrow at the sight of the brave young men--the light and joy of many a
                        home--cut down in the pride, strength and glory of all their young manhood.
                        Yet it is wonderful to witness the uniform cheerfulness which they evince
                        even while suffering from the severest wounds. In the hundreds of times that
                        I have visited these hospitals, conversed with these patients and written
                        letters dictated by them to friends at home, I have found no word of regret,
                        but the same cheerful tone throughout, and in cases where death is
                        inevitable, there is still the same satisfied look and expression which
                        clearly shows their appreciation of the magnitude of the object for which
                        they are sacrificing themselves.</p>
                    <p>Our hearts bleed for the mothers that bore noble men, for the young wives
                        left desolate, for the sisters who will wait in vain for their return. Alas!</p>
                    <p>"No more return-- <lb/>Till sisters, brothers all unite. <lb/>In another and
                        a better world."</p>
                    <p>After the gallant charge of Duncan's Black Brigade on the outer works of
                        Petersburg, who will stand up and say that "poor old slave" will not fight.
                        As the blacks approached, the rebels stood upon their works with a black
                        flag, taunting them to come on, with all the odious epithets which the
                        genius of blackguardism has invented. Notwithstanding all this, the blacks
                        rushed on undaunted, and after a terrible struggle, in which some rebel
                        cannon were captured and immediately turned upon their late owners, and with
                        the terrible bayonet dealt out death right and left, sparing none who fell
                        in their way, taking not a single prisoner, they compelled the remainder to
                        flee in utter confusion to the woods in their rear, and held the ground
                        which to-day gives Grant a position where he can at any time lay Petersburg
                        in ashes.</p>
                    <p>This heroic act of the colored soldiers has raised them very high in the
                        estimation of our old veterans, and hereafter they will be found side by
                        side in the hottest of the fight for their country and universal freedom,
                        and so they will fight on, until no spot shall be saddened by the footprints
                        of a single slave.</p>
                    <p>The bill amendatory of the Enrolling-act was passed last night in the evening
                        session of the Senate by a vote of 24 to 7. The Commutation clause is
                        stricken out, and all drafts hereafter made are to be for such term of time
                        as the President shall direct, <emph rend="italic">not exceeding one
                        year.</emph> Each district is to be allowed for the number of men
                        volunteering up to the time of draft and that number deducted from the
                        number to be drafted.</p>
                    <p>It is to be hoped that the House will yet acquiesce in this action of the
                        Senate. The question is simply, shall the contest for the suppression of the
                        rebellion be continued or abandoned? If it is to be continued, we must have
                        the additional troops necessary to do so, and to get them the commutation
                        law must be repealed. The cause requires the men, not money; and he who
                        votes to exempt any drafted man capable of serving efficiently without
                        furnishing an exempt substitute, simply votes to insure the eventual success
                        of the rebellion.</p>
                    <p>The news from the front is still very encouraging. Petersburg can be taken at
                        any time Grant sees fit. Grant is aiming at a deeper game than the taking of
                        that town. One more move from the ground he yesterday occupied and
                        Petersburg must fall without an attack on it.</p>
                    <p>S.C.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"S.C."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports news from the Washington correspondent on the wounded in Union
                    hospitals, the "gallant charge of Duncan's Black Brigade" on the outer works of
                    Petersburg, and the Senate's passage of the conscription bill ending
                    commutations and increasing the number of drafted men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Grant and Meade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a colorful description of General Grant and Major General Meade
                    and their camplife.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Rebel Views of Our Nominations</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner, June 13th.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"whether they shall ever be elected or not depends upon the Confederate
                    army altogether."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Links the candidacy of Lincoln and Johnson to the military situation. The
                    taking of Richmond by a Union general would secure their nominations. The defeat
                    of Grant would give hope to the Democrat Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Army Bill Signed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports Lincoln's approval of an increase in pay for soldiers. The article
                    gives the new wages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Washington Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the Secretary of War's efforts to create a freedmen's village at the
                    Arlington estate of General Lee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Election Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>High Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harvey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mullen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliott</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces an election on August 2, to ratify proposed amendments to the
                    state constitution. The article provides a list of voting places including the
                    following owned by private persons: the Public House of J. Taylor for the south
                    ward of Chambersburg; the Public House of J. Gordon, for Hamilton Township; the
                    Public House of M. Shoemaker, for part of Green Township; the house of J.
                    Harvey, for part of Fannett Township; the house occupied by G. Anderson, for
                    Quincy Township; the house of J. Adams, for Antrim, and part of Peters and
                    Montgomery townships; at the school house on the land of M. Cook, for the Warren
                    Township; the house of J. Mullen, for Peters Township; at the log house on the
                    farm of J. Elliott, for the Welsh Run district (part of Montgomery Township);
                    and the house of T. McAfee, in Mercersburg, for parts of Peters and Montgomery
                    townships.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.03">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Gov. Curtin's plans to speak at Gettysburg on July 4 were
                    disrupted by the rumors of a rebel invasion. He returned to Harrisburg to confer
                    with Gen. Couch.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Military Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses reactions to the rumors of rebel invasion, suggests the
                    exaggeration of the number of rebels attracted to large stores at Martinsburg,
                    mentions that Gen. Couch's and other area forces are prepared for a rebel
                    invasion, details recent Union movement by Gen. Wilson and Kautz that isolated
                    Richmond from the south, and reports that Gen. Sherman forced Johnston to
                    surrender Marietta and that Atlanta will be Johnston's last stand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Resignation of Mr. Chase</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses Chase's resignation as Secretary of the Treasury. The Repository
                    criticizes his policy of contracting the currency to lower the price of gold and
                    prices in general. The author believes his policy produced the opposite effect.
                    Gov. Tod declined the position and Hon. William Pitt Fessenden, Senator of
                    Maine, has been appointed. Upon the announcement of Chase's resignation,
                    government securities rallied.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Bolstering Traitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes a recent article in the Valley Spirit that attributes military
                    failures to Generals Stanton, Grant, and Hunter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Whither Goeth Democracy?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thus in pitiable dishonor and treachery lies the once proud and defiant
                    Democracy."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Celebrates the downfall of the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Circulate the Old Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages a wide circulation of the campaign paper, "The Old Flag." Notes
                    the desire to supply soldiers with "cheap and useful political news."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Acceptance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Lincoln's acceptance of the nomination of the Baltimore
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A bad cause seldom commands credible witnesses, and as the cause, the
                    organ and the witness in this case seem to be in happy sympathy, we commend
                    alike the enterprise and the logic of our neighbor."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository criticizes a Valley Spirit article that accuses Lincoln of
                    needlessly protracting the war and that cites Jefferson Davis as its witness.
                    The author accuses Davis of treachery and perfidy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the close of the Great Philadelphia Fair. The article includes a list
                    of the gifts and awards to be given to favorite generals and their wives.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Hunter's Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes General Hunter's destruction of the Virginia and Tennessee
                    Railroads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the men that Gov. Curtin sent to care for Pennsylvania soldiers in
                    hospitals across the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Stewart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Stewart, the chairman of the Union County Committee, called a
                    meeting. The Repository urges the Union ticket to start canvassing after
                    harvest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository provides the specifics of the conscription bill including
                    drafts of one, two, or three years, with bounties of $100, $200, and $300
                    respectively; the end of commutation; the allowance of substitutes for draftees
                    ; and a fifty day notice before enforcing the draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the contention that Andrew Johnson abandoned his mother in her old
                    age to live in poverty. The Repository reports that his mother died seventeen
                    years ago surrounded by family.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a quote Andrew Johnson reportedly said to Jefferson Davis as the
                    secessionists left their posts: "If I were the President I would arrest you as
                    traitors, try you as traitors, and hang you as traitors!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the Sentinel's praise for Gen. Koontz and support for his candidacy
                    for Congress as a Union man.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Carlisle Herald</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markley</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rheem</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that J. M. Markley joined Rheem as joint proprietor of the Carlisle
                    Herald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Middletown Press</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter printed in the Middletown Press that describes the hard
                    fighting and army life for Gen. Grant's soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Succor Our Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Gov. Curtin's appeal to send supplies to aid soldiers in the
                    hospitals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Capt. McDowell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Easton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerns</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the death of S. McDowell, son of J. McDowell of Chambersburg. He
                    was promoted to Chief of Artillery of his division. He died soon after, during
                    Sherman's unsuccessful assault in Chattanooga. He was buried at the national
                    cemetery. He is the fourth commander of a battery from Franklin County to die,
                    joining Capts. Easton and Kerns on the peninsula and Stevens at Chickamauga.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Casualties In The 77th</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neely</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stark</ln>
                        <fn>Albert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troutman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardsock</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Pvt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Capt. Walker, Co. A, 77th Pa. Volunteers, provided a list of
                    casualties from various counties: Co. A: Killed--D. Neely and J. Colter from
                    Washington; Wounded--A. Stark, in the breast, from Dry Run; P. Troutman, in the
                    foot, from Chambersburg; P. Hardsock, in the arm and side, from Funkstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To Friends Of Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges that citizens send onions and other supplies to the Union soldiers.
                    The soldiers need vegetables and the onion is "most invigorating."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Contribution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository acknowledges the receipt of $58.20, collected by Misses A.
                    M. and Maggie E. Sharp, in Green Township, for the U. S. Christian Commission at
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Episcopal Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Bishop</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces two sermons by Bishop Stevens on Sunday morning and evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzpatrick</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Michael Fitzpatrick cut off several of toes by accidentally
                    stepping on mower blades while working on Strock's farm in Cashtown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Col. Boyd</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Boyd gradually recovers from his bullet wound.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rev. H. Reeves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that H. Reeves, the principal of the Female Seminary, will leave
                    Chambersburg after the session to go to west Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces a concert by the Female Seminary pupils on June 30 to benefit the
                    Christian Commission.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>J. R. Kinney, Esq</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that J. R. Kinney, former principal of the Chambersburg Academy,
                    left for a professorship in California.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Call Accepted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carnahan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Rev. Carnahan, of Fayetteville, has accepted the call of the
                    Presbyterian congregation of Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an article in the American congratulating Maryland for adopting an
                    amendment to their constitution to abolish slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the Democrats' "sad blunder" in their postponement of the Chicago
                    Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Pirate Alabama Sunk</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the sinking of the pirate Alabama by the U. S. gunboat Kearsaye.
                    Nine rebels were killed and 20 wounded in the engagement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Wilson and Kautz Safe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details Gen. Wilson's engagements. The article mentions raiding parties,
                    severe fighting, Union losses, the destruction of property, and the murder of
                    blacks by the rebels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hunter's Command at Charleston, W. Va.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository mentions the actions of Hunter's command in Charleston, West
                    Virginia including his great raid, his accomplishments, and his prospects for
                    another movement. The article reports five successful battles and the
                    destruction of $5,000,000 in government property in the Shenandoah Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Great News From Gen. Sherman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports news from Gen. Sherman including the capture of Kenesaw Mountain
                    and the occupation of Marietta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulmer</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 26, in Chambersburg, by Rev. Davis, W. Fulmer married Rebecca
                    Knisely.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swift</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Needy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 14, in Allegheny city, by Rev. Swift, J. Needy, of Waynesboro,
                    married Mary Graham, of Allegheny city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>J. Clemson</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhoads</ln>
                        <fn>Hellen S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 4, by Rev. Dyson, J. Briggs, of Philadelphia, married Hellen
                    Rhoads, of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.06">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and train schedules.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.07">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.06.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Old Flag</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stone</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Advertises the weekly campaign paper, "The Old Flag," "devoted exclusively
                    to the election of Abraham Lincoln and Andrew Johnson." The paper will include
                    maps of battles and battlefields and portraits of Lincoln and Johnson. The
                    Repository urges the creation of clubs to promote its circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and real estate notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
