<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.10.26">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-26">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Maj. Gen. Geo. B. McClellan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a history of McClellan's participation in the Civil War. The
                    Repository evaluates McClellan as excellent in organizing his troops but poor in
                    offensive operations against the enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements, a list of all the state legislature
                candidates, and a picture of George McClellan.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union Men!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In less than one week the people of the North must determine by their
                    suffrages whether the war for the life of the Republic shall be arrested in the
                    midst of our victories by a humiliating 'cessation of hostilities'--whether our
                    sacrifices of brave men fallen in our country's cause, and of millions of
                    treasure, shall be pronounced vain and fruitless."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Union Men! the time for argument is past. Action, earnest, systematic,
                        tireless action alone remains to fulfil[l] the measure of loyal duty. In
                        less than one week the people of the North must determine by their suffrages
                        whether the war for the life of the Republic shall be arrested in the midst
                        of our victories by a humiliating "cessation of hostilities"--whether our
                        sacrifices of brave men fallen in our country's cause, and of millions of
                        treasure, shall be pronounced vain and fruitless.</p>
                    <p>The issue cannot, must not be evaded. It stares every loyal man in the face;
                        is plain as if written in letters of living light, so that he who runs may
                        read, and the subtlest sophistry is defied to conceal the momentous issue
                        from the candid, intelligent and faithful citizen. If Gen. M'Clellan shall
                        be chosen President it must be accepted by friend and foe at home and
                        abroad, as a verdict in favor of Peace upon any terms, even at the cost of
                        dismemberment; while if the national verdict is for Mr. Lincoln, as it
                        surely must be, it is a declaration that the war, now to all human
                        appearances on the threshold of final and complete success, shall be
                        prosecuted until despairing traitors yield to the majesty of the laws and
                        the unity of the States.</p>
                    <p>We appeal to faithful men to appreciate the issue and give it that effort its
                        crowning importance merits. It is fraught with the peace, the order, the
                        safety of, every citizen, for the maintenance of government is the first
                        duty--the last refuge of all. If we would accept a degrading peace our
                        government would be without honor and power, and its millions of suicides
                        would be without shame; and anarchy would be the sad fate of the fairest
                        continent of the world. We should be without credit, without security,
                        without law, and oppressed in every hand; the direst despotism would be at
                        last welcomed as the fruits of our perfidy to our own and a sacred country's
                        cause.</p>
                    <p>The loyal hearts beat strong with confidence of final triumph. Indiana has
                        spoken by 22,000 majority; Ohio by over 50,000 and Pennsylvania by over
                        12,000--with one accord declaring for the preservation of the government and
                        the vindication of the honor of brave armies. Thus foreshadowed by the
                        October verdict, the Nation cannot turn upon itself in November. But it must
                        be decisive, as it can be. The faithful people would stand appalled, should
                        the result of the great struggle of Tuesday next exhibit the Union ticket
                        but barely successful. And that is possible if there be remissness or over
                        confidence. Already the most glaring friends are shown to be in course of
                        consummation by our desperate and unscrupulous foes, and every loyal heart
                        must be quickened and every loyal arm strengthened to give overwhelming
                        victory to the Right. Forward loyal men! The day is at hand--the crowning
                        triumph is within your grasp, and enduring Peace, through victory, must soon
                        be restored to our Union, in honor, might and Freedom!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages all Union supporters to vote and argues that a vote for
                    McClellan will be a vote for "Peace upon any terms." A vote for Lincoln, on the
                    other hand, will be a declaration that the war "shall be prosecuted until
                    despairing traitors yield to the majesty of the laws and the unity of the
                    States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How The Tails Wriggle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It therefore proclaims victories to its defeated and despairing ranks, and
                    wriggles its slimy tails through every election table and into every dispatch
                    recording the verdict of October. Mr. Ward wriggles the tail of the defunct
                    Democratic State Committee into the columns of the Spirit, and declares
                    Pennsylvania to have gone Democratic 'by a majority of seven to ten thousand of
                    the home votes!' 'The votes of the soldiers' wriggles Mr. Ward, 'may, or may
                    not, reduce this aggregate!'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository criticizes the Valley Spirit's recapitulation of the
                    election and its 'supposed' Democratic victories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congressmen Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository predicts the election results for the United States
                    Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Koontz</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffroth</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository predicts the victory of General Koontz over General
                    Coffroth, the incumbent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Vote For Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Updates the votes for judge as of Monday. King has a majority of 73 over
                    Kimmell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Democracy of Franklin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository notes how the desperate Democratic party, pushed on by
                    Stenger, is trying to emphasize its one victory in the elections--Sharpe--in
                    order to keep the party alive for the November election for President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Cautions readers about the circulation of spurious electoral tickets with
                    one or two Lincoln electors leading a list of McClellan electors. The Repository
                    instructs its readers to compare their tickets with one obtained from the
                    newspaper's office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds persons receiving proxy votes of soldiers to leave them unopened
                    and deposit them with the election officers. Several votes were lost at the late
                    election by persons opening the envelopes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Moseby . . .</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "Moseby's gang, on Wednesday morning, appeared at Falls
                    Church, seven miles from Washington, and murdered a Mr. Reed, a Union man, and
                    one of his negroes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Phil. Sheridan "Whirling" Again!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a Union victory at Cedar Creek on October 19 and 20. Philip
                    Sheridan defeated General Longstreet and captured 48 rebel cannons and 2,000
                    prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements urging support for Lincoln.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Railroad Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>S. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roddy</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baer</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details a meeting of the commissioners of the Connellsville and Southern
                    Pennsylvania Railroad Company. The Repository urges support for the railroad as
                    economically beneficial to Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Swords Presented</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phenicie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knowles</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that enlisted men of the 21st, Company K, presented Phenicie a
                    sword, sash, and belt. Palmer made the presentation. The men of Company G in the
                    21st presented Knowles with horse equipment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Native Tobacco</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkle</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors acknowledge the gift of tobacco grown, cured, and pressed by
                    Solomon Dunkle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Address Of The Union State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'It follows, therefore, that every vote for McClellan and Pendleton is an
                    earnest invitation to Jefferson Davis to continue this fearful war to waste more
                    of our treasure and to murder others of our sons.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Simon Cameron, chairman of the Union State Central Committee,
                    gave a speech on October 21, urging votes for Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes unsuccessful attempts to break Sherman's lines of
                    communications.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Union On Home Vote!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Updates news on Pennsylvania's Union vote at home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Thanksgiving</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the last Thursday of November as a day of "thanksgiving and
                    praise."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Major Harry White</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces Major Harry White's recent release by the rebels and his return
                    home to Indiana. White attempted to escape four times from prison.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edson</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Charles R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>M. India</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 5, in Indianapolis, by Rev. Edson, C. Aughinbaugh married Miss
                    Williams, both of that city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>N. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Laura M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 20, in McConnellsburg, by Rev. White, L. Hoke, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, married L. Hoke, daughter of W. Hoke, Esq., of McConnellsburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>M. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandt</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 20, in Orrstown, by Rev. Humebaugh, H. Etter married H.
                    Brandt, both of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lenhart</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 19, by Rev. Smith, S. Lenhart married S. Fisher, both of
                    Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 20, by Rev. Smith, T. Gorman married E. Myers, both of
                    Montgomery Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Neiswanger</ln>
                        <fn>Willis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 20, by Rev. Smith, W. Neiswanger married M. Miller, both of
                    Montgomery Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bashore</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 9, by Rev. Smith, H. Small, of Guilford Township, married Mrs.
                    R. Bashore, of Quincy Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatter</ln>
                        <fn>Simon C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Sue H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the marriage of Simon C. Shatter and Sue H. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Die</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 14, at his father's home, in Hamilton Township, D. W. Heckman,
                    died at about 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Die</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On October 8, in Chambersburg, George Houser, died at 67 years, 10 months,
                    and 16 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Die</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGaughey</ln>
                        <fn>D. Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On September 25, at Newberne, North Carolina, D. Calvin McGaughey (a
                    telegraph operator) died at 22 years, 1 month, and 21 days. McGaughey was a
                    member of the 126th Pa. Reg. and participated in the Battles of Fredericksburg
                    and Chancellorsville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.10.26.04">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
