<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Rachel Onuf</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/10/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-20">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Harrisburg: General Gantt and Col. Montgomery in Harrisburg--Their
                    Speeches--Withering Rebukes to the Democrats--Legislative Matters</head>
                <origin>Harrisburg</origin>
                <commentary>Correspondence of the Franklin Repository</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Horace</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Correspondence from Harrisburg describing speeches by General Gantt and
                    Col. Montgomery about the assurances given to them by Northern Democrats, and
                    Pennsylvanians in particular, about how they would help the South win the war by
                    "defeating the conscription and otherwise rendering the administration powerless
                    to prosecute it." The deadlock in the Senate continues.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Brief War Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This column includes a number of unrelated news items, and mentions in
                    passing that Dr. Lane, of Chambersburg, is Surgeon of the Fifth Pennsylvania
                    Reserve Regiment, who have just re-enlisted for three years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page also includes a reprint of a letter from the Union members of the
                Pennsylvania legislature to Abraham Lincoln, expressing support for his re-election,
                an excerpt from the annual message of Governor Bradford of Maryland, urging the
                abolition of slavery in that state, news from Washington, the "Political
                Intelligence" column, and a poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.02">
            <pageNote>Page comprised entirely of advertisements, with the following headings: Lines
                of Travel; Tobacco and Segars; Medical; Musical; Insurance; Gutta-Percha Roofing;
                Liquors; Watches and Jewelry; Hats, Caps and Furs; Justices of the Peace.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.03">
            <pageNote>Page comprised entirely of advertisements, with the following headings: Trees,
                Plants and Vines; Seeds; Agriculture; Dry and Fancy Goods; Boots and Shoes; Medical;
                Groceries, &amp;c; Clothing; Education.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gossip with our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Ladies, imagine a spacious room hung round with handsome pictures, such as
                    you never saw in your parlors, portraits of celebrated danseuses, race horses,
                    Heenan, Morrissey, King, Sayers; Adam and Eve in the garden, Susannah surprised
                    at her bath by the Elders (Biblical); Jupieter et Semele et Danse et Alise,
                    Diana et Endymion, Cupid et Psyche, Venus et Adonis (classical); correct
                    likenesses of Thais, Aspasia, Sappho, etc., etc."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Among the many advantages possessed by a gossiper, preeminent is that of
                        gossiping about what is not (the ladies will please note and appreciate,) as
                        well as what is. We love our native town with all her faults and wants; and
                        often plan in our mind what <emph rend="italic">we</emph> would do were we
                        elected Burgess or High Constable. We are not fully aware how far the powers
                        of the above mentioned officers extend, but would presume either could
                        accomplish what we purpose should ever have the chance. Chambersburg needs a
                        good Restaurant, with its accompanying bar, very much. Now we know that the
                        ladies (God bless them) as rule are opposed to such things, but we will for
                        their benefit explain. We have restaurants in town, but not a single fancy
                        one. Let no Restaurateur take offence at what we say for each one may, if he
                        will, open one whenever he pleases. Ladies, have any of you ever calculated
                        how much money is spent in this town per month for ale and oysters and such
                        like? We will whisper it to you, but you must not breathe it, for should
                        your lords (don't bridle) discover the source of your information our life
                        would not be worth a tinker's --hem! On second thoughts, however, we think
                        we had better <emph rend="italic">not</emph> tell it. You were never in a
                        first-class restaurant were you? (We still address the ladies.) Some we dare
                        say have not. Shade of Michael Angelo assist us! Ladies, imagine a spacious
                        room hung round with handsome pictures, such as you never saw in your
                        parlors, portraits of celebrated danseuses, race horses, Heenan, Morrissey,
                        King, Sayers; Adam and Eve in the garden, Susannah surprised at her bath by
                        the Elders (Biblical); Jupieter et Semele et Danse et Alise, Diana et
                        Endymion, Cupid et Psyche, Venus et Adonis (classical); correct likenesses
                        of Thais, Aspasia, Sappho, etc., etc. One entire side of this spacious room
                        is devoted to a handsome marble-topped counter, upon which are arranged at
                        intervals silver chafing dishes containing fried oysters, pigs' feet, fish,
                        fowls, birds, scallops, slaw, pies, everything edible. Behind the same, on
                        gorgeous shelving are tastefully placed cut-glass decanters containing many
                        colored liquids; stone bottles holding within their ample bellies many a
                        kind of malt liquor; pyramids of limes and lemons. Immediately underneath
                        you will find casks and barrels. Cigars and tobacco too are there, crackers
                        and bread and cheese, spices and condiments; what will make you hungry, that
                        which will induce thirst. Here and there are little apartments curtained off
                        where your husbands and sons can eat and drink and be merry without
                        annoyance from vulgar gaze. Some restaurants occupy the entire building, in
                        which case there are private rooms to which your husbands can take other
                        men's wives to what Gallic neighbors call <emph rend="italic">un petit
                            souper</emph>. (These houses have all private entrances.) Shut your
                        eyes, if you are alone and your husband is <emph rend="italic">on
                        business</emph> to the city (or even to Harrisburg), and if it be say 11
                        P.M., and conceive the scene of such a room as we have faintly pictured,
                        brilliantly lighted, adorned with huge mirrors and crowded with
                        gentlemen--add to all this the clatter of knife and fork, popping of corks,
                        exchange of jest, oaths and laughs, cigar smoke, tobacco spittle, and an
                        occasional fight. The picture can be made more complete by introducing the
                        billiard table and card room which occasionally accompany the foregoing. Now
                        ladies, dear ladies, let us have such an establishment here, and my word for
                        it, we (your male appendages) would not find so much <emph rend="italic"
                            >necessary</emph> business to take us to the cities. As Patrick Henry
                        once felicitously remarked upon a like occasion, "if this be gossip, make
                        the most of it."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author addresses the ladies of Chambersburg, telling them that if
                    Chambersburg had a fancy restaurant and bar, their "male appendages" would be
                    far less likely to go to the cities on "necessary business."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Acquittal of Forney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ford</ln>
                        <fn>E. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Forney was acquitted of the murder of Lieut. E. N. Ford, who he shot
                    while resisting a second arrest for desertion when he had already proved that he
                    was too old to be drafted. Isaac H. McCauley, Esq., Mr. Kimmell and Mr. Sharp,
                    all of Chambersburg, were among those representing the Commonwealth at the
                    trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Time for Volunteers Extended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxel</ln>
                        <fn>Elias S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The time for volunteering has been extended until March 1st. Capt. Eyster,
                    the Provost Marshall, has issued hand-bills stating that veterans will receive
                    $402 and new recruits $302 bounties upon enlisting. Col. Elias S. Troxel, Capt.
                    John Doebler and Lieut. Benjamin Zook are the local recruiting agents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gov. Curtin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gov.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Gov. Curtin was in Chambersburg on Friday evening, the guest of A. K.
                    McClure. He returned to Harrisburg on Saturday afternoon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>McDowell's Battery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Captain, with a large number of the members from this place, are now
                    home on thirty days leave. They are all in excellent health and by speech and
                    action enthusiastically in favor of a vigorous prosecution of the war."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This Battery, commanded by Capt. Samuel McDowell, of this place, has
                        re-enlisted for three years. It comprises three officers and eighty-two men,
                        and is the largest Battery in the Army of the Cumberland, and the only one
                        from Pennsylvania. Formed in this place in 1861, it was originally attached
                        to the 77th Regt., commanded by Col. Stumbaugh, but was afterwards made an
                        independent organization. Its first officer was Capt. Meuler, who
                        subsequently resigned and was succeeded by Capt. Stevens. Upon his death at
                        the battle of Chickamauga, Lieut. Samuel McDowell, the present commander,
                        was appointed. During the time it has been in service, it lost fifteen men
                        killed or died from wounds. For honorable and courageous service at the
                        battles of Murfreesboro, Chattanooga and Chickamauga, favorable notice was
                        taken by the commander of the army in his regular reports. It is the first
                        Battery reported at Harrisburg for re-enlistment.</p>
                    <p>The Captain, with a large number of the members from this place, are now home
                        on thirty days leave. They are all in excellent health and by speech and
                        action enthusiastically in favor of a vigorous prosecution of the war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevens</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meuler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The McDowell Battery was originally formed in Chambersburg in 1861 and
                    attached to the 77th Regiment, commanded by Col. Stumbaugh. Capt. Meuler was the
                    first officer of the Battery, and he was succeeded by Capt. Stevens. When
                    Stevens died at Chickamauga, Lieut. (now Capt.) Samuel McDowell took command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The District Quotas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The various districts of Franklin County have to provide the following
                    number of men: Antrim 48, Greencastle 21, Chambersburg NW 41, Chambersburg SW
                    31, Fannett 29, Green 35, Guilford 38, Hamilton 18, Letterkenny 23, Lurgan 15,
                    Metal 17, Montgomery 39, Mercersburg 15, Peters 34, Quincy 34, St. Thomas 20,
                    Southampton 21, Warren 9, Washington 31, Waynesboro 17. The total is 536 men.
                    Greencastle and Mercersburg have filled their quotas, and Chambersburg is about
                    full.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Military Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anyone wishing to make claims against the State for performing military
                    duty at camp McAllen, should contact John R. Orr, Esq., who has been
                    successfully presenting claims to the Military Board of Claims at Harrisburg.
                    Gen. McAllen has selected him for the job, and so far every case he has
                    presented has been decided upon favorably.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lieut. M. W. Houser</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas L.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sides</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. M. W. Houser, attached to Co. C, 57th Regt. Penna. Vols. (Gen.
                    Campbell's old command), has opened a recruiting station in the office of Thomas
                    L. Fletcher, Esq. on East Market Street. The Regiment is commanded by Col. Peter
                    Sides.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Col. Boyd's Cavalry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Col. Boyd is a superior officer, and will be held in grateful remembrance
                    by the people of the border for his services during the last six months."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Col. Boyd's Cavalry, the 21st Pennsylvania, has been ordered here for
                        re-organization. The companies on duty with him on the border are now
                        encamped near town, and three other companies on duty in the coal regions,
                        will be here in a few days. This command has won unusual credit for new
                        troops by its uniform gallantry and arduous service, and we are glad to
                        learn that most of the men will re-enlist for three years. Col. Boyd is a
                        superior officer, and will be held in grateful remembrances by the people of
                        the border for his services during the last six months.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The 21st Pennsylvania Cavalry, under the command of Col. Boyd, soon will be
                    re-organizing in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To Drafted Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The author observes that Jere Cook, Esq., has an advertisement in this
                    paper, offering his services to men who have legal claims for exemption from
                    military service. "His official connection with the Provost Marshall's office
                    during the late draft, makes him perfectly familiar with the laws and the
                    routine of business, and applicants can confide such cases to him fully assured
                    that they will not be wronged by extortion."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Acknowledgement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are requested by Mr. Henry Williams, (colored,) to acknowledge the receipt
                        of forty-five dollars and twenty cents contributed by a number of our
                        citizens for the purpose of placing new seats in the Bethel (colored) Church
                        of this place.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>(colored)</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"We are requested by Mr. Henry Williams, (colored,) to acknowledge the
                    receipt of forty-five dollars and twenty cents contributed by a number of our
                    citizens for the purpose of placing new seats in the Bethel (colored) Church of
                    this place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Pastor Chosen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>F. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Rev. F. W. Conrad, of Lancaster, has been unanimously elected pastor of
                    the Lutheran Congregation of this place."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page includes follow-up articles from last week's stories about the need to
                fill up the armies and the Democratic "thimble-rigging" in the state Senate. There
                are some miscellaneous news items and information about current issues of various
                publications. One short article in column six has been cut out.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Extraordinary Success</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Ward of Co. D, 11th Pennsylvania Cavalry, has recruited nearly fifty
                    men at his station in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trone</ln>
                        <fn>Abner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cobaugh</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Messrs. Abner Trone, William D. Cobaugh and Josiah Gamble, all of
                    Shippensburg and members of Co. H 3rd Pennsylvania Cavalry, were wounded on the
                    night of January 6, 1864, while on picket duty. Trone and Cobaugh have each had
                    a leg amputated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jere</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Watson and Jere Cook, Esqs., have been appointed Notaries of the
                    Public by Gov. Curtin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Legal Intelligence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wardlick</ln>
                        <fn>F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wardlick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demas</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Demas</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brotherton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Laubargh</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koons</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshart</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goshart</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Edmond</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koons</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alleman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benford</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>Holker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slichter</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slichter</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slichter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coon</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Charlott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brechbill</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gettys</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hains</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>These writs were issued in the Court of Common Pleas last week: F. C. and
                    John Wardlick vs. Robert Wright, David Demas and heirs at law of Jacob Demas,
                    "Sci. fa. to mechanics lein to revive the same;" James Brotherton vs. Andrew
                    Strealy, to revive Judgment 33 of January term, 1859; Nill and Kennedy,
                    executors of James Beatty, dec'd. vs. W. Brown, summons in debt on notes for
                    $944.72, $109.27, $107.06 and $80; Nill and Kennedy, executors of James Beatty,
                    dec'd. vs. George Laubargh, summons in debt on a note for $180; Nill and
                    Kennedy, executors of James Beatty, dec'd. vs. Henry Bickley, summons in debt on
                    a note for $100; Nill and Kennedy, executors of James Beatty, dec'd. vs. William
                    Koons, summons in debt on a note for $57.88; Nill and Kennedy, executors of
                    James Beatty, dec'd. vs. Jacob Goshart, summons in debt on a note for $300; Nill
                    and Kennedy, executors of James Beatty, dec'd. vs. William and Jacob Goshart,
                    summons in debt on a note for $500; Samuel Anderson vs. Edmond Hays, summons in
                    assumpsit on a note for $137.14; Mary Koons vs. Benjamin Alleman, capias for
                    breach of promise; A. W. Benford, use of Jacob Ely vs. Holker Hughes, summons in
                    assumpsit on a note for $183; George and Henry Slichter, administrators of John
                    Slichter, dec'd. vs. Elizabeth and Samuel Lehman, summons in debt on a note for
                    $1200; George and Henry Slichter, administrators of John Slichter, dec'd. vs.
                    David Lehman, summons in debt on a note for $600. These letters of
                    administration were granted in Orphan's Court last week: to Jeremiah Besore and
                    John W. Coon, for the estate of Josiah Besore, of Washington township; to T. J.
                    Nill, for the estate of Charlott Smith, of Chambersburg; to Christian Brechbill,
                    for the estate of Christian Sollenberger, of Green township; to John W. Walker,
                    for the estate of Mary Gettys, of Metal; to William S. Hains, for the estate of
                    Josiah J. Elliot, of Fannett township. The final account of Franklin Besore,
                    executor of George Besore, dec'd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrenfeld</ln>
                        <fn>C. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>S. D.</fn>
                        <sf>M. D.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Ella M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. D. Kell, M. D., of Orrstown, married Miss Ella M. Cressler, of
                    Shippensburg at her parent's residence on December 23, 1863. Rev. C. L.
                    Ehrenfeld performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W. R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kitzmiller</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darrah</ln>
                        <fn>Annie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John A. Kitzmiller, of the vicinity of Shippensburg, married Miss Annie J.
                    Darrah at her mother's house near Scotland, also in Franklin County, on January
                    12, 1864. Rev. W. R. H. performed the ceremony.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckley</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Briggs</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bivins</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. G. Briggs and Miss Elizabeth B. Bivins, both of Peters township, were
                    married on December 24, 1863, at the same time that John Glass and Miss Mary E.
                    Donathan were married. Rev. J. W. Buckley performed the ceremony at the M. E.
                    Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donathan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckley</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Glass and Miss Mary E. Donathan, both of Valley Forge near Loudon,
                    were married on December 24, 1863, at the same time that M.G. Briggs and Miss
                    Elizabeth B. Bivins were married. Rev. J. W. Buckley performed the ceremony at
                    the M. E. Parsonage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherren</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Ann McPherren died near Funkstown, Franklin County, on January
                    13, 1864 at the age of 46 years, 5 months and 6 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Morris of Hunderdon County, New Jersey, died in Fayetteville on
                    January 14, 1864, at the age of 36 years and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. C. Bender died in Montgomery township on December 27, 1863, at the age
                    of 1 year, 10 months and 29 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Rice died in Washington County, Maryland on January 1, 1864, aged 36
                    years, 8 months and 7 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donathen</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Donathen died near Loudon on January 12, 1864, at the age of 78
                    years, 9 months and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham Lehman died in Mahoning County, Ohio on January 3, 1864, aged 74
                    years, 9 months and 10 days. He moved from Franklin County to Ohio 30 years
                    before his death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sackman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Sackman died in St. Thomas on January 3, 1864 at the age of 79 years,
                    6 months and 9 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Andrew Jackson Shuman died in St. Thomas on January 3, 1864, aged 6 years,
                    5 months and 3 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overcash</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Alice Overcash died in Guilford township on January 8, 1864, at the
                    age of 1 year, 4 months and 24 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>William Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Franklin Walter died in St. Thomas on January 8, 1864, aged 15
                    years, 9 months and 13 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonebrake</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Bonebrake died in Guilford township on January 11, 1864, at the
                    age of 46 years, 2 months and 12 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keckler</ln>
                        <fn>Valentine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Valentine Keckler died near Waynesboro on January 12, 1864, at the age of
                    64 years and 21 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigger</ln>
                        <fn>John Laird</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Laird Bigger died in St. Thomas on January 5, 1864, at the age of 63
                    years, 10 months and 6 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Mail Proposals</head>
                <origin>Post Office Department, Washington</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The United States Post Office Department is soliciting proposals for
                    conveying mail in Pennsylvania, based on the routes and schedules of departures
                    and arrivals they specify, in tremendous detail, below the solicitation. They
                    are accepting bids until March 31, and the accepted proposals will be in effect
                    from July 1, 1864 to June 30, 1868. Prospective bidders are asked to pay
                    particular attention to the latter half of section 19 of the "Form of Proposal,
                    Guarantee, and Certificate," which is also printed, that states: "Under this
                    law, bids that propose to transport the mails with 'celerity, certainty, and
                    security,' having been decided to be the only legal bids, are construed as
                    providing for the entire mail, however large, and whatever may be the mode of
                    conveyance necessary to insure its 'celerity, certainty, and security,' and will
                    have the preference over all others, and no others will be considered."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page also includes an account of Gov. Curtin's second inauguration in
                Harrisburg, market reports, miscellaneous news items and new
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.06">
            <pageNote>The U. S. Post Office's solicitation for mail proposals continues on this
                page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.07">
            <pageNote>The U. S. Post Office's solicitation for mail proposals continues on this
                page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.01.20.08">
            <pageNote>The U. S. Post Office's solicitation for mail proposals continues on this
                page, and there are advertisements with the following headings: Military Notices;
                Financial; Real Estate Sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
