<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1864/pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 1/16/99</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1864-07-27">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hon. Abraham Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a biography of Lincoln. The Repository believes that Lincoln
                    "wisely and faithfully discharged the duties of his great office."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Horace"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports news from the Harrisburg correspondent. Describes the meeting of
                    the Democratic State Committee as the event of the week. Reports Democratic
                    opposition to the proposed amendment to the state constitution to allow soldiers
                    to vote. Condemns Democrats for considering means to prevent enrollment and
                    ensure defeat on the battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Army Of The Cumberland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Old Soldier"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunkinson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the battle near Marietta, Georgia. The report includes the
                    evacuation of Marietta, the conflict on July 4, the Pennsylvania Battery and the
                    77th, prisoners and deserters, and the vulnerability of Atlanta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Summary Of War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes items of war news including the report that General Rousseau
                    levied and collected over $40,000 from rebel citizens for the murder of four
                    soldiers; a letter from a Franklin County soldier from Peters Township who was
                    with General Hunter in Lynchburg reporting Union retreat, the starvation of
                    horses, butchery on both sides, and retreat to Parkersburg with only birch bark
                    for food.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Financial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the new four hundred million loan bill in coupons or bonds of
                    fifty dollars, redeemable with interest. One-half of the four hundred million
                    may be issued in treasury notes (of not less than ten dollars) that can be used
                    as legal tender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides general news including the report of the death of Colonel Daniel
                    McCook and the title of prettiest girl of Cattawissa to Hallie S. Reifsnyder, a
                    nurse for soldiers of the Army of the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>New Call For Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints Lincoln's Proclamation calling for an additional 500,000 volunteers
                    for one, two, or three years, to be entitled to the bounty provided by law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Pulpit Of Rebellion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>F. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Publishes excerpts from a sermon by Rev. Conrad, Pastor of the English
                    Lutheran Church of Chambersburg. Conrad's sermon discusses the degenerate
                    actions of the Confederate troops and citizens and looks expectantly to the end
                    of the rebellion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Slavery And Its Victims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We append a telling description of one of the evils of slavery as given
                    by a soldier of the 104th Pennsylvania. Whoever can read it, knowing that is
                    only one of thousands that can be written, and still defend and seek the
                    preservation of the 'institution' is lost as well to the dictates of reason, as
                    to those of humanity. The soldier saw whereof he writes, as well as all who were
                    with him, and details his impressions in a style of simple and touching
                    earnestness. After some introductory remarks he continues:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository prints the report of a soldier of the 104th Pennsylvania on
                    the evils of slavery. The soldier details the genealogy of one Southern
                    plantation. The master fathered many slaves and committed incest with at least
                    one slave daughter, which produced an idiot son.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Remember Fort Pillow</head>
                <origin>The Buffalo Express</origin>
                <commentary>"Doctor Hunt, formerly of the Buffalo press, now in the service, writes
                    from Memphis to t he Buffalo Express. He says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository reprints a Buffalo Express letter that details discussions
                    under truce between General Washburne and General Forrest, the rebel leader at
                    Fort Pillow. Washburne did not deny that black troops have sworn to show no
                    mercy to Forrest's troops and did not express any desire to dissuade them from
                    their oaths.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and election proclamations.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.03">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Union County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the men nominated at the Union County Convention as follows:
                    Alexander K. McClure, of Guilford for Assembly; Hugh B. Davidson, of
                    Chambersburg, for Commissioner; John H. Criswell, of Green, for Director of the
                    Poor; Morrow R. Skinner, of Lurgan, for Auditor; William H. Koontz, of Somerset,
                    for Congress; and Alex King, of Bedford, for Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is a palpable, whole cloth falsehood. The Proposed amendment simply
                    confers the right to vote upon 'qualified electors of this commonwealth' who
                    shall be in the service; and the 'qualified electors' are, as every one knows,
                    white men over twenty-one years of age."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Bedford county correspondent writes us that the copperheads in that section
                        are industriously circulating the report, that if the soldiers are allowed
                        to vote, negroes in the service will also be enabled to vote. By this sort
                        of misrepresentation they hope to induce men to vote against the amendment
                        conferring the right of suffrage on our brave soldiers. It is a palpable,
                        whole cloth falsehood. The proposed amendment simply confers the right to
                        vote upon "<emph rend="italic">qualified electors of this
                        commonwealth</emph>" who shall be in the service; and the "qualified
                        electors" are, as every one knows, white men over twenty-one years of
                    age.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository dispels the rumors--supposedly spread by copperheads--that
                    the amendment granting suffrage to soldiers includes black soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>Gens. Crooks And Averill</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports fighting in Martinsburg, causing great anxiety to the neighboring
                    counties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Whispers Of Peace</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes an attempt to bring peace. Unauthorized Confederate men--Clay,
                    Holcomb, and Sanders--sought a meeting via Horace Greeley of the New York
                    Tribune with the president. Lincoln declined a meeting with unauthorized agents.
                    The Repository points out that Gens. Sherman and Grant are likely to be the
                    agents bringing peace to the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Volunteers And Bounties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports Franklin County's quota for the new call for 500,000 volunteers as
                    870. The editors express the need for a uniform bounty system to prevent the
                    wealthier cities from stealing away men from poorer regions. They propose that
                    the county should offer a $100 bounty and also a $100 payment to the families of
                    drafted men. The Repository urges enlistment, arguing that an additional 50,000
                    men in Grant's army would allow the defeat of Lee and the capture of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democratic Treachery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository claims that the Democratic Party remains silent on the issue
                    of suffrage for soldiers because it fears that many of its "honest and
                    patriotic" followers would bolt if they discovered the party's opposition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>J. M'Dowell Sharpe, Esq</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowell</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Predicts the election of King as judge for Franklin's district. The Valley
                    Spirit supports J. McDowell Sharpe and F. M. Kimmell as Democratic candidates
                    for judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We therefore censure Colonel Pearce for running away, but think him
                    entitled to some credit on account for leaving his command to his braver and
                    better subordinates."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository commends the actions of the 12th Pennsylvania Cavalry in the
                    absence of Colonel Pearce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'It must be confessed that our 'invasion' just at this moment looks like
                    one of the most paltry affairs of the war. Washington was not taken. Baltimore
                    was not taken.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a note of disappointment in the Confederacy in the Richmond
                    Examiner regarding the Confederate army's recent invasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Charles A. Gather, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gather</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the purchase of the Fulton Democrat newspaper by Charles A. Gather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Union County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowermaster</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zeigler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruthrauff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foltz</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>P. Dock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartzell</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>J. M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criswell</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stotler</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haulman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollar</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saltsman</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>J. McGinley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keys</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seabrooks</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middlecauff</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cressler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearman</ln>
                        <fn>Salsbury</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peekman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fegan</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washabaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the nominations of the Union County Convention: J. Rowe--President,
                    J. Bowermaster and D. Hays as Vice Presidents, and H. E. Wertz and J. A. Hyssong
                    as Secretaries. The following were delegates: Antrim--J. Rowe, J. Shank, J.
                    Fleming, G. W. Zeigler, J. Ruthrauff, A. Shirey, D. W. Rowe, W. A. Reed, A.
                    Davidson; Chambersburg--(North Ward) C. C. Foltz, K. S. Taylor, W. Gelwicks;
                    (South Ward) G. J. Balsley, H. S. Stoner, P. Dock Frey; Dry Run--J. M. Rankin,
                    R. G. Ferguson, S. M. Skinner; Fayettesville--J. W. Barr, Dr. E. Hartzell, J. M.
                    P. Snyder, J. E. Crawford, John Downey; Greenvillage--Dr. C. T. Maclay, J. H.
                    Criswell, J. Bolinger; Guilford--J. Bowman, W. Ferguson, A. Stotler, J. L.
                    Shank; Hamilton--H. Keefer, I. Miller, A. McElwain; Letterkenny--A. B. Wingert,
                    J. H. Kaufman, S. K. Lehman; Loudon--J. Haulman, J. S. Hassler, J. Hollar;
                    Lurgan--J. E. Maclay, T. Pomeroy, J. M. Saltsman; Mercersburg--J. A. Hyssong, D.
                    Hays, S. A. Bradley, T. Kuhn; Metal--J. H. WAlker, Dr. J. Flickinger, J.
                    McGinley Wilhelm; Orrstown--D. Hays, A. Miller, S. Knisely; Peters--W. L.
                    McLellan, S. Alexander, W. E. McDowell; Quincy--H. E. Wertz, D. Price, J. Keys,
                    F. Mentzer, O. Seabrooks; Southampton--M. Cressler, D. Middlecauff, J. Cressler;
                    St. Thomas--Salsbury Shearman, J. Bowermaster, F. Peckman; Sulphur Spring--J. E.
                    Fegan, W. Piper; Washington--G. W. Walker, J. Gehr. The convention made the
                    following nominations for commissioner: J. B. Miller, H. R. Davidson, U.
                    Washabaugh, and L. S. Clarke. Davidson was chosen. For Director of the Poor, the
                    convention nominated J. H. Criswell, J. S. Hassler, and S. Alexander and chose
                    Criswell of Green. For Auditor, the convention nominated J. Cressler, M. R.
                    Skinner, and G. Cook (Montgomery) and chose M. R. Skinner, of Lurgan. For
                    Assembly, the convention nominated W. W. Britton (nominated by Lehman), D. W.
                    Rowe (nominated by Walker), A. K. McClure of Guilford (nominated by Hyssong) and
                    chose A. K. McClure. For Coroner, the convention nominated H. E. Wertz of
                    Quincy. The Appointed Congressional Conferees (to support W. H. Koontz for
                    Congress) are G. J. Balsley, J. E. Crawford, and D. W. Rowe. The Appointed
                    Judicial Conferees (to support Alex. King for President Judge) are W. S.
                    Everett, H. E. Wertz, and S. A. Bradley. The Appointed Legislative conferees (to
                    support A. K. McClure for the Legislature) are J. A. Hyssong, J. Ruthrauff,
                    General D. Middlecauff.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a smelly sewer in town and several absurd explanations for the
                    stench including murder and a dumped body.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the citizens of Greencastle held a meeting on Thursday evening
                    to take measures for filling their quota of troops. Rev. T. G. Apple presided
                    and J. M. Irwin served as secretary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Quotas Under The New Call</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the quotas and regulations for the new call for 500,000 soldiers.
                    Substitutes and exemption certificates may be used for only one year. Men
                    subject to the draft may not be used as a substitute. The Repository criticizes
                    the decision that men who paid $300 commutation before the new law passed are
                    not subject to another draft for three years, whereas men who paid the
                    commutation after the law can be subject to the next draft. The article lists
                    the quotas within the county, but is illegible for half the townships: Metal-25,
                    Montgomery-68, Mercersburg-20, Peters-47, Quincy-63, St. Thomas-37,
                    Southampton-39, Warren-12, Washington-48, Waynesboro-28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Capt. Samuel M. McDowell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides a detailed biography of the recently killed Captain McDowell, son
                    of J. McDowell of Chambersburg. The article includes excerpts from letters he
                    wrote before his death and from a letter from a former teacher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Franklin County Crops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that, despite of the rebel raid and a hard winter, most of the
                    crop harvests will be average or better.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Serious Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grey</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserotte</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Senseny</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a serious injury for J. P. Grey. While attempting to retrieve a
                    stray cow from Colonel Boyd, Grey got into a fight with Boyd's stock man and
                    accidentally shot himself in the knee while using his gun as a club. Drs.
                    Suesserotte, Richards, and Senseny amputated his leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Recruiting Agent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates Gov. Curtin's announcement that one recruiting agent will be
                    appointed from each county of each of the rebel states to help ease the draft
                    quotas in the Northern states. The Repository expresses skepticism for the
                    success of this attempt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Guilford Township</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Guilford Township offers an additional $100 to the bounty
                    already offered by the federal government. Also reminds that only volunteers
                    receive a bounty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gone To Europe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langheine</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Dr. Langheine, of Chambersburg, has left for Germany, "for
                    illness and pleasure."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Suspended</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCrory</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mourns the suspension of publication of the Greencastle Pilot. The
                    Repository hopes that McCrory will be able to resume publication soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen Couch's staff</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that General Couch's staff returned to their old headquarters in
                    Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>In Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mentions the presence of J. Black in Chambersburg on Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Latest from Atlanta</head>
                <origin>Nashville, July 26</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Union forces have not yet captured Atlanta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Atlanta Besieged!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the attack of the rebels at Atlanta. The Repository believes that
                    the city will soon be in Union control.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository describes General Smith's outmaneuvering of General Forrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffmeier</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koons</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Malone</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 20, in McConnellsburg, by Rev. Hoffmeier, R. Koons, of Greencastle,
                    married Anna Malone, of Woodbury, Bedford County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Israel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Lavinah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 12, near Waynesboro, Nathaniel, son of Israel and Lavinah Hess,
                    died at 1 year, 2 months, and 13 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 28, in Quincy Township, Jacob, son of Martin Sollenberger, died at
                    18 years, 8 months, and 1 day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 20, near New Franklin, J. Keller, died at 58 years, 10 months, and
                    9 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 27, in Mercersburg, M. Taylor died at 42 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllister</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllister</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 13, in Mercersburg, Elizabeth, wife of Adam McAllister, died in her
                    89th year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William Campbell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 22, in Mercersburg, William, son of Matthew Smith, died in his
                    second year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 17, in the attack on Petersburg, 1st Sergt. Wolff, of Battery A,
                    2nd Pennsylvania Artillery, and son of David Wolff of Welsh Run, was killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On July 17, Rebecca, daughter of Jacob and Catharine Bickley, died at 10
                    years, 7 months, and 7 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Receipts And Expenditures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cameron</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wills</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reamer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deitz</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ege</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the donors who gave to the Ladies Fair for the benefit of the
                    Christian Commission: Miss Walk of Upper Path Valley &amp; Concord--$159.74;
                    Mrs. Burgess of Loudon $14.50; General Cameron $10.00; Mrs. Monn and Miss Wertz
                    of Quincy $164.30; Mr. Pomeroy of Roxbury $4406; Mrs. Eberly $1.00; J. Wallace
                    $5.00; H. Wills $2.00; Mrs. Fisher $5.00; Mrs. Dr. Reamer of Bedford $10.00;
                    Mrs. Dr. Wright $3.00; G. A. Deitz, wood $11.40; Captain Ege $5.00. Net Profits
                    $3,527.77. Mrs. Dechert, the treasurer, reported the donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and market reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.06">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.07">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1864.07.27.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Rebels In Hagerstown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The Hagerstown Herald gives the following account of the operations of
                    General McCausland and his command while they occupied that place, during the
                    late rebel raid on the border:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a detailed description of the ransom demanded of Hagerstown under
                    the threat of fire and their frantic and successful attempts to satisfy
                    McCausland's terms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository describes the pressure of Grant's army on Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>List of Causes for Trial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zellers</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rule</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennock</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pennock</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritch</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoch</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lochbaum</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambert</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoap</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>K. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the causes for trial of the August term for Common Pleas, starting
                    Aug. 8th, 1864: E. Kuhn vs. W. Crooks' Executors; M. Zellers vs. J. Rule; S.
                    &amp; M. Pennock &amp; Co. vs. W. Reber; J. Tritch vs. J. Price; C. Hoch
                    vs. A. S. Adams, et al.; A. J. Lochbaum vs. Dr. Lambert et al.; G. Gaff's use
                    vs. J. H. Tritle; W. Bush vs. J. Shoap. K. S. Taylor, the Prothonotary,
                    published the list.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
