<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.03.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-03-16">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Problem with cropping on p. 01.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.16.01">
            <pageNote>Only has cols. 1-4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="01a" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.16.01a">
            <pageNote>Page 01, cols 5-7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. Douglas' Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Douglas' Speech.</p>
                    <p>Our readers will find, in to-day's paper, a portion of the exceedingly able
                        speech of Judge Douglas, (which we will conclude next week,) in reply to Mr.
                        Seward's elaborately prepared campaign speech.</p>
                    <p>We publish this speech because we believe it to be a complete answer to Black
                        Republicanism as expounded by its great mouthpiece, and a masterly
                        vindication of Democratic principles and Democratic integrity. In one
                        particular this effort of Mr. Douglas is peculiarly gratifying to us and
                        beneficial to the party--we refer to its perfect refutation of the oft
                        repeated slander, that the Democratic party is responsible, in a moral
                        sense, for the repeal of the Missouri Compact. 'Tis true, that the
                        Democratic party believe that act unconstitutional--'tis true the whole
                        nation confesses this fact--'tis also true that that act, unconstitutional
                        as it was, had become, by years of acquiescence by all parties, consecrated
                        and sacred--'tis also true, that through the agency of the Democratic party,
                        that compact was repealed; but, there is another fact which precedes and
                        justifies the action of the Democratic party in repealing this compromise.
                        Our party was ready and willing to carry out this compact of our fathers,
                        unjust and unequal as it was; but, the anti-slavery men of the North, though
                        the Compromise gave them more than they were entitled to, were unwilling, in
                        good faith, to extend the line to the Pacific; thus the contract was
                        rendered null and void by the failure of one of the parties to comply with
                        its conditions, and the Democracy, thus released, did a good and great and
                        glorious action by thus repealing and spurning from the statute-book the
                        foul and oppressive compact. This speech of Mr. Douglas is impromptu, <emph
                            rend="italic">apropos</emph> and withal the best shot on the wing which
                        has been made in the last ten years. It is peculiarly fortunate that it was
                        made immediately after Mr. Seward's, and appeared in the same number of the
                        Congressional Globe, thus following throughout the country the effort of
                        that arch-agitator, and killing it as it runs.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Douglas' reply to Seward's campaign speech. Describes it as a
                    vindication of Democratic principles. Text of the speech is in columns 5-6.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar60.html#3.16a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sam'l Forrest, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrest</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obituary for Forrest, distinguished local citizen and member of the
                    Protestant Episcopal Church. He died of Typhoid Pneumonia on March 15.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>More Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>More Orders.</p>
                    <p>We are gratified to learn through Mr. O'Rork, the energetic Superintendent of
                        the Staunton Woolen Factory, that orders from military companies in various
                        parts of the State, continue to be received for hundreds of yards of the
                        handsome cadet mixture they are manufacturing. We trust that the day is not
                        far distant when not only large orders for this particular kind of goods but
                        also other fabrics will be sought after, and the number of hands employed
                        increased to over one hundred.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Rork</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Woolen Factory has received more orders from various Virginia
                    militia companies.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar60.html#3.16b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Brooke has been appointed to Harper's Ferry.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton Artillery.</p>
                    <p>This company turned out in full uniform on Saturday evening last and paraded
                        the streets for some three hours, notwithstanding the day was very
                        unfavorable. Under the training of their Captains and aids, the Artillery
                        and West Augusta Guards bid fair, at no distant day, to reflect credit on
                        Staunton.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Artillery paraded the streets for three hours last Saturday
                    evening.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar60.html#3.16c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>CLOD HOPPERS; March 10th, 1860</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter about the judicial elections.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional and Virginia legislature reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.16.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Carra</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Paulina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Carra Kolner died on January 27 at age 4.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Paulina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fanny Kolner died on March 4 at age 5.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kolner</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Kolner died on March 2 at age 4.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arode</ln>
                        <fn>Edda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arode</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arode</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edda Arode died on March 12 at age 4.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>D.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Reeder died at his father's home in Waynesboro on February 28 at age
                    25.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page has a cropping problem--only cols 1-3. Markets in col. 2. Candidates
                announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.16.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
