<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.02.10">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-02-10">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.02.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Results of African Labor in the New World</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that slavery brought prosperity to the United States, while
                    abolition will result in the extinction of the African race. Bottom of the
                    article seems to have been cut off.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Scratches are pretty bad on this page. Column 7 is too faint to
            read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.02.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Judicial Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Defends Thompson from an attack by "R. L. J." in the Spectator.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Southern Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"What, we would ask Southern men, can be the objection to a peaceable
                    conference of the Southern States upon the state of the country, and to devise
                    the best means for preserving the Union as our father's framed it."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Southern Conference</p>
                    <p>We had hoped that the events of the last three months would leave Virginia
                        united as one man upon the subject. We had fondly believed that the
                        necessity for concerted action, for purposes of self-defense, on the part of
                        all the Southern States, would be readily acknowledged by all. We had
                        commenced to congratulate ourselves that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >conservatism</emph> which has degenerated into systematic lukewarmness
                        for the honor and interests of the South, and of affiliation with the most
                        bitter enemies of our section, was forever silenced, if not annihilated, in
                        Virginia; and we believe that such results of paramount good would have
                        flown from the Harper's Ferry raid, could it have been possible to expel
                        from the arena the foul demon of party. What, we would ask Southern men, can
                        be the objection to a peaceable conference of the Southern States upon the
                        state of the country, and to devise the best means for <emph rend="italic"
                            >preserving</emph> the Union as our father's framed it? It is quite a
                        mistake to suppose that this conference is intended to be a preparatory step
                        to going out of the Union. Such a purpose is expressly disclaimed by Mr.
                        Memminger, the Commissioner from South Carolina.</p>
                    <p>We hope our Legislature will accept the invitation extended to Virginia by
                        her sister State, for, besides the necessity for concerted action, which the
                        threatening attitude of affairs devolves upon us, we owe peculiar courtesy
                        to the gallant State from which the invitation to this conference first
                        officially emanates.</p>
                    <p>On another occasion, Virginia took the lead, and pledged her faith to South
                        Carolina to stand true to her in a certain emergency; that emergency
                        arrived; South Carolina gallantly met and defied it; Virginia--as a
                        Virginian we blush to say it-- Virginia ignominiously, and to her
                        everlasting disgrace, backed down from her position, and left her noble
                        sister to stand alone.--This blot, while it remains on the escutcheon of
                        Virginia, forever stops her from arrogating to herself the pre-eminence in
                        chivalry and honor, which the Union, before, had agreed to award to her.</p>
                    <p>For the information of our readers, and that they, one and all, may know the
                        shame of their native State, and unite in wiping it out, we publish the
                        resolutions of the Virginia Legislature in 1849:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we regard the passage of a law by the Congress of the United
                        Stats, abolishing slavery or the slave trade in the district of Columbia, as
                        a direct attack upon the institutions of the Southern States, to be resisted
                        at every hazard.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That in the event of the passage by congress of the Wilmot proviso,
                        or any law abolishing slavery or the slave trade in the District of
                        Columbia, the governor of this Commonwealth is requested immediately to
                        convene the Legislature of this State (if it shall have adjourned,) to
                        consider of the mode and measure of redress."</p>
                    <p>South Carolina again responded and declared that the time for action had
                        come, and she was not mistaken, for the following law passed both Houses of
                        Congress the <emph rend="italic">next year</emph>:</p>
                    <p>"It shall not be lawful to bring into the District of Columbia any slave
                        whatever, for the purpose of being placed in depot to be subsequently
                        transferred to any other State or place to be sold as merchandise; and if
                        such slave be brought into the said district by its owner, or by the
                        authority or consent of its owner contrary to the provisions of this act,
                        such slave shall thereupon become liberated and free."</p>
                    <p>Thus was the issue raised upon which Virginia and South Carolina had pledged
                        the . . . [text missing].</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator had hoped that Virginia would be united on the conference
                    issue, but it isn't. The resolutions of 1849, in which Virginia backed away from
                    supporting South Carolina, are a "blot" on Virginia's character.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvfeb60.html#2.10a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Report on the Harper's Ferry Affair</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Richmond Whig has a complaint about the legislative report. The Vindicator
                    disagrees.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Respectfully yours &amp;c, Wm. S. H. Baylor</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Baylor corrects a report in the Vindicator about how much money was raised
                    for the West Augusta Guard to go to Charlestown.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>House of Delegates, Feb 8, 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>A.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Rep. Christian, including the text of a bill to amend
                    Staunton's Town Charter and change the town limits. The Bill includes a
                    street-by-street description of the proposed town boundries.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>Conservator; Feb 8, 1858--Spectator please copy.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter regarding the many contests for local office, especially about
                    making sure that the Sheriff's candidates are honest.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional report in column 2.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.02.10.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Many Farmers</head>
                <origin>Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>David Fultz; Jan 31, 1860</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Judge</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fultz is also a candidate in the hotly contested race for the circuit
                    judgeship.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 8.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooke</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Markhood</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 7.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blain</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bailey</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rutlidge</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 26. Bailey is from St. Louis.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>List of letters left at post office in column 2. Candidates
            announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.02.10.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
