<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.07.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-27">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Extracts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Selected quotes from Stephen Douglas and Hershel Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about Caleb Cushing, President of the National Convention at
                Charleston and Baltimore in column 3. Another article about President Buchanan's
                role in the election in column 4. Page is faint and blurry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Vindicator for the Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator is being made more available during the Presidential
                    campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Hobbs will take over as postmistress at West View, Augusta County
                    after James Hobbs resigns.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Veitch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Second quarterly meeting of this conference of the M. E. Church is meeting
                    in Staunton, and Rev. Veitch will preach.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Augusta Court--E. Hunter was charged with stealing John Churchman's horse.
                    Also H. Peck "gave his bond as Sheriff."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Meeting on Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Meeting on Monday.</p>
                    <p>The announcement through the columns of the Vindicator, that several
                        distinguished speakers from a distance had been invited by the friends of
                        Breckinridge, and were expected to address the people of Augusta on Monday
                        last, and that Dr. Moffett would also speak on that day, together with other
                        proceedings contemplated by the friends of each of the Democratic
                        candidates, drew to the Court-House a large number of citizens from town and
                        country. Immediately after the adjournment of the Court, the friends of
                        Douglas and Johnson took possession of the Court- House, organized the
                        meeting, transacted their business, and gave way to the friends of
                        Breckinridge and Lane, who did likewise. After this the audience was
                        addressed by Messrs. Smith and Leake, friends of Breckinridge, and Dr.
                        Moffett, a supporter of Douglas. By agreement these gentlemen abstained from
                        discussing the views of the two candidates and directed their efforts to the
                        harmony and unity of the party in the coming momentous contest. The tendency
                        of the speeches was pacific and we are sure a more pleasant and fraternal
                        feeling pervaded the Democracy at the close of the discussion than before.
                        While it was very clear that the friends of Douglas and Johnson numbered as
                            <emph rend="italic">four</emph> to <emph rend="italic">one</emph> of the
                        supporters of Breckinridge and Lane, still the majority manifested that same
                        spirit of conciliation which has characterized the action of friends of
                        Judge Douglas and the regular organization of the party, in this District,
                        since the adjournment of the Baltimore Convention.</p>
                    <p>It is gratifying to us, occupying the position we did heretofore, and now do,
                        in the unfortunate Democratic intercine contest, to find the great bulk of
                        the honest, unsuspecting, and dispassionate and practical thinking masses
                        coinciding with the views we have advanced and now sustain. We are fully
                        satisfied that the Democracy of Augusta county are favorable to the election
                        of Judge Douglas to the Presidency, by an overwhelming majority, and that
                        they firmly and unalterable believe him to be the nominee of the only
                        Democratic Convention authorized to make a nomination, and as such are
                        determined to support him.</p>
                    <p>The disappointment to our opposition friends was most cruel. With laughing
                        faces, and hearts beat on a rich treat at the expense of Democratic unity,
                        they placed themselves conspicuously in the Court-house so that everything
                        that passed might be seen and heard. But, "alas and alack!" for their
                        calculations. As the speakers, especially Messrs. Smith and Leake, began to
                        develop the record of Bell and Everett and clinch down the evidence of their
                        hostility to the constitutional rights of the South--piling fact upon fact
                        to force the conclusion that they were unworthy of Southern support--the
                        galled jades winced, twisted, turned, cursed, "not loud but deep," and
                        finally swore out right that they had been bamboozled, cheated into the
                        exhibition by forged bills and had not received the "worth of their money."
                        It was, indeed, to them a sore disappointment, and convincing proof that the
                        Electoral vote of Virginia will not so easily fall into the hands of the
                        friends of Bell and Everett as they had imagined.</p>
                    <p>From the manifestations on Monday, we are lead to assume that at least in
                        Augusta county, this canvass can and will be conducted without crimination
                        between Democrats, and that a spirit of fraternal regard will be observed,
                        even should the Charlottesville Convention refuse to adopt the compromise
                        tendered by the friends of both candidates on last Monday.</p>
                    <p>It is proper to state as a fact connected with the proceedings on Monday,
                        that the friends of Douglas proposed to go into a general meeting and for
                        the majority to determine whether delegates should be sent to Staunton or
                        Charlottesville. This proposition was peremptorily rejected by the friends
                        of Breckinridge.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting of Augusta Democrats was held on the previous Monday. Messrs.
                    Smith and Leake for gave speeches in support of Breckinridge and Dr. Moffett
                    spoke in favor of Douglas. All speakers stressed party harmony and did not speak
                    of the issues of either candidate. According to the editor, there were four
                    times as many Douglas supporters as there were Breckinridge supporters in
                    attendance.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.27a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Richmond Examiner</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A response to an article in the Richmond Examiner, which supports
                    Breckinridge, that accused the Vindicator of using "innuendo" and "sneer."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrill</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. Terrill came through Staunton this week to see his father, Col. W. H.
                    Terrill.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Misapprehension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator denies the Spectator's assertion that Capt. J.A. Harman has
                    ever favored dissolving the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Democratic Meeting</p>
                    <p>At a meeting held of the Democracy of Augusta favorable to sending delegates
                        to the Democratic Convention at Charlottesville, upon motion of Jacob
                        Baylor, Wm. A. Abney, Esq., was called to the Chair and H.B. Michie, Jr.,
                        appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion of James H. Skinner the following resolutions were adopted
                        unanimously:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, 1. That we, a portion of the Democracy of Augusta, cordially
                        endorse the nominations of those distinguished Democrats, Breckinridge and
                        Lane, and with equal cordiality the platform of principles upon which they
                        were nominated, as an exposition of the true principles of the power of
                        Congress and the Territorial Legislatures over the Territories.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, 2. In our opinion that it is very desirable that the divisions
                        existing in the ranks of the Democracy of Virginia, growing out of the
                        several nominations for the Presidency and Vice Presidency recently made at
                        Baltimore, should be healed, and that unity of action should be brought
                        about, if this can possibly be affected upon terms which may be honorably
                        accepted by all, and understanding the Convention which is to meet at
                        Charlottesville, on the 16th of August next to be called for the purpose of
                        effecting, if practicable, this union upon the terms aforesaid, therefore</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That the Chairman of this meeting be and is hereby authorized to
                        appoint fifty delegates to represent us in said Convention.</p>
                    <p>Under the above resolution the following gentlemen were appointed delegates
                        to the Charlottesville Convention:</p>
                    <p>Abney, Wm. A.; Abney, U.V.; Alexander, Moses; Alexander, John Jr.;
                        Armentrout, Charles; Baylor, William S.H. Capt.; Baylor, Jacob; Beard,
                        David; Berkeley, Thomas Dr.; Byars, John D. ; Caldwell, William; Clark,
                        Hatch; Cochran, Alex.; Cupp, John; Davis, Columbus; Dickie, R.O.; Fisher,
                        Richard; Harper, Samuel C.; Harrison, Henry; Hill, R.D.; Hunter, Wm. J.;
                        Johnson, Thomas; Jordan, Wm.; Kenney, John Jr.; Koiner, Cyrus; Koiner,
                        Solomon D.; Koiner, Martin; Koiner, George; Koiner, D.W.; Lightner, Thomas;
                        Long, Joseph; Lynn, Wm. H.H.; Marquis, James; McChesney, Wm. N. Dr.; McCune,
                        Givens; Michie, T.J.; Michie, H.B.; Opie, H.I.; Peyton, Wm. H.; Points,
                        B.J.; Pork, Wm. F.; Shaw, Daniel; Shmucker, P.; Shuey, John; Simms, Richard;
                        Skinner, James; Spack, David; Walker, Alexander; Walker, B.F. Dr.; Watts,
                        John B. Maj.</p>
                    <p>Upon motion of Jacob Baylor, Esq., the following resolutions which had been
                        previously agreed upon by the friends of Breckinridge and Douglas, and
                        passed by the meeting of the Democrats favorable to Douglas and Jonson, were
                        offered as a proposition of adjustment and accepted without dissent;</p>
                    <p>Resolved: That we recommend to the Convention to which our delegation is
                        appointed, to agree upon the following form of compromise between the two
                        contending wings of the Virginia Democracy, viz: that the Virginia Democracy
                        shall vote for but one Electoral Ticket, and that he Electors if elected
                        shall cast the vote of Virginia for Breckinridge or Douglas according as it
                        may elect either of them, if that election is possible, but if it will not
                        elect either of them, then it shall be cast for Breckinridge if he has a
                        large electoral vote outside of Virginia than Douglas, or for Douglas if he
                        has more than Breckinridge.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That Messrs. Moffett, Smith, and Leake are recommended to speak to
                        the favorable consideration of this proposition.</p>
                    <p>On motion the meeting then adjourned.</p>
                    <p>Wm. A. Abney, Ch'n.</p>
                    <p>H.B. Michie, Jr., Sec'y</p>
                    <p>Richmond papers please copy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Thomas Burke, Chairman. S. M. Yost, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G.M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>N.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes from a Augusta Democratic meeting held on July 23. The Democrats
                    elected Burke Chair and Yost Secretary. They endorsed the Douglas ticket and
                    affirmed the Baltimore Convention's decisions. In addition, they attempted to
                    unify the two Democratic factions, at least in Virginia. Moffett, Smith and
                    Leake all spoke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Wm. Abney, Ch'n. H. B. Michie, Esq. Sec'y.</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>U.V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byars</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Hatch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickie</ln>
                        <fn>R.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>H.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H.I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pork</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaw</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shmucker</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simms</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spack</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting of the Democracy of Augusta that supported Breckinridge in order to
                    send delegates to the Charlottesville Convention. 50 delegates were named, and
                    they decided that Virginia's electoral votes would go to "Breckinridge if he has
                    a larger electoral vote outside of Virginia than Douglas, or for Douglas if he
                    has more than Breckinridge."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.27b</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article on Greenbrier District in column 3. A couple short articles about the
                Staunton convention and the differences between Breckinridge and Douglas.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.27.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Western Virginia.</p>
                    <p>We extract the following from a letter written by an intelligent gentleman of
                        this county, now travelling in Western Virginia. It is dated, "Charleston,
                        Kanawha county, Virginia:</p>
                    <p>"We had a pleasant trip, and enjoyed it very much. Judge Brockenbrough
                        traveled with us. He is an exceedingly affable and agreeable travelling
                        companion, and the hours passed away delightfully as we glided with the
                        swiftness of thought almost, through valleys, hills and mountains, enchanted
                        by the majestic beauty of nature which invited our willing gaze from every
                        side. The Valley of the Kanawha is the finest country I have ever seen. The
                        corn oats and grass, are the most luxuriant I have ever witnessed in my
                        life. It does a farmer's eye good to look at the beautiful growth of
                        vegetation of all kinds.</p>
                    <p>Politics are very dull here. I find that the lawyers and office holders are
                        for Breckinridge and Lane, but the people are for non-intervention and
                        Douglas and Johnson. I saw some men from Putnam and the other counties
                        adjoining, who inform me that the <emph rend="italic">people</emph> are
                        almost unanimously for Douglas. Keep the ball rolling. I see you are to have
                        a mass meeting in Staunton on the 16th of August. That is as it should be. I
                        saw the address to the Democracy of Virginia. It is right. I endorse the
                        whole of it." Yours truly, M. A. K.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter written by M. A. K. of Augusta County, who is travelling in Western
                    Virginia. He says that the lawyers and politicians are for Breckinridge, but the
                    people are for Douglas.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.27c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huston</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married in Harrisonburg on July 25.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Smith Bateman died near Fisherville on July 24 at an advanced age.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Other political news from various papers in column 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.27.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
