<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.08.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-03">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Accomac Murderess</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miss Simpson, convicted of the murder of a man named Budd in Accomac,
                    passed through Staunton on her way to the State Penitentiary in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Meeting of Randolph County Democrats in column 3. Article from Alabama paper
                about Yancey and Rhett and the conspiracy to dissolve the Union in column 4. Article
                on Bell's views in column 6. Extract from Kansas-Nebraska Act in column
            7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Bifurcated Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the Seceders' speeches that attack the Douglas Democrats and
                    responds to them with vigor.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for the Staunton Convention to deal with problem of Breckinridge
                    running in the North, where he can only take votes from Douglas and give states
                    to Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Adams</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hill's Pump has finally been fixed, but the editor points out that the
                    Market-house Bridge and plank walk near Adams Lushbaugh's house need repairs as
                    well.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Black Republican flag at Ocoquan, Prince William, has been cut down. It
                        took 50 or 100 gallant militia of that ancient county to accomplish the job.
                        The pole, it is true, was a defiant insult to the South, but is it not a far
                        more aggravated case to permit 50 living, talking, walking Black Republicans
                        to live in Virginia, than it is to raise a pole with a piece of canvas
                        floating from its top, with the names of Lincoln and Hamlin? Is it not
                        necessary, in order to be consistent, to drive the pole-raisers themselves
                        from the soil of Virginia?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short article on a Republican flag that was cut down in Ocoquan.
                    Vindicator endorses running out of Virginia those that raised the flag
                    initially.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.3a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Ground Swell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Several excerpts from letters from Western Virginia supporting Douglas.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Politicals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A series of political tidbits about the Presidential race, which largely
                    support Douglas or say that Breckinridge has no chance.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Politicians and the People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Politicians and the People.</p>
                    <p>The politicians of the country who have undertaken to manage the great
                        Democratic party and introduce new tests of party fealty, will be taught a
                        lesson in the Presidential campaign which will prevent them hereafter from
                        assuming to act and think for those who are the real guardians of American
                        liberty--the American people. They will be taught that the Democratic creed
                        is limited by lines which cannot be transgressed at pleasure by the madness
                        of fanaticism or the hatred and jealousy of ambitious aspirants, and
                        unscrupulous office holders.--They will be taught, that public spoils and
                        public plunder, whilst they may govern the action and control the sentiments
                        of unworthy officials and policemen, have no power to influence the opinions
                        of the <emph rend="italic">patriotic public</emph>.</p>
                    <p>That most miserable conjunction of Yankee excitability and administrative
                        power, introduced on the one hand for the purpose of precipitating a
                        revolution of the "cotton States," and, on the other, to serve the
                        vindictive malice of James Buchanan against <emph rend="italic">his
                        superior</emph> in patriotism and intellect, will fall to pieces beneath the
                        rod of public indignation, and the Democratic numbers, free from the
                        contaminating influence of <emph rend="italic">disunion furor</emph> or
                        political jugglery, will still bear aloft in triumph the banner of national
                        patriotism, every fold radiant with the light of liberty and hope.</p>
                    <p>The great Democratic party and this glorious Union will survive unharmed the
                        shock of fanatical assault and malicious revenge. The despotic reign of
                        Buchanan will come to an inglorious end, the desperate madness of William L.
                        Yancey will be broken against the walls of Southern conservatism, and the
                        fiendish schemes of Black Republican treason crushed beneath the power of
                        popular will, whilst fresh in its pristine beauty and purity as the
                        immutable principle of justice from which it springs, <emph rend="italic"
                            >Democratic faith</emph> and <emph rend="italic">Democratic
                        influence</emph> will continue to inspire the hearts and control the
                        destinies of the <emph rend="italic">American people</emph>.</p>
                    <p>The reign and rule of <emph rend="italic">trading</emph> politicians is over.
                        The people--the true depository of all power in a republican
                        government--will exercise their authority for the protection of free
                        institutions and their own safety by the triumphant election of STEPHEN A.
                        DOUGLAS to the Presidency.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial claiming that the people will teach the Seceders a lesson in the
                    election, namely that the people want Union and Douglas.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.3b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Baltimore Conference</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A meeting was held of the members of the Baltimore Conference of the M. E.
                    Church. They called for a Convention to be held in Staunton to decide whether or
                    not to stay in the General Conference of the M. E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Charlottesville Jeffersonian is trying to hatch a complaint against
                        Staunton, and takes as a pretext the fact that the passengers on the Central
                        Road dine at this place going west, and remain here all night going east,
                        greatly to the annoyance of the Hotel Keepers in Charlottesville. We are
                        surprised at Uncle Alec. Does he not know that Charlottesville is nothing
                        more than a respectable turn-out as compared with Staunton. Nature has done
                        more for the City of Staunton, than for the hamlet of Charlottesville,
                        located near the University. If Charlottesville were here and Staunton where
                        Charlottesville is, then this apparent favoritism would not strike our
                        friend so forcibly. Be charitable, friend, Alex. Dont "kick against the
                        pricks," for you cannot alter the nature of the case. The Central company
                        are doing the best they can, and it does not become our venerable
                        contemporary to complain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Charlottesville Jeffersonian complained that people stop in Staunton
                    and eat dinner or spend the night when they ride the Central Railroad instead of
                    going to Charlottesville. The Vindicator chides them for complaining about
                    Nature giving more to Staunton than to Charlottesville.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.3c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>William L. Yancey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of Yancey and his history in politics.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Copt-Teste, J. D. Imboden, Clerk. per Charles S. Arnall, D. C.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickie</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Court ordered the Committee to investigate the Poor House and
                    report back to the court. Members include Guy, Harman, Newton, Bickie, Hailman,
                    McCue, White, Wilson and Anderson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Several political articles on the Douglas campaign in other states in columns
                6 and 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.03.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reedman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. William B. Reedman died near Spring Hill on July 19 at age 24.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Surry County Democratic Meeting in column 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.03.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available></pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
