<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.03.30">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-03-30">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Some cropping problems. See page tags. Change of ownership announced in this
            issue. Now owned by Samuel M. Yost.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.01">
            <pageNote>Page is cropped badly--missing columns 6-7. Print is also darker, more smudged
                than usual.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="01a" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.01a">
            <pageNote>Fragment: columns 6 and 7. Left edge of 6 is cut off.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Change of Proprietorship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Change of Proprietorship</p>
                    <p>It will been seen by the Salutatory of Mr. Samuel M. Yost, that the
                        VINDICATOR has changed hands, and from and after this issue will be under
                        the sole conduct of Mr. Yost.</p>
                    <p>The accounts for the paper for subscription to the 1st of January, 1860, and
                        for advertising and job work to the 1st of April, 1860, will be retained by
                        us.</p>
                    <p>It is proper for us to state to the Democracy of Augusta, whose organ has
                        been under our control for the past two years and a half, that the
                        VINDICATOR was never in so flourishing a condition as at present--the
                        subscription list never so large, and the advertising columns never so full.</p>
                    <p>We also take this opportunity to return our sincere thanks to our patrons in
                        and out of the county for the liberal and generous patronage extended to us
                        during our editorial career as Editors of the VINDICATOR.</p>
                    <p>MICHIE &amp; CO</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by the above announcement that the undersigned, from and
                        after the 1st proximo, becomes the sole editor and proprietor of the
                        VINDICATOR newspaper.</p>
                    <p>In resuming the relations to the readers of the VINDICATOR which he
                        reluctantly severed nearly four years ago, it would be sheer affectation
                        were the writer to confess to a feeling of timidity, or aver an apprehension
                        of his qualifications to meet the demands of the patrons of the paper. An
                        intimate connection with the press for many years would necessarily, if
                        merely obeying the law of mechanics, acquaint him with the routine of
                        editorial life, and more or less, inspire him at least, with a small degree
                        of confidence in himself, without being amenable to the charge of vanity or
                        egotism. Hence, the undersigned hopes, and expects, to publish a paper
                        worthy of the patronage of a generous people, with whom in years gone by,
                        both in the bright days of success and the gloom of defeat, he has shared
                        the fortunes of the Democratic party. An absence from the State of a few
                        years has neither abated his zeal for the perfection of the organization of
                        the party, nor shaken his convictions as to the healthiness and nationality
                        of its principles. On the contrary, a change of latitudes has only served as
                        a tangible demonstration of the great conservative and catholic creed of the
                        Democracy and wedded him to the belief that with its success is intimately
                        linked the prosperity and perpetuity of our system of government.</p>
                    <p>Entertaining, therefore, an honest and conscientious belief that the
                        Democratic party is the only national organization--whose principles are the
                        same East and West, North and South--and that the elements which constitute
                        the Opposition are dangerous, heterogeneous and impracticable of good, the
                        writer will address himself with zeal and energy to the advancement of the
                        interests of the one and the defeat of the other. Yet in the discussion of
                        the political topics of the day, a studied purpose shall prevail to avoid
                        unjust criminations, and to shrink from trespassing upon limits forbidden by
                        honorable and legitimate rules of political argumentation. Men and measures
                        will be discussed and criticized freely, as it has been the writer's wont
                        heretofore, but he trusts with a delicate regard to what is due private and
                        personal character.</p>
                    <p>With factions and cliques, if any there be, the VINDICATOR will have no
                        connection. One paramount idea will govern the editor in his political
                        efforts-the publication of a paper which can be looked to by the Democracy
                        of Augusta and of the State as a just and fair and fearless exponent and
                        advocate of the <emph rend="italic">principles</emph> of the party--seeking
                        with faithful ardor to uphold its great interests, to cement its
                        organization and secure its success. That the party has been rent and torn
                        by the indiscreet and suicidal course of the friends of particular
                        individuals is a question beyond disputation. The undersigned will be no
                        man's man, but with a free and untrammeled pen, he expects to oppose and
                        repudiate as faithless to the traditional policy of the party any man or set
                        of men who, to promote selfish ends, may be willing to sacrifice the
                        interests of the organization. As its mission is too grand, and its
                        fundamental principles too comprehensive, for it to depend upon the support
                        of any particular individual to give it character and stability, so is it
                        beneath the dignity of the Democratic party to bend to the persecution or
                        promotion of any particular man. With these views, the editor cannot other
                        than deplore and deprecate the unwise and foolish contest which is now being
                        bitterly waged in this State between the friends of two distinguished
                        members of the party. There can no good grow out of it, but possibly great
                        harm; and to the work of healing this imaginary breach it seems to the
                        undersigned to be the paramount duty of every true Democrat. Let not
                        Virginia mar the bright page of her political history by presenting herself
                        at the National Convention divided and distracted; but rather let the
                        approaching occasion be signalized by another exhibition of that unselfish
                        patriotism which has ever marked its action, and again demonstrate her
                        willingness and ability, if need be, not only to <emph rend="italic"
                        >give</emph> Presidents, but also to <emph rend="italic">make</emph> them.</p>
                    <p>In the general character, the editor hopes to make the VINDICATOR an
                        acceptable <emph rend="italic">newspaper</emph>--devoting its columns to the
                        advocacy of every measure or suggestion which can in any way promote the
                        interests of the community.</p>
                    <p>With this outline, the undersigned announces that after this issue he will
                        assume all the duties and responsibilities of editor and proprietor of the
                        VINDICATOR. By his works he hopes to be judged, and craves that
                        encouragement which it may be the pleasure of an intelligent and refined
                        constituency to extend.</p>
                    <p>S. M. YOST.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator has changed hands. It is now owned and edited by Samuel M.
                    Yost, who had been affiliated with the paper 4 years ago.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvmar60.html#3.30a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Free Lectures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Schedule of Hunter's lectures over the weekend. Topics include "The most
                    wonderful thing ever known" and "The importance of the mental and moral training
                    of the young as touching the Destiny of America."</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Southern Retaliation</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Again, I contend that the same moral law by which we hold our negroes as
                        slaves, justifies us in making slaves of all negroes upon whom we can lay
                        our hands, wherever they may be found."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proposes that all free blacks be sold into slavery. Northerners will then
                    want to sell all Northern free blacks back to the South. This way the South
                    won't need to reopen the African trade.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Surrender of a Fugitive Slave</head>
                <origin>Philadelphia</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fugitive slave has been captured and returned by Judge
                Cadwallader.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Judge Thompson</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Response to article in Spectator about Thompson. The Vindicator likes
                him.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>North River</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Samuels</ln>
                        <fn>Shadrock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nominates Samuels for Magistrate.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Dark and smudgey, lots of scratches. State Legislature, Congressional
            reports</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>Hetty</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Patterson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Brown and Miss Coalter were married at the residence of David Polmer.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stombock</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddle</ln>
                        <fn>Ruth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemake</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 22.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>X.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Henry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Frances E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 22. Mr. Orebaugh is from Green county.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Spec. please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawn</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawn</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on March 15.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Bickle died on March 28.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Spectator please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Alonzo Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Sylvester</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alonzo Hoffman died on March 20 at age 4 months. Obituary includes a short
                    poem.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cannon</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>H. Jewett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Meeting of Mossy Creek Academy to commemorate the death of H. Jewett Smith
                    of Harrisonburg.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Candidates announcements in column 2. Cropped badly--missing columns 5-7.
                Markets in column 3.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03a" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.03a">
            <pageNote>Columns 6 and 7 from p. 03. Missing column 5, and edge of 6 is cut
            off.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.03.30.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
