<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.07.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-20">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>20</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.20.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Coalition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses Buchanan's firing of government workers who support Douglas.
                    Claims Buchanan is in coalition with W. L. Yancey to keep Douglas out of office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>From the Enquirer. Address of Messrs. Rives and Harman.</head>
                <origin>Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Timothy Rives, John A. Harman, Richmond, Va., July 11, 1860.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia Democratic State Central Committee supports Douglas and
                    Johnson as the Democratic ticket, but proposes a meeting to attempt to reconcile
                    the two parts of the party.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>What the Dred Scot Case Decided</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reviews the implications of the Dred Scot case. Hon. Beverdy Johnson said
                    that the case decided that Congress does not have the "power to prohibit slavery
                    in a Territory."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The "Virginia Pacificator", a gun made in North River Gap, was demonstrated
                    by Sibert and McCue.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Annual Exhibition at Loch-Willow Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Conservator</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>H.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Loch-Willow Academy's exhibition was enjoyed by all. Mr. Cook of Augusta
                    spoke on "Cultivated Intellect" and Rev. Baker delivered the "Anniversary
                    Address."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.20.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War Proclaimed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This movement we consider a virtual throwing down of the glove to the
                    friends of Douglas and Johnson--a formal declaration of war--and as such, we
                    accept the challenge."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>War Proclaimed</p>
                    <p>It will be seen by the notice in another column, that the friends of
                        Breckinridge and Lane have called a meeting for Monday next, to appoint
                        delegates to the Charlottesville Convention, and that it is expected Hons.
                        S.F. Leake and Wm. Smith will address the people on that occasion. This
                        movement we consider a virtual throwing down of the glove to the friends of
                        Douglas and JOHNSON--a formal declaration of war--and as such, we accept the
                        challenge. Anxious for an adjustment, upon fair and honorable terms, of the
                        differences which exist in the Democratic party, the friends of Judge
                        Douglas in this District have manifested a generous disposition of
                        conciliation, and striven in an unselfish spirit to bring together the riven
                        parts of our organization. In this they have been animated by no sensation
                        of timidity or want of faith either in the numerical strength of their
                        friends, or the sound, conservative and catholic sentiments of their
                        platform or position of their candidate. We have been for peace and harmony.
                        According to others the same honesty of purpose that we claim for ourselves,
                        we have carefully approached and examined the points of difference, without
                        discovering any insuperable barrier to fraternization for the accomplishment
                        of a common end--the defeat of the Black Republicans. In this spirit, we
                        presented for the consideration of the Democratcy of the State a fair and
                        just basis of agreement, which ass been totally disrespected by the friends
                        of Mr. Breckinridge. Indeed, instead of exhibiting a willingness to
                        harmonize and meet upon terms of equality, they have rather manifested a
                        spirit of supercilious superiority, and, through some of their presses,
                        affected to hold as "aliens to the Commonwealth of Israel"--as fungi to be
                        lopped off from the party organization-- the friends of Judge Douglas. With
                        an air of impudence, better suited to the council-chamber of an
                        irresponsible despot, than the threatre upon which play both personal and
                        political equals, they threaten to <emph rend="italic">read us out of the
                            party!</emph> if we do not subordinate our convictions of right, based
                        upon a principle which lies at the foundation of our system of government,
                        and which is dear to every American citizens who is not blinded by
                        prejudice, or whose common sense has not been lost in the mazes of
                        metaphysical absurdities, to their speculative ideas of political economy
                        and governmental polity.</p>
                    <p>To such demands and threats, coming from a bastard organization, conceived
                        and consummated in a spirit of disunion and disorganization, every element
                        of manhood in our nature rebels. A degree of presumption is manifested by
                        these Seceders, the proper classification of which would be the vagaries of
                        the demented, were it not that it comes from men ordinarily esteemed sane,
                        but the result of whose "concerted action," if successful, must destroy the
                        Union and win for them the renown of infamy which history has associated
                        with the name of Erostratus.</p>
                    <p>In their view of dissension, disorganization and disunion, is the meeting
                        called here for next Monday. Conscious of their own weakness--of the
                        abhorrence of the great mass of the Democratic voters of this county to the
                        revolutionary and disunion schemes of Yancey and his followers--they have
                        invited two distinguished speakers from a distance to be present to cajole
                        and deceive the pole into the belief that the interest of Virginia and the
                        South demand the support of the nominees of the Seceders' Convention.</p>
                    <p>We shall not believe until we see it, that William Smith and Shelton F. Leake
                        will so far forget the relations they bear to the Democratic party of
                        Virginia, and especially this Tenth Legion District, as to interfere in our
                        county meetings, and thus assist in widening the breach that already exists
                        in our organization. The writer of this and those with whom he acts in this
                        important emergency, have been the true, tried and faithful friends of these
                        gentlemen. When Mr. Smith was distrusted and assailed by his own party in
                        every section of the State, we stood firmly by him, defending and upholding
                        him, and jeoparding [sic] our own interests by facing an incensed Democracy
                        in his behalf. We wrote for him, spoke for him, and fought for him, in a
                        time when he needed friends--when he was the object of assault from every
                        quarter, and when the popular current was so fearfully against him that he
                        had not at one time a dozen friends in this county. Still, in this hour of
                        difficulty and gloom, we the more boldly proclaimed our confidence in his
                        devotion to the Democracy, and the more fiercely denounced his enemies,
                        until, at last, we had the proud satisfaction of witnessing his complete
                        triumph, and the vindication of the justice and wisdom of our course. We can
                        scarcely, therefore, believe that Mr. Smith will be so oblivious of the
                        past, so disregardful of the present, and indifferent to the future, as to
                        wilfully throw himself across the path, in hostile attitude, of those who
                        have been so true to him, when it required nerve and will to be a friend.</p>
                    <p>We may with equal point and propriety ask Mr. Leake whether he can reconcile
                        it to his sense of fairness and justice and to the obligations of past
                        associations to permit himself to be used to cleave asunder and separate
                        forever the Democratic party of Augusta? The very men against whom Mr. Leake
                        is solicited (and to which solicitation we learn he has yielded) to
                        war--whose honest convictions he is invited to impugn--whose Democracy is to
                        be assailed and whose policy denounced--are the men who proved themselves
                        friend to him who sticketh closer than a brother, and never forsook him,
                        until overpowered by numbers, and yielded then only in obedience to a loyal
                        adherence to the usages of the Democratic party. We cannot see the necessity
                        for either of these gentlemen interfering in the party affairs of this
                        county. But on the contrary, we shall deem it an indelicate intrusion upon
                        contested ground, and cause sufficient to wipe out all past recollections of
                        friendship, and to commence anew as implacable enemies. If they are so far
                        forgetful of what is due to the Democracy, and to those who have fought
                        bravely for the cause of the party, as to officiously obtrude themselves
                        upon a county meeting for the purpose of distraction and strife, and that,
                        too, by virtue of an invitation from those who have no authority to speak
                        for the <emph rend="italic">Democratic party of Augusta</emph>, we shall
                        feel absolved from all restraint imposed by party or personal associations,
                        and treat them as political intermeddlers and enemies. Our voice is for
                        peace, but if the opponents of the regular organization of the Democratic
                        party and its Presidential nominees will have war, we have no alternative
                        but to throw aside the scabbard, and enter the field in defiance of the
                        right, and the honor and integrity of the Democratic party.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Friends of Breckinridge have called a meeting to appoint delegates to
                    the Charlottesville Convention. This angers the Vindicator's editor and other
                    Douglas supporters. Article includes an appeal for unity among the Democrats of
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.20a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the National Democracy of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John A. Harman. National Committeeman for Virginia.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of meeting for all supporters of Douglas in Staunton, "for the
                    purpose of framing an electoral ticket." Meeting called by John A. Harman,
                    National Committeeman for Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Public Speaking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Moffett will speak to Augusta Democrats on Monday, August 16.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Eclipse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A partial solar eclipse took place around 8:30 on Wednesday.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>False Statements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attacks the papers that support Breckinridge for their "sensation
                    announcements" that often turn out to be false rumors.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Contest-- State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial expresses support for Douglas because he is the only candidate
                    who can stop Lincoln from being elected. It includes a prediction of the states
                    Douglas will win. The editor also questions how effective the Convention will be
                    in healing the differences between the Breckinridge and Douglas factions.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Disgruntled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Responds to attacks from the Examiner and Sentinel, two Breckinridge
                    papers.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>Lawrence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hale, an "impudent itinerant lecturer on Electro-Biology," was kicked out
                    of Selma, Alabama when it was discovered that he had been posing as a bachelor
                    although he was actually married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Do not our City Fathers intend to do something for Hill's Pump? It is a
                    shame to neglect this great public convenience."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Summary of Virginia Democratic Executive Committee meeting in column 1.
                Several small articles about the upcoming Staunton Convention in columns 1 and 3.
                Page is difficult to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.20.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. Beverdy Johnson, of Maryland.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter written to decline an invitation to speak at a Douglas rally in
                    Philadelphia. In it Johnson declares his support for the Douglas ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kile</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Kile was arrested for having counterfeit money.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Public Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. W. King, Pres. J. D. Hanger, Sec'y.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Public picnic at Brown's Springs. All are invited.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. Spectator please copy!</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>John David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Eliza Grove, wife of John Grove, and her 3 week old son, John David, died
                    in Staunton. She died on June 28 at age 32. Her son died shortly thereafter at
                    age 3 weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>B. Spectator please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Peachy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Matheny, daughter of the late Peachy Matheny of Staunton, died on May
                    31 at age 23. She was a member of the M.E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Entire page is hard to read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.20.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
