<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.11.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-11-30">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.11.30.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Outlawry in Kansas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about Montgomery, the "abolition bandit."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article about a young woman who was in a carriage driven by "a drunken
                    negro" that was caught in the middle of a river. The woman was able to save the
                    black man and swim to shore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator, The Hon. S. A. Douglas.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports Douglas, who is working to keep the Union together.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Interesting Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>James S. Brisbin, Please Answer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to Gov. Letcher of Virginia from James Brisbin of Pennsylvania and
                    the governor's response. The letter concerns the abolition of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Tale of a woman who eloped in column 4. Connecticut Blue Laws listed in
                columns 3&amp;4. Moral tales in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.11.30.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Staunton banks have suspended specie payments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The lay members of the M. E. Church--Baltimore Conference will meet in
                    Baltimore to discuss the slavery issue on December 5.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Howe Peyton went South to New Orleans and Texas on November 27.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reiley</ln>
                        <fn>J. McK.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The new M. E. church will be finished soon, and the dedicatory speech will
                    be given by Rev. Reiley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Wheeler of the Methodist Church declared that the separation of the
                    Baltimore Conference was inevitable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"M. E. C."</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes a letter from "M. E. C." that objects to the separation of the
                    Baltimore Conference from the General Convention of the M. E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Virginia and South Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Virginia and South Carolina</p>
                    <p>The spirit of cringing subserviency to the behests of the Cotton States
                        manifested by a few of the Democratic press, is totally at variance with the
                        sentiments of the people of Virginia. We were much surprised, and no little
                        fretted at a suggestion in the Alexandria Sentinel a few days ago, to the
                        effect that the State should go to South Carolina, "apologise" for not
                        yielding to her proposition for a Southern Convention last Winter, and
                        implead her to counsel with us now.---The idea of Virginia apologising to
                        South Carolina or any other State for doing that which she believed to be
                        right, is a proposition so ridiculous in itself and so suggestive of a
                        spirit of conscious inferiority, that we can hardly think our able
                        contemporary meant that which his language conveys. We are one of those who
                        believe Virginia did what was precisely right in refusing a conference with
                        the Southern States on that particular occasion, and under those peculiar
                        circumstances. John Brown had invaded Virginia, violated her laws and
                        insulted her sovereignty. Virginia believed she could vindicate her violated
                        laws, and defend her honor by her own inherent agencies. While she treated
                        the commissioner South Carolina was pleased to send with the courtesy and
                        dignity due his mission, she respectfully declined the aid of her sister
                        States in that emergency, believing that she knew her rights and knowing
                        dared maintain them. This she did most triumphantly in bringing the chief
                        offender and his confederates to a speedy trial and a just and significant
                        punishment. John Brown and his party were hung, the violated law was
                        satisfied, and the honor of the State vindicated. Virginia then saw, as she
                        now sees, a remedy within the Union for the defense of her constitutional
                        rights and the maintenance of her sovereign character unimpaired. Whilst the
                        tender of South Carolina on that occasion was doubtless designed in the
                        spirit of sisterly affection, still we cannot dismiss from our mind that it
                        had the appearance of an insult, or of a covert attempt to take advantage of
                        the excited state of public sentiment to carry out her purposes of
                        dissolution. Virginia acted with that dignity, character and
                        self-reliance--that proud sense of self-reliance, which rises above the
                        craven sensation of danger when honor and right are at stake--which have
                        ever distinguished her. She would have been untrue to herself--false to her
                        sons, her honor and her history, had she listened to any offers of aid in
                        that hour of her trial. It seems to us, therefore, that any allusions
                        adverse to and condemnatory of the action of the State on that occasion are
                        unjust, and made without due reflection. It is enough for such outlawed and
                        revolutionary sheets as the Charleston Mercury to pour their streams of
                        foul-mouthed abuse on her, without the press within her own limits taunting
                        her with the insulting suggestion of <emph rend="italic">apologising</emph>
                        to South Carolina! Shame on the thought.</p>
                    <p>South Carolina and her confederates of the Cotton States in their scheme of
                        precipitating a revolution, meet with but little sympathy in Virginia. In
                        her character as a Sovereign State, nothing, we believe, is farther from her
                        purpose than to affiliate and coalesce with them in their reckless and
                        criminal purpose to break up, without sufficient cause, this, the greatest
                        and best government the world has ever seen.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial supports Virginia's refusal to attend South Carolina's proposed
                    Southern Conference.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvnov60.html#11.30a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meeting on Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Editorial on the Union meeting and the resolutions adopted there. The
                    editor would have used stronger language, but he agrees with the general
                    principals expressed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Disunion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . . the secession of the Cotton States is a fixed fact . . . . Nothing
                    can now keep them in the Union . . . . They will become conquered provinces
                    before 10 years."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator believes that the Cotton States will secede, not because of
                    any perceived oppression, but because they have a "wilful, deliberate and
                    criminal purpose to dissolve the Union, establish a Southern Confederacy, and
                    then re-open the African Slave Trade." The Middle States should remain aloof
                    from the seceders schemes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Virginia Gun Factory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Imboden, Harman and McCue are establishing a factory to make the repeating
                    gun just invented by Lorenzo Sibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Vote of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Final election returns for Virginia. Nine Bell and six Breckinridge
                    electors were elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>M. E. C.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter to the editor objecting to the secession of the Baltimore Conference
                    of M. E. Church from the General Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Short joke about fugitive slave law in column 2. South Carolina Legislature
                news in column 6. Short piece on troops in Virginia in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.11.30.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Augusta County Union Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Transcript of Union Meeting</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The free negroes of the Cotton States are rapidly leaving for the North,
                    fearful that the Legislatures may pass a law compelling them to leave or choose
                    masters."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. Ward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>Emily S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on November 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Christena Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Christena Miller died in Sangersville on October 30 at age 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John Burner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Miller died in Sangersville of Diptheria on November 5 at age 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.11.30.04">
            <pageNote>Poetry and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
