<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- !DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd' -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.04.27">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Anne Sarah Rubin</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-27">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.27.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gov. Wise and the Presidency</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Gov. Wise in which he discusses the possibility of his
                    nomination by the Charleston Convention.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Nothing of much interest" occurred at the April term of the County Court.
                    Various licences were granted to taverns and an election district was
                    established at Parnassus.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Committed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMullin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caster</ln>
                        <fn>Tom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mcmullin (white) and Caster (free black) were arraigned for stealing bacon
                    from Davis.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Market House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Will not our City Fathers look to the Market House?  Until it is paved it cannot be comfortable? 
                    Until it is locked and the negroes are put out, it will be dirty! </p>
                    <p>This is a subject of great 
                    importance, and we invite attention to it.  Our present efficient Chief of Police, we are 
                    confident, will be active and energetic in carrying out any resolution the Council may adopt.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for the city government to take action to improve the Staunton Market
                    House.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.27b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Charleston, S. C. Ap. '60</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The negro population is far inferior to the same class in Virginia. One of
                    our best negroes is worth a half-dozen of the dwarfish, disfigured, filthy
                    creatures which swarm the streets of Charleston. Their dialect is different, and
                    almost unintelligible, resembling more the chattering of a monkey or a parrot
                    than the conversation of a human being. Indeed, it is a question whether some of
                    their 'abe shine' (I beg Gov. Wise's pardon) are not a modification of the ape,
                    and divested of that element of our Creator which partakes of the divine."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Editorial Correspondence.</p>
                    <p>CHARLESTON, S. C., Ap. 21, '60.</p>
                    <p>We reached this beautiful city yesterday morning, after forty-eight hours
                        travel from Staunton. The cool, refreshing breezes which invigorate and
                        enliven the physical man in the Valley of Virginia, are sadly missed here.
                        Those of us who had never experienced the heat of so Southern a latitude,
                        were unprepared with wardrobe for the change of temperature, and
                        consequently, are gradually loosing, by profuse perspiration, our surplus
                        flesh. The thermometer stands to-day about 93 degrees.</p>
                    <p>The country through which we passed, both in North and South Carolina, before
                        we reached Charleston, is very uninviting, and is only endurable in the fact
                        that its appearance is novel. The large turpentine orchards, so to speak,
                        are sights with which most of us were unacquainted, and of course were
                        viewed as of the new things that are always presented in traversing strange
                        countries. The soil is very barren and, to all appearances, totally
                        incapable of sustaining a population, save only by means of the "pitch, tar
                        and turpentine" manufactories.</p>
                    <p>The foliage of the trees is beautiful. Vegetation is much farther advanced
                        than I had anticipated, and awakens a lively remembrance of the months of
                        June and July in Virginia. The graceful and symmetrical holywood, luxuriant
                        in its verdant apparel, and festooned by the growth of moss, hanging in
                        negligent grace from every bough and twig, impersonating, figuratively to
                        speak, a lovely maiden <emph rend="italic">en dishabille</emph>--are very
                        attractive, and from which we could scarcely turn our eyes, to glance at
                        other pleasant sights, gradually developing as we neared the city.</p>
                    <p>Charleston is a handsome, compactly built city, containing between 30 and
                        40,000 inhabitants. From appearances, its business is brisk and large. Some
                        of the most beautiful store-rooms I have ever seen are to be found here. The
                        streets are narrow, a defect traceable to the French taste of those who must
                        have laid out the city--a defect similar to the one which so disfigures and
                        embarrasses the city of St. Louis. There is a strong element of the French
                        and Spanish races discernible in the population.</p>
                    <p>The negro population is far inferior to the same class in Virginia. One of
                        our best negroes is worth a half-dozen of the dwarfish, disfigured, filthy
                        creatures which swarm the streets of Charleston. Their dialect is different,
                        and almost unintelligible, resembling more the chattering of a monkey or a
                        parrot than the enunciation of a human being. Indeed, it is a question
                        whether some of these "ebo-shins" (I beg Gov. Wise's pardon) are not a
                        modification of the ape, and divested of that element of our Creator which
                        partakes of the divine.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Memminger, the gentleman recently sent to Virginia from this State, to
                        discuss . . . [text missing] . . . South Carolina in iniatory steps to
                        secure a Conference of the Southern States, has been very attentive to our
                        delegation. Yesterday he took us to the Orphan's Asylum, a noble
                        institution, of which the State might well be proud. There are now there 310
                        orphan children, being educated at the expense of the State, happy and well
                        cared for. When asked how the system worked, he remarked, with evident pride
                        and a glow of genuine gratitude, "Admirably. I am one of its creatures."
                        McDuffie, also, was in a great measure educated under the auspices of this
                        institution.</p>
                    <p>The delegations from the different States are rapidly coming in, and the city
                        is assuming a thronged and jammed up appearance. There can be no legitimate
                        speculations made as to the result of the Convention. Douglas' friends are
                        very sanguine, as are Hunter's. I am fully convinced that it will be one of
                        these two aspirants who will receive the nomination. Douglas now has the
                        inside track. The North and Northwest are very candid in stating that their
                        political existence depends upon his nomination.</p>
                    <p>Green peas, new potatoes, onions, lettuce, radishes, and in fact every
                        description of vegetables are in abundance.</p>
                    <p>Not one-third of the visitors expected here arrived, being kept away by the
                        swindling prices imposed by the Yankee landlords of this city.</p>
                    <p>S. M. Y.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report from Mr. Yost, the editor of the Vindicator and a delegate to the
                    Charleston Convention. He describes the scenery around Charleston, the
                    architecture of the city, and the black population, among other topics.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvapr60.html#4.27a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Coalter announced his candidacy for Commissioner of Revenue in the 1st
                    district. He states that he needs the job because he lost an arm in an accident
                    and has to support his family.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brace</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting in Waynesboro chose four candidates for magistrate (Colner,
                    Brace, Ellis, Kennerly).</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.27.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>ROCKBRIDGE; April 20th, 1860.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter about the Circuit Court elections that supports Thompson.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Judge Thompson and His Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A COUNTRYMAN</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Response to letters from "Z" and "A Farmer."</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Richmond papers please copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>D. Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married at Warm Springs on April 24.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Baily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Hanger of Granville, Missouri married Miss Mary E. Dunlap of Augusta
                    County, daughter of Baily Dunlap, on April 17.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsberger</ln>
                        <fn>Anne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harnsberger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Anne G. Harnsberger, widow of Col. Samuel Harnsberger, died on April
                    13 at age 64.</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>Eagon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. Greiner died of a sore throat at age 14 in Waynesboro at the home
                    of her uncle, George W. Greiner. She was the daughter of Eagon Greiner, formerly
                    of Staunton.</summary>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Markets in column 4</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.04.27.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
