<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.07.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-13">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Difference</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discussion of the conventions at Charleston and Baltimore. At the
                    Charleston, the disunionists insisted that the nominee could only win when he
                    received a vote equal to two-thirds of the Electoral College. Once they left
                    Charleston, they changed the rule in their "Bolters" conference. There, they
                    stated that the nominee had to receive two-thirds of the vote of the states
                    present and voting at the conference. The Enquirer criticizes them for this
                    flip-flop.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Stephen A. Douglas, of Illinois</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A mini-biography of Stephen Douglas's life.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A speech by Douglas in Philadelphia in column 4.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>State Convention of the National Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>State Convention.</p>
                    <p>The State Executive Committee met in Richmond on the evening of the 10th and
                        by a vote of <emph rend="italic">five</emph> to <emph rend="italic"
                        >four</emph>, determined to call a Convention to meet in Charlottesville on
                        the 16th of August. We look upon this step as the most unwise and suicidal,
                        and calculated to still widen the breach that already exists in the
                        Democratic party. The friends of Judge Douglas and the regular Democracy,
                        could not of course, think of going into a Convention, the object of whose
                        assembling is to commit them to the support of candidates who represent a
                        fragmentary and disorganizing portion of the Democratic party of Virginia.
                        In addition to this, it is perfectly apparent to the most partially informed
                        that a State Convention composed of the friends of the two Democratic
                        candidates for the Presidency, with passions inflamed as they are and will
                        continue to be, could result in no other way but strife, contention and
                        disruption. We never will go into a Convention with men in whose political
                        integrity we have no confidence.--The leaders of this movement we believe to
                        be composed in part of such men. We desire to unite on one electoral ticket,
                        but it must be done upon fair, equal and honorable terms. Otherwise, the
                        seceders must take the responsibility of defeating the Democratic party of
                        Virginia.</p>
                    <p>We dislike very much to differ with many of our personal and political
                        friends-- men who are too proud to resort to the subtle tricks of the
                        political tradesman--who scorn to vacillate for a temporary advantage, and
                        who esteem their convictions of right above place and preferment. Such we
                        found the friends of Gov. Wise to be both at Charleston and Baltimore, and
                        we would enter this contest with more satisfaction to ourself were we
                        fighting side by side with these men, to whom we could look with confidence
                        to stand firm in the right. But we will, we fear, have to be separated, for
                        the friends of Douglas and Johnson, and the National Democracy, will never,
                        never, submit to be dragooned and bucked and gagged by the tricksters and
                        wire-pullers who have of late years controlled the State Conventions of
                        Virginia.</p>
                    <p>Had the Executive Committee fallen upon a plan of reconciliation such as we
                        suggested last week, we would cheerfully have agreed to it. But the majority
                        ignored all propositions tending to settle the difficulties in the party,
                        and nothing is left for us now to do, but to proceed at once to organize the
                        National Democracy, and marching forth in the right, to fight the battle
                        through, and either fall or triumph in defense of the honor and integrity of
                        the National Democratic party, and their candidates, DOUGLAS and
                    JOHNSON.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Virginia members of the National Democratic Party will meet in Staunton
                    on August 16 to organize and "take such steps as will secure the electoral vote
                    of Virginia for DOUGLAS and JOHNSON."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj. General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. General Harper appointed Covell to his staff as a Major.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Association gave a demonstration.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Douglas and Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article comparing the two candidates on the slavery issue. Clearly
                    pro-Douglas.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Non-Intervention the True Doctrine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports Douglas and his policy of non-intervention in the area of slavery.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Horse Stealing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Thornton</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two of John Churchman's horses were stolen by Elijah Hunter. The thief was
                    caught in Lynchburg and was being brought back to Staunton when he escaped. He
                    was caught again by R. Bickle and put in the Augusta jail.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Ladies' Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announcement of a Fair at the Town Hall, done by the women of the M. E.
                    Church.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corely</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rippetoe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Rippetoe of Augusta died after collapsing to the ground before fishing.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"We look upon this step as most unwise and suicidal, and calculated to still
                        widen the breach that already formed in the Democratic party."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Breckinridge supporters have called a convention to meet in
                    Charlottesville.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.13a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Rule and Ruin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Buchanan is firing all government workers who support Douglas for
                    President. The editor attacks this purge of government.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The M. E. Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The church is almost completed.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Several small articles about Douglas and rallies for him around the country.
                Letter from New York city mayor supporting Douglas in column 5. "Political history"
                of Edward Everett, Bell's VP candidate in column 6. Speech on "Irrepressible
                Conflict" in column 7. Hard to read at the bottom of the page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.13.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter attacks the Black Republicans and calls for unity among the South.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator. Church Meeting.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Church Meeting.</p>
                    <p>At a Quarterly Meeting Conference held at Calvary Chapel, July 7th, 1860, for
                        Augusta Circuit, Rev. B. H. Smith was called to the Chair, and Rev. W. K.
                        Boyle appointed Secretary. The object of the meeting being explained, John
                        W. Reeder, D. Hinkle, Geo. Hall and H. W. Burkholder, were appointed a
                        committee to prepare resolutions, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>The following preamble and resolutions were unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p>Whereas, the last General Conference of M. E. Church, held in Buffalo, N. Y.,
                        introduced a new chapter into the Discipline upon the subject of slavery,
                        which is contrary to the civil laws of our country, and to the wishes of our
                        people in the border Conferences; and, whereas, other charges have signified
                        their unwillingness to submit to it, and have expressed a desire to hold a
                        Convention and take steps to separate from the Northern portion of the
                        Church: Therefore</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we, the official members of Augusta Circuit, hereby enter our
                        solemn protest against, and repudiate the sentiments in the new chapter,
                        whether it be regarded as law or advice.</p>
                    <p>Rosolved, That we believe the time has come for us to separate from a church
                        which has now become thoroughly abolitionized.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That we approve of holding a Convention previous to the next annual
                        conference.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That this meeting elect delegates to attend a District Convention
                        to be held in Harrisonburg on the first Thursday in August.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That a copy of these proceedings be sent to our county papers with
                        a request to publish.</p>
                    <p>(Signed,)</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ministers.</cell>
                            <cell>B. H. Smith, Minister</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Wm. K. Boyle.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Laymen.</cell>
                            <cell>John W. Reeder,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>David Hinkle,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>George Hall,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>R. Trevey,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>J. B. Hamner,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>S. Fitch,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>H. W. Burkholder,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>J. Lockridge.</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Signed by all below</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>B.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hinkle</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trevey</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammer</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Augusta Circuit of M. E. Church decides to support a split from the
                    Northern part of the church over the slavery issue. The conference was led by
                    Revs. Smith and Doyle.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvjuly60.html#7.13b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eddins</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Eddins, age 63, died at the home of her brother-in-law, James Craig.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morehead</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Hopson, age 79, died at the home of his son-in-law, Samuel Morehead.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Article about a minister who was executed in N. J. for murdering his wife in
                column 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.07.13.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
