<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.08.10">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-08-10">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To the Editors of Enquirer: Gentlemen:</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . . we would have been content to leave the decision of the question, as
                    to whether those who participated in the deliberations of the National
                    Democracy, or those who seceded therefrom, were right, to the tribunal of public
                    intelligence undisturbed by appeals or statements from either side of the
                    controversy. The seceders, however, having . . . issued an address on their own
                    behalf to the Democracy of Virginia, we are induced to submit the following
                    facts as incontestibly sustaining the actions of the National Democratic
                    Convention upon the authority of the Democratic president, congressional
                    compromise, conservative patriotism, and enlightened public policy."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffett</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A brief letter to the Enquirer's editors from S. M. Yost and S. H. Moffett
                    is followed by an editorial "To the Democracy of the Eleventh Electoral
                    District" which supports Douglas as the true Democratic nominee.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>S. M. Yost, S. H. Moffett</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuation of the article on page 1.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. S. Arnall, Sec'y. Spectator copy.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>C.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>West Augusta Guards thank Capt. Koiner and his company and the ladies of
                    Fishersville for the "pic-nic" last Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Large Radish</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn>P.O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Polmer's wife grew an 18-inch radish.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Great Freshet--Heavy Loss</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Great Freshet-Heavy Loss.</p>
                    <p>On last Saturday our "City of the Hills" was visited by another of those
                        floods which on occasions heretofore have been the terror of our citizens.
                        Between eleven and two o'clock of the day we had never felt the heat more
                        oppressive. The atmosphere seemed ladened with heat, and the slight air that
                        stirred parched like the breath of a furnace. Any one who has ever traversed
                        the great ocean of land called the "plains," lying west of the Mississippi
                        river and reaching to the Colorado of the West, can form an idea of the
                        intensity of the heat, by comparing it to one of those still days, when not
                        a breath of air is stirring, the sun pouring down his burning rays, and as
                        far as the eye can reach, not a bush, or shrub, or tree to be seen, but one
                        vast expanse of arid, sandy, parched up earth. The sensation we experienced
                        on last Saturday, before the rain began to fall, was something similar to
                        that felt on the plains under such circumstances. About two o'clock a heavy
                        cloud had gathered in the North-east, and the rain commenced falling
                        rapidly, with a slight North-western wind. About half past two, another
                        immense black cloud formed in the Northwest, and moving in a Northerly
                        direction, met the cloud in the Northeast, which had continued to grow in
                        intensity and size. The windows of heaven seemed then to have opened, and
                        the rain descended in torrents, accompanied by a sea of hail-stones. The
                        five of six trenches which pass through the farms of Col. Opie and W. W.
                        Donaghe, Esq., soon began to empty their muddy, turbulent waters into Lewis'
                        Creek immediately above the residence of Mr. Donaghe. The channel of that
                        stream was too small to carry off the immense body of water that rushed into
                        it from its dozen feeders, and from the residence of Mr. Mayse back to the
                        foundry of Garber &amp; Co., the bottom lands and gardens were entirely
                        inundated. The destruction to the gardens between these points was great and
                        almost total. The impediments to the passage of the wateralong the
                        legitimate channel were so great from Mr. Mayse's down to Beverly street,
                        that it founds its way east of the creek by making a course through the
                        gardens of W. Burke, Benj. Crawford, T. Shumate, Geo. Harlan, A. F. Kinney,
                        R. G. Bickle and others. In fact, after the waters had passed Mr. Mayse's,
                        there was a complete inundation extending from Lewis to August Streets.
                        Fences, corn-cribs, hog-pens, chicken-coops, wagons, drays, barrels, boxes,
                        wood-piles, and rubbish of every description, were borne off on the bosom of
                        the maddened element. The damage from Mr. Mayse's back to the Foundry was
                        considerable, embracing gardens and property, the owners of which we are
                        unable to mention. The damage to gardens and fences from Mr. Mayse's down to
                        Beverly street falls principally upon Messrs. Burke, Crawford, Shumate,
                        Harlan, Kinney, Morris and Hickle. The water rushed through the garden of
                        Mr. Crawford and into the basement of his residence with terrible fury,
                        tearing away everything in its course. The volume here divided, one part
                        seeking an outlet in August street, and the other rushing on down through
                        the gardens of Harlan, Shumate, Kinney and Bickle, and coming out into
                        Beverly street through the business and dwelling houses ranging between
                        Union Hall and Crawford &amp; Cochran's store, fronting about one and a
                        half squares.</p>
                    <p>The course of the water down August street is marked by the most distressing
                        evidences of its fury. The side walks on either side were literally plowed
                        up. On the west side of the street, down to Beverly, Messrs. Benj. Crawford,
                        T. Shumate, A. F. Kinney, H. G. Bickle and A. M. Bruce, grocer, are the
                        sufferers, the damage amounting to not less than $2000 or $2500. On the east
                        side the pavement is entirely torn up from Dr. Waddell's to the Grocery of
                        Mr. Hultz. The damage to private residences is not much, mostly falling on
                        Miss Waddell and H. J. Crawford. The loss of Mr. Hultz, grocer, on the
                        corner of Augusta and Beverly, is very heavy, reaching to as much as $1500,
                        which falls hard upon a very deserving gentleman. P.N. Powell, grocer, loses
                        heavily. Woods &amp; Gitkeson, hardware merchants, have sustained severe
                        damage. Blake's shoe store and Elick's saddlery also come in for a
                        considerable share of the loss. On North Beverly street the damage fell upon
                        J. B. Antoni, confectioner, and Mrs. K. M. Kelley, Miss Lucy Snider, and
                        Mrs. Stevenson, milliners, Mr. Morrik, Faust &amp; Co., shoe store, D.
                        A. Kaysar, dry good merchant, Dr. Eichelbarger, druggist, Crawford &amp;
                        Cochran, dry goods merchants, and Mosby, Taylor &amp; Co., dry goods
                        merchants. On the South side, Geo. E. Price, hardware merchants, loses
                        heavily; also P. H. Trout &amp; Co., druggists, and J. B. Evans,
                        tobacconist, slightly. From Beverly down Augusta street to the bridge across
                        Lewis Creek the destruction was great. The corner of the foundation of the
                        store of O. C. Morris was completely swept away, and an immense gorge washed
                        in front of the building on both Beverly and Augusta streets. His loss in
                        groceries, damage to other goods and building, is heavy. The pavement down
                        the west side of August street was torn up, and considerable damage done to
                        the foundations of Baylore's Law Office, Mrs. Carros's residence, the new
                        brick building of R. G. Bickle, and Bledsoe &amp; Co.'s store. The
                        partitions in the basement of Bledsoe's building, and the Southern wall
                        fronting on Irish Alley were swept away, and about $2,000 worth of groceries
                        entirely destroyed. One-half of the South end of the building gave way and
                        fell, exposing the entire inside of the store and residence. Their loss is
                        very heavy and will not be covered by less than $8,000 or $8,500.</p>
                    <p>Irish Alley was completely cleaned of the rubbish which had accumulated there
                        since the last flood. The loss is not heavy, but falls on those poorly able
                        to bear it--The floors of the row of store rooms on the wharf gave way as
                        did a part of the foundations. Jno. O'Hare's loss is considerable in goods
                        and damage to building. A part of the front yard and a wall around the back
                        yard of the jail were washed away. Down New Court-house Street the damage
                        was not very severe. It reached to Michie, Harman &amp; Bell, and
                        Sheffey &amp; Bumgardner's law offices, and Rankin's building. The
                        basement of Mrs. Brandeburg's residence was inundated. On the west side of
                        August street from Adam Bickle's corner to the corner of the Court-house
                        yard, on New C. H. Street, no damage was done to private property, save to
                        W. Tate and W. Carroll. The front wall of the foundation was swept away and
                        a deep gorge washed immediately in front of Mr. Carrol's house. The sidewalk
                        was torn up and considerable damage done to the Corporation interests around
                        the Court-house inclosure. On New Street the damage to individuals is
                        comparatively small. W. Miller Boot and Shoe Store, loses slightly; C. T.
                        Cochran, tobacconist, lightly; Dr. Young, druggist, lightly; John B.
                        Scherer, considerably; as also J. Beck, both grocers and confectioners. The
                        pavements on both sides of the streets are torn up. The cellars were all
                        filled with water.</p>
                    <p>The damage to Garber &amp; Co.'s Foundry is quite serious, and will
                        prevent them for several weeks from operating their machinery. Much of their
                        metal has been washed off, some of which will never be found. James Mayse,
                        tanner, also loses heavily, and will have a great deal of repairing to do
                        before he can again go to work. The loss to Mrs. Farrar, whose house is
                        built immediately over the creek, is very serious. All the furniture in the
                        lower part of her house was destroyed; also clothing, bedding, and what
                        little money this excellent old lady had accumulated by hard labor, were
                        washed away. Her case is one that appeals strongly to the charity of the
                        community.</p>
                    <p>The damage along the course of Lewis' Creek, below Staunton, is considerable.
                        The Woolen Factory sustained a slight injury, amounting to several hundred
                        dollars. The corn-fields and bottom lands of Capt. J. A. Harman, Mosby
                        &amp; Taylor, Davis Bell, M. G. Harman, A. W. Harman, and others, were
                        much damaged, and much of the corn almost entirely destroyed.</p>
                    <p>It is impossible to estimate the loss sustained by this almost unprecedented
                        flood. To commute the actual loss, the inconvenience, and the incidental
                        costs, into money, the sum would be no small item. It is sufficient to
                        arouse our citizens to the absolute necessity of arming themselves against a
                        recurrence of the disastrous results which have followed this freshet. Many
                        plans have been suggested, but we think the wisest idea has been adopted by
                        the Council, and that is to employ a competent Engineer to examine into the
                        cause and suggest a remedy if possible. All the Council can possibly do,
                        they have determined to perform.</p>
                    <p>On Wednesday another freshet occurred, but not so heavy as the one on
                        Saturday. Our citizens, and especially those on the water course, were much
                        alarmed and some of them left their homes, and sought higher and drier
                        quarters with their neighbors. The waters were dammed up above Mayse's
                        premises, and were forced to either side of the main channel to seek a
                        temporary one for the occasion. This was easily found in the line marked by
                        the current on Saturday.</p>
                    <p>The flood of the 4th inst., was greater and more destructive than the freshet
                        either of 1844 or 1855.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayse</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>C.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wadell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>P.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blake</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antosi</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>K.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Faust</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>D.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eichelberger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosby</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrol</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hare</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Davis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandeburg</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farrar</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Heavy rains caused floods in Staunton last Saturday. Most of town was hit
                    hard. Damage was done to property belonging to Opie, Donaghe, Mayse, Burke,
                    Crawford, Shumate, Harlan, Kinney, Bickle, Morris, Cochran, Bruce, Wadell,
                    Hultz, Powell, Woods, Gilkeson, Blake, Elick, Antosi, Kelley, Snider, Stevenson,
                    Morris, Faust, Kayser, Eichelberger, Mosby, Taylor, Price, Evans, Carrol,
                    Bledsoe, O'Hare, Michie, Ball, Sheffey, Bumgardner, Rankin, Brandeburg, Tate,
                    Carroll, Miller, Young, Scherer, Beck, Garber, Farrar and Harman.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.10a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Small Business</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrot</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Response to W. J. Parrot from Gordonsville, who returned a copy of the
                    Vindicator with "want no such paper" written over Douglas's and Johnson's names.
                    The editor points out that Parrot violated Postal laws and is 16 months behind
                    on his subscription to the Vindicator. If his bill (of $3.50) is not paid, then
                    they will send a collection agent after him.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Incidents of the Flood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Incidents of the Flood.</p>
                    <p>A little son of D. C. McGuffin, Esq., came near being drowned on Saturday
                        during the freshet. The basement story of his house was filled with water. A
                        servant woman was standing with her back to the cellar door, and hearing a
                        splash, remarked - "There goes my cupboard," and turning around, beheld
                        instead of her cupboard, Mr. McGuffin's oldest child strangling in the
                        water. A few moments more and life would have been extinct. The little
                        fellow had fallen head foremost, and strangulation had commenced before he
                        could call attention to his perilous situation.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Farrar was driven from the lower rooms of her house to the attic. Her
                        little grandson happened to be away from the house when the flood rushed
                        suddenly upon it. Knowing that his grandmother was in the building, the
                        little fellow became almost frantic, and once or twice attempted to get to
                        the house by rushing through the waters, but was prevented by Dr. Downey.
                        But for this timely intervention, the little boy's affection for his
                        grandmother would have proved his death.</p>
                    <p>"Old Uncle Sam," a servant belonging to Benj. Crawford, Esq., was barely
                        rescued from drowning by being drawn out of a cellar by a son of Mr.
                        Crawford. Several persons in Irish alley came very near being drowned.</p>
                    <p>The chimney of the residence of Addison Waddell, and one of the Catholic
                        church, were blown down. A number of trees were also twisted off by the
                        restless force of the storm. The stable of Mr. J. McCoy was taken from its
                        foundation.</p>
                    <p>One of the lamp posts--cast iron--was torn up and washed fifteen or twenty
                        feet. The gas pipes were slightly injured, in consequence of which the gas
                        was cut off on Saturday night. The defect was speedily repaired on Monday,
                        and the town lighted up as usual that night.</p>
                    <p>The barn of W. W. Donaghe, Esq. situated near his residence in the vicinity
                        of the North-west corporate limits, was struck by lightning during the storm
                        on Saturday last, and consumed. There were also destroyed with the barn
                        about 200 bushels of wheat in the straw, 250 bushels of rye, 300 or 400
                        bushels of oats, a threshing machine, a new wagon, and a number of other
                        farming implements. Four negro men belonging to Col. H. L. Opie were in the
                        barn at the time it was struck, having gone there for protection from the
                        storm. The electric fluid struck very near one of the men, who describes it
                        as surrounding him with a blaze of fire. The negroes were very much
                        frightened, and rapidly made their escape, not slacking their utmost speed
                        until they had reach [sic] their home, some five or six hundred yards
                        distant.</p>
                    <p>Capt. H. H. Peck, a Mr. Reed, and Dr. King, were severely stunned by
                        lightning on Saturday last, during the storm while standing in the porch of
                        the house at Brown's Spring. The electricity struck the watch and chain of
                        Capt. Peck, partially melting them, and passed down the leg to the foot,
                        tearing off his boot. The shock was severe, but not sufficiently so to
                        prevent him from traveling a few miles to his residence that evening. Mr.
                        Reed was badly shocked , but will recover.</p>
                    <p>We saw Capt. Peck on Wednesday last. He is nearly entirely recovered from the
                        shock. There is still a slight soreness in his right arm.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farrar</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Ben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>"Old Uncle"</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details more damage done by the recent flood. D. C. McGuffin's eldest son
                    almost drowned and Mrs. Farrar was driven to her attic because the lower rooms
                    flooded. "Old Uncle Ben," a servant of Benjamin Crawford, almost drowned in a
                    cellar and Addison Waddell's chimney blew down. J. McCoy's stable was taken off
                    its foundation and W. W. Donaghe's barn was destroyed. Capt. Peck, Mr. Reed, and
                    Dr. King were hit by lighting during the storm, but seem to be okay now.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.10b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Flood</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses ways the town can prevent another flood from happening.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Grand Picnic, Military Display, Flag Presentation, &amp;amp;c. at Brown's
                    Spring</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>D.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The big Picnic at Brown's Spring near Fishersville was attended by many
                    people, including the West Augusta Guard with Capt. Baylor, the Staunton
                    Artillery with Capt. Imboden, Capt. Koiner's Augusta Rifles, Capt. Peck's
                    Cavalry and Turner's Cornet Band. J. Bumgardner presented a flag to the Augusta
                    Rifles from the ladies of the vicinity. A good time was had by all.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Dr. S. H. Moffet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moffet</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Moffet spoke to the Rockingham Democracy in support of Douglas and Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp Meeting.</p>
                    <p>A Camp Meeting for Churchville Circuit, Baltimore Conferences, commences
                        today, under the charge of Rev. D. W. Arnold. A number of ministers from a
                        distance will be present.</p>
                    <p>Jas. I. A. Trotter, Esq., will run a daily stage to and from the camp ground.
                        Persons wishing to engage passage can do so by calling at the Stage Office
                        at the Virginia Hotel.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>James I.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>There will be a camp meeting led by Rev. Arnold.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvaug60.html#8.10c</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote>August elections in other states in column 2. A couple of short articles on
                political news around the nation are in column 5. Discussion of a speech attacking
                Douglas in column 5. Rockingham Methodist meeting in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. Bolivar Christian from Staunton gave an address entitled "The
                    Scotch-Irish Settlers of the Valley of Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A black man working for the Central RR Company died of "congestion of the
                    brain" after drinking too much water in the heat.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Brown died on August 4 at the residence of John Brown.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Political attack on the Alexandria Sentinel in column 1. A couple of ads for
                runaway slaves in column 3.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.08.10.04">
            <pageNote>No Page Information Available</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
