<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1860/va.au.rv.1860.12.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Josh Rothman</taggerName>
            <tagDate>6/12/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>3rd Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-14">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Law of Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Decisions by the Attorney General of Virginia regarding election practices
                    as a result of the recent election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Well Done Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator praises Missouri for voting for Douglas over Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial supporting the Breckinridge electors that resigned their
                    positions and thereby gave the state to Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts from the New York Herald and the Daily South Carolinian stating
                    that the Cotton States have no desire to reopen the slave trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mormons are said to be happy with the idea of disunion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Wouldn't Own Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short story about "Joe" and "Polly."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Defends Douglas from Alexandria Sentinel in column 3. Assorted short political
                articles in cols. 3&amp;4. Love letter from 1674 in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial asking subscribers with past accounts to pay their bills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>There are thirteen women in the State Penitentiary: six white and seven
                    black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Military</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Baylor and his Augusta Guards had their regular monthly drill as did
                    Capt. Imboden and the Staunton Artillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association will be performing this Thursday, December
                    20, in the Armory Room.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Light</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Light.</p>
                    <p>We are very little acquainted with Gas arrangements of Staunton, and
                        consequently cannot give any very satisfactory reason for the outrageous
                        negligence or carelessness which has deprived the town of light for a week
                        past. We have understood that the resin, from which our gas is made, was
                        suffered to give out, and hence the exhaustion of the gasometer. We are not
                        informed as to the exact terms of the contract on which the gas is supplied,
                        but if there can be any justification for it, we hope the council will at
                        once bring suit against the contractors for damages, or failure to comply
                        with stipulations. In the present condition of our streets it is extremely
                        dangerous to walk at night without gas lights. We urge the council to at
                        once enquire into the cause of the absence of the lights, and ascertain
                        whether or not this great inconvenience has been occasioned by unavoidable
                        necessity, or inexcusable negligence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial questioning the failure of the gas lights in Staunton for the
                    past week.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec60.html#12.14a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Business Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminder that the Vindicator accepts advertisements and has a wide
                    circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Manifest Destiny</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Manifest Destiny.</p>
                    <p>The philosophy of history has been studied to little purpose, if the
                        intelligent reader does not see in the causes which are shaking the
                        fundamental structure of our government, the agencies that overthrew
                        destroyed the Republics of Greece and Rome. Xenophon and Isocrates have
                        transmitted the beneficial instruction that popular government was
                        administered with singular success in Athens and Sparta, so long as the
                        people were held to a rigid observation of the laws, and never permitted to
                        indulge in habitual neglect of the stern requirements of mutual confidence,
                        respect and fraternity. So long as an elevated sense of obedience to
                        government animated the people, those cities marched forward in all the arts
                        of civilization, and attained the eminence that eclipsed in renown and
                        splendor the then known world. The first symptoms of decline and decay were
                        manifested in a departure from the teachings and examples of the founders of
                        the cities. A gradual laxity in the administration of the laws quickly
                        succeeded, and finally the whims of the popular mob became the ruling
                        element in the administrations; license assumed the mantle of law; the
                        governments of regulated liberty were swiftly converted into warring and
                        chaotic elements, and the last hopes of a once happy, prosperous and
                        contented people blotted out in a sea of blood and carnage.</p>
                    <p>No less impressive are the lessons drawn from the graphic historical recitals
                        of Gibbon, as he traces, with the charm of Romance, the "decline and fall"
                        of the Roman Empire. The incipient signs of disease in the body politic, at
                        first apparently trifling and insignificant, and no larger than a man's
                        hand, gradually spread, until the entire system became corrupted, and the
                        dark cloud of impending ruin broke in destructive fury upon it.</p>
                    <p>We do not think it is drawing upon the imagination to an absurd degree to
                        assume that Washington himself, when penning that rich legacy to
                        posterity--his Farewell Address--had vividly before his mind's eye the
                        mournful lessons of the history of these ancient governments. It cannot
                        escape the intelligent reader's attention, that his earnest warnings and
                        patriotic injunctions are directed against the very evils which proved the
                        bane of the political systems of Greece and Rome, and are, therefore, not so
                        much the result of a prophetic vision as the philosophic teachings of
                        history. The same may be written of the Farewell Address of Jackson, who,
                        instructed by the realization of many of the evils which Washington
                        predicted would grow out of sectional prejudices and geographical parties,
                        was thus, with the lights of actual experience, as well as of historical
                        record, beaming all around him, enabled to point out with the greater
                        accuracy the evils which threatened the stability and existence of our
                        government.--Could those great and good men have lifted the curtain of time
                        itself, and been permitted to glance down its unveiled vista, they could not
                        have invested their patriotic warnings with more instructive truths. And if
                        the seals that have thus far been broken attest the prophetic wisdom of
                        Washington and Jackson, how can we close our eyes to the rushing conviction
                        that the mournful fears which pressed upon them may be realized to the very
                        letter in our own day and generation. Sectional parties have been formed.
                        Against these they warned us.--Embittered feelings have been engendered.
                        This, they told us, would be the natural result of sectional parties. Mutual
                        distrust, antipathy and hate do exist, which they plainly pointed out to us.
                        The Union is now shaking and creaking under fratricidal blows, and will, we
                        fear, speedily be riven asunder, thus realizing their most painful fears and
                        forebodings. If in these respects, Washington and Jackson were the faithful
                        chroniclers of unseen events, is it not more than possible that the warring,
                        petty Republics and States which they pictured in the dim future, may be our
                        destiny, until we fall prey to more wise and united powers?</p>
                    <p>We confess that the actual developments which loom up before us in the
                        history of our government, have startled and shaken our faith in the destiny
                        of the American Republic. While ever skeptical, when left alone with reason,
                        as to the continuance of an united Confederacy of all the States, we have
                        thrown our intellectual doubts and fears down before the triumphs of an
                        abiding faith that the reins of this free and happy government would be
                        controlled by the Ruler of the Army and Council of the Skies, for the
                        purpose of spreading, by the agency of Democratic Republican government, the
                        principles of Christianity throughout the world. Believing that the destiny
                        of peoples and governments are determined in the Councils of Divinity, we
                        still cling to the conviction that whether united or separated, some good
                        end is destined to be accomplished.</p>
                    <p>The historical truth that the negro slave and the acquisition of Territory
                        constitute the rock which will eventually break asunder the Union of the
                        States, affords us a gleam of light as to the pat "Manifest Destiny,"
                        marching before us like a pillar of cloud by day and fire by night, is
                        pointing out for the Southern Confederacy. We have ever believed that the
                        genius of American liberty was destined to overspread the Mexican Republic,
                        and thus pave the way for the triumph of Christianity over the religious
                        superstition of that benighted and priest-ridden people--wresting one of the
                        loveliest countries beneath the sun from the rule of ignorance, tyranny, and
                        wickedness, and making her beautiful valleys to blossom as the rose, and her
                        auriferous mountains to yield up their immense treasures, under the magic
                        touch of Anglo-Saxon energy and industry.</p>
                    <p>The question presents itself, is this possible so long as the enemies of the
                        expansion of negro slavery have the numerical power in our national
                        councils? We think not, for it is a conclusion fortified by the most
                        powerful arguments-- adaptation of soil and climate--which can be adduced,
                        that negro slavery is destined to be established in old Mexico, if ever that
                        country passes from the ruse of the race that at present governs it, and
                        becomes a part of the American domain. This being admitted, then it follows,
                        the antipathy of the Northern mind to the expansion of slavery being greater
                        than a desire for territorial acquisition, that no scheme, however
                        plausible, could ever be carried into successful operation, the object of
                        which would be the possession of Mexico, so long as the Union of these
                        States continues.</p>
                    <p>But establish a Southern Confederacy, then the difficulty arising from
                        division of sentiment on the negro question would be removed, for there
                        would be but one opinion in common with all the component parts of such a
                        government, and that, the dedication of all territory to slavery where it
                        could be made profitable.</p>
                    <p>May it not be, then, an arrangement in the economy of Providence--</p>
                    <p>an unfolding in the "Manifest Destiny" of our race--that from the rending
                        asunder of the bonds that unite these States, is to be accomplished the
                        peaceful religious and political regeneration of that land of beauty,
                        mystery and romance, around whose history is thrown a charm and attraction
                        unsurpassed by the most fascinating pictures of modern fiction? Under the
                        auspices of a Southern Confederacy, this could be attained without the fear
                        of violent controversies, sectional wars, and personal hatreds; while, if
                        attempted by a Confederacy united in name, but divided in sentiment, a scene
                        of strife and crimination would follow, shocking to the civilized world, and
                        a libel upon the name of an enlightened patriotism. The history of Kansas,
                        written in tears and blood, is a fearful warning against the acquisition of
                        more territory as an united people.</p>
                    <p>We have implicit faith that it is the "Manifest Destiny" of this country,
                        under Providence, to absorb the chaotic, torn and tattered powers of the
                        North American Continent, and bring them under the genial sway of
                        Republicanism and Christianity. If the union of these States lies in the way
                        of the accomplishment of that end, then we believe there will be a peaceable
                        and permanent separation, each Confederacy contributing its quota to
                        carrying out the grand scheme of reformation.</p>
                    <p>It is very evident, too, that the moral and religious conviction of the South
                        is better adopted to the dissemination and inculcation of the simple truths
                        of free government regulated by law, and the Bible, than the North. There,
                        the great substratum of society is corrupt and polluted, sending forth a
                        stream of infidelity, heresy and blasphemy unparalleled in the history of
                        the world.--With no permanent rule of moral action, but liable to break out
                        in the assertion of some monstrous doctrine of religious and political
                        fanaticism, such as Millerism, Foreurism, Woman's Rightism, &amp;c., the
                        respect and confidence of an inferior people could not be commanded, for the
                        example of immorality and radicalism would successfully estop the
                        enforcement of virtuous precepts.</p>
                    <p>The social and moral status of Southern society is of more substantial
                        character, and better adapted to the great work of implanting the living
                        truths of free government and christian religion and virtue, in the minds of
                        an inferior race. The steady political conservatism, the firm morality, and
                        elevated conscientiousness of Southern character, would at once
                        revolutionize, by the silent, yet potential agencies of precept and example,
                        the social structure of that unhappy and misguided people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial supporting the spread of "the genius of American Liberty" into
                    Mexico as a possible solution to the present crisis.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/rvdec60.html#12.14b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary>"Like the Whig, the Vindicator will stand by Virginia, in or out of the
                    Union."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Whig believes that the South must demand its rights. If these demands
                    are not met by the North, then the South should withdraw from the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Slavery in the Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Supports the decision of the laity of the Baltimore Conference of the M. E.
                    Church to break off from the General Conference and looks forward to the
                    Baltimore Convention when the break can be made official.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sabbath School Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Sabbath School of the M. E. Church will host a celebration on Christmas
                    day in the church basement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Letter from Gen. Harman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Hastily, but truly, &amp;amp;c., Wm. H. Harman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Gen. Harman to Nat. Tyler, Esq., advocating staying in the
                    Union and resolving the differences with the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officers for the Grand Lodge of Masons were picked Tuesday night in
                    Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>123 black men from the Penitentiary have been hired to work for the
                    Covington and Ohio Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Congressional notes in column 6.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.14.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator, To Whom it May Concern</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter complaining about the condition of the Staunton and Parkersburg
                    Road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Minutes of the meeting of the Lay Convention of the Baltimore Methodist
                    Episcopal Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A white woman in Cincinnati spit in the face of a black man who offered to
                    accompany her home. A Republican justice fined her and sent her to prison for 10
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransbottom</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchens</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Gustavus L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>E.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Gustavus A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William, Gustavus, and E. L. Crockett, ages 22, 8, and 10, respectively,
                    died in Wytheville of Diptheria. A short tribute is included.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Popular vote of the Union in column 2.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1860.12.14.04">
            <pageNote>Poem in column 1.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
