<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-10-05">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Characteristic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reprint of the Spirit's two contradictory articles on the protection of
                    Naturalized citizens, preceded by a dicussion of Jerry Black's role in claiming
                    the Secretary of the State did NOT represent the administration when he said the
                    citizens do not have protection. Black tried to convince the people in order to
                    salvage the naturalized citizens' vote for him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Repeated articles: on the reduction of the State debt; reminders to vote for
                the Republican ideals and candidates; other papers criticisms of the Spirit's attack
                on Mcclure.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05.02">
            <div type="">
                <column/>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>A poem; Serial story of a Haunted House; humorous stories; advertisements; the
                proclamation of the General Election.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05.03">
            <pageNote>Recommendations for music on Sundays; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The War Of The Judges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>". . .but the privilege--we willl not say right, for law even cannot make
                    right out of wrong--of holding our fellow-man, the image our Creator, as
                    property is not general in its character, it is altogether local, and can only
                    exist where local, unholy, wicked legislation upholds the sin."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>Johnny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Description of a battle between Judges Douglas and Black for the Democrat
                    Presidential nomination--that Black responded in the Washington Constitution to
                    Douglas' speech on Popular Sovereignty in Harper's Magazine Sept. 1859. The
                    Repository how Black must be shirking his duties as Attorney General, and that
                    he also must have had a hand in articles written, supposedly by Johnny Cooper,
                    in the Spirit (Black's paper). The Repository criticizes Black's logic in a
                    Spirit article that defends the maintenance of slave property from state to
                    state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Naturalized Citizens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository claims that Jerry Black simply restated what several
                    previous Whig adminstrations have said--that a naturalized citizen is protected
                    by the U. S. government just as if he had been born in the country. Black is
                    part of the Democrat Administration that does not believe in this protection.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Brand The Falsifier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A reference to an article last week in the Spirit, written by Brand, that
                    accuses McClure of having lost his Party's and friends' support. The Repository
                    challenges the Spirit to name the friends.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Make Him Explain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When we hear a calf bellowing at the tail of a cow we infer that it is
                    after milk--and when we see a man calling upon another for a sight of his purse
                    we conclude he wants money."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The editor of the smut machine, on the other side of the Cove Mountain,
                        ycleped the <emph rend="italic">Fulton Democrat</emph>, is calling upon Col.
                        A. K. McClure to come over into Fulton County, and "bring his long purse
                        with him." </p>
                    <p>What is Samson to do with McClure's purse? How does he know that the Col.
                        carries a "long purse?" Has he ever seen it? If he has, under what
                        circumstances? Please explain. The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, just
                        now, is very anxious to find some-body who has handled "the long purse" of
                        the gallant Col.; or who has filled it for the man above all others whom the
                        conductors of that journal hate. But they have not succeeded. Haul up Sansom
                        [sic] and make him explain the <emph rend="italic">dark</emph> meaning of
                        his editorial.</p>
                    <p>When we hear a calf bellowing at the tail of a cow we infer that it is after
                        milk--and when we see a man calling upon another for a sight of his purse we
                        conclude he wants money. We would not insinuate that Sansom is
                        purchasable--well, stop, we feel like taking that back, when we consider
                        that he is a locofoco--or that he is thus making an offer to McClure, (whom
                        he alleges will buy votes) but we ask for an explanation of the mystery
                        surrounding his appeal to McClure to "come to Fulton County and bring his
                        long purse with him."</p>
                    <p> We say that considering that he is a locofoco he may be among the
                        purchasable. Our reason for saying this is founded upon the charges made by
                        the <emph rend="italic">Democrat</emph>, and the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> that McClure buys votes. Whose votes does he buy? Are they
                        not locofocos? This slur is of their own manufacture.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors wonder why Samson, the editor of the FultonDemocrat, is asking
                    Col. A. K. McClure to come over with his long purse. Does this mean that the
                    vote of Samson, a locofoco, is for sale? And can he or the Spirit produce names
                    of people whose votes Mcclure has bought.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/froct59.html#10.5a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Astonishing!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors make fun of the Spirit for accusing McClure for not paying for
                    the debt himself, as a way of avoiding acknowledgement that he is greatly
                    responsible for the sale of the Public Works and the abolition of the Canal
                    Board--which reduced the debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>We Cannot Stand It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository lists the amount of money that paid for foreign
                    goods--startin in 1852 and through Sept. 1859. The nine months of '59 have a
                    total ($57,995,371) greater than the combination of the two highest (and
                    previous) years. This export of money is the fault of the Democrats' Free Trade
                    policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Remember The Foundry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reminds readers of the embarassing pamphlets issued during
                    last fall's elections that claimed if Hon. Wilson Reilly were elected, then the
                    National Foundry would be located in Franklin county. The Repository had
                    caricatured the pamphlet, and the embarassed Democrats had quickly pulled the
                    pamphlets from public circulation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Jay-Bird Heels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors respond to the Spirit's mention of their deformed feet. The
                    editors reply that the Spirit's editor has long heels which are always being
                    tread on.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>No Wonder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository responds to the Spirit that it is not afraid of the Spirit
                    having listed Jerry Black as a Presidential candidate--especially when the
                    Repository saw the ears of a donkey on Black.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mention of L. S. Clarke's and Snively Strickler's consistent attendance
                    (where they have spoken) at nightly Republican meetings all over the county, and
                    praise for their characters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Reminders to vote and to vote Republican.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.05.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A prediction that Col. McClure will receive more Democratic votes on Oct.
                    11th than ever before.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cheering News From Adams</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from Adams county reporting that Col. McClure has campaigned in
                    Adams and has drawn large crowds, and that claims that 200 to 400 Democrats have
                    pledged to vote for Douglas is impossible, when so many favor McClure.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Farewell</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Whenever this solemn word must be pronounced, it carries with it sorrow
                    and pain. Sometimes, and under one class of circumstances, the grief can
                    scarcely be assuaged which arises from the cause that requires this word to be
                    uttured [sic]. At other times the bitter cup is so well mingled with sweets that
                    the paroxysm of grief is of short duration."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--Whenever this solemn word must be pronounced, it carries with it sorrow and
                        pain. Sometimes, and under one class of circumstances, the grief can
                        scarcely be assuaged which arises from the cause that requires this word to
                        be uttured [sic]. At other times the bitter cup is so well mingled with
                        sweets that the paroxysm of grief is of short duration. It never can fall
                        from the lips of parents upon a daughter about to leave the home of her
                        childhood, without being attended with heartfelt anguish. No matter how good
                        a match she may have made; no matter how happy may be the prospect before
                        their loved one, she is lost to them--a vacant place is made at the family
                        table.</p>
                    <p>Sometimes a Father, Mother, Sisters and Brothers are called upon to part with
                        one whose voice has ever been gentle and kind in their midst--who has never
                        been long absent at any one time--and whose place they all know can never be
                        filled. Such was the case last Saturday morning when Mr. John L. Cooper, of
                        Santa Cruz, California, left his place, with his young wife, the youngest
                        daughter of our townsman, Mr. W. W. Paxton. She, the tender, beloved,
                        amiable Alice, departed for her new home in the far off golden State with
                        the husband of her confiding heart's choice. The separation was too tender
                        for the eye of the public; we will draw a vail [sic] over it.</p>
                    <p>The happy couple are to set sail this afternoon, from the port of New York,
                        for their home on the Pacific coast. As an evidence of the excellent choice
                        our highly-esteemed young neighbor--the loved Alice--has made of a partner
                        for life, we have but to say that, in addition to the Carriages, Stoves,
                        &amp; c., of which we made mention in a former issue, which Mr. Cooper
                        purchased, of Chambersburg manufacture, for his own use in California, we
                        have the pleasure to add that he subscribed and paid for the best family
                        newspaper on the Atlantic side of the Rocky Mountains--<emph rend="italic"
                            >The Repository and Transcript</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A farewell to John L. Cooper, of Santa Cruz, who left for California on
                    Oct. 1st from Chambersburg with his wife, Alice, the youngest daughter of W. W.
                    Paxton.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/froct59.html#10.5b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Franklin County Teachers' Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richards</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noble</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swisher</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwaine</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKeehan</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFadden</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pfoutz</ln>
                        <fn>F. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoeler</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckerman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolt</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walk</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckart</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caufman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Betz</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Omwake</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eby</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElwain</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hayman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>Perry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Executive Committee of the Franklin Country Teachers; Association mett
                    at Montgomery's Hotel, Chambersburg, on Sept 10th to set the program for the
                    Annual meeting on Nov. 2nd: Othograph--James Montgomery; Phonetics--T. M.
                    Richards, F. Noble; Reading--W. H. H. Newman, William H. Blair; Penmanship--J.
                    N. Snively, Peter Swisher; Philosophy of Arithmetic--J. S. McElwaine, J. B.
                    McKeehan; Arith. Fundamental Rules--J. L.P. Deatrich, P. K. Shoemaker, Isaac
                    Miller; Common Fractions--D. S. McFadden, H. Atherton, F. J. Pfoutz; Decimal
                    Fraction--A. B. Stoeler, J. B. Eckerman; Ratio and Proportion--J. F. Bolt, J. W.
                    Coble, Frederick Walk; Extraction of Roots--Joseph Eckart, J. B. Caufman;
                    Percentage--G. W. Betz, George Eby; Oral Arithmetic--H. Omwake, W. H.
                    Hockenberry; Geographpy--H. B. Kendig, Samuel Gelwicks; English Grammer--J. K.
                    Shryock, S. H. Eby; Arithmeticial and Geometrical Progression--J. W. Hays, Jacob
                    Cook; Mensuration--A. McElwain, J. H. Youst; Algebra--J. C. Atherton, R. A.
                    Moore; Natural Ph</summary>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No pen can describe the distress of the fond mother on beholding her dead
                    babe--certainly no blame can attach to the parents for the sad accident."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--A child of Mr. George Cook, residing near Mt. Hope, Quincy township, aged
                        about 18 months, was accidentally drowned on the 24th ult., under the
                        following circumstances: The mother left the child, which was unable to
                        walk, in the room, while she went to attend to some domestic affairs. During
                        her absence, which was but for a few minutes, the child crept from the room
                        into the yard, where a small stream of water passes. As soon as the mother
                        returned the child was missed, when search was made for it and its lifeless
                        remains were found in the rivulet referred to. No pen can describe the
                        distress of the fond mother on beholding her dead babe--certainly no blame
                        can attach to the parents for the sad accident.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A child left momentarily unattended drowns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
