<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-09-28">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Hail To Reform</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The details of the sale of the Public Works promoted by Gov. Packer, and
                    supported by Col. McClure, Austin and Brewster. The sale reduces the state debt
                    by $1,137,155.36. The actual Proclamation of the governor is printed, given to
                    the Repository by the Democratic Union newspaper in Harrisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>McClure On Legislative Pay.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The year before Mr. Nill had claimed to be for a reduction in pay for
                    members of the Legislature, whereas McClure had justified not voting for it.
                    This year however McClure proposed the same reduction. A mock proposition was
                    also made at an absurdly drastic reduction of pay, which was defeated (McClure
                    voted against it, and Nill voted nay before it became a proposition, and yea in
                    the vote to ratify it.). McClure's proposition was also defeated, and when there
                    was a vote to ratify the standing pay, McClure voted against, and Nill did not
                    vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Abolition of the Canal Board</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"'We are glad that Col. McClure, with an eye to the public interests, has
                    moved this early in this matter, and we may now congratulate the people of the
                    State upon soon getting rid of a set of men who have clung, with leechlike
                    tenacity, to the public treasury in defiance of popular sentiment.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article provides the Legislative votes for the abolition of the Canal
                    Board--that only six people voted against it and they were Democrats. Also
                    included in the article is the reminder that the abolishment of the Canal board
                    also helped reduce the state debt, and a Harrisburg Telegraph article praises
                    McClure for his instrumental efforts in bringing this about.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Doctors Will Differ</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository notes that other Democrat newspapers found the Spirit's
                    attack of McClure distasteful--and prints articles from Forney's Press, the
                    Juniata Register and the Harrisburg State Sentinel that either disparage the
                    Spirit's article or praises McClure (even if he is a Republican).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors print an article from the Gettysburg Star and Banner that
                    wondered what Douglas was doing at the Compiler newspaper, and speculated he was
                    soliciting votes by giving the Compiler money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Repeated articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.02">
            <pageNote>Fiction; advice and anecdotes; advertisements; the proclamation of the General
                Election.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.03">
            <pageNote>A Sermon; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Voice Of The Free</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article praising the NewEngland States' support for Free Labor. The
                    Editors express in the voice of the Free, and strongly hope that none of the
                    citizens of this free nation ever call to dissolve the Union, based on liberty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Casey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Austin</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Note of the campaign starting on the 9th of August with a meeting at the
                    Court House where Hon. Joseph Casey and Col. A. K. McClure (candidate for
                    Senator) spoke. Casey also spoke in Mercersburg and Loudon. Hon. Thomas E.
                    Cochran (candidate for Auditor General) has spoken in several places and has
                    been compared to William F. Johnston for his speaking ability. James C. Austin
                    (candidate for the Legislature) and George Eyster, Esq., (candidate for District
                    Attorney) have also spoken in the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Which Is Right?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLanahan</ln>
                        <fn>James X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository reminds readers that, although the Valley Spirit endorses
                    the Democrats' resolution that endorses the Buchanan administration, the Spirit
                    found several faults in Buchanan during his campaign for Presidency--most
                    importantly that Buchanan claimed to be a citizen of Pennsylvania and yet he
                    refused to pay tax in the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Tune Changed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An accusation that when there were no democrat candidates back in June and
                    so no German votes were needed , the Spirit denied naturalized citizens
                    government protection, but now that their votes are needed, the Spirit demands
                    protection for their rights overseas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Dodger Dodging</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors suggest that Douglas, the Democrat candidate for Senator, has
                    been avoiding his own county, Franklin, because people there are familiar with
                    his adamant stance on Free Trade. They also suggest that the Spirit has helped
                    him to tone down his words and to have him claim to be a friend of the Tariff--a
                    contradiction to his party's platform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sealer Of Weights And Measures</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A reminder that Col. McClure was responsible for abolishing the office of
                    Sealer of Weights and Measures in Franklin County--which will lower the people's
                    taxes</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Frightened To Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors suggest that the Spirit is frightened at the extreme Free Trade
                    doctrines of candidate Douglas, and is trying to explain them in its paper. The
                    Repository reminds readers of a speech by Mr. Douglas in the Court House last
                    August where he denounced the "intollerable Tariff question" and that he was
                    opposed to protection of industry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>What Is The Money For</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Locofocos of this place have raised three hundred dollars by private
                    subscriptions to aid the election of their ticket. What is the money for?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Locofocos of this place have raised three hundred dollars by private
                        subscriptions to aid the election of their ticket. What is the money for?
                        The late Locofoco County Convention passed a resolution forbidding the use
                        of money for electioneering purposes, and the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Spirit</emph> has denounced the use of money in every issue of that paper
                        since the campaign commenced. And yet in the face of all this, the Locofocos
                            <emph rend="italic">have raised this year the largest amount of money
                            that has been subscribed in this place by either party for many
                        years!</emph> We repeat--what is to be done with it? Can the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> tell? It will of course come out with a
                        perfect broadside of denunciation against their corrupt and corrupting step.
                        It will of course re-publish the resolution of the late Convention
                        forbidding the use of it, and will read Douglas out of the party for heading
                        the list of subscribers with the enormous sum of $20. We advise the Spirit
                        to use Mr. Douglas's contribution to keep Mr. Douglas from voting for Col.
                        McClure. He has had such a hankering that way for the last six years, that
                        it will require at least that sum judiciously expended on Mr. Douglas to
                        keep him from voting for Col. McClure and against himself.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors note that although the Democrat convention banned the use of
                    money for aid in elections, and yet Democrats have raised the largest amount yet
                    this year--$300 (Douglas gave $20)--the editors give several speculations and
                    suggestions as to how the money is be used.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.28a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>"The Next Governor"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Boyle has supported Judge Nill as the next governor of Pennsylvania,
                    and the Repository suggests that Boyle expects the favor to be returned with a
                    vote for him as Director of the Poor (who has a vote for Phpysician to the Alms
                    House).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Beware Of Spurious Tickets</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A warning to Republican voters to examine their tickets to make sure the
                    Republican candidates names have not been replaced with the locofocos'
                    candidates'.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Sellers is begging the party to vote for him, and the Repository
                    wonders if it is true, as the Spirit claims, that Sellers has never split his
                    ticket between the parties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>general articles repeating criticism of Democrat candidates and urging
                Republicans to vote Republican.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Repository criticizes the Fulton Democrat for insinuating that Col.
                    McClure will use money to win--the Repository wonders if anyone who has voted
                    for him is also corrupt, because then they would have to include Douglas, the
                    Democrat candidate for Senator, since he voted for McClure on several occasions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sellers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Douglas and Sellers had accused Brand of using whiskey to buy votes from
                    the Dutch, and yet now Douglas is wooing the Dutch with beer. The editors state
                    that Douglas'll never buy the Germans' votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Distinguished Visitor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As an evidence of the desolating effects of war, and the soldier's life,
                    it is not out of place for us to say that of the large company some 90 men, with
                    which he went West, that encamped near this place, on the 26th of June 1846,
                    Sergeant Nixon, and two others are all that survive--the balance have all paid
                    the debt of nature."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We feel proud of our brave, gallant friend, Serg't G. T. A. Nixon, of the
                        United States Army, who is now in our midst--on a visit to his Mother,
                        Brother, and large circle of relatives and friends.</p>
                    <p>This gentleman, a native of Chambersburg, returned to this place, on
                        Wednesday the 14th inst., after an absence of thirteen years--all of which
                        time he spent in active camp service. He has been connected with the Army
                        for nearly fifteen years; entering as a private and, by marked ability,
                        courage and industry, has worked himself up to an honorable and profitable
                        position.</p>
                    <p>It will be remembered that at the battle of Buena Vista, in the war with
                        Mexico, he distinguished himself by his intrepid defense of the Battery to
                        which he was attached--under the lamented O'Brian. Since that war closed he
                        has been variously employed by the Government--part of the time he was
                        engaged in the defense of the Texas frontier, from thence he was removed to
                        Fort Riley, Kansas Territory, in the Spring of 1856; where he remained till
                        early in the present year, when he was removed to Fort Leaven worth, also in
                        Kansas Territory.</p>
                    <p>As an evidence of the desolating effects of war, and the soldier's life, it
                        is not out of place for us to say that of the large company some 90 men,
                        with which he went West, that encamped near this place, on the 26th of June
                        1846, Sergeant Nixon, and two others are all that survive--the balance have
                        all paid the debt of nature.</p>
                    <p>The arrival and reception of Sergeant Nixon, was a grand sight. The Chambers
                        Artillery, under command of Col. F. S. Stumbaugh, in full uniform, and
                        hundreds of our citizens were assembled at the Depot to welcome the brave
                        man to his home. The military took him in charge and escorted him to the
                        residence of his mother. Here a scene of affection occurred which we will
                        not attempt to describe. Long live the valiant soldier.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>G. T. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sergt. G. T. A. Nixon returns to visit his mother, after an absence of 13
                    years. He has served in the army for 15 years--including the Mexican war--and
                    was stationed at Fort Riley ('56-'59') and presently at Fort Leavenworth, both
                    in the Kansas Territory. Of the 90 men in his company with whom he went West,
                    only he and one other are still alive. The Chambers Artillery, commanded by Col.
                    F. S. Stumbaugh greeted his arrival at the depot on Sept 14th.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frsept59.html#9.28b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Our Mechanics Ahead!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A note of praise for local mechanics, like the blacksmith D. M. Lesher, and
                    mention of John L. Cooper, who stopped in Chambersburg a few months, married a
                    local girl, and is returning to California. He purchased two buggies from M. P.
                    Welsh and two stoves from Etter and Hamilton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Game As Is Game</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A mention of Isaiah Keefer and A. S. McCulloh, both of Warren Twp., who
                    went hunting a few days ago; Keefer shot 5 wild turkeys, 1 Pheasant, 1 Chicken
                    Hawk, 1 Red Fox and 3 Squirrels and McCulloh shot 3 wild turkeys ( 2 from 260
                    yds.), 1 crow and 5 squirrels. An interesting note from the editor--that these
                    men would wreak havoc on the ranks of an invading enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Announcements of Republican meetings; advertisements; general news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.06">
            <pageNote>Fiction and news stories; advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.07">
            <pageNote>General news and stories; anecdotes; advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.09.28.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fritze</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckert</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathon</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnel</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rininer</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept 15th, in Chambersburg, Rev. C. Bowman married Rev. C. A. Fritze,
                    Pastor of the German Lutheran Church of Carlisle, to Mary Jane Eckert, of
                    Chambersburg. On Sept 20th, Jonathon Wright, Esq., married William Arnel to
                    Rebecca Rininer, both fo the vicinity of Loudon. On Sept 20th, Rev. William A.
                    West married Wilson Piper to Ann Eliza Shearer, daughter of Peter Shearer, all
                    of the vicinity of Sulpher Spring, Amberson's Valley, Franklin co. On Sept 22nd,
                    Rev. Dr. Creigh married Matthew Smith to Mary A. Grove, both of Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickell</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stickell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reynolds</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 5th, at her husband's home in Antrim Twp., Margaret Stickell, wife
                    of Henry Stickell, died at 68 years, 8 months and 20 days. On Sept 24th, at
                    Harrisburg, William Teynolds, son of T. B. Reynolds of Mercersburg, at age 39.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>advertisements; Facts and Fancies; land and house sales.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
