<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Drew VandeCreek</taggerName>
            <tagDate>Sept. 29</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-05-18">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.01">
            <pageNote>Page covered by miscellaneous stories - national and international.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.02">
            <pageNote>Page largely covered by "An Irish Love Story;" remainder
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.03">
            <pageNote>Page occupied by various international and human interest stories, plus
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>"The True Friend of Working Men"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If he were a true friend of working men, he would disregard the approaches
                    of labor-owning capitalists and, he would use all the power of his official
                    position to procure the passage of such laws as would tend to elevate, from
                    their present helpless, dependent position, that noble, worthy portion of our
                    American citizens."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>He who earnestly encourages every effort made by the philanthropic, to
                        promote the welfare of industry; who loses no opportunity for making himself
                        useful to the productive enterprises of his country; who does everything in
                        his power to ensure constant employment to all who earn their daily bread by
                        their daily labor, at fair, remunerating prices, may justly be denominated
                        the true friend of working men.</p>
                    <p>Under circumstances altogether different to those in which we find ourselves
                        placed, perhaps, there might be no great necessity for giving <emph
                            rend="italic">protection</emph> to labor; but in the midst, as we now
                        are, of a warfare between wealth and muscles, it behooves us to guard well
                        the latter, knowing that the former can take care of itself. Money never has
                        suffered, and never will, on account of inability to procure an equivalent
                        for <emph rend="italic">its</emph> use; whilst labor has been (even within
                        the last twenty months) almost entirely destroyed in consequence of being
                        unable to obtain employment, even at indifferent wages.</p>
                    <p>The financial crises, of the fall of 1857, which paralyzed our manufacturing
                        establishments throughout the land; spreading universal consternation;
                        depressing every branch of business, prostrated the working men and their
                        families completely. Our business men, and our labor engendering
                        establishments had no <emph rend="italic">protection</emph> behind which to
                        screen them from the force and violence of the storm, of this destroying
                        pecuniary simoon, as it rushed on in its havoc-dealing course, carrying
                        dessolation into every department of industry and enterprise, dislodging
                        hundreds of persevering men from their positions at the head of many of our
                        manufacturing houses, and thousands from their occupations at the loom, the
                        anvil, the forge, the furnace and the mines.</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvania, with her immense mineral resources, has a deep interest in
                        fostering labor. The general Government could aid in developing the hidden
                        treasures of the Keystone of the Federal Arch, to the great benefit of all
                        the other members of the great confederacy, by simply providing for
                        enforcing the first law of nature- self preservation. But as long as she is
                        so miserably misrepresented in Congress, as she has often been, by men who,
                        to gain their positions - to secure their election - most loudly proclaimed
                        themselves to be the peculiar friends of the protective policy; and as long
                        as the chief office of the nation is filled by a native of her soil who
                        basely deserts the principles he advocated when anxious to procure votes,
                        and after being inducted into the highest post of honor in the world,
                        ungratefully turns his back upon the State that gave him birth, she will not
                        be able to rise from her present recumbent position.</p>
                    <p>Other measures than those which the present imbecile national administration
                        suggests, i.e., borrowing money to carry on the Government, and borrowing
                        more to pay the interest on the sum borrowed, must be devised and put into
                        operation, before permanent relief can be given to the prostrate energies of
                        our beloved country. Assisting the country to arise from the present
                        prostrate position, will help Pennsylvania to shake from off her shoulders
                        the load which bears her down; and this can only be done by giving
                        encouragement to her hardy sons of toil - her sun-browned, honest,
                        industrious working men- when they are properly provided for, the old Ship
                        of State will ride triumphantly oer the billows of commercial revulsions and
                        manufacturing competition, and arrive safely in the harbor of prosperity.
                        When Pennsylvania is flourishing, the whole country is prosperous. The most
                        certain method, therefore, of advancing the business prospects of every
                        section of our country, would be by giving ample protection to every
                        industrial enterprise which affords large employment for working men; for
                        only when those who are willing to work are kept busy can we claim to be in
                        a prosperous condition as a people. He is, therefore, a real patriot who is
                        the true friend of working men.</p>
                    <p>The whole country looks forward with great anxiety to the doings of the next
                        Congress. Will the expectations of the people be fully realized? Will the
                        measure of relief, which is so badly needed, be provided by the people's
                        Representatives? No fears are entertained about a majority of Congress being
                        willing to revise the present inadequate revenue laws; but will their action
                        be approved by the <emph rend="italic">Pennsylvanian</emph> (?) who presides
                        over the destinies of the Republic? is the question which keeps the public
                        mind in a state of feverish anxiety. If he were a true friend of working
                        men, he would disregard the approaches of labor-owning capitalists and, he
                        would use all the power of his official position to procure the passage of
                        such laws as would tend to elevate, from their present helpless, dependent
                        position, that noble, worthy portion of our American citizens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story makes the usual indictment of the "imbecile national administration"
                    and deems it responsible for the economy's "prostrate" position. It goes on to
                    vigorously espouse a high protective tariff for the nation's economic ills.
                    "When Pennsylvania is flourishing, the whole country is prosperous. The most
                    certain method, therefore, of advancing teh business prospects of every section
                    of our country, would be by giving ample protection to every industrial
                    enterprise whihc affords large employment for working men . . . "</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay59.html#5.18a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>"A Mirror for Democrats"</head>
                <origin>Washington "States"</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We ask the Northern Democrats to look at the 'appalling list of surrenders
                    of principle' they have made to retain party fellowship with slaveholders; and
                    put this question to them: 'How much Jeffersonian Democracy have they left among
                    them?'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>After the series of brilliant victories won by the Republicans in the March
                        and April elections, the Washington <emph rend="italic">States</emph> (a
                        Democratic paper,) made a clean breast of the real cause of the crushing
                        defeats its party had sustained. Here is what it said:</p>
                    <p>In this critical contingency they (the Northern Democrats) are appalled by a
                        demand for still farther and still more embarrassing concession. It is not
                        enough that they should sanction slavery in its most objectional aspect, by
                        aiding in the recapture of the fugitive negro- it is not enough that they
                        should admit slavery into the Territories under cover of the Constitution-
                        it is not enough that they should consent to reverse the traditional policy
                        of the government and to accept the illimitable extension of the Southern
                        institutions- it is not enough that they should fetter the arm of Congress,
                        hitherto so active and efficient in the restrictions of Slavery, and evoke
                        the dormant energies of the judiciary for its protection in the Federal
                        domain- <emph rend="italic">all these things, and more besides, the Northern
                            Democracy have yield;</emph> but their Southern associates are not yet
                        content. <emph rend="italic">They must agree to employ the power of the
                            Government for the propagation of Slavery</emph>. It is a condition they
                        cannot accept. It is an exaction for which they were not prepared after the
                        solemn recognition of non-intervention among the fundamental principles of
                        the party.</p>
                    <p>What wonder is the Northern Democracy now surrender in despair? Who is
                        surprised when they say, it is no use for us to struggle against such
                        overwhelming odds-on one side the frantic fanaticism of our own section; on
                        the other, the ever-increasing exactions of our Southern allies. Why attempt
                        to bear up under this accumulation of embarrassment?--Over and over again
                        have we encountered defeat in support of the South, but the sacrifice is not
                        yet sufficient. Why make further effort, when, at best, it will be
                        unavailing against our foes, and unsatisfactory to our friends? Without
                        pausing to discuss the propriety of the conviction and feelings involved in
                        this complaint, we have no hesitation in affirming that the prevalence
                        among, the Northern Democracy explains the result of the recent elections.
                        May the party profit by the lesson.</p>
                    <p>We ask the Northern Democrats to look at the "appalling list of surrenders of
                        principle" they have made to retain party fellowship with slaveholders; and
                        put this question to them: "How much Jeffersonian Democracy have they left
                        among them?"</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a copy of the Washington States story pointing to the causes of
                    recent Democrats's routs as their consistent deference to Southerners' demands
                    for pro-slavery laws, especially the odious Fugitive Slave law and slavery in
                    the territories. The Democratic "States" identifies these issues as the death of
                    the Northern Democracy. The Repository agrees, with the final commentary: "We
                    ask the Northern Democrats to look at the appalling list of surrenders of
                    principle they have made to retain party fellowship with slaveholders; and put
                    this question tothem: `How much Jeffersonian Democracy have they left among
                    them?'"</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay59.html#5.18b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article notes the unexpected death of Dr. Duncan after an illness of only a
                    few hours. Supplies no information as to his place of residence or age.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. William Weston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weston</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article notes that Mr. Weston, a well-known figure in Franklin County, has
                    been appointed Traveling Agent for the sale of the "renowned" Golden Salve in
                    Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Proclamation!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proclamation announces McCauley's intent (as newly-elected burgess) to
                    enforce ordinances long left to decline.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>John M. Pomeroy, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pomeroy</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article approvingly notes Mr. Pomeroy's election to the City Councils of
                    Philadelphia. A former resident of Franklin County, Mr. Pomeroy received the
                    highest vote total of any candidate for his office in the recent elections.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Military Encampment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces an upcoming encampment by the Uniformed Militia of Pennsylvania,
                    Second Brigade, Fifteenth Division, outside Chambersburg, and the preparations
                    underway to welcome the visitors. The encampment is to begin on May 31.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the YMCA meeting of Monday evening, the 16th, in their new room in
                    the Mansion House. Meetings largely devoted to prayer.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that about three miles of the new Franklin Railroad has been
                    completed.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Eli Beatty, Esq.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the unexpected death of the longtime cashier at the Hagerstown Bank
                    and the fact that Mr. Marshall had been named his replacement.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.06">
            <pageNote>Page occupied by "English Bible Translations, "Memories of the Scriptures",
                etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.07">
            <pageNote>Page covered by "Woman's Love: A Beautiful Incident"</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.18.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raber</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Leah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the May 9 wedding. Both parties of Franklin County. No church noted.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bridenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayhoe</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the wedding of May 10. Both parties of Greencastle, no church noted.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr. Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fine</ln>
                        <fn>L.S.</fn>
                        <sf>of Chambersburg</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomson</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie</fn>
                        <sf>sister-in-law of Mr. Lesley</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dayton</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf>of Camden, NJ</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding held in Philadelphia, at Mr. Lesley's home. Bride, daughter of the
                    late Judge Thomson of Franklin Co., married to Mr. Dayton of Camden on the 19th
                    of April. Notes the groom is a younger brother of the Republican candidate for
                    Vice-President in 1856 and a "first class lawyer." Bride obviously of a leading
                    Chambersburg family because she elicited fulsome comments from the Repository's
                    editor, attached.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of Catharine Harmon, aged 20 years, of consumption. In
                    Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
