<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23">
 <header>
  <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
   <tagDate/>
   <tagNote/>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
  <date n="1859-11-23">
   <year>1859</year>
   <month norm="11">November</month>
   <day>23</day>
   <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>08</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.01">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>John Brown's Speech From The Scaffold</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Speculation as to whether John Brown will be allowed to give a speech before he is
     hung. Also a discussion of what the scaffold will represent to Northerners--tyrrany of
     slavery--and what it means to Southerners--terror of a huge slave uprising.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>A list of the members of Congress; national news; Facts &amp; Fancies.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.02">
   <pageNote>Humorous stories; Gov. Pollacks address.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.03">
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>General Houston and the Ladies.</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"Your presence exercises a calming influence upon those antagonisms which are too often
     engendered in the heat of political contests. All parties desire your approving smile, and
     therefore are encouraged by your presence. I know that in the direct administration of
     political affairs you have no share; but yet, reigning as you do, supreme in the realm of love,
     your influence often controls the destiny of nations.</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>Gen. Sam Houston lately delivered a capital speech at the South, and his peroration is so
      beautiful a panegyric of the ladies--a panegyric of whom, irrespective of politics, we must
      all agree to--that we publish it entire, hoping the sex will appreciate it:</p>
     <p>"Ladies, I know that politics are always uninteresting to you, yet I believe you have in the
      general result an abiding interest. It is always a gratification to me to behold my fair
      countrywomen in assemblages like these. It is a guarantee that their husbands and fathers and
      brothers are men of intelligence and refinement, who appreciate their mental capacities, and
      desire their countenance in their undertakings. Your presence exercises a calming influence
      upon those antagonisms which are too often engendered in the heat of political contests. All
      parties desire your approving smile, and therefore are encouraged by our presence. I know that
      in the direct administration of political affairs you have no share; but yet, reigning as you
      do, supreme in the realm of love, your influence often controls the destiny of nations.
      Woman's love is the great lever which arouses man to action. The general, as he plans the
      strategic combinations which are to insure victory, look [sic] forward to a recompense dearer
      than the laurels upon his brow; the soldier as he trudges along on his weary march, or mingles
      in the scenes of the battle field, even with death around him, forgets awhile the carnage, and
      turns his thoughts to the fond girl he left behind him; the mariner, tempest tossed, driven by
      the rude waves, sings merrily aloft as he thinks of the little cottage by the shore, where his
      wife and dear ones await him; the statesman, as he devises amid deep and painful thought,
      plans of government, which are to tell upon his own and his country's fame, never loses sight
      of the joys which await him when cabinet councils are over, and he enters the portals of home;
      the sentinel, as he paces his weary watch, loves the moonlight tramp, that he may look beneath
      its rays at the dear moments of a beloved mother's or a fond sister's love. Over man in all
      his relationships, the influence of woman hangs like a charm. Deprived of her influence, which
      dignifies and stimulates us to noble deeds we become worse than barbarians. Let it be our's,
      and we can brave the cannon's mouth or face danger in ten thousand forms. You stimulate all
      that is good. You check in us ignoble purposes. You have also an important influence upon
      posterity. The early impressions which the child receives from you, outlive all the wisdom of
      latter days. Sages may reason, and philosophers may teach, but the voice which we heard in
      infancy will ever come to our ears, bearing a mother's words and a mother's counsel. Continue
      to instil [sic] into your children virtues and patriotism. Imbue them with proper veneration
      for the fathers of liberty. Learn them to love their country, and to labor for its good, as
      the great end of their ambition. Bid them proudly to maintain our institutions. Point them to
      the deeds of their ancestors. Make these their escutcheon. and bid them hand it down to their
      children as free from stain as it came to them. Do this, ladies, and your influence will not
      be lost in the future. In the language of the poet, it will still be said:</p>
     <p> "Woman is lovely to the sight, <lb/> gentle as the dew of even, <lb/> As bright as
      morning's earliest light, <lb/> And spotless as the snows of Heaven."</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>In a recent speech, Gen Houston talks of the woman's behind-the-scenes influence on her
     husband--militarily or politically--and that the attendance of women at his speech indicates
     their husbands and male relatives must be intelligent.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/frnov59.html#11.23a</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Execution without a judge or jury; advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.04">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Federalism Intensified.</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>An argument that Jefferson's Democratic party is very different than Buchanan's modern
     version; that Jefferson created the party to prevent the strengthening of the central
     government; Buchanan's administration is doing just the opposite.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>The Money Market</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>This article, which begins with a reprint form the Philadelphia Ledger, discusses the
     evils of spending beyond ones means, and the Repository continues the argument by applying it
     to the Federal Government's debt problems.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>The Irrepressible Conflict</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>This article argues that the locofoco papers are the South's worst enemies, because of
     their inaccurate accusations that the Harper's Ferry incident is a result of Republican
     doctrine. The Repository wants to remind Democrats that Thomas Jefferson spoke out against the
     evils of slavery, and of the retribution God will take on a people upholding such a system.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>The Dissolution Of The Union Postponed</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A response to Southern secession threats if the Nothern states carried Republican
     candidates in the recent election--Republicans did carry many Northern states, and yet the
     South has not seceded; perhaps the election of a Republican President will provoke it.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>A Confederation Of Free States.</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>This article reminds readers (and Democrats) that the concept of a Confederation of
     Free States--free of slavery-- was espoused by George Washington. The Repository proposes that
     the Valley Spirit would probably call Washington an abolitionist and a "freedom shrieker."</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Buchanan On The Supreme Court</head>
    <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Repository reprints a speech (given in 1841) of Pres. Buchanan, in which he claimed
     that he would never want the Court to be the final arbiter on between the Government and the
     people on the question of constitutional liberty--a direct opposition to what occurred with
     Judge Taney and the Dred Scott decision.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Sketch Of Mr. Buchanan</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Repository ribs the Valley Spirit for a sketch of Buchanan--the Repository offers a
     better one done by the Spiriti's editor, himself.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>The Next Presidency</head>
    <origin>The Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Telegraph argues that the most important duty at the February convention will be a
     unified Pennsylvania support of a Republican candidate for President, whether it is Gen. Simon
     Cameron or someone else.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>General news articles from around the country.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.05">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Franklin Rail Road</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Brewer</ln>
      <fn>G. W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Hon.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Rowe</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Major</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Jones</ln>
      <fn>A. J.</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Cook</ln>
      <fn>Jay</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Pres.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Clark</ln>
      <fn>Clarence</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Description of a meeting at Hagerstown, on Nov. 21st, between committees of the
     Cumberland Rail Road and the Franklin Rail Road (consisting of A. J. Jones, Esq., President Jay
     Cook, Esq., and Clarence Clark, Esq.). Others accompanied them, including Hon. G. W. Brewer, of
     Chambersburg, and Major John Rowe, of Greencastle. The meeting's purpose was to arrange that
     the Franklin R. R. run by the engines and cars of the Cumberland V. R. R.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Lushbaugh &amp; Carson</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Carson</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Carson</ln>
      <fn>J. O.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Hon.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>A report of the move of a new baniking firm in Brownsville, Nebraska. One of the
     praised partners, Mr. Carson, is teh youngest son of Hon. J. O. Carson, of Mercersburg.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Painful Accident</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Ligget</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf>Esq.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Richards</ln>
      <fn>J. C.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Dr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ligget</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>John Ligget, Esq., Post Master for the Chambersburg area, accidentally wounded his hand
     with a pistol. Dr. J. C. Richards treated his wound, and his wife, Mrs. Carson, has been
     nursing him.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Appointments Of The East Pennsylvania Eldership</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Beck</ln>
      <fn>B</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Mackey</ln>
      <fn>J.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Kelser</ln>
      <fn>J.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Price</ln>
      <fn>C.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Nov. 9th, the East Pennsylvania Eldership appointed the following men: Chambersburg
     Station--B. Beck; Orrstown--J. Mackey; Shippensburg--J. Kelser; Newburg--C. Price.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Correction</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Kelley</ln>
      <fn>Jacob</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Kelley</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Kelley</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The brother of Jacob Kelley (whose arrest was announce in the previous issue) visited
     the editors to correct their statement that Jacob Kelley is mulatto; he is, in fact, white and
     the editors were confusing him as a son of John Kelley, who is a mulatto.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Election</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Heyser</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Wingerd</ln>
      <fn>A. B.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Eyster</ln>
      <fn>J. Allison</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Immel</ln>
      <fn>G. W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Linn</ln>
      <fn>S. M.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Stouffer</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Piper</ln>
      <fn>David</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Caufman</ln>
      <fn>A. D.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Schneck</ln>
      <fn>B. S.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Nill</ln>
      <fn>James</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Culbertson</ln>
      <fn>Edmund</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Chambers</ln>
      <fn>Benjamin</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Cressler</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The following men were elected, on Nov. 21st, to the Board of Directors of the Bank of
     Chambersburg for the next year: William Heyser, A. B. Wingerd, J. Allison Eyster, B. W. Immel,
     S. M. Linn, John Stouffer, of J., David Piper, A. D. Caufman, B. S. Schneck, James Nill, Edmund
     Culbertson, Benjamin Chambers, John Cressler.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Election</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Rankin</ln>
      <fn>A. B.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Carson</ln>
      <fn>J. O.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ritchey</ln>
      <fn>Jno.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
      <fn>J.</fn>
      <sf>Jr.</sf>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Gordon</ln>
      <fn>A.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Frantz</ln>
      <fn>A.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Buhrman</ln>
      <fn>S.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Zeigler</ln>
      <fn>G. W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The Mercersburg, Greencastle and Waynesboro Turnpike Company held an election on Nov.
     14th, and chose: President--A. B. Rankin; Managers--J. O. Carson, Jno. Ritchey, J. Wilhelm,
     Jr., A. Gordon, A. Frantz, S. Buhrman; Treasurer--G. W. Zeigler.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Lydia Marie Child's Reply To Gov. Wise</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Repository prints Lydia Marie Child's response to Gov. Wise's answer to her request
     to come nurse John Brown. He had said that she has a constitutional right to visit Virginia,
     and in her response she lists a number of people who were not allowed to express their opinions
     while living in the South.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>national news stories; War on the South border; advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.06">
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>A New Phrase Of The Harper's Ferry Affair</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>One of the participants in the Harper's Ferry insurrection reportedly said that he
     understood the purpose of the raid to run off slaves, because there were laboring men at
     Harper's Ferry who wished to get rid of the slaves.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Humorous stories; anecdotes; advertisements</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.07">
   <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.11.23.08">
   <div type="s">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Nelson</ln>
      <fn>A. K.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Armstrong</ln>
      <fn>Alex C.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McDowell</ln>
      <fn>Catharine P.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McDowell</ln>
      <fn>James</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Major</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Philips</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Cook</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Bemisderfer</ln>
      <fn>Lydia R.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Nov. 15th, Rev. A. K. Nelson married Alex. C. Armstrong, of Knox co., Ill., to
     Catharine P. McDowell, daughter of Maj. James McDowell, of Franklin co. On Nov. 17th, in
     Chambersburg, Rev. Samuel Philips married Samuel Cook to Lydia R. Bemisderfer, both of Quincy
     Twp.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Fisher</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Hoke</ln>
      <fn>Hannah</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mrs.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Hoke</ln>
      <fn>Michael</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Poe</ln>
      <fn>Thomas</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Poe</ln>
      <fn>John</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Poe</ln>
      <fn>Isabella</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Nov. 3rd, in Pittsburgh, William Fisher, formerly a citizen of Chambersburg, died at
     age 51 after a protracted illness. On Nov. 12th, in the "Corner," Hannah Hoke, wife of Michael
     Hoke, died at age 47 years, 4 months and 19 days. On Oct. 19th, in Culbertson's Row, Thomas,
     son of John and Isabella Poe, died at age 19.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Rural Matters--cereals, spaying cows, and keeping stock warm; advertisements; real
    estate sales.</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
