<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Drew VandeCreek</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-05-04">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Oberlin Trials</head>
                <origin>Ashtabula (Ohio) Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Ashtabula <emph rend="italic">Sentinel</emph> says that it is the
                        intention of one of the defendants in the Oberlin rescue cases, to apply to
                        the Supreme Court of Ohio for a writ of <emph rend="italic">habeas
                        corpus</emph>, as soon as the proper time arrives, and test the question
                        whether the State is powerful enough to protect its citizens from the
                        tyranny and oppression of the general government. When every principle of
                        law and justice is set aside by the minions of the government for the
                        purpose of punishing men guilty of no crime, it is time that the State
                        should assert its supremacy within its own limits, if it has any to
                    assert.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story reports that one of the abolitionist defendants in the Oberlin trials
                    intends to apply to the Supreme Court of Ohio for writ of habeas corpus to "test
                    the question whether the State is powerful enough to protect its citizens from
                    the tyranny and oppression of the general government. In this case the
                    abolitionists of Oberlin rescued a runaway slave from his Southern pursuers,
                    only to face prosecution under the fugitive slave act. To the Republican
                    Repository, the policy of the Democratic National administration seems like
                    tyranny.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay59.html#5.4a</note>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.02">
            <pageNote>Page largely covered by advertisements and novelty stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.03">
            <pageNote>Page largely covered by national and international stories, and
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Patriotism Then, Heresy Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The times have changed so much, from what they were in the earlier and
                    purer days of the Republic, that what was then orthodox is now denounced, by the
                    wise acred of modern Democracy, as rank heresy; almost high treason."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A bitter condemnation of the southern slave power as soiling the ideals of
                    the old Republic. Where the Founders stood for principles, the Southern
                    Democracy induces Americans to retreat from their principles in the hope of
                    preserving Union. The author especially scores weak-kneed northern dough-face
                    Democrats for caving in to their Southern brethren in this regard. The result is
                    a most unfavorable comparison between the Founding Fathers and President
                    Buchanan.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Farmers adn Machanics Industrial Association of Franklin County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces a meeting of May 10, to solicit membership.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Odd Fellows Jubilee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mishler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lafferty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Account of the Odd Fellows Ball and procession, celebrating the fortieth
                    anniversary of the order in Franklin County. The county's two lodges,
                    Chambersburg and Columbus, gathered in front of the Franklin Hall on April 25 at
                    1 pm. They marched through the streets of Chambersburg, then retired to Franklin
                    Hall for addresses, toasts and a supper.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>none</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>M.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the receipt of a letter from the local Rev., a missionary in China.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Borough Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--The annual election for Burgess, Town Counsel, School Directors,
                        &amp;c., took place in Chambersburg on Monday last, and the People's
                        Ticket was most triumphantly sustained. Strange as it may seem, it is
                        nevertheless the fact, that Republicans and Locofocos, Jews and Gentiles,
                        Catholics and Protestants, all joined in voting the same identical Ticket-a
                        Ticket formed by a meeting of the People's Party on the Friday evening
                        previous. Such a Unanimity of political sentiment, probably, never has been
                        exhibited in any town of the same population, in Pennsylvania.</p>
                    <p>The Locofocos, it is true, marshalled by a few disaffected and factious
                        members of the Opposition, made a dead set at one of the School Directors on
                        the People's Ticket.-They led off in the support of Hon. Wilson Reilly, but
                        they were most gloriously defeated. Out of a poll of some 400 votes Mr.
                        Henninger's majority was no less than 58! This triumphant support, in view
                        of the means made use of to defeat him, is alike creditable to Mr. H., as
                        well as to the citizens of our Borough-it is a most emphatic approval and
                        endorsement of his previous acts as School Director, and a proud vindication
                        from the aspersions of his opponents.</p>
                    <p>The following is the Ticket that was elected:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Burgess.</emph>-I.H. McCauley.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Town Council.</emph>-A. D. Kaufman, Geo. Flack, Andrew
                        Banker, R.E., Tolbert, Sam'l Reisher.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Borough Auditors.</emph>-E. Kuhn, Jno. Rhodes, J.B.
                        Wright.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">School Directors.</emph>-Jacob Henninger, T.B. Woods.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">High Constable.</emph>-Geo. Gross.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf>defeated Democrat for School Director</sf>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>Victorious Republican for School Director</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>I.H.</fn>
                        <sf>elected Burgess</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kaufman</ln>
                        <fn>A.D.</fn>
                        <sf>elected to town council</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>elected to town council</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Banker</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf>elected to town council</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>R.E.</fn>
                        <sf>elected to town council</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>elected to town council</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf>Borough Auditor-elect</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhodes</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Borough Auditor-elect</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf>Borough auditor-elect</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>T.B.</fn>
                        <sf>School Director-elect</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gross</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf>elected High Constable</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Repository crows over the "People's Ticket" (Republican) victories in local
                    elections in Chambersburg. Claims that "Republicans and Locofocos, Jews and
                    Gentiles, Catholics and Protestants, all joined in voting the same identical
                    Ticket.... Such unanimity of political sentiment, probably, never has been
                    exhibited in any town of the same population in Pennsylvania."</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay59.html#5.4b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Town</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Chambersburg, at present, is decidedly on the increase, in imporvements,
                    in population, and in wealth, and well look forward to the day when it will
                    become one of the very prominent and most populous inland towns of Pennsylvania,
                    as it now one of the prettiest and most pleasant."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--For twenty years past our town has not witnessed the same spirit of
                        improvement that is now manifested in every quarter. The buildings that have
                        been and those that are now being erected, embracing some twenty-five or
                        thirty, are of the most substantial and durable kind, and we hear of a
                        number of other buildings that are to be erected the present, as well as
                        others that will be put up the next season. While many of our citizens are
                        thus engaged in improving our town in the erection of new buildings, many
                        others are adding decided improvements to their present residences by
                        remodeling and repairing them, thus furnishing a large amount of employment
                        to our mechanics and laboring people.</p>
                    <p>Chambersburg, at present, is decidedly on the increase, in improvements, in
                        population, and in wealth, and we look forward to the day when it will
                        become one of the very prominent and most populous inland towns of
                        Pennsylvania, as it is now one of the prettiest and most pleasant. We
                        possess the facilities for extensive manufacturing of various kinds- are
                        surrounded by a rich and productive soil, and but a few years more will
                        elapse before we are placed in direct Railroad communication with the South,
                        as we are now with the East and West.</p>
                    <p>The Franklin Railroad is now being re-laid, and the work is progressing very
                        rapidly.-With the hands there employed, as well as the bustle and stir among
                        our own people, gives to our town quite a business-like appearance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Boasts of Chambersburg's reinvigorated "spirit of improvement" visible in
                    new construction and civic projects.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frmay59.html#5.4c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCrory</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>Chief Clerk in the office of the Receiver of Taxes</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. McCrory took ill on Saturday evening, April 30, and died within minutes
                    in the lobby of the American hotel of Philadelphia. He was a longtime resident
                    of Chambersburg, and was 50 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Great Resort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Frankling Railroad construction has become "a great
                    resort for anyone who has the time. It was for such a long time such a great
                    humbug, that our citizens can hardly realize that they are really to have a real
                    bona fide railroad to Hagerstown, and they must needs go up occasionally to
                    convince themselves that they are not dreaming."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Franklin Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Engineer</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the good progress of the Franklin Railroad, despite inclement weather
                    retarding construction. Engineer Murray even ran an engine on the track and
                    sounded the whistle.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Admitted to the Bar</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Orr</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Above men admitted to the local bar after undergoing a thorough and
                    credible examination in open court.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>New Railroad Route</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that with the completion of a new railroad link connecting the
                    Reading with the Lehigh railroad, Chambersburg now enjoys a direct connection to
                    New York.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sold</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Worley</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the sale of the late Mr. Culbertson's home to Messrs. Worley and
                    Aughinbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>Parade</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf>commanding</sf>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes a parade of the Chambers Artillery on Saturday, May 7.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>none</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Mr. Phillips will call upon citizens of Warren Township to
                    solicit subscriptions for the building of small brick church in the township.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.05">
            <pageNote>Page covered by national stories and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.06">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and novelty stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.07">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and novelty stories, including "Neck Twisting
                in Church."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.05.04.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinney</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKinney</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>Archibald</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes wedding of Mr. McDowell and Miss McKinney, both of Peters township,
                    on the 28th of April. No location noted.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnstone</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf>of Carrick Furnace, Path Valley</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Levi</fn>
                        <sf>of Horse Valley</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wedding of April 28. Married by Mr. Witherow.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
