<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26">
 <header>
  <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass</taggerName>
   <tagDate/>
   <tagNote/>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
  <date n="1859-10-26">
   <year>1859</year>
   <month norm="10">October</month>
   <day>26</day>
   <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>08</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.01">
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Who Is Responsible?</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt> "Who is responsible? asks <emph rend="italic">The Journal of Commerce</emph>, in
     reference to the late affair at Harper's Ferry. If we were to look beyond the immediate actors
     in that affair, says the New York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, we should say those were
     responsible who first set on foot and afterward encouraged and sustained the Border-Ruffian
     Pro-Slavery war against the Free-Labor settlers of Kansas." </excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>Who is responsible? asks <emph rend="italic">The Journal of Commerce</emph>, in reference to
      the late affair at Harper's Ferry. If we were to look beyond the immediate actors in that
      affair, says the New York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph>, we should say those were
      responsible who first set on foot and afterward encouraged and sustained the Border-Ruffian
      Pro-Slavery war against the Free-Labor settlers of Kansas. John Brown, then a peaceful and
      quiet citizen, went to Kansas with no intention to do anything against Slavery, except so far
      as his vote and influence might go to keep it out of that Territory by purely peaceable and
      legal means. He settled himself at Osawatamie, built a steam saw-mill there, gathered quite a
      settlement about him, and devoted himself with energy to the business in which he was
      engaged.--Finding, however, that the elections of the Territory had been invaded by armed
      intruders from Missouri, who drove the legal voters from the polls and returned as elected
      such persons as they saw fit, and that this usurpation of the powers and authority of a
      Territorial Legislature was countenanced by the Administration at Washington, he joined with
      the great body of the free- labor settlers in the movements that led to the framing of the
      Topeka Constitution. Under that Constitution, one of his sons was elected to the Legislature,
      and, about the same time that Gov. Robinson and others were indicted for high treason, this
      son of Brown was arrested at Osawatamie under a similar charge, his feet and hands were
      chained together, a heavy oxchain being employed for that purpose, and he was compelled to
      walk the whole way to Lecompton under a burning sun, the iron wearing the flesh from his
      ankles. Fatigue excitement, and bad treatment, brought on a brain fever, and, as no proper
      attention was paid to him, he died a few days after. The sacking of Lawrence followed.
      Buford's men, imported from South Carolina for the express purpose of driving the free-labor
      settlers out of the Territory, made their appearance, and these free-labor settlers had no
      alternative except to suffer themselves to be thus expelled or to take up arms in defense of
      their houses and property. Capt. Brown chose the latter; and it was thus that he was converted
      from a peaceful settler into the captain of a band of rangers. The first military exploit of
      his which made him known beyond the limits of the Territory, was a collision with a party of
      Bufford's men, in which, with an inferior force, he made thirty-one prisoners, and recovered a
      large quantity of plunder which these marauders had collected. Osawatamie itself was sacked by
      a large party of Pro-Slavery marauders, who committed great atrocities. It was at this time
      that the Sharp's rifles, to which <emph rend="italic">The Journal of Commerce</emph> refers
      with so many affected starts of horror, were sent to Kansas as a means of enabling the
      free-labor settlers to maintain themselves in the Territory; and unquestionably but for the
      assistance thus sent, those settlers would have been expelled or cowed, and Kansas before now
      admitted into the Union as a Slave State.-- It is, perhaps, the agency of the Sharp's rifles,
      thus placed in the hands of the free-labor settlers, in promoting that consummation, that
      makes them such objects of detestation to <emph rend="italic">The Journal of Commerce</emph>.
      The Missourians on the border, finding that the free-labor settlers were making an effective
      resistance, mustered a fresh force of more than of a thousand men, and, under Atchison as
      commander-in chief, marched into the Territory. A large detachment of this force proceeded
      against Osawatamie. As they approached the town, a son of Brown was taken prisoner and
      afterward shot in cold blood. The few inhabitants, taken by surprise, were unable to defend
      the place, which was first plundered and then burned.</p>
     <p>Even after this partisan war was appeased in some parts of the Territory, it was kept up in
      Southern Kansas, and Brown had an active part in it. He began on the principle of defense--he
      now acted on that of revenge.--This feeling on his part was still further aggravated by the
      Missouri expedition, under the notorious Captain Hamilton which invaded Southern Kansas,
      seized eleven citizens quietly at work, and shot them in cold blood. Brown retorted by an
      invasion of Missouri during which he liberated a number of slaves whom he succeeded in
      transporting safely through Kansas, Nebraska, Iowa, and Illinois, to Canada. It was probably
      the success of this enterprise which suggested to him the idea of another of the same sort on
      a larger scale, and which resulted in the wild adventure in which he lost his life. But for
      the attempt to force Slavery upon Kansas, and to that end to drive the free-labor settlers out
      of it, Brown would have remained a quiet and industrious man, and would never have been heard
      of beyond the limits of his immediate neighborhood. It was the sufferings of himself and his
      family at the hands of the Pro-Slavery party in Kansas that inspired him with a bitter spirit
      of hatred against the whole institution, and, by breaking up his home and making him an
      outlaw, left these feelings at full liberty to work. And it was principally among persons who
      went, as he did, to Kansas, as peaceful settlers, but whom the civil war kindled in that
      Territory on behalf of Slavery had converted in fierce and desperate men, that he found the
      most of his associates. If anybody is to be held responsible for Brown's conduct, we must say
      it must be those who made him what he is.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A response to the Journal of Commerce's question "who is responsible?" for the John
     Brown raid at Harper's Ferry. The editors provide a history of John Brown's experiences in
     Kansas, and the riots in which his sons were killed (or died as result of mistreatment during
     arrest) and his property destroyed. The editors argue that if the attempt to force slavery on
     Kansas had not been made, John Brown would still be living there peaceably.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/froct59.html#10.26a</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Oration of the Funeral of Broderick; report of Broderick's death as a murderous plot;
    article on a very tall family; election news from Vermont.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.02">
   <pageNote>Serial fiction of a Haunted House; Advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.03">
   <pageNote>A List of Premiums for the fair; Advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.04">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Insurrections</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"We believe slavery to be wrong; that it is an unmitigated curse. But we believe it to
     be a greater evil to the master than to the slave."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A history of insurrections in the U. S. is detailed: The Whiskey Insurrection, 1791;
     The Northampton Insurrection, 1798; The Nat Turner Rebellion, 1831; South Carolina's secession
     in reaction to the Revenue Law, 1832; The Kansas War, 1854 (in which John Brown's sons were
     killed and his property destroyed). The editors do not condone John Brown's actions; They do
     not approve of slavery, but do not want to blot it out with bloodshed.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>State Treasurer</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>High praise for Col. Eli Slifer, as State Treasurer, for paying more for the state debt
     in this year, than any other year before.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The official vote for Sur. Gen. [Keim (R) 6,787, Rowe (D) 6,789], Auditor General
     [Cochran (R) 6,937, Wright (D) 6,656] and Senator [McClure (R) 6,975, Douglas (D) 6,572] in the
     Senatorial district composed of Franklin, Fulton and Adams counties. The editors explain Rowe's
     success in that he did not support the territorial policy of the national administration.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>A Word For Chambersburg</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>". . . to suppose that they would, in the most remote degree, countenance or favor, or
     'aid and abet' such a ruthless and murderous plot, or anything even slightly approximating to
     it, with a view to the wiping out of their 'peculiar institution,' is ungenerous--nay, it is
     cowardly."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>From what we have heard, it appears our Southern neighbors of Maryland and Virginia,
      bordering on Pennsylvania, are very indignant at the citizens of Chambersburg-- regarding them
      as the most fanatical <emph rend="italic">"abolitionists"</emph> with which the country is
      troubled; and as thoroughly identified with "Old John Brown" and his crazy followers, in their
      late fool-hardy attempt at stirring up insurrection among the slaves at Harper's Ferry.</p>
     <p>In the various accounts published, Chambersburg figures very conspicuously as having been
      the head-quarters of these deluded men. Here is where they had their implements of war
      consigned, and from which it also appears, some of their correspondence was directed.--That
      all this is true, will not admit of a doubt; but that any one of our citizens "aided or
      abetted" them, or had the most remote idea of their designs, we do not for one moment believe.</p>
     <p>Several strange men, for some time past, were stopping in Chambersburg, boarding at
      different places; who they were or what their legitimate business was, nobody knew, and the
      strangers themselves did not see proper to tell. They purchased a number of articles at our
      Edge-tool Factory, such a Picks, Axes, &amp;c., they had a variety of boxes of heavy
      merchandise of some kind consigned to one of our Forwarding Houses, directed to I. Smith
      &amp; Sons,"--and they paid their way as they went. They represented themselves as
      Mineralogists, but who they were, what they were and what they were after, nobody knew. Our
      citizens were as totally ignorant of their designs--of their dark and damning plot--as were
      the citizens of Harper's Ferry, into whose midst these Sharp's Rifles, Revolvers, Pikes,
      Picks, Shovels, Spades, &amp;c. were transported and secreted.</p>
     <p>That the heavy boxes which passed through one of the Forwarding Houses of Chambersburg,
      contained war implements, and that they belonged to "Capt. John Brown" or "Osawatomie Brown"
      and his followers, must be true, judging from what has lately been revealed; that these
      Rifles, &amp;c., were landed in or near Harper's Ferry, is equally clear of demonstration;
      but that our "Southern brethren" should, therefore, be incensed at the citizens of
      Chambersburg, stigmatizing them as a nest of vile "abolitionists," who had knowledge of and
      winked at the diabolical transaction, is, to say the least of it, simply silly--as foolish as
      to assert, that the citizens of Harper's Ferry or Hagerstown were privy to the plot of these
      crazy conspirators, because these Rifles were transmitted through their midst.</p>
     <p>The citizens of Chambersburg are an order-loving, law-abiding people, and in these respects,
      or in any other moral virtue that goes to make good American citizens and lovers of the Union,
      are the superiors of our "Southern berthern" located on the "border" or in any other part of
      "Niggerdom." But because our people love Liberty more than Slavery, is no reason why they
      should be charged with a knowledge of the doings or designs of the Harper's Ferry
      insurrectionists, or that any, even one, of our citizens, was in the secret; and to suppose
      that they would, in the most remote degree, countenance or favor, or "aid and abet" such a
      ruthless and murderous plot, or any thing even slightly approximating to it, with a view to
      the wiping out of their "peculiar institution," is ungenerous--nay, it is cowardly. Had our
      people had the least inkling of the designs of these deluded men, they would have nipped the
      plot in the bud; but being as ignorant of their designs as were the people of Harper's Ferry,
      it is folly for them, in their blind rage, to be heaping execrations upon our community, as
      being, in any manner, cognizant of their proceedings.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A defense against accusations that Chambersburg aided in John Brown's Raid, since this
     was the head quarters of the raiders. The editors state that the people of Chambersburg were
     equally as ignorant as the people of Harper's Ferry, and if they had known, they would have
     tried to stop it.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/froct59.html#10.26b</note>
    <look>*</look>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>A Suspicious Character</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"Our community was somewhat excited on Friday last, about noon, by the appearance of a
     suspicious character, supposed, at first, to have been Capt. Cook, of Harper's Ferry
     notoriety."</excerpt>
    <transcript>
     <p>Our community was somewhat excited on Friday last, about noon, by the appearance of a
      suspicious character, supposed, at first, to have been Capt. Cook, of Harper's Ferry
      notoriety.</p>
     <p>Mr. Hiram Wertz, of Quincy, while on his way to this place, overtook a man on the road, who
      was carrying a short rifle wrapped up in a blanket. Mr. W. kindly invited him into his buggy.
      When about 3 miles from his place, the man got out, remarking that his business required him
      to take another road.--As he got out of the vehicle, the skirt of his coat was turned up by
      the wheel, and a large new revolver fell from the pocket. This at once aroused the suspicion
      of Mr. Wertz.--When he got to town, he related the circumstance to several of his friends, and
      while yet, in conversation upon the subject, the man made his appearance. He was followed and
      tracked to a house at which some of Brown's men boarded when in this town. Posting a man to
      watch the premises, the others went to obtain the necessary legal authority to arrest him; but
      before they returned the suspected party escaped, unobserved, from the rear of the house,
      through the back yard. On searching the premises, a blanket was observed under a board at the
      foot of the garden. On being taken out and unrolled, it was found to contain an unloaded
      Sharpe's rifle. The blanket is marked "E.H.", and both it and the rifle are in the possession
      of Sheriff Brown. Immediate pursuit was made by a number of citizens, but his whereabouts
      could not be discovered.</p>
     <p>On the next morning several of our citizens went in pursuit of this man, believing him to be
      "Capt. Cook," one of Brown's leading men in the Harper's Ferry insurrection, and for whom a
      large reward has been offered by the Government. Sheriff Brown, Capt. C. T. Campbell and M. W.
      Houser went to Carlisle, as the man was tracked in that direction; and while on the look out
      for him in that locality, Mr. H. overhauled and arrested him on one of the streets of
      Carlisle, and had him lodged in the jail of that place, where he will be detained for a
      further hearing upon the charge for which he was arrested.</p>
     <p>Cook's wife and child were boarding, for the past week or more, at the house to which this
      man was tracked and from which he escaped; but she denies this man being Cook. From the
      initial letters on the blanket that was found around the rifle, he is supposed to be Lieut.
      Hazelett, who was reported killed at Harper's Ferry. Mrs. Cook started for New York on Monday
      morning last.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Wertz</ln>
      <fn>Hiram</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Brown</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Sheriff</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Campbell</ln>
      <fn>C. T.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Houser</ln>
      <fn>M. H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Hiram Wertz gave a ride to a man, suspected later of being Capt. Cook, of Harper's
     Ferry notoriety. A short rifle and a revolver aroused Wertz' suspicions, and he alerted others.
     The man was eventually apprehended at Cook's wife's residence, and found to be Lieut. Hazelett.</summary>
    <note>frbrowser/froct59.html#10.26c</note>
    <look>**</look>
   </div>
   <div type="j">
    <column>5</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Nead</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The civil suit of McClure vs. Nead has been removed from Court by Mr. Nead on a rule to
     arbitrate it; therefore, it cannot be tried at the next court.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>A letter from China; advertisements; general news stories.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.05">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Pennsylvania Election</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The results of the counties' votes for Cochran (R) 181,835; Wright (D) 164,544; Keim
     (R) 182,282; Rowe (D) 163,970</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Next Legislature</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>McClure</ln>
      <fn>A. K.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>The list of the members of the State Senate (21 Republicans and 12 Democrat--including
     A. K. Mclure from the district of Adams, Franklin, and Fulton counties. The number listing of
     the House of Representatives (35 Democrats and 65 Republicans)--the district of Franklin and
     Fulton counties has two Republican representatives.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>The Brown-Black Plot</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Note that a war will take place in the newspapers of the North and South over the
     insurrection at Harper's Ferry--that Virginia and the South will create a certain paranoia that
     will promote civil war.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>A Card</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A letter from J. R. Giddings, defending against the insinuation that John Brown
     consulted with him before his raid at Harper's Ferry. He also blames the South for creating the
     atmosphere conducive to such an insurrection, both in the South itself, and by encouraging
     slavery in Kansas, which caused the riots there that killed John Brown's sons.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>A letter from China continued from Page 4; advertisements; market reports.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.06">
   <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.07">
   <pageNote>Description of John Brown's Raid at Harper's Ferry.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.10.26.08">
   <div type="s">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Married</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Eyster</ln>
      <fn>William F.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Spangler</ln>
      <fn>Jacob</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Seibert</ln>
      <fn>Ann E.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>West</ln>
      <fn>William A.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Stoubs</ln>
      <fn>Martin L.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Evits</ln>
      <fn>Nancy E.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McHenry</ln>
      <fn>S.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Rev.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Gift</ln>
      <fn>John A.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Arnold</ln>
      <fn>Mary A. D.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Miss</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Oct. 20th, in Hagerstown, Md., Rev. William F. Eyster married Jacob Spangler to Ann
     E. Seibert, both of Chambersburg. On Oct. 19th, Rev. William A. West married Martin L. Stoubs
     to Nancy E. Evits, both of Dry Run, Franklin co. On Oct. 20th, Rev. S. McHenry married John A.
     Gift, of Bridgeport, to Mary A. D. Arnold, of Loudon, all of Franklin co.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p/>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Barclay</ln>
      <fn>Andrew</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Mr.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>On Oct. 14th, near Dry Run, in Franklin co., Andrew Barclay died of Consumption at the
     age 68 years, 9 months, and 21 days.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Continuation of the description of the insurrection at Harper's Ferry; advertisements;
    real estate sales.</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
