<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1859/pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Drew VandeCreek</taggerName>
            <tagDate>September 18</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1859-02-02">
            <year>1859</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.01">
            <pageNote>Page occupied with miscellaneous national stories and selfl-help
            literature.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.02">
            <pageNote>Page covered with romance stories, advertisements and national
            stories.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.03">
            <pageNote>Page covered with romance stories and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Too Sharp to Be Caught</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Repository applauds a bill introduced in Congress to force Congressmen to
                    vote yea or nay on some (unspecified) aspect of the slave trade. It assumes the
                    bill will force northern doughface Democrats to choose between their party's
                    leadership and their constituents' wishes.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Not So Fast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It has been against the vast importations induced by the present low
                    Tariff, that we complain; and if those importations cease, from whatever cause,
                    we are satisfied."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, of last week, attempts to show that we
                        are inconsistent in advocating a protective Tariff, while we admit, by
                        publishing a week or two ago, an article from the Philadelphia <emph
                            rend="italic">N. American</emph>, that the business of the country is
                        reviving, although, as our neighbor says, the Tariff has not been touched.</p>
                    <p>We can answer the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, on this subject, in a
                        very few words. The beggary of the National Treasury is evidence that there
                        is but little importation of foreign merchandise or other manufacturers. Our
                        merchants have been so much crippled by former importations, that foreign
                        purchases are now out of the question, and our manufacturers are putting
                        forth efforts to supply whatever demand may spring up in our markets. A
                        non-importation of foreign fabrics, whether produced by the operations of a
                        Tariff or the inability of our merchants to buy, must prove advantageous to
                        the business interests of our country; and if importations would cease, at
                        least to such an extent as not to injuriously interfere with the industry of
                        our own people, we would not care for a revision of the present Tariff. It
                        has been against the vast importations induced by the present low Tariff,
                        that we complain; and if those importations cease, from whatever cause, we
                        are satisfied. Is the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> answered?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article clarifies the Repository's tariff position, in response to the
                    Valley Spirit's earlier challenge and charge of inconsistency. The author
                    defends a tariff as advantageous to home manufacturers and points out the
                    economic difficulties created by the present low duties.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb59.html#2.2a</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Local Items: The Hook and Ladder Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"While we like to see an active, zealous and earnest competition, with a
                    desire to excel in usefulness, we know no reason why a spirited rivalry cannot
                    exist without exciting bad blood between the several companies. With this new
                    addition to our Fire Department, and a hearty and friendly co-operation on the
                    part of the several Companies, our town is tolerably well prepared to subdue a
                    conflagration."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--We announced, several weeks ago, that an effort was making to raise means
                        to purchase the necessary apparatus and to organize a Hook and Ladder
                        Company. A sufficient amount was subscribed by our citizens to warrant the
                        organization of such a Company, which was done by the election of Mr. James
                        King, President; Dr. James Hamilton, Vice President; Mr. J. S. Nixon,
                        Treasurer, and Dr. W. H. Boyle, Secretary. The Company, thus organized,
                        appointed a Committee, consisting of Messrs, Jas. King, P. B. Housum and J.
                        P. Culbertson, to purchase the necessary apparatus, with instructions to
                        visit Harrisburg and Philadelphia for that purpose. They succeeded in
                        purchasing the necessary apparatus, with instructions to visit Harrisburg
                        and Philadelphia for that purpose. They succeeded in purchasing the
                        apparatus used by the <emph rend="italic">"Protection"</emph> Company of
                        Philadelphia, a very complete affair, at a cost of not quite $500.</p>
                    <p>This apparatus arrived on the Cumberland Valley Burthen Train of Cars on
                        Saturday afternoon last, and according to previous arrangements, the <emph
                            rend="italic">Protection Hook and Ladder Company</emph> were very
                        politely escorted to the Depot by the <emph rend="italic">Friendship</emph>
                        and <emph rend="italic">Hope Fire Companies</emph>, in full uniform, to
                        receive their apparatus, who took it in charge, and, preceded [sic] by the
                        Mechanics' Brass Band, who also kindly tendered their services for the
                        occasion, formed in procession and marched through the various streets of
                        our borough, presenting quite an attractive appearance, and were at last
                        drawn up in front of the Court House.--Here Mr. James King, through Capt. F.
                        S. Stumbaugh, who, in some appropriate remarks, presented the <emph
                            rend="italic">Protection Hook and Ladder Company</emph> with a very fine
                        silver-mounted Brass Speaking Trumpet, which had been presented to him by
                        the <emph rend="italic">Protection Hook and Ladder Company of
                        Philadelphia</emph>--from whom this apparatus was purchased--and it was
                        received, on behalf of the Company, by Dr. W. H. Boyle, in a short but
                        suitable address of thanks. The several Companies then re-formed, and
                        marched to the House prepared for the reception of this new apparatus, where
                        it was deposited, and the several Companies then, in order, returned to
                        their respective Halls.</p>
                    <p>Altogether, this was a pleasant union of the Fire Department of our town, and
                        was as agreeable as it was pleasant. While we like to see an active, zealous
                        and earnest competition, with a desire to excel in usefulness, we know no
                        reason why a spirited rivalry cannot exist without exciting bad blood
                        between the several companies. With this new addition to our Fire
                        Department, and a hearty and friendly co-operation on the part of the
                        several Companies, our town is tolerably well prepared to subdue a
                        conflagration.</p>
                    <p>While we are upon this subject, we cannot refrain from saying, that inasmuch
                        as the <emph rend="italic">Hope</emph> Company is provided with a most
                        excellent and powerful Suction, we think that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Friendship</emph> should be furnished with an equally good one. The one
                        now used by the latter, is not very servicible [sic], and although active
                        and prompt, a great deal of their precious time is lossed before their
                        Suction can be made to operate in forcing water through their hose. A number
                        of City Companies are now supplying themselves with Steam Fire Engines, and
                        are throwing their former Apparatus aside. Could our Town Council not
                        purchase a very good Suction Engine, thus thrown out of use, at a greatly
                        reduced price? We throw out this suggestion, and hope it will be acted upon.
                        Better or more active Companies no other town in the interior can boast than
                        those we have, but it is discouraging and disheartening for a Company to be
                        compelled to operate with an inefficient Apparatus, and to see all their
                        exertion and activity amount to be but little, owing to such a cause. We,
                        therefore say, let the Friendship be speedily supplied with another Suction,
                        or what would be better, with a Suction Engine.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>President, Chambersburg Hook and Ladder Company</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Vice-President, Chambersburg Hook and Ladder Company</sf>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf>Treasurer, Chambersburg Hook and Ladder Company</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf>Secretary, Chambersburg Hook and Ladder Company</sf>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>member, purchasing committee</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf>member, purchasing committee</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf>member, purchasing committee</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the purchase of a new hook and ladder apparatus for the city's fire
                    company and the election of officers for its organization. The article is
                    unclear as to exactly which company will use the machine, but describes in great
                    detail a welcoming march held for the new apparatus by the Friendship and Hope
                    fire companies of Franklin County. The article also describes the march in vivid
                    detail.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb59.html#2.2b</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Young Men's Christian Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf>President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>W.R.H.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamsher</ln>
                        <fn>B.Y.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf>Vice President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebman</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf>Recording Secretary</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf>Corresponding Secretary</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Treasurer</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mingle</ln>
                        <fn>G.H.</fn>
                        <sf>Librarian</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article describes the organization of a new Young Men's Christian
                    Association in Chambersburg, and lists officers.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Conference of the Brethren</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>T.M.</fn>
                        <sf>Presiding Elder</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raber</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf>representative, Chambersburg Station</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>T.B.</fn>
                        <sf>representative, Big Spring Station</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coursey</ln>
                        <fn>W.R.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Greencastle Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H.Y.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Greencastle Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Mercersburg Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Enterline</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Orrstown Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>S.K.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Orrstown Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clem</ln>
                        <fn>T.C.</fn>
                        <sf>representative, Rocky Spring Circuit</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Owen</ln>
                        <fn>W.O.</fn>
                        <sf>Representative, Path Valley</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the Pennsylvania Conference of the United Brethren in Christ, at
                    Mechanicsburg, with a list of appointments made for Chambersburg District. This
                    conference, one of three annually, comprised ministers and members from
                    Franklin, Cumberland, Adams and York Counties, a total of 52 churches. In
                    Franklin County alone there are over 1300 members of this church.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Death of Mr. Edmiston Johnston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Edmiston</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes story of Mr. Johnson's death at the home of his brother, John. Story
                    originally published in Shippensburg News. Notes date of death as January 29;
                    cause of death as "malignant disease."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This story describes the sudden death of the aged and esteemed Mr. Stover
                    while on a visit to his neighbor Mr. Shank. Mr. Stover was a resident of Quincy
                    township, and died on January 25 after a fall from his horse.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A terrific volume of flame suddenly burst from a Brick Stable, on the
                    alley immediately West of Main street, on the lot occupied by Judge J. L. Black,
                    which, with its contents, were soon destroyed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>--On Sabbath night last, between 8 and 9 o'clock, our town was again alarmed
                        by the cry of fire. A terrific volume of flame suddenly burst from a Brick
                        Stable, on the alley immediately West of Main street, on the lot occupied by
                        Judge J. L. Black, which, with its contents, were soon destroyed. The
                        several Fire Companies, together with the Protection Hook and Ladder
                        Company, were soon on the ground, and prevented the flames from extending
                        further. This fire showed conclusively the great utility of a Hook and
                        Ladder Company. A large portion of the valuable part of our town was in
                        imminent peril from this conflagration, and several houses on Main street
                        were on fire communicated by the flying embers. This was the property of
                        Judge Eyster, and we learn there was no insurance. The fire was the work of
                        an incendiary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>J.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The story describes a fire "Sabbath night last" which destroyed Mr. Black's
                    stable "on the alley immediately West of Main Street." The fire showed the
                    utility of the new hook and ladder, as several houses involved by the flying
                    embers, including that of Judge Eyster, were saved by the new fire company.</summary>
                <note>frbrowser/frfeb59.html#2.2c</note>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Late Fire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This story describes a fire of "last Saturday evening a week." The fire
                    began in a shed belonging to Mrs. Grove of Queen St. and involved her stable.
                    The story also gratuitously notes that Nixon's Drug Store, though nearby, was
                    saved "so that those who wish to purchase pure Medicines &amp;c., can still
                    do so from NIXON."</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This story notes the opening of the Chambersburg Female Boarding School on
                    February 1.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>none</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At a meeting, held on Monday evening January 31, 1859 at the Hope Engine
                    house of the Directors and standing committee of the Hope Fire company, the
                    following resolution was adopted unanimously, vis: - "Resolved, That hereafter
                    no member of the Hope Fire Company shall, under any consideration whatever,
                    place, erect or handle any of the Ladders of Hooks belonging to the Protection
                    Hook and Ladder Company,unless at the request of a Director of the Protection
                    Company, under the penalty of expulsion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story details Hope fire company's policy of not utilizing the new
                    Protection Fire Company's hook and ladder.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fayetteville Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Joshual</fn>
                        <sf>principal</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monroe</ln>
                        <fn>S.L.</fn>
                        <sf>teacher of music and drawing</sf>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnstock</ln>
                        <fn>F</fn>
                        <sf>teacher of other branches</sf>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>teacher of other branches</sf>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story notes the school's opening on Feb. 1.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Death of Mrs. McPherson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>Howard</fn>
                        <sf>congressman-elect from our district</sf>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>N.B.</fn>
                        <sf>relative, of Hagerstown, Md.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the date of the widow McPherson, mother of the Congressman-elect
                    Howard McPherson, while at the home of her son- in-law N.B. Scott of Hagerstown.
                    She was 68 years of age.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Remainder of the page is covered by advertisements and market
            reports.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.06">
            <pageNote>page covered by advertisements and non sequiturs.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.07">
            <pageNote>Page covered by advertisements and novelty stories</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1859.02.02.08">
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>W.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf>of Chambersburg</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf>of Guilford Township</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Couple married in the Chambersubrg Lutheran parsonage on January 13, 1859.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodrock</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beam</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the couple's marriage of January 13, in Chambersburg. Both are from
                    Guilford Township.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Albaugh</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>E.J.C.</fn>
                        <sf>of Franklin Co.</sf>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harn</ln>
                        <fn>J.E.M.</fn>
                        <sf>of Washington Co., Maryland</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story notes marriage of January 30.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story notes the death of Mr. Stover on January 25, aged 70 years.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johns</ln>
                        <fn>Susanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Story notes the death of the 77 year old widow Mrs. Johns, who raised a
                    family of five while a widow for over forty years, after a week's illness.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Remainder of page covered by advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
