<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1863/pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sally Henninger, 1st pass; Susanna Michele Lee, 2nd pass, 12/28/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-12-16">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>08</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Organization Of Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the failed attempt by Democrats to prevent the election of Colfax
                    as Speaker of the House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Southern Coast. Winter in North Carolina--Rain and Mud--Visit of Gen.
                    Butler--His Enthusiastic Reception--Rebels Trembling at His Advent--Thanksgiving
                    Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"J."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes the spread of small-pox and its disproportionate affect on the black
                    population relative to the white. The correspondent believes that "the filthy
                    habits of the negroes is doubtless one of the principal causes of this great
                    increase in the number of cases, as well as that so many deaths occur."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Financial</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses news on banks and railroad companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Brief War Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He is of the opinion that as a negro fills the same space in the ranks as
                    a white man, and if shot fills as large a grave, he should receive the same pay
                    as the white soldier does."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes brief items of war news including the outbreak of small pox among
                    the Union prisoners at Danville, Va.; the pursuit of Moseby by the Army of the
                    Potomac; Gen. Butler's urging for equal pay for black soldiers; and the capture
                    of the steamer Chesapeake by rebels disguised as passengers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes various items of news including that the Paymaster, Maj. Jordan,
                    was in Chambersburg last Saturday, on his way to Beford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Jeff. Davis's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "Jeff. Davis's message to the rebel Congress dated December
                    7th, is desponding over the losses of the strongholds of Vicksburg, Port Hudson
                    and many other points . . . He says that 'there are no improvements in the
                    relations with foreign countries' . . . The public finances demand the strictest
                    and most earnest attention."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints Lincoln's message in which he discusses a large number of topics,
                    including relations with nations; naturalized citizens avoiding military
                    service; the establishment of a new Navy Yard; Government expenditures; land
                    disposal; Indian territory treaties; construction of the Pacific Railroad;
                    Emancipation; and pardons and reprieves of secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.03">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Fugitive Slave Law will probably be repealed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that men exempted by the present draft board need not apply again
                    under the current draft call.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Call For Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides information on the upcoming draft, including premiums for
                    volunteers, veterans, and new recruits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This proclamation meets the cordial approbation of every loyal man in the
                    county, and will be zealously supported as the basis of re-organization in the
                    South. . . The President's proposition then is the simplest and easiest plan of
                    restoration to the blessing and benefits of a beneficent government."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Since President Lincoln's late Proclamation has been spread before an
                        intelligent and loyal people, every one who has sustained him in his efforts
                        to crush this rebellion and vindicate the integrity of the Government, must
                        breathe freer when after two years of war a Proclamation of Amnesty is
                        extended to the rebels. This Proclamation of Amnesty is extended to the
                        rebels. This Proclamation settles very easily and practically the difficult
                        questions which even great men were stumbling at, and which often looked as
                        troublesome as the vindication of the Government and the restoration of the
                        Union. This proclamation meets the cordial approbation of every loyal man in
                        the country, and will be zealously supported as the basis of re-organization
                        in the South. The institution of Slavery is emphatically dead, and cannot in
                        the future, even by party triumph, be galvanized into a show of vitality.
                        The President's proposition then is the simplest and easiest plan of
                        restoration to the blessings and benefits of a beneficent government.</p>
                    <p>It is also satisfactory to the loyal people because it fixes the status of
                        those high in power in the so-called Confederate Government, upon whose
                        shoulders rest the responsibility of this war. It has been repeatedly said
                        that human slavery was at the bottom of this unhallowed rebellion. This we
                        believe, for an institution so barbarous can only be vindicated by its
                        advocates allying themselves to the atrocities of the savage, from which the
                        common instincts of an enlightened people rebel. Liberty needs not the dirt
                        of the assassin to support it. It asks an unlimbered press and the
                        privileges of free speech, and when these are checked in this enlightened
                        age, a revolution in sentiment will necessarily overturn the obstacles in
                        the way, and give free course to the mighty channels which give power to the
                        thoughts and notions of representative men.</p>
                    <p>Two years ago the South had the advantage in political leaders by common
                        consent. Now they are singled out as only fit for the traitor's doom. To day
                        the President offers terms to the unfortunate and the innocent, leaving the
                        alternative to the guilty. The majesty of the Government must be respected
                        and its power acknowledged, or those who raise the arm of rebellion must
                        themselves be the victims of their own atrocity. In this day, when
                        enlightened opinions are gaining ground, and when governments freely
                        scrutinize each other, and by the free press of at least two powerful
                        nations, England and America, neither the institution of slavery, nor those
                        who by rebellion attempt to sustain it, can exist. Total destruction is
                        their fate. If the people of England more than two centuries ago taught
                        kings a wholesome lesson by impeaching, dethroning, trying and condemning
                        one by the very laws he had violated, so may the people of the United States
                        demand the death of the authors of fraternal war, because of their bold and
                        bloody effort at usurpation and rebellion. The Queen of England is as much
                        bound by her oath as any private citizen. She is the servant of the people;
                        the people are her peers; not the crowned heads of other nations. If she
                        commit offences against the people and the Constitution, accepted and
                        honored by the people, she may be tried like a private individual for her
                        offence, and if proved guilty be punished therefor. Such men the noble
                        arguments brought to bear upon the case of Charles I by the great Milton,
                        and in a blundering, blood-thirsty way, such were the pretexts made use of
                        by the French Jacobins upon the trial of Louis XVI.</p>
                    <p>The English people did execute the beautiful but misguided Mary Stuart, and
                        it must be remembered that this took place at a period of earnest religious
                        reform and excitement, when the conflict was for freedom of
                        thought--Protestantism as opposed to Romanism, and for offences and deep
                        laid conspiracies against a Queen. For this she was condemned and suffered a
                        felon's doom. The world's history is full of examples of men high in power,
                        as well as private citizens, who for schemes and devices against recognized
                        authority, have paid the penalty of their folly by the forfeiture of their
                        lives.</p>
                    <p>Many of the South are sincerely loyal and long for the blessings they once
                        enjoyed under the United States Government, but there are also many that
                        need the strong arm of power just as they love the pomp and show of
                        arbitrary Empire. To take away from such the strong arm of power, would not
                        be to restore them to liberty with its natural attendants law and order, but
                        to absolute anarchy and license, and bring back the summary executions upon
                        the nearest tree, the hunting down by blood hounds, and the savageness of
                        men who are little better than a race of ferocious tigers when given over to
                        their unrestrained instincts. Abolish the institution of Slavery, and
                        restore the Union of States on the President's proposition, and those who
                        have originated and carried on this unholy rebellion must necessarily seek
                        refuge and find homes in foreign lands. Free soil, Free Institutions and
                        Free Government are not suited to their depraved notions of social and
                        political economy. The Country will be better rid of them. The great idea of
                        Human Freedom, that is destined to carry everything before it, as the
                        crowning glory of the nineteenth century, needs not their services, nor can
                        it be long impeded by their opposition.</p>
                    <p>In no other country in the world, nor under the operations of any other
                        government could so gigantic a rebellion have been met and crushed in so
                        short a time, and with such paramount blessings to the world resulting from
                        it, as the one now rapidly closing in America. Let us hope in the future,
                        for it is full of promise, and while we contemplate its glories and
                        blessings let us not forget the stern reality of the present.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Approves Lincoln's Proclamation of Amnesty to the rebels, arguing that
                    "many of the South are sincerely loyal and long for the blessings they once
                    enjoyed under the United States Government."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Meade's Late Movement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is now clear that from some cause not yet fully explained, the duties
                    assigned to different corps commanders were not executed with such promptness as
                    to secure success."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After reviewing the evidence, the author deem Meade's inaction prudent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses Gen. Butler's report that the rebels stopped delivering supplies
                    and packages sent by Northerners to Union soldiers imprisoned in the South. The
                    Repository reports that even members of the rebel Congress expressed outrage at
                    the treatment of Union soldiers in rebel prisons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Army Of The Potomac. The Plan Of The Late Campaign. The Causes Of Its Failure</head>
                <origin>The New York Times</origin>
                <commentary>"A correspondent of the New York Times has furnished a complete review
                    of the late advance and retreat, from which we take the following important
                    statement, intended to prove that Gen. Mead's failure could not have been by him
                    prevented."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details numerous reasons for Meade's refusal to attack the rebel forces
                    including the misdirection of the 3rd Corps, delays in the march which allowed
                    rebel troops to concentrate, and Warren's decision against an attack because of
                    the strength of the enemy's position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="05" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.05">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Important From Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Gen. Foster assumed command of the troops formerly under
                    Burnside.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Steamer Chesapeake</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarizes the situation of the steamer Chesapeake: "The Chesapeake is
                    doubtless hovering about the coast as there are several traces of her since
                    leaving Shelburne on Saturday. The gunboats in pursuit of her have not been
                    heard from."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sleighter</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>Ellie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 10th, at the home of Daniel Byers near Rocky Spring, by Rev.
                    Bishop, Benjamin Sleighter married Ellie Cormany, both of Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clever</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hosfield</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 10th, by Rev. Bishop, at Pleasant Retreat Parsonage, Henry Clever
                    married Barbara Hosfield, both of Cumberland County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rebok</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minick</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Martha S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 8th, by Rev. Rebok, at his residence near Orrstown, Adam Minick
                    married Martha Metz, both of Letterkenney Township, Franklin County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sweitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Henry L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicodamus</ln>
                        <fn>Ann M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 8th, in Waynesboro, by Rev. Krebs, Henry L. Sweitzer married Ann
                    Nicodamus, both of Franklin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shrader</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowen</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 9th, by Rev. Krebs, at Bowden's Hotel, George Shrader married Mary
                    Mowen, both of the vicinity of Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckly</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rizner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 3rd, in Shimpstown, by Rev. Buckly, Lewis Rizner, of Welsh Run,
                    married Mary Bricker, of Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordon</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 9th, in Chambersburg, John Jordon died at the age of 37 years, 11
                    months and 20 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mong</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin McClellan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mong</ln>
                        <fn>G. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mong</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 7th, near Waynesboro, Benjamin, son of G. V. and Maria Mong, died
                    at 1 year and 9 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 25th, in Antrim Township, Anna Brubaker died at the age of 35
                    years, 5 months and 5 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>onn Dec. 8th, near Waynesboro, Anna, daughter of Aaron Wingert, died at the
                    age of 21 years and 17 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catron</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 2nd, in Mercersburg, Margaret Catron died in her 94th year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Mary H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 2nd, in Evansville, Ind., Mary Louisa, youngest daughter of Robert
                    and Mary H. Early, died at the age of 2 years and 2 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes market reports and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="06" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.06">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="07" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.07">
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="08" image="pa.fr.fr.1863.12.16.08">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gossip With Our Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the construction of a board walk on the road leading from the north
                    end of Chambersburg to Shippensburg. The article also suggest that the growing
                    suburb, through which the board walk passes, should be renamed Lewistown, after
                    the first person to live in the area, Alexander Lewis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Poor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges those blessed with abundance to share with the poor, especially those
                    dependent on men serving in the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ill-tempered Under A Mistake</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Waynesboro Record believed that the Repository claimed to be
                    the newspaper with the largest circulation in the county. The Repository deems
                    their reaction "ill-tempered" and corrects their mistaken assumption. Instead of
                    claiming to be the largest paper, the Repository merely sought legal
                    certification as the largest paper to fulfill the state law requiring all legal
                    notices to be published in the two papers with the largest circulation in the
                    county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Sanitary Commission</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the appeals of the Sanitary Commission to the "Ladies of the
                    North" to increase their donations to soldiers in the battlefields, hospitals,
                    and prisons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Identified</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that officials finally discovered the identity of a dead soldier
                    found on the Gettysburg battle field.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death Of Gen. James Allen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the death of James Allen. He was born in Chambersburg in 1800 and
                    moved to Ohio when quite young. He served under Gen. Houston and Gen. Scott in
                    the Mexican War, moved to California during the Gold Rush, moved to Nevada and
                    established the Nevada Transcript. At the time of his death, he served as editor
                    of the Washoe Times.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Acquitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Clarence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmell</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the acquittal of Capt. Clarence Clayton, who was in the Quarter
                    Master's Department in Franklin. He was accused of unlawfully selling and
                    disposing of property belonging to the United States. John Stewart conducted the
                    trial and George W. Brewer and F. M. Kimmell defended him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. Porter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Updates the condition of Franklin County soldiers imprisoned by the rebels.
                    The sister of J. Porter Brown received a letter reporting the transportation of
                    the rest of the Franklin County prisoners to Salisbury, N. C. Brown related the
                    assertion by Culbertson that the prisoners fared well in North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the decision by the Directors of the Poor that the county would
                    only pay the bills of legally-recognized paupers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Melancholy Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beasore</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the suicide death of Josiah Beasore, a citizen and leading
                    businessman in Waynesboro. "Laboring under a fit of temporary insanity," Beasore
                    shot himself while standing before a mirror in the stable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Concert</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces a Concert of Vocal and Instrumental Music in the Court House on
                    the evening of December 21. The proceeds of the 25 cent admission will benefit
                    wounded and sick soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>On A Voyage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPherson</ln>
                        <fn>T. H. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that McPherson left Shippensburg for a voyage to Europe to restore
                    his health after serving in the military.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Recruiting Agent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxel</ln>
                        <fn>E. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointment of E. S. Troxel, of Waynesboro, as Recruiting
                    Agent for the 16th Congressional District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>School House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the new brick school house built by the directors of Antrim
                    Township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Exempt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises that school teachers received thanksgiving days, Christmas,
                    Washington's birthday, and Independence Day as holidays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the results of the festival held by the "Ladies of Mercersburg."
                    The women garnered donations totaling $235, which they sent to the Christian
                    Commission."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Legal Intelligence. Common Pleas--Writs Issued</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brocius</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowan</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stake</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shugart</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baughman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Secrist</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moll</ln>
                        <fn>Abner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moll</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dysert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imbre</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowery</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monn</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAfee</ln>
                        <fn>Mark</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warner</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reges</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reasner</ln>
                        <fn>SAmuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohn</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the writs issued in the Court of Common Pleas the previous week:
                    Brocius vs. Hawbecker, Admr. of Bowan, dec'd.--Amicable action on assumpsit;
                    Lehner vs. Stake--Appeal from judgment of Esquire Davison; Shugart vs.
                    Baughman--Replevin for one Bay Mare of value of $100; Secrist vs. Long--Foreign
                    Attachment in debt not exceeding $100; Moll vs. Yost, adm'r of Moll,
                    dec'd--Appeal from judgment of Esquire Hamman; Snyder vs. Dysert--Summons case;
                    Imbre vs. Mowery--Fi. Fa. to judgment No. 56, January term, 1863; Raby, use of
                    Monn vs. Dull--Fi. Fa. to judgment No. 71, August term 1862; McAfee vs.
                    Warner--Fi. Fa. to judgment No. 3. January term, 1863; Reges vs Reasner and
                    Kohn, Garnishes--Fi. Fa. to judgment No.127 August term 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page includes advertisements and legal notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
