<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0006"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0006">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">First Manassas, 1st Va. Cavalry, Report of Col. J. E. B. Stuart,
                    July 26, 1861 </title>
        <title type="sort">first manassas, 1st va cavalry report of col j e b stuart july 26 1861</title>
        <author>Stuart, J.E.B.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0006</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500057</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. IX. THE BULL RUN CAMPAIGN, No. 83 Report of Col. J. E. B.
                            Stuart, First Virginia Cavalry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix the bull run campaign, no 83 report of col j e b stuart first virginia cavalry</title>
            <author>J.E.B. Stuart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 2. Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 482</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-26">1861-07-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term/>
                    <term>Regiment: 1st Va. Cav.</term>
                    <term>Company:</term>
                    <term>Battle: First Manassas</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0006T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>J.E.B. Stuart commanded the First Virginia Cavalry which is in the Army of the
                    Shenandoah. He writes about the cavalry's role in guarding Gen. Jackson's right
                    and left flanks.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HEADQUARTERS FIRST VIRGINIA CAVALRY REGIMENT
                    <name type="recipient">General</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-26">July 26, 1861</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report of the operations of my regiment in
                    the battle of Manassas:</p>
                <p>I received your order to charge the enemy's flank, and proceeded immediately
                    across the run to his left flank, but finding that it would be easier to attain
                    his right flank, I immediately returned and marched rapidly towards the heaviest
                    fire. As I approached the ground Gen. Jackson, whose brigade was then engaged,
                    sent me word to protect his flanks, but particularly his left flank. I divided
                    the regiment, giving Maj. Swan half (I had but 300 men for duty), and with the
                    remainder hurried up to Jackson's left, leaving his right to Swan. Entering a
                    skirt of woods, I received intelligence that the enemy was rapidly outflanking
                    us. I hastened forward through several fences just as a regiment dressed in red
                    was running in disorder towards a skirt of woods where the fire had been
                    heaviest. I took them to be ours, and exclaimed with all my might: "Don't run,
                    boys; we are here." They paid very little attention to this appeal. When passing
                    in column of twos through a narrow gap to gain the same field and very close to
                    them I saw in their hands the U. S. flag. I ordered the charge, which was
                    handsomely done, stopping their flank movement and checking the advance upon
                    Jackson. I rallied again for another charge, as only a portion of my command was
                    in the first, owing to the difficulty of closing up; but finding the enemy had
                    gained the woods to my right and front, leaving no ground for charging, I
                    retired to the next field to give them another dash if they penetrated beyond
                    the woods, which, however, they did not attempt.</p>
                <p>In this encounter the enemy's line, or rather column, was broken and many killed.
                    Capt. Carter's company, on which the heaviest of the action fell, lost 9 men
                    killed or mortally wounded, and-wounded, and 18 horses killed. Capt. Carter's
                    horse was shot dead as he was gallantly leading his company in to the enemy.</p>
                <p>Of the gallantry of those engaged I cannot speak in too high terms. The regiment
                    charged was the Fire Zouaves, and I am informed by prisoners subsequently taken
                    that their repulse by the cavalry began the panic so fearful afterwards in the
                    enemy's ranks.</p>
                <p>Just after the cavalry charge our re-enforcements arrived upon the field and
                    formed rapidly on right into line. The first was Col. Falkner's regiment
                    (Mississippians), whose gallantry came under my own observation. As these
                    re-enforcements formed I gradually moved off to the left, where I soon found
                    myself joined by a battery, under the direction of Lieut. Beckham, which my
                    cavalry supported. This battery made great havoc in the enemy's ranks and
                    finally put them in full retreat. The principal credit here was due to this
                    battery; but having thrown forward vedettes far out on the eminences, the
                    important information I was thus enabled to give the battery as to position and
                    movements must have contributed greatly to its success, and here I may add that
                    this information was also sent back to the infantry, which was still far to our
                    right, notifying what woods could be gained, &amp;</p>
                <p>The enemy being now in full retreat, I followed with the cavalry as rapidly as
                    possible, but was so much encumbered with prisoners, whom I sent as fast as
                    possible back to the infantry, that my command was soon too much reduced to
                    encounter any odds, but I nevertheless followed our success until I reached a
                    point twelve, miles from Manassas, when, by sending back so many detachments
                    with prisoners, I had but a squad left. The rear of the enemy was protected by a
                    squadron of cavalry and some artillery. We cut off a great many squads, many of
                    whom fired upon us as we approached, and the artillery gave us a volley of
                    grape. One man of ours was killed and another wounded at this point. I have no
                    idea how many prisoners were taken.</p>
                <p>I encamped that night on Sudley farm, where was a large church, used as a
                    hospital by the enemy, containing about 300 wounded, the majority mortally.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak in too high praise of those whom I had the honor to command on the
                    field, but to Mr. L. T. Brian, and Mr. P. W. Hairston and J. F. Brown, having no
                    commissions, whose meritorious conduct and worth have been made the subject of
                    previous letters to the general, I was specially indebted for valuable
                    assistance.</p>
                <p>Of my regiment the acting chaplain, Rev. Mr. Ball, was conspicuously useful,
                    while my attention was particularly attracted to the adjutant, Lieut. W. W.
                    Blackford; the sergeant-major, Philip H. Powers, and Lieut. Cummings, whose good
                    conduct on this as on every other occasion deserves high commendation. Lieut.
                    Beckham deserves high praise for the success of his battery, as he acted as
                    gunner to each piece himself. In the pursuit Lieut. William Taylor alone
                    captured six of the enemy with arms in their hands. A large number of arms,
                    quantities of clothing and hospital stores, and means of transportation were
                    found abandoned on the road.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J.E.B. Stuart, Col. First Virginia Cavalry.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
