<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0029"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0029">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Antietam, 107th Pa. Infantry, Report of Capt. James MacThompson,
                    October 7, 1862 </title>
        <title type="sort">antietam, 107th pa infantry report of capt james macthompson october 7 1862</title>
        <author>MacThompson, James</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0029</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500079</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. XXXI. THE MARYLAND CAMPAIGN, No. 28 Report of Capt. James
                            MacThompson, One hundred and seventh Pennsylvania Infantry, First
                            Brigade, of the battles of South Mountain and Antietam.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi the maryland campaign, no 28 report of capt james macthompson one hundred and seventh pennsylvania infantry first brigade of the battles of south mountain and antietam</title>
            <author>James MacThompson</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 19. Part I, Reports. Serial No. 27.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 262</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-07">1862-10-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term/>
                    <term>Regiment: 107th Pa.</term>
                    <term>Company:</term>
                    <term>Battle: Antietam</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0029T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Capt. James MacThompson commanded the 107th Pa. which was in the Army of the
                    Potomac. MacThompson reports that his forces held a numerically superior force
                    at bay before ultimately falling back.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ONE HUNDRED AND SEVENTH PENNSYLVANIA VOLS
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. KENNY, Acting Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-07">October 7, 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Mercerville, Md.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report respecting the One hundred and
                    seventh Regiment Pennsylvania Volunteers in the two actions, September 14 and
                    17, at South Mountain and Antietam:</p>
                <p>The coveted ground gained by our force, and night coming on, no farther advance
                    was made, and both armies lay on their arms, ready for the fierce fight of
                    tomorrow, our brigade having reached a point less than half a mile in rear of
                    the outer pickets.</p>
                <p>At early dawn, agreeably to orders, I moved the One hundred and seventh Regiment
                    by the flank to the field on the right. Here, forming column by divisions, we
                    moved forward through a narrow strip of timber, gained the night previous, into
                    a plowed field, in which, opposite side, Thompson's Pennsylvania battery had
                    just gotten into position. Advancing half way across the field to within easy
                    supporting distance of the battery, we halted for about five minutes, the
                    enemy's shell and round shot haying about us like hail, killing and wounding
                    some of our poor fellows, but not injuring the morale of the regiment in the
                    least. Shortly we were again advancing and passing the battery, and over a
                    clover field reached the spot so frequently mentioned in the reports of this
                    battle--the corn filed. Deploying into line, we entered the field and pushed
                    rapidly through to the other side. Here we found, in different positions, three
                    full brigades of the enemy. We opened fire immediately upon those in front, and
                    in fifteen minutes compelled them to fall back. Receiving re-enforcements,
                    however, he soon regained his position, and an unequal conflict of nearly
                    three-quarters of an hour resulted in forcing us back through the corn-field.
                    Our brigade had, however, done its work. We had held at bay a force of the enemy
                    numerically five times our superior for considerably more than an hour, and at
                    one time driving them. We were now relieved by re-enforcements coming up, and
                    retired to the rear. During the balance of the day we were constantly on the qui
                    vive, but were not again called into action save to support batteries.</p>
                <p>In the battle of Antietam the One hundred and seventh Regiment had 190 men
                    engaged, and lost 19 men killed and 45 wounded, a total loss of 85 killed and
                    wounded in both engagements. Too much cannot be said of the dashing bravery of
                    both officers and men at South Mountain or of their heroic firmness and cool
                    bearing when standing still in line of battle at Antietam. They, for more than
                    an four, received [and returned] the fire of a force infinitely superior.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With much respect, I am, sir, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JAMES MacTHOMSON, <lb/> Capt., Comdg. One hundred and seventh Regt.
                        Pennsylvania Vols., in the engagements of September 14 and 17, 1862. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
