<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0037"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0037">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Fredericksburg, Staunton Artillery, Report of Lieut. Gen. Thomas
                    J. Jackson, January 31, 1863 </title>
        <title type="sort">fredericksburg, staunton artillery report of lieut gen thomas j jackson january 31 1863</title>
        <author>Jackson, T. J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0037</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500087</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. XXXIII. BATTLE OF FREDERICKSBURG, VA., No. 303 Report of Lieut.
                            Gen. Thomas J. Jackson, C. S. Army, commanding Second Army Corps.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxiii battle of fredericksburg, va no 303 report of lieut gen thomas j jackson c s army commanding second army corps</title>
            <author>T. J. Jackson</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 21. Serial No. 31</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 630</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-31">1863-01-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term/>
                    <term>Regiment: Staunton Artillery</term>
                    <term>Company:</term>
                    <term>Battle: Fredericksburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0037T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Gen. Thomas J. Jackson commanded the Second Army Corps of the Army of
                    Northern Virginia, which included the Staunton Artillery. Jackson notes the
                    specific positions of the guns.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. SECOND CORPS, ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. R. H. CHILTON, Asst. Adjt.and Insp. Gen., Army
                        of Northern Virginia. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-31">January 31, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor herewith to submit to you a report of the operations of my corps
                    in the battle of Fredericksburg on Saturday, December 13, last.</p>
                <p>On the morning of that day the troops were arranged as follows: Maj. Gen. A. P.
                    Hill occupied the front line, formed of two regiments of Field's brigade,
                    commanded by Col. [J. M.] Brockenbrough, and the brigades of Archer, Lane, and
                    Pender [posted from right to left in the order named], his right resting on the
                    road leading from Hamilton's Crossing to the Port Royal road, and his left
                    extending to within a short distance of Deep Run. These troops were partially
                    concealed by the wood, near the edge of which they were posted. The remainder of
                    Brockenbrough's command, consisting of the Fortieth and Fifty-fifth Virginia,
                    was immediately in rear of Walker's batteries, and acting as a support to them.
                    Of the other two brigades, Gregg's and Thomas', of the same division, the first
                    was in rear of the interval between Archer and Lane, and the second in rear of
                    the interval between Lane and Pender. The divisions under Gen.'s Early and
                    Taliaferro formed the second line, Early being on the right. The division of
                    Maj. Gen. D. H. Hill, which was still farther in rear, constituted the reserve.
                    Upon the eminence immediately to the right, Lieut.-Col. [R. L.] Walker, [Maj.
                    Gen. A. P. Hill's chief of artillery] had in position fourteen guns, composed of
                    the batteries of Pegram and McIntosh, with sections from the batteries of
                    Crenshaw, Latham, and Johnson, commanded, respectively, by Lieut.'s [J.] Ellett,
                    [J. R.] Potts, and [Valentine J.] Clutter. On the left of the line, and near the
                    Bernard cabins, were posted twenty-one guns, of the batteries of Capt.'s
                    Davidson, Raine, Caskie, and Braxton, all under the immediate direction of Capt.
                    Davidson. To the right and some 200 yards in front of these, and beyond the
                    railroad, were posted twelve guns, from the batteries of Capt.'s Carpenter,
                    Wooding, and Braxton, under the direction of Capt. Brockenbrough, Gen.
                    Taliaferro's chief of artillery; Carpenter's battery commanded by Lieut.
                    [George] McKendree, and Braxton's by Lieut. [Edward A.] Marye. On my left was
                    Maj.-Gen. [John B.] Hood, of Longstreet's corps, and on my right and front the
                    cavalry, under command of Maj.-Gen. [J. E. B.] Stuart, with a battery near the
                    Port Royal road, under the direction of Maj. [John] Pelham, of the Stuart Horse
                    Artillery, aided in the course of the day by sections from the batteries of
                    Capt. [William T.] Poague, Lieut. [Archibald] Graham commanding; Capts. David
                    Watson, B. H. Smith, jr., [A. W.] Garber, [Willis J.] Dance, and the Louisiana
                    Guards, of my corps, thrown into position so as to cross their fire with the
                    guns of Lieut.-Col. Walker, and designed to check the advance of the enemy in
                    that direction.</p>
                <p>I trust that the victory of Fredericksburg, with which god had blessed our cause,
                    will continue to be gratefully remembered.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>T. J. JACKSON, <lb/> Lieut.-Gen. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
