<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0033"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0033">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Fredericksburg, Staunton Artillery, Report of Capt. J.W. Laitmer,
                    December 25, 1862 </title>
        <title type="sort">fredericksburg, staunton artillery report of capt j w laitmer december 25 1862</title>
        <author>Latimer, J.W.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0033</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500083</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. XXXIII. BATTLE OF FREDERICKSBURG, VA., No. 322 Report of Capt.
                            J. W. Latimer, Acting Chief of Artillery.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxiii battle of fredericksburg, va no 322 report of capt j w latimer acting chief of artillery</title>
            <author>J.W. Latimer</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 21. Serial No. 31</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 139</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-25">1862-12-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term/>
                    <term>Regiment: Staunton Artillery</term>
                    <term>Company:</term>
                    <term>Battle: Fredericksburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0033T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Capt. J. W. Latimer was Acting Chief of Artillery of the Staunton Artillery which
                    was in the Army of Northern Virginia. Latimer reports that the batteries' role
                    was to cover the advance of the infantry.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    CAMP NEAR PORT ROYAL, VA
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. S. HALE, Acting Assistant Adjutant-Gen., Ewell's
                        Division. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-25">December 25, 1862</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In obedience to orders, I would most respectfully beg leave to submit the
                    following report of the operations of the batteries of Ewell's division in the
                    engagements with the enemy, near Fredericksburg, on the 13th and 14th of the
                    present month:</p>
                <p>Early on the morning of the 13th, I was ordered by Gen. Early to take command of
                    the batteries of the division as acting chief of artillery, and I immediately
                    reported to Col. Crutchfield, chief of artillery Second Corps, for instructions.
                    He ordered me to park the batteries in a sheltered spot behind a range of hills
                    about half a mile behind our line of battle and there await orders. He shortly
                    after returned and directed me to take my own battery, under command of Lieut.
                    [W. A.] Tanner, and Capt. Brown's, under command of Lieut. [John E.] Plater, to
                    the relief of some batteries occupying a position near the extreme left of the
                    line formed by the Second Corps, and to report to Brig.-Gen. Pender, whose
                    brigade then occupied this position. Only five guns were required, and by
                    direction of Gen. Pender I relieved five of the guns at that point by the two
                    rifles belonging to my battery, and the three rifles composing Capt. Brown's.
                    The position on which these guns were posted was not a very advantageous one,
                    but the best that could be selected. It was a small rising in an open field,
                    with a wood to the right, in which a portion of Gen. A. P. Hill's division was
                    posted, and on the left was a ditch and bank running parallel with the railroad,
                    behind which a portion of Gen. Hood's division was posted. In front, at the
                    distance of about a mile, were four of the enemy's batteries, with lines of
                    skirmishers considerably advanced in front of said batteries. We were exposed to
                    quite a heavy fire from these batteries, but gained the position without loss.
                    My orders were to fire only at infantry unless the batteries advanced, which
                    orders I obeyed, firing only once at them, an then only to cover the advance of
                    Gen. Law's brigade, which was made late in the day. I was kept constantly
                    engaged at this point from 11 a.m. [when I gained it] until night, repelling
                    repeated advanced of the enemy by the use of canister. I relieved these
                    batteries that night by Capt. Carrington's battery, which engaged the enemy next
                    morning upon the advance of their skirmishers, successfully driving them back.</p>
                <p>Shortly after moving to the left with the batteries spoken of above, Capt.
                    D'Aquin's and the Staunton Artillery, Lieut. [A. W.] Garber, were ordered by
                    Col. Crutchfield to the right of our lines, to report to Maj. [John] Pelham,
                    where they were engaged most of the day. Not having personally superintend their
                    movements during the day, I am unable to describe them minutely. Capt. Dement's
                    battery was ordered to the front on 14th, where it remained in battery until we
                    marched to this point, without, however, becoming engaged at any time.</p>
                <p>We have to lament the loss of Capt. L. E. D'Aquin, of the Louisiana Guard
                    Artillery. A more gallant officer or more worthy man never fell upon the field
                    of battle. Also Lieut. [James] Grayson, Capt. Brown's battery. He fell nobly, at
                    his post.</p>
                <p>The losses in the different batteries are as follows:</p>
                <p>Louisiana Guard Artillery [Capt. D'Aquin]: Capt. D'Aquin killed, 1 private
                    wounded, 2 horses disabled, 1 gun disabled.</p>
                <p>Capt. Brown's battery [Lieut. Plater]: Killed, Lieut. Grayson and 1 private;
                    wounded, 9; 16 horses disabled; also 1 gun and 1 caisson.</p>
                <p>Staunton Artillery [Lieut. Garber]: None killed or wounded; 1 horse disabled, and
                    1 gun carriage, afterward repaired.</p>
                <p>Courtney Artillery [Lieut. Tanner]: Killed, 1 private; wounded, Lieut. Tanner and
                    6 privates; 8 horses disabled.</p>
                <p>Capt. Carrington's battery: Wounded,4; horses disabled, 7.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your most obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. W. LATIMER, <lb/> Capt. and Acting Chief of Artillery, Ewell's
                        Division. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
