<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0045"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0045">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 5th Va. Infantry, Report of Maj. Gen. Edward Johnson,
                    September 30, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 5th va infantry report of maj gen edward johnson september 30 1863</title>
        <author>Johnson, Edward</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld, Virginia Center for Digital History</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0045</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500094</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX N.C., VA., W.VA., MD., PA., ETC., No. 481, Reports of
                            Maj. gen. Edward Johnson, C.S. Army, commanding division.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix n c , va w va md pa etc no 481 reports of maj gen edward johnson c s army commanding division</title>
            <author>Edward Johnson</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 27. Part II. Reports. Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 503</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-30">September 30, 1863</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 5th Va. inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0045T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Maj. Gen. Edward Johnson commanded the division of the Army of the Potomac which
                    included the Army of Northern Virginia. Johnson reported a constant, bloody
                    battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Johnson's Division
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. A. S. Pendleton, Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-30">September 30, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Maj.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of my division
                    from June 15 to July 31, embracing the campaign in Pennsylvania and battle of
                    Gettysburg:</p>
                <p>The last day's march was 25 miles, rendered the more fatiguing because of
                    obstructions caused by wagons of Longstreet's corps.</p>
                <p>Late on the night of July 1, I moved along the Gettysburg and York Railroad to
                    the northeast of the town, and formed line of battle in a ravine in an open
                    field, Nicholls' brigade on the right, next Jones'; Steuart's and Walker's on
                    the left. Pickets were thrown well to the front, and the troops slept on their
                    arms.</p>
                <p>Early next morning, skirmishers from Walker's and Jones' brigades were advanced
                    for the purpose of feeling the enemy, and desultory firing was maintained with
                    their skirmishers until 4 p. m., at which hour I ordered Maj. Latimer to open
                    fire with all of his pieces from the only eligible hill within range, Jones'
                    brigade being properly disposed as a support. The hill was directly in front of
                    the wooded mountain and a little to the left of the Cemetery Hill; consequently
                    exposed to the concentrated fire from both, and also to an enfilade fire from a
                    battery near the Baltimore road. The unequal contest was maintained for two
                    hours with considerable damage to the enemy, as will appear from the
                    accompanying report of Lieut.-Col. Andrews. Maj. Latimer having reported to me
                    that the exhausted condition of his horses and men, together with the terrible
                    fire of the enemy's artillery, rendered his position untenable, he was ordered
                    to cease firing and withdraw all of his pieces excepting four, which were left
                    in position to cover the advance of my infantry.</p>
                <p>In obedience to an order from the lieutenant-general commanding, I then advanced
                    my infantry to the assault of the enemy's strong position--a rugged and rocky
                    mountain, heavily timbered and difficult of ascent; a natural fortification,
                    rendered more formidable by deep intrenchments and thick abatis--Jones' brigade
                    in advance, followed by Nicholls' and Steuart's. Gen. Walker was directed to
                    follow, but reporting to me that the enemy were advancing upon him from their
                    right, he was ordered to repulse them and follow on as soon as possible.</p>
                <p>The opposing force was larger and the time consumed longer than was anticipated,
                    in consequence of which Gen. Walker did not arrive in time to participate in the
                    assault that night.</p>
                <p>By the time my other brigades had crossed Rock Creek and reached the base of the
                    mountain, it was dark. His skirmishers were driven in, and the attack made with
                    great vigor and spirit. It was as successful as could have been expected,
                    considering the superiority of the enemy's force and position. Steuart's
                    brigade, on the left, carried a line of breastworks which ran perpendicular to
                    the enemy's main line, captured a number of prisoners and a stand of colors, and
                    the whole line advanced to within short range, and kept up a heavy fire until
                    late in the night. Brig.-Gen. Jones and Col. Higginbotham, Twenty-fifth
                    Virginia, were wounded in this assault, and the command of Jones' brigade
                    devolved upon Lieut.-Col. Dungan.</p>
                <p>Early next morning, the Stonewall Brigade was ordered to the support of the
                    others, and the assault was renewed with great determination. Shortly after, the
                    enemy moved forward to recapture the line of breastworks which had been taken
                    the night previous, but was repulsed with great slaughter. Daniel's and Rodes'
                    brigades (Col. [E. A.] O'Neal commanding), of Rodes' division, having reported
                    to me, two other assaults were made; both failed. The enemy were too securely
                    intrenched and in too great numbers to be dislodged by the force at my command.</p>
                <p>In the meantime, a demonstration in force was made upon my left and rear. The
                    Second Virginia Regt., Stonewall Brigade, and Smith's brigade, of Early's
                    division, were disposed to meet and check it, which was accomplished to my
                    entire satisfaction. No further assault was made; all had been done that it was
                    possible to do.</p>
                <p>I held my original position until 10 o'clock of the night of the 3d, when, in
                    accordance with orders, I withdrew to the hill north and west of Gettysburg,
                    where we remained until the following day, in the hope that the enemy would give
                    us battle on ground of our own selection.</p>
                <p>My loss in this terrible battle was heavy, including some of the most valuable
                    officers of the command.</p>
                <p>Maj. J. W. Latimer, of Andrews' battalion, the "boy major," whose chivalrous
                    bearing on so many fields had won for him a reputation to be envied by his
                    seniors, received a severe wound on the evening of the 2d, from the effects of
                    which he has since died.</p>
                <p>Maj. B. W. Leigh, my chief of staff, whose conscientious discharge of duty,
                    superior attainments, and noble bearing made him invaluable to me, was killed
                    within a short distance of the enemy's line.</p>
                <p>Maj. H. K. Douglas, assistant adjutant-general, was severely wounded while in the
                    discharge of his duties, and is still a prisoner.</p>
                <p>My orderly, W. H. Webb, remained with me after being severely wounded. His
                    conduct entitles him to a commission.</p>
                <p>Fewer wounded from my division were left in the hands of the enemy than from any
                    other division of the army; for which I am indebted to the active exertions of
                    Chief Surg. R. T. Coleman.</p>
                <p>Mr. E. J. Martin, my volunteer aide-de-camp, rendered valuable service by his
                    prompt transmission of orders, and Maj. E. L. Moore faithfully performed his
                    duties as assistant inspector-general.</p>
                <p>The troops are much indebted to Majs. T. E. Ballard and G. H. Kyle, of the
                    commissary department, for supplies during the trying period covered by this
                    report. Cattle and flour were frequently procured within the enemy's lines.</p>
                <p>All of the officers and men of the division who came under my observation during
                    their three days' exposure to the enemy's incessant fire of musketry and
                    artillery from the front and artillery from the left and rear behaved as brave
                    men.</p>
                <p>For particular instances of gallantry, I have the honor to refer you to the
                    reports of brigade and regimental commanders, herewith transmitted.</p>
                <p>I take pleasure in bearing testimony to the gallantry of Brig.-Gen. Daniel and
                    Col. O'Neal, and to Brig.-Gen. [William] Smith, and their brigades, while under
                    my command.</p>
                <p>We marched on the 5th across the mountain, by Waynesborough, toward Hagerstown,
                    and remained for a few days within 3 miles of the latter place. Thence the
                    division moved 2 1/2 miles from Hagerstown, and formed line of battle on both
                    sides of and perpendicular to the Hagerstown and Williamsport pike.</p>
                <p>On the night of the 13th, I recrossed the Potomac 1 mile above Williamsport, and
                    continued the march next day to within 4 miles of Martinsburg; thence to
                    Darkesville on the 15th, where we remained until ordered to return to
                    Martinsburg, to destroy the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and repel an advance of
                    the enemy. This done, the division by steady marches recrossed the Blue Ridge at
                    Front Royal, and went into camp near Orange Court-House about August 1.</p>
                <p>The casualties in my division during the operations around Gettysburg were:
                    Killed, 219; wounded, 1,229; missing, 375; total, 1,823.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, with great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>ED. JOHNSON, Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
