<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0047"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0047">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 52nd Va. Infantry, Report of Col. John S. Hoffman,
                    August 4, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 52nd va infantry report of col john s hoffman august 4 1863</title>
        <author>Hoffman, John S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0047</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500096</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX THE GETTYSBURG CAMPAIGN, No. 476 Report of Col. John S.
                            Hoffman, Thirty-first Virginia Infantry, commanding Smith's Brigade.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix the gettysburg campaign, no 476 report of col john s hoffman thirty first virginia infantry commanding smiths brigade</title>
            <author>John S. Hoffman</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 27. Part II. Reports. Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 488</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-04">1863-08-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52nd Va. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0047T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. John S. Hoffman commanded the brigade of the Army of Northern Virginia which
                    included the 52nd Va. Inf. Hoffman reports little pitched fighting during the
                    battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Smith's Brigade
                    <name type="recipient"> Maj. John W. Daniel, Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-04">August 4, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Maj.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>This brigade was commanded by Gen. [William] Smith from the time it left the
                    vicinity of Fredericksburg till July 10 last, when, having tendered his
                    resignation and obtained leave of absence, the command devolved upon me. The
                    brigade accompanied the main body of the division during the campaign, excepting
                    that portions were temporarily detached, as will be mentioned.</p>
                <p>Having left the Thirteenth and Fifty-eighth Virginia Regt.'s near Winchester,
                    only the three others constituting the brigade, on July 1 it formed on the
                    northward of the town of Gettysburg, and twice moved forward toward the town.
                    After the enemy had been driven beyond the town, the brigade moved to the left,
                    crossing the [Gettysburg] Railroad and York turnpike. The Forty-ninth Virginia
                    Regt. was advanced as skirmishers. On several occasions during the day the
                    brigade was exposed to fire from the enemy's batteries.</p>
                <p>On the 2d, it being reported that the enemy's cavalry was approaching from the
                    northward, the brigade, with that of Gen. Gordon, moved on the York turnpike,
                    and the Forty-ninth Virginia Regt. was sent forward as skirmishers, and the
                    Thirty-first Virginia Regt. was sent across to the Hunterstown road, to report
                    to Maj.-Gen. Stuart, who ordered that it should remain in support of a part of
                    his cavalry during the night.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 3d, the Forty-ninth and Fifty-second Virginia Regt.'s moved
                    to the left and forward eastwardly, crossing the creek, and formed between the
                    creek and the enemy's works near the left of Gen. Johnson's division, and thence
                    moved to the left, and formed nearly at right angles to the extreme left of that
                    division, when the Forty-ninth, supported by the Fifty-second Virginia Regt.,
                    advanced upon a large body of the enemy near the left flank of that division,
                    and dislodged it from its position. The Thirty-first Virginia Regt. having been
                    relieved by Gen. Stuart and joining the others about this time, the Forty-ninth
                    Virginia Regt. was left, while the other two regiments recrossed the creek and
                    moved down southeastwardly, and formed, and thence moved back up the creek and
                    to the rear, and rested, when they were joined by the Forty-ninth Virginia Regt.</p>
                <p>Early in the afternoon, the brigade moved, and again crossed the creek and formed
                    under the enemy's works to the right of its former position, in rear of the
                    Stonewall Brigade, of Gen. Johnson's division, where it remained till after
                    dark. During most of the early part of the day the brigade was exposed to a
                    heavy fire of artillery, and during a part to that of musketry also. The
                    Forty-ninth Virginia Regt. suffered very severely, losing, indeed, more than two
                    fifths of its members. During the latter part of the day, the brigade was much
                    annoyed by the fire of the enemy's sharpshooters, protected by rocks.</p>
                <p>In the night, the brigade moved to the rear and around to the right, and, on the
                    morning of the 4th, formed westward of the town, on a ridge to the left of the
                    Chambersburg turnpike, on the left of Gen. Gordon's and right of Gen. Hays'
                    brigade, where we remained during the day.</p>
                <p>During the three days of the battle, the loss of the brigade was 3 officers and
                    12 men killed, 5 officers and 105 men wounded, and 17 men missing.</p>
                <p>On all occasions of exposure to danger during the campaign, as far as my
                    observation has extended, while the conduct of the officers has been, without
                    exception, highly creditable, the unfaltering steadiness of the men has
                    surpassed anything that I had before witnessed.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>J. S. HOFFMAN, Col., Comdg. Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
