<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0041"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0041">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Chancellorsville, 126th Pa. Infantry, Report of Brig. Gen.
                    Erastus B. Tyler, May 10, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">chancellorsville, 126th pa infantry report of brig gen erastus b tyler may 10 1863</title>
        <author>Tyler, Erastus B.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0041</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500090</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. XXXVII. THE CHANCELLORSVILLE CAMPAIGN, Report of Brig. Gen.
                            Erastus B. Tyler, U. S. Army, commanding First Brigade.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii the chancellorsville campaign, report of brig gen erastus b tyler u s army commanding first brigade</title>
            <author>Erastus B. Tyler</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 25. Part I, Reports. Serial No. 39.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 551</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-10">1863-05-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term/>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa.</term>
                    <term>Company:</term>
                    <term>Battle: Chancellorsville</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0041T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. Erastus B. Tyler commanded the First Brigade of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 126th Pa. Tyler reports that the brigade faced a
                    greater enemy force and ultimately had to retire.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    CAMP NEAR FALMOUTH, VA.
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. CARSWELL McCLELLAN, A. A. G., Third Division, </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-10">May 10, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to transmit herewith a list of casualties of my command in the
                    action of the 3d instant, and also to submit the following report of the part
                    taken by my brigade in that engagement:</p>
                <p>About 9 a.m. I received an order from Maj.-Gen. Meade to put my command in
                    motion, and go to the support of Gen. French, Lieut.-Col. Webb to indicate the
                    position we were to occupy. That officer in person out the line we were to take
                    possession of, directly in the face of the enemy, and on the right of Gen.
                    French's command, in the woods.</p>
                <p>The regiments were scarcely in position before the enemy opened fire upon us,
                    which was promptly and effectively returned by our men. I at once saw the enemy
                    outnumbered us, as they were in double line, and extended beyond our right. I
                    immediately asked for re-enforcements, but was informed they could not be
                    furnished. Col. Webb, who had remained in front for same moments, started back
                    promising to bring up re-enforcements if he could obtain them, but he returned
                    in a short time without them. The rapid and incessant fire of our men prevented
                    the enemy form advancing, although they made several efforts to do so.</p>
                <p>After holding our position for nearly or perhaps quite and hour, reports reached
                    me that our ammunition was being exhausted, many of the men supplying themselves
                    from the dead and wounded. About this time, I discovered that the enemy was
                    receiving re-enforcements; another double line was plainly seen advancing and
                    extending farther to our right. I sent for ammunition twice without being able
                    to obtain it, as, I afterward understood, it had not come up from the rear. I
                    reported the fact to Gen. French, with the further information that the enemy
                    were pressing us, and asked for orders. He replied that he could not furnish me
                    with ammunition, and that we should retire in as good order as we could when we
                    had exhausted what we had. The moment our fire slackened the enemy pushed
                    forward with at least twice our number.</p>
                <p>As near as I can tell, we were in position from an hour to an hour and
                    three-quarters before we were forced to retire. During this time the whole line
                    was under my eye, and I to say that I never saw officers and men behave with
                    more bravery and coolness than did the entire command. The officers were very
                    active, and I saw many of them aiding the men by preparing their cartridges for
                    the guns. The field officers were passing up and down the line, encouraging
                    their men with great spirit and coolness.</p>
                <p>The Ninety-first Pennsylvania Volunteers was on the right, and received the first
                    fire of the enemy. They are entitled to great credit for their conduct during
                    the action. Col. Gregory received a slight would early in the engagement, and
                    left the field, yet the men kept well at their work, under Lieut.-Col. Sinex.</p>
                <p>The One hundred and thirty-fourth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers, Col. O'Brien,
                    was second in line, and no set of men could have behaved better. The officers,
                    one and all, following the example of their colonel (who was constantly on the
                    alert), were very active, and not a man shirked his duty.</p>
                <p>The One hundred and twenty-sixth Pennsylvania Volunteers, Lieut. Col. D. W. Rowe,
                    was third in line, and for earnest, spirited work it could not be excelled. Col.
                    Rowe exhibited the true characteristics of the soldier-brave, cool, and
                    determined-and this spirit was infused into every officer and soldier of his
                    command.</p>
                <p>The One hundred and twenty-ninth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers was on our left,
                    and no man ever saw cooler work on field drill than was done by this regiment.
                    Their firing was grand-by rank, by company, and by wings, in perfect order. Col.
                    Frick's stentorian voice was heard above the roar of the musketry, and, with the
                    aid of his lieutenant-colonel and major, his regiment was splendidly handled,
                    doing its duty well.</p>
                <p>Too much credit cannot be given the officers and men of this brigade; not a
                    single neglect came under my notice during the engagement. The colors of the
                    different regiments show that they were carried well to the front, and I saw
                    them repeatedly waved in the face of the enemy. The officers of my staff,
                    Capt.'s [Henry C.] Ranney and [William H.] Davidson, and Lieut.'s [James B.]
                    Diehl and [Stearns E.] Tyler, rendered me every assistance in their power, under
                    an incessant fire.</p>
                <p>Among the officers seriously wounded, I have with regret to mention Maj. Anthony,
                    of the One hundred and I went-ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers, a true soldier and
                    dutiful officer. Lieut.-Col.'s Rowe and Shaw were slightly wounded, as was also
                    Lieut. Diehl, aide-de-camp.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, &amp;,</salute>
                    <signed>E. B. TYLER, <lb/> Brig.-Gen., Cmdg. Brigade. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
