<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0044"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0044">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 5th Va. Infantry, Report of Col. J.H.S. Funk, August
                    18, 1863 </title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 5th va infantry report of col j h s funk august 18 1863</title>
        <author>Funk, J.H.S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0044</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500093</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX THE GETTYSBURG CAMPAIGN, No. 492 Report of Col. J.H.S.
                            Funk, Fifth Virginia Infantry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix the gettysburg campaign, no 492 report of col j h s funk fifth virginia infantry</title>
            <author>J.H.S. Funk</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 27. Part II. Reports. Serial No. 44.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 526</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-13">1863-08-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 5th Va. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0044T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. J. H. S. Funk commanded the Fifth Virginia Infantry which was in the Army of
                    Northern Virginia. Funk reports that the regiment fought the enemy before its
                    works until the regiment ran out of ammunition.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. C. S. Arnall, Acting Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-18">August 18, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>In conformity to a circular from brigade headquarters, I have the honor of
                    submitting the following report of the engagement at Gettysburg:</p>
                <p>On the morning of July 1, my regiment left camp near Fayetteville with the
                    brigade. We crossed South Mountain, and marched in the direction of Gettysburg,
                    where Gen. Heth's division had engaged the enemy. Reached Gettysburg near dark,
                    passing through a portion of the town, and following the York and Gettysburg
                    Railroad nearly 2 miles, then filing to the right, where we were thrown in line
                    of battle with the brigade on the extreme left of the division, northeast of the
                    town, my regiment being in the center of the brigade.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 2d, we were aroused early by our skirmishers firing. We
                    remained in this position until late in the afternoon, when, after changing our
                    position several times, moved in direction of Wolf's Mountain (or Red Hill),
                    where the enemy had taken refuge.</p>
                <p>About 2 a. m. of the 3d, we were placed in position in rear of Steuart's brigade.
                    At dawn we moved up to some breastworks, behind which lay Steuart's brigade, who
                    were then skirmishing with the enemy. Remained here an hour or more; then
                    ordered by Gen. Walker to the right, to relieve the Fourth Virginia, which had
                    exhausted their ammunition. Advancing to the top of the hill in front of the
                    enemy's works, we were engaged for over two hours. After having exhausted our
                    ammunition, and used the cartridges of the killed and wounded, were relieved by
                    Daniel's brigade. The brigade was then reformed. Moving to the right some 400
                    yards, relieved Gen. Nicholls' brigade, where we were hotly engaged for some
                    three-quarters of an hour, under a murderous and enfilading fire.</p>
                <p>The line on the left began to give way, which was soon followed by the whole
                    line. Falling back some 300 yards, reformed, and took position on the right of
                    Jones' brigade, where we remained skirmishing with the enemy until 1 a. m. the
                    4th, when we fell back, and took position on the hills 1 mile westward of the
                    town, the enemy being in too crippled a condition to follow.</p>
                <p>It is gratifying to state that the coolness, bravery, and determination displayed
                    by both officers and men during this engagement have not been equaled by them on
                    any of the hard-fought fields which have been marked by their dead. Their
                    efforts not being crowned with the usual success, they retired stubbornly from
                    the field, manifesting a willingness to hurl themselves upon the foe again, if
                    so ordered.</p>
                <p>I regret the loss of Lieut. Jacob [H.] Keifer, who fell, mortally wounded. He was
                    a gallant and efficient officer. His loss is felt throughout the command.</p>
                <p>Color-Sergeant Speck deserves mentioning for his gallantry throughout the
                    engagement.</p>
                <p>The casualties were 3 killed, 42 wounded, and 11 missing.*</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>J. H. S. FUNK, Col. Fifth Virginia Infantry.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
