<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0050"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0050">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 52nd Va. Infantry, Report of Lieut. Col. H.P. Jones,
                    August 18, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 52nd va infantry report of lieut col h p jones august 18 1863</title>
        <author>Jones, H.P.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0050</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500099</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX N. C., VA., W. VA., MD., PA., ETC., No. 478 Report of
                            Lieut. Col. H.P. Jones, C.S. Army, commanding Artillery Battalion.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix n c , va w va md pa etc no 478 report of lieut col h p jones c s army commanding artillery battalion</title>
            <author>H.P. Jones</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. Vol. 27. Part II. Reports. Serial No. 44.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 495</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-18">1863-08-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52nd Va. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0050T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Col. H. P. Jones commanded the Artillery Battalion of the Army of Northern
                    Virginia which included the Staunton Artillery. Jones reports that on July 1st,
                    the battalion fired at the retreating enemy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"> Maj. John W. Daniel, Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-18">August 18, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report of the operations of this battalion
                    from the time it was attached to Gen. Early's division until its return into
                    Virginia:</p>
                <p>After resting at York one day, we marched back in the direction of Gettysburg,
                    before which place we arrived on Wednesday, July 1. Here, finding the enemy
                    heavily engaging Gen. Rodes on our right, the major-general commanding ordered
                    me to put the batteries in position, so as to open fire. Acting under his
                    orders, I immediately placed twelve guns in position, and opened fire with
                    considerable effect on the enemy's artillery, and upon the flank of a column of
                    troops that were being massed upon our right.</p>
                <p>On the advance of Gen. Gordon's brigade from our right, we directed our fire
                    farther to the left, on the disordered masses of the enemy that were rapidly
                    retreating before our troops. This was continued until the advance of our men
                    rendered it dangerous to continue firing from that position. I immediately, by
                    order of Gen. Early, sent Capt. Carrington's battery across the creek to take
                    position in front of Gettysburg, but, moving with all rapidity, as it did,
                    before it could reach any position the enemy had been driven through the town by
                    Hays' brigade. In the first position we occupied, three guns were temporarily
                    disabled by having shots wedged in the bores, and one Napoleon permanently
                    disabled by being struck on the face of the muzzle and bent by a solid shot from
                    the enemy.</p>
                <p>We had 1 man killed of Capt. Green's, and 1 man of Capt. Garber's battery
                    wounded. The guns that were temporarily disabled were soon rendered fit for
                    service again, and I was enabled to replace the Napoleon gun permanently
                    disabled by one of the two Napoleon guns captured by Gen. Hays' brigade. The
                    disabled gun and the other captured Napoleon I had carried and turned over to
                    the ordnance department, thereby securing them.</p>
                <p>In the other two days of the battle of Gettysburg, my battalion was not actively
                    engaged, but was in position to guard against a reported flank movement of the
                    enemy on our left, and afterward any advance the enemy might attempt to make
                    from the hills in front of Gettysburg.</p>
                <p>On the 2d, I ordered two guns of Capt. Green's battery, at the request of Gen.
                    Stuart, to report to Gen. Hampton at Hunterstown, where he engaged the enemy,
                    with a loss of 1 man killed and 1 sergeant and 14 men wounded.</p>
                <p>Capt. Tanner having exhausted his ammunition, excepting a few rounds of canister,
                    and it being impossible to supply him, I ordered him to go with the wagon train
                    to the rear. When this was attacked in the mountains, he rendered very efficient
                    service with his few rounds of canister, driving back the enemy's cavalry. Here
                    he lost 2 men, missing. On reaching Williamsport, he received more ammunition,
                    and rendered good service when the wagon train was attacked, with a loss of 1
                    man and 2 horses killed and 1 horse disabled.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 5th, we fell back from Gettysburg, the division bringing up
                    the rear of the army, and continued our march to Hagerstown, where we remained
                    in line of battle a few days; then recrossed the river. Two empty wagons,
                    ordered to report to the surgeon at Gettysburg, to bring off the wounded, have
                    never since been heard from. One forge sent over with the wagon train was lost
                    at the river.</p>
                <p>In the expedition to and around Hedgesville, Capt. Tanner's battery was detached,
                    and went to Johnsontown with Col. [Lawrence S.] Baker, commanding cavalry
                    brigade, where it fired a few rounds at the enemy across the river. From
                    Hagerstown to this point the horses suffered very much from long marches and
                    want of proper food.</p>
                <p>My thanks are due to both officers and men for their conduct in presence of the
                    enemy and the patience with which they endured the hardships of the campaign.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>H. P. JONES, Lieut.-Col., Comdg. Artillery Battalion.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
