<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0053"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0053">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 107th Pa. Infantry, Report of Capt. Emanuel D. Roath,
                    August 15, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 107th pa infantry report of capt emanuel d roath august 15 1863</title>
        <author>Roath, Emanuel D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0053</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500102</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX THE GETTYSBURG CAMPAIGN, No. 51 Report of Capt. Emanuel
                            D. Roath, One hundred and seventh Pennsylvania Infantry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix the gettysburg campaign, no 51 report of capt emanuel d roath one hundred and seventh pennsylvania infantry</title>
            <author>Emanuel D. Roath</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 27. Part I. Reports., Serial No. 43.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 304</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-15">1863-08-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 107th Pa.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0053T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Emanuel D. Roath was a member of the one hundred and seventh Pennsylvania
                    Infantry of the Army of the Potomac. Roath reports that on July 2, his unit
                    assisted in repulsing the Confederate charge.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. Byron Porter, Asst. Adjt. Gen., First Brig., Second
                        Div., First Army Corps. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-15">August 15, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Rappahannock, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Capt.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report, as per orders from brigade
                    headquarters, from June 28 to July 22, inclusive, viz:</p>
                <p>The following is the report of Lieut. Col. J. MacThomson, of the One hundred and
                    seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, during the action of July 1, at Gettysburg, he
                    being in command up to that time, viz:</p>
                <p>July 1.--After the engagement, we fell back to the left of Cemetery Hill, and
                    threw up strong breastworks, which we occupied until next morning.</p>
                <p>July 2.--During the forenoon we were relieved by the Third Division, Second
                    Corps, and taken a few hundred yards in the rear to support a battery. We lay on
                    our arms until about 6.30 p. m., when we were marched to the left, toward the
                    Round Top, under a heavy and effective fire, to assist in driving the rebel
                    hordes back in the famous charge of the second day of the fight. After the
                    charge, we marched back to near the cemetery, and were ordered to lay in rear of
                    a stone fence, being a protection for the men from the enemy's sharpshooters in
                    our front.</p>
                <p>Our casualties during the second day were 1 commissioned officer and several men
                    wounded. Our strength was about 78 guns and 12 commissioned officers.</p>
                <p>July 3.--At 4.30 a. m. we were posted in the rear of Cemetery Hill, in support of
                    the batteries stationed on that point, remaining in that position until 1.30 p.
                    m., when the enemy opened upon us with a heavy and furious artillery fire. Our
                    division was moved to the right of Cemetery Hill, at the same time lying under
                    two direct fires of the enemy's sharpshooters and one battery. The strife became
                    terrific and the artillery firing terrible. At this crisis our services were
                    required to support the batteries, when the regiment was marched with others
                    along the crest or brow of the hill in rear of the batteries, through the most
                    deadly fire ever man passed through, it appearing as though every portion of the
                    atmosphere contained a deadly missile.</p>
                <p>After our services were no longer needed to support the batteries, the division
                    to which my regiment was attached was moved to the left of Cemetery Hill, to
                    participate in crowning our arms with the glorious victory achieved that day.</p>
                <p>My strength was about 72 guns and 11 commissioned officers. Casualties, 2
                    commissioned officers wounded; 1 private killed and several slightly wounded.
                    The day being very hot, 3 of my men were carried insensible from the field on
                    account of the intense heat.</p>
                <p>After resting a few hours, we sent out a line of skirmishers to the front, and
                    threw up breastworks to protect the men in our position, where we remained for
                    the night.</p>
                <p>July 4.--We lay all day in the position of the previous night and strengthened
                    it; did some skirmishing with the enemy's sharpshooters; had no casualties.</p>
                <p>It is proper here for me to state that the officers and men displayed great
                    gallantry and determination throughout all the engagements of the previous days,
                    and are entitled to the praise and gratitude of a free and loyal people.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted. I am, captain, with much respect, your most
                        obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>E. D. ROATH, Capt., Comdg. One hundred and seventh Pa. Vols.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
