<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0056"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0056">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 107th Pa. Infantry, Report of Brig. Gen. John C.
                    Robinson, July 18, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 107th pa infantry report of brig gen john c robinson july 18 1863</title>
        <author>Robinson, John C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0056</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500104</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX N. C., VA., W. VA., MD., PA., ETC., No. 43 Report of
                            Brig. Gen. John C. Robinson, U. S. Army, commanding Second Division.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix n c , va w va md pa etc no 43 report of brig gen john c robinson u s army commanding second division</title>
            <author>John C. Robinson</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 27. PartI Reports, Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 289</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-18">1863-07-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 107th Pa.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0056T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. John C. Robinson commanded the Second Division of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 107th Pa. Robinson reports that his men continually
                    repelled enemy attacks.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Second Division, First Army Corps,
                    <name type="recipient">The Assistant Adjutant-Gen., First Army Corps. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-18">July 18, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of this
                    division in the engagements of the 1st, 2d, and 3d instant:</p>
                <p>On the morning of Wednesday, the 1st, the division marched from Emmitsburg,
                    bringing up the rear of the column, and when about 3 miles from Gettysburg,
                    hearing firing in front, it was pushed rapidly forward, and, arriving on the
                    field, was placed, by order of the major- general commanding First Corps, in
                    reserve, near the seminary. Almost immediately after taking this position, I
                    received notice that the enemy was advancing a heavy column of infantry on the
                    right of our line of battle, when I sent the Second Brigade, under Brig.-Gen.
                    Baxter, to meet it. Orders being received at this time to hold the seminary, the
                    First Brigade, under Brig.-Gen. Paul, was set at work to intrench the ridge on
                    which it is situated. I then rode to the right of the line, to superintend the
                    operations there. On my arrival, I found my Second Brigade so placed as to cover
                    our right flank, but with too great an interval between it and the line of the
                    First Division. I at once directed Gen. Baxter to change front forward on his
                    left battalion, and to close this interval, toward which the enemy was making
                    his way. By the time this change was effected, the whole front of the brigade
                    became hotly engaged, but succeeded in repulsing the attack. The enemy, however,
                    soon after brought up fresh forces in increased masses, when, finding the
                    position so seriously threatened, I sent for and brought up the First Brigade,
                    and placed part of it in the position first occupied by Baxter's brigade, and
                    the remaining battalions as a support to his second position. The enemy now made
                    repeated attacks on the division, in all of which he was handsomely repulsed,
                    with the loss of three flags and about 1,000 prisoners.</p>
                <p>In one of these attacks I was deprived of the services of the veteran commander
                    of the First Brigade, Brig.-Gen. Paul, who fell, severely wounded, while
                    gallantly directing and encouraging his command.</p>
                <p>The division held this position on the right--receiving and repelling the fierce
                    attacks of a greatly superior force, not only in front, but on the flank, and,
                    when the enemy's ranks were broken, charging upon him and capturing his colors
                    and men--from about noon until nearly 5 p. m., when I received orders to
                    withdraw. These orders not being received until all other troops (except
                    Stewart's battery) had commenced moving to the rear, the division held its
                    ground until outflanked right and left, and retired fighting.</p>
                <p>From the nature of the enemy's attacks, frequent changes were rendered necessary,
                    and they were made promptly under a galling fire. No soldiers ever fought
                    better, or inflicted severer blows upon the enemy. When out of ammunition, their
                    boxes were replenished from those of their killed and wounded comrades.</p>
                <p>The instances of distinguished gallantry are too numerous to be embodied in this
                    report, and I leave it to the brigade and regimental commanders to do justice to
                    those under their immediate command. Where all did so well, it is difficult to
                    discriminate. As, however, they came under my personal observation, I cheerfully
                    indorse the remarks of Gen. Baxter in commendation of Col. Coulter, Eleventh
                    Pennsylvania; Col. Wheelock, Ninety-seventh New York; Col. Lyle, Ninetieth
                    Pennsylvania; Col. Bates and Lieut.-Col. Allen, Twelfth Massachusetts;
                    Lieut.-Col. Moesch, Eighty-third New York, and Maj. Foust, Eighty-eighth
                    Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>After the fall of Gen. Paul, the command of the First Brigade devolved
                    successively upon Col. Leonard, Thirteenth Massachusetts, Col. Root,
                    Ninety-fourth New York, and Col. Coulter, Eleventh Pennsylvania, all of whom
                    were wounded while exercising the command.</p>
                <p>After withdrawing from this contest, I took up a position on a ridge to the left
                    of the cemetery, facing the Emmitsburg road, and remained there until afternoon
                    of the next day, when I was relieved by a division of the Second Corps, and
                    ordered to the support of the Eleventh Corps. In the evening, I was ordered to
                    the left of our line, but was soon after directed to return.</p>
                <p>On Friday morning, 3d instant, the division was massed, and held ready to push
                    forward to the support of the Twelfth Corps, then engaged with the enemy on our
                    right.</p>
                <p>About noon, I was informed by the major-general commanding the army that he
                    anticipated an attack on the cemetery by the enemy's forces massed in the town,
                    and was directed to so place my command that if our line gave way I could attack
                    the enemy on his flank. I proceeded to make this change of position at the
                    moment the enemy commenced the terrific artillery fire of that day. Never before
                    were troops so exposed to such a fire of shot and shell, and yet the movement
                    was made in perfect order and with little loss.</p>
                <p>Later in the day, the enemy having made his attack on our left instead of the
                    center, I was ordered to the right of the Second Corps, which position I held
                    until Sunday, when the line was withdrawn.</p>
                <p>My thanks are due to Brig.-Gen.'s Baxter and Paul for the able and zealous manner
                    in which they handled their brigades. The officers of my staff were actively
                    engaged during the whole of the three days' engagements. Lieut. [Samuel M.]
                    Morgan, acting assis tant adjutant-general; Lieut. [Frederick M.] Hallock,
                    aide-de-camp, and Lieut.'s Bratton and Mead, acting aides, were at all times
                    distinguished for their gallantry and good conduct. Capt. [John G.] Hovey,
                    acting assistant inspector-general, was wounded and taken from the field early
                    in the fight. Lieut. Smith, ordnance officer, was diligent in the performance of
                    his duty, and collected and turned in 2,251 muskets and a large number of
                    equipments.</p>
                <p>It affords me pleasure to call special attention to the gallant conduct of one of
                    my orderlies, Sergt. Ebenezer S. Johnson, First Maine Cavalry, whose chevrons
                    should be exchanged for the epaulette. When we make officers of such men, the
                    soldier receives his true reward and the service great benefit.</p>
                <p>This division went into battle with less than 2,500 officers and men, and
                    sustained a loss of 1,667, of which 124 were commissioned officers.</p>
                <p> I transmit herewith a nominal and tabular statement of casualties, showing the
                    loss of each regiment.<ref n="1" target="note1">[1]</ref></p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JNO. C. ROBINSON, Brig.-Gen., Comdg. Division.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="notes" id="d6">
                <head>Notes</head>
                <p>
                    <note n="1" id="note1" place="foot"><seg type="note-symbol"><hi rend="super">[1]</hi></seg><p> See letter of Jno. C. Robinson to George C. Meade dated<lb/>
                        November 15, 1863.</p></note>
                </p>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
