<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0065"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0065">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 17th Pa. Cavalry, Reports of Maj. Gen. Alfred
                    Pleasonton, August 5, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 17th pa cavalry reports of maj gen alfred pleasonton august 5 1863</title>
        <author>Funk, J.H.S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0065</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500112</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI MINE RUN, VIRGINIA, CAMPAIGN, No. 111 Report of Col. J. H.
                            S. Funk, Fifth Virginia Infantry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli mine run, virginia campaign no 111 report of col j h s funk fifth virginia infantry</title>
            <author>J.H.S. Funk</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 29. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 852</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-22">1864-01-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 5th Va. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Payne's Farm/Mine Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0065T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. J. H. S. Funk commanded the Fifth Virginia Infantry. He reports being hotly
                    engaged with the enemy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"> Capt. R. J. BARTON, Assistant Adjutant-General. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-22">JANUARY 22, 1864</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPTAIN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In obedience to circular, I have the honor to submit the following report of the
                    part taken by my regiment in the engagement at Payne's Farm, November 27, 1863:</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 26, I was ordered, in company with the brigade, down the
                    Germanna Ford road, which runs through our fortifications, behind which we lay
                    the previous night, and keeping this road for near a mile, we turned off
                    abruptly to the right, crossing Mine Run at Bartlett's Mill. Continuing on the
                    old Culpeper and Fredericksburg road 2 miles, we halted, hearing heavy
                    skirmishing in front. In a few minutes, to my surprise, I heard skirmishing in
                    our rear along the road which we had traveled. We faced about and marched back
                    some 200 yards. Skirmishers were deployed and soon became engaged. We then
                    fronted and moved in advance of the road some 50 paces, when we received orders
                    to erect temporary fortifications.</p>
                <p>In a few minutes an order was received from the brigade commander to prepare to
                    move forward, it having been ascertained that there was nothing but the enemy's
                    cavalry in our front. The regiment was immediately put in motion. A charge was
                    commenced on the left of the brigade, which was immediately taken up by my
                    regiment. After proceeding about 200 yards, and arriving at the edge of the
                    field, I found that my regiment was very much scattered, owing to the denseness
                    of the undergrowth. I halted and reformed it. By this time the left of the
                    brigade became engaged with the enemy's infantry, posted behind a fence at the
                    skirt of a woods which run at right angles with our line of battle. Finding no
                    enemy in my front, I wheeled my regiment to the left and took position in a lane
                    leading to and some 300 yards from the residence of Mr. Madison Payne, which
                    threw me within some 200 yards of the enemy's lines, when we soon became hotly
                    engaged, which was about 4 o'clock. General Stafford's brigade came up on our
                    right and continued the line along the lane.</p>
                <p>About sunset Captain Dement's battery was placed in position immediately in my
                    rear, opened fire, but was soon silenced by the enemy's infantry. We were
                    engaged until dark, when I received an order from General Walker to fall back to
                    our fortifications along the old Culpeper and Fredericksburg road, carrying our
                    dead and wounded with us. Owing to a number of horses in the battery being
                    disabled, I sent Captain Hall and a squad of men, who assisted in bringing off
                    the piece. About 1 o'clock, we took up the line of march, moving toward Zoar
                    Church, and took position along Mine Run.</p>
                <p>It only remains for me to say that the officers and men displayed their usual
                    gallantry and determination. There was a greater exhibition of personal courage
                    than I have witnessed upon any of the many fields upon which they have fought.</p>
                <p>Capt. William T. Hall, Lieut. John M. Brown, Color Sergt. W. Grimm, Sergeant
                    Thompson (Company G), and Sergeant Fauber (Company H), are mentioned for
                    behaving with marked gallantry on this occasion.</p>
                <p>I am indebted to Lieutenant-Colonel Williams, Major Newton, and Adjt. Charles S.
                    Arnall for their valuable assistance and untiring energy in keeping the men to
                    the post of duty.</p>
                <p>My casualties were as follows: Six killed, 24 wounded, and 1 missing; total, 31.</p>
                <p>With deep regret at the loss of so many noble and brave men of my command,</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, most respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>J. H. S. FUNK, Colonel Fifth Virginia Infantry.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
