<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0068"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0068">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Payne's Farm/Mine Run, 87th Pa. Infantry, Report of Lieut. Col.
                    James A. Stable, December 3, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">paynes farm mine run, 87th pa infantry report of lieut col james a stable december 3 1863</title>
        <author>Stable, James A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0068</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500114</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI MINE RUN, VIRGINIA, CAMPAIGN., No. 73. Report of Lieut.
                            Col. James A. Stable, Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Infantry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli mine run, virginia campaign no 73 report of lieut col james a stable eighty seventh pennsylvania infantry</title>
            <author>James A. Stable</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 29. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 788</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-03">1863-12-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 87th Pa. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Payne's Farm/Mine Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0068T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Col. James A. Stable was of the Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Infantry.
                    Stable reports that the regiment skirmished with the enemy in the woods.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HEADQUARTERS 87TH PENNSYLVANIA INFANTRY
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. S. C. JUDSON, Acting Assistant Adjutant-General</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-03">December 3, 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Brandy Station, Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>SIR: In compliance with circular from headquarters Third Brigade, Third Division,
                    Third Army Corps, bearing date December 3, 1863, I have the honor to report the
                    following as the part taken by my command in the recent movements and operations
                    of the Third Brigade:</p>
                <p>Marched from camp at Brandy Station, Va., November 26, at 8 a.m., marching on the
                    left of the brigade, left in front; arrived at Rapidan River, crossing over the
                    river on pontoon bridge, marched about 3 miles, then marched back to the river,
                    and bivouacked. November 27, 7 a.m., marched with Third Brigade on the left
                    center of the brigade, left in front, about 2 miles, rested in the woods till 3
                    p. m., marched forward, met the rebels, and had a very brisk fight, losing 1 man
                    killed and 11 men wounded. Marched with Third Brigade to a new position; lay on
                    arms during the night. November 28, 3 a. m., marched with Third Brigade on the
                    right center of the brigade, left in front: bivouacked in the field. November
                    29, brigade formed line at 3 p.m. for the purpose of storming rebel
                    fortifications, my regiment on the right center of the brigade; remained in line
                    till night, then bivouacked.</p>
                <p>November 30, marched at 3 a.m. on the right of Third Brigade, left in front;
                    formed line of battle by brigade, my regiment on the right; deployed one company
                    of 60 men in advance of regiment as skirmishers. The company advanced about 500
                    yards into a very thick under growth of pine woods, when they were fired upon by
                    the rebels lying in ambush, killing 3 enlisted men and wounding 4 enlisted men.
                    The company returned the fire, and held their position. I immediately sent one
                    company of 40 men to support the skirmishers. The two companies remained in
                    position till relieved by the Second Corps, and then rejoined the regiment,
                    which had marched to the ground from where it had marched in the morning;
                    bivouacked in the woods.</p>
                <p>December 1, 1 p.m., marched on the right center of the Third Brigade, right in
                    front; bivouacked in the woods. December 2, marched at 6 a.m. on the right of
                    the brigade, right in front, crossing the Rapidan River on pontoon bridge; took
                    position in line of battle on a hill in the woods close by the river to guard
                    the ford; remained in position for three hours, then marched on the right of
                    brigade; bivouacked in the woods.</p>
                <p>December 3, marched at 1 a.m. on the left of brigade, right in front, arriving at
                    Brandy Station 8 a.m.; encamped in the woods near Brandy Station.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Hoping this will prove satisfactory and correct, I am, sir, very
                        respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JAMES A. STABLE, Lieutenant-Colonel, Comdg. 87th Pennsylvania
                        Volunteers.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
