<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0061"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0061">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 16th Pa. Cavalry, Reports of Maj. Gen. Alfred
                    Pleasonton, August 5, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 16th pa cavalry reports of maj gen alfred pleasonton august 5 1863</title>
        <author>Pleasonton, Alfred</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0061</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500109</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP XXXIX N. C., VA., W. VA., MD., PA., ETC., No. 336 Reports of
                            Maj. Gen. Alfred Pleasonton, U. S. Army, commanding Cavalry Corps.*</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix n c , va w va md pa etc no 336 reports of maj gen alfred pleasonton u s army commanding cavalry corps</title>
            <author>Alfred Pleasonton</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I, Volume 27. Part I. Reports., Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 9913</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-05">1863-08-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pennsylvania Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0061T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Maj. Gen. Alfred Pleasonton commanded the Cavalry Corps which included the 16th
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry. In this report Pleasonton provides details about the
                    events preceding the battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Cavalry Corps
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. S. Williams, Assistant Adjutant-Gen., Army of
                        the Potomac. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-05">August 5, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Amissville, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of the Cavalry
                    Corps in the late campaign, including the battle of Gettysburg, with
                    accompanying reports of subordinate commanders:</p>
                <p>On June 28, the army being in the vicinity of Frederick City, Md., the Cavalry
                    Corps was placed as follows: The First Division (Buford's) was posted near
                    Middletown, covering the left, and watching the enemy in the direction of
                    Hagerstown. The Second Division (Gregg's) was stationed at different points from
                    Frederick City to Ridgeville, on the Baltimore turnpike, covering the right of
                    the army. The Third Division (Kilpatrick's) was at Frederick City, and was
                    assigned to the corps on that day.</p>
                <p>Orders having been issued for the advance of the army toward Pennsylvania, on
                    June 29, Buford's division moved as follows, to cover and protect the left flank
                    of the line of march: The Reserve Brigade was detached under Brig.-Gen. Merritt,
                    and moved to Mechanicstown and afterward to Emmitsburg. The First and Second
                    Brigades passed through Boonsborough, Cavetown, and Monterey Springs, and
                    encamped near Fairfield, within a short distance of a considerable force of the
                    enemy's infantry.</p>
                <p>On June 30, these two brigades moved toward Gettysburg; met two regiments of
                    rebel infantry, with some artillery, and after some skirmishing, not wishing to
                    use artillery, they turned off, and reached Gettysburg in the afternoon, just in
                    time to meet the enemy entering the town, and to drive him back before he
                    secured a position. The enemy withdrew in the direction of Cashtown, leaving his
                    pickets about 4 1/2 miles from Gettysburg.</p>
                <p>By daylight on July 1, Gen. Buford had obtained positive information of the
                    enemy's position and movements, and made his dispositions to hold him in check
                    until the First Corps, under Maj.- Gen. Reynolds, could arrive upon the field.</p>
                <p>Between 8 and 9 o'clock in the morning, the rebels advanced with superior numbers
                    on Buford's position, but for more than two hours were gallantly checked in
                    every attempt that was made, when the troops of the First and Eleventh Corps
                    began to arrive and to relieve the cavalry from their perilous position. This
                    division continued in the fight throughout the day, displaying great obstinacy
                    in holding all their positions, and splendid courage and skill in their
                    treatment of the rebels.</p>
                <p>On July 2, Buford's division held a position on our left at Gettysburg until
                    relieved by the Third Corps, when it was directed to take post at Westminster,
                    to assist in guarding the army trains at that point.</p>
                <p>On June 29, Gregg's division moved by the right flank of the army on Westminster,
                    covering the country toward York and Carlisle by reconnaissances and patrols.
                    Kilpatrick's division advanced from Frederick City, on June 29, direct to the
                    front on Hanover by way of Littlestown.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 30th, they were attacked by Stuart's cavalry in full force.
                    After a gallant fight, the enemy was repulsed, losing one battle-flag, and
                    retreated in the direction of Carlisle.</p>
                <p>On July 1, they were pursued as far as Berlin, by the way of Abbottstown, a
                    detachment under Lieut.-Col. Alexander, chief of staff, proceeding as far as
                    Rosstown.</p>
                <p>Kilpatrick's division on July 2 moved toward Gettysburg from the direction of
                    Heidlersburg, to prevent the enemy from concentrating his forces by that road,
                    and to protect our right flank from being turned. Late in the afternoon, this
                    division met the rebel cavalry near Hunterstown, and, after a spirited affair
                    for two hours, the enemy was driven from his position. The division was then
                    ordered to Two Taverns, which it reached at daylight.</p>
                <p>It being now apparent that the rebel army intended making a vigorous attack on
                    the left of the position held by our army on the heights of Gettysburg, Gen.
                    Kilpatrick was directed to move to the right of the enemy's line, connect with
                    Merritt's brigade, ordered up from Emmitsburg, and attack the enemy in flank and
                    rear, as well as prevent our own flank from being turned, Custer's brigade, of
                    this division, remaining on our right flank, in connection with Gen. Gregg. Gen.
                    Kilpatrick did valuable service with the First Brigade, under Gen. Farnsworth,
                    in charging the enemy's infantry, and, with the assistance of Merritt's brigade
                    and the good execution of their united batteries, caused him to detach largely
                    from his main attack on the left of our line.</p>
                <p>It was in one of these brilliant engagements that the noble and gallant
                    Farnsworth fell, heroically leading a charge of his brigade against the rebel
                    infantry. Gifted in a high degree with a quick perception and a correct
                    judgment, and remarkable for his daring and coolness, his comprehensive grasp of
                    the situation on the field of battle and the rapidity of his actions had already
                    distinguished Gen. Farnsworth among his comrades in arms. In his death was
                    closed a career that must have won the highest honors of his profession.</p>
                <p>On June 30, immediately after the fight of Kilpatrick at Hanover, the enemy
                    hastily withdrew his forces from York and Carlisle and began to concentrate on
                    Gettysburg. As soon as this was known, Gregg's division was directed to leave
                    one brigade (Huey's) to cover the depot at Westminster, and move with the other
                    two brigades toward Gettysburg, to take up a position on the right of our line
                    of battle, and prevent the enemy from turning the flank and gaining the rear.
                    This position was established about noon of July 2, and was at the intersection
                    of the Gettysburg and Hanover turnpike with the road which ran in rear of our
                    line of battle. The enemy attacked this point late in the evening with two
                    regiments deployed, but were compelled to retire.</p>
                <p>On July 3, Custer's brigade, of Kilpatrick's division, having occupied the
                    position of Gregg's division of the day before, the latter was posted
                    three-quarters of a mile nearer the Baltimore and Gettysburg turnpike.</p>
                <p>About noon the enemy threw a heavy force of cavalry against this position, with
                    the intention of gaining our rear. This attack was met and handsomely defeated
                    by Gen. Gregg, who reports several fine charges made by the First Michigan
                    Cavalry, of Custer's brigade, and the First New Jersey and Third Pennsylvania
                    Cavalry, of his own division. The enemy withdrew from his position with heavy
                    loss, and evacuated his lines that night. Custer's brigade then proceeded to
                    join its division on our left.</p>
                <p>The grand attack of Gen. Lee's army on July 3, on the left of our line at
                    Gettysburg, having been successfully repulsed and defeated, orders were given
                    for the cavalry to gain his rear and line of communication, and harass and annoy
                    him as much as possible in his retreat.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>A. PLEASONTON, Maj.-Gen., Comdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
