<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0060"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0060">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 16th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Brig. Gen. David McM.
                    Gregg, July 25, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 16th pa cavalry report of brig gen david mcm gregg july 25 1863</title>
        <author>Gregg, David McM.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0060</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500108</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX THE GETTYSBURG CAMPAIGN, No. 344 Reports of Brig. Gen.
                            David McM. Gregg, U. S. Army, commanding Second Division.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix the gettysburg campaign, no 344 reports of brig gen david mcm gregg u s army commanding second division</title>
            <author>David McM. Gregg</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 27. Part I. Reprts, Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-25">1863-07-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0060T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. David McM. Gregg commanded the Second Division of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 16th Pennsylvania Cavalry. Gregg reports on repulsing
                    the enemy's cavalry charges.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Second Division, Cavalry Corps,
                    <name type="recipient"> Lieut. Col. A. J. Alexander, A. A. G., Cavalry Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-25">July 25, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Col.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The First and Third Brigades, of the Second Division, Cavalry Corps, arrived on
                    the battle-field at Gettysburg, July 2, about noon, the Second Brigade having
                    been sent to Westminster.</p>
                <p>In compliance with orders from Maj.-Gen. Pleasonton, commanding the corps, I
                    placed these brigades on the extreme right of our line of battle, and at the
                    point of intersection of the Gettysburg and Hanover turnpike with the road which
                    ran in rear of the right of our line of battle. A line of pickets was
                    established in front, connecting with the right of the infantry line and
                    extending well to the right of the turnpike. An attempt made to dislodge some of
                    the enemy's sharpshooters posted in front of the center of my line caused the
                    enemy to throw out two regiments deployed. This force advanced against my line,
                    but was soon compelled to withdraw under the admonition of a half dozen
                    well-directed shells and a telling carbine fire from behind a line of stone
                    fence.</p>
                <p>On the morning of July 3, I was again ordered to take a position on the right of
                    our line, and make a demonstration against the enemy. The First and Third
                    Brigades were again posted on the right of the infantry, but about three-fourths
                    of a mile nearer the Baltimore and Gettysburg turnpike. This position was taken
                    because I learned that the First [Second] Brigade, of the Third Division, was
                    occupying my position of the day before. A regiment was dismounted and put in
                    the woods as skirmishers, but the enemy was not found in any considerable force.</p>
                <p>At 12 a.m. I received a copy of a dispatch from the commander of the Eleventh
                    Army Corps to the major-general commanding the Army of the Potomac, that large
                    columns of the enemy's cavalry were moving toward the right of our line. At the
                    same time I received an order from Maj.-Gen. Pleasonton, through an
                    aide-de-camp, to send the First [Second] Brigade, of the Third Division, to join
                    Gen. Kilpatrick on the left. The First Brigade of my division was sent to
                    relieve the brigade of the Third Division. This change having been made, a
                    strong line of skirmishers displayed by the enemy was evidence that the enemy's
                    cavalry had gained our right, and were about to attack, with the view of gaining
                    the rear of our line of battle. The importance of successfully resisting an
                    attack at this point, which, if succeeded in by the enemy, would have been
                    productive of the most serious consequences, determined me to retain the brigade
                    of the Third Division until the enemy were driven back. Gen. Custer, commanding
                    the brigade, fully satisfied of the intended attack, was well pleased to remain
                    with his brigade. The First New Jersey Cavalry was posted as mounted skirmishers
                    to the right and front in a wood, the Third Pennsylvania Cavalry deployed as
                    dismounted skirmishers to the left and front in open fields, and the First
                    Maryland on the Hanover turnpike, in position to protect the right of my line.</p>
                <p>The very superior force of dismounted skirmishers of the enemy advanced on our
                    left and front required the line to be re-enforced by one of Gen. Custer's
                    regiments. At this time the skirmishing became very brisk on both sides, and an
                    artillery fire was begun by the enemy and ourselves. During the skirmish of the
                    dismounted men, the enemy brought upon the field a column for a charge. The
                    charge of this column was met by the Seventh Michigan Cavalry, of the First
                    [Second] Brigade, Third Division, but not successfully. The advantage gained in
                    this charge was soon wrested from the enemy by the gallant charge of the First
                    Michigan, of the same brigade. This regiment drove the enemy back to his
                    starting point. Other charges were made by the enemy's columns, but in every
                    instance were they driven back. Defeated at every point, the enemy withdrew to
                    his left, and on passing the wood in which the First New Jersey Cavalry was
                    posted, that regiment gallantly and successfully charged the flank of his
                    column. Heavy skirmishing was still maintained by the Third Pennsylvania Cavalry
                    with the enemy, and was continued until nightfall. During the engagement, a
                    portion of this regiment made a very handsome and successful charge upon one of
                    the enemy's regiments. The enemy retired his column behind his artillery, and at
                    dark withdrew from his former position. At this time I was at liberty to relieve
                    the First [Second] Brigade of the Third Division, which was directed to join its
                    division.</p>
                <p>Our own and the enemy's loss during this engagement was severe. Our loss:
                    Offcers, 1 killed, 17 wounded, and 1 missing; enlisted men, 33 killed, 140
                    wounded, and 103 missing.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 4th, I advanced to the enemy's position, but found him
                    gone. Following toward Hunterstown, I found many of his wounded abandoned. From
                    these we learned that the enemy had been severely punished and his loss heavy.
                    One general officer was severely wounded</p>
                <p>Brig.-Gen. Custer, commanding First [Second] Brigade, Third Division, very ably
                    assisted me in the duties of my command. Col. J. B. McIntosh, commanding First
                    Brigade of my division, handled his brigade with great skill, and deserves
                    particular mention for his gallantry and untiring energy throughout the day. The
                    Third Brigade, Second Division, Col. J. Irvin Gregg commanding, was held in
                    reserve upon the field. The batteries commanded by Capt. A. M. Randor and Lieut.
                    A. C. M. Pennington, jr., rendered most effective service. The fire of the
                    artillery during this engagement was the most accurate that I have ever seen.</p>
                <p>It gives me great pleasure to bring to the notice of the major- general
                    commanding the efficiency and gallantry exhibited by my entire staff on this
                    occasion.</p>
                <p>A list of casualties of this engagement has heretofore been forwarded, and will
                    again be found in a consolidated list.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>D. McM. GREGG, Brig. Gen. of Volunteers, Comdg. Second Division.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
