<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0062"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0062">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Gettysburg, 17th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Col. Thomas C. Devin,
                    August 6, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">gettysburg, 17th pa cavalry report of col thomas c devin august 6 1863</title>
        <author>Devin, Thomas C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0062</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500110</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX THE GETTYSBURG CAMPAIGN, No. 339 Report of Col. Thomas C.
                            Devin, Sixth New York Cavalry, commanding Second Brigade.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix the gettysburg campaign, no 339 report of col thomas c devin sixth new york cavalry commanding second brigade</title>
            <author>Thomas C. Devin</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 27. Part I. Reports, Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 938</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-06">1863-08-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 17th Pennsylvania Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Gettysburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0062T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. Thomas C. Devin commanded the Second Brigade which included the 17th
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry. Devin reports that the regiment's skirmishers engaged the
                    enemy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Second Brigade, First Cavalry Division,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. T. C. Bacon, A. A. G., First Cavalry Division.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-06">August 6, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of this
                    brigade, since crossing the Potomac at Edwards Ferry to take part in the
                    Maryland campaign:</p>
                <p>Arriving at Poolesville, Md., June 27, the brigade marched with the division to
                    Jefferson, where it encamped for the night, reaching Middletown on the morning
                    of the 28th.</p>
                <p>On the 29th, marched by way of Cavetown and Monterey across South Mountain to
                    Fountain Dale, near Millerstown.</p>
                <p>On the 30th, marched by Emmitsburg to Gettysburg, Pa., and encamped. Scouting
                    parties were immediately sent out to observe the approaches from Carlisle,
                    Harrisburg, and York. The country toward the above points was thoroughly
                    scoured, and a number of prisoners were taken, from whom important intelligence
                    was elicited and forwarded to headquarters.</p>
                <p>BATTLE OF GETTYSBURG, PA.</p>
                <p>On the morning of July 1, the pickets of the First Brigade, on the road to
                    Cashtown, were driven in by a heavy force advancing from that direction, and the
                    Second Brigade was ordered to prepare for action, and form on the crest of the
                    hill on the right of the First Brigade. I immediately formed as ordered, with my
                    right resting on the road to Mummasburg, and deployed a squadron of the Sixth
                    New York to the front and left as skirmishers, dismounted, and connecting with
                    those of the First Brigade, at the same time connecting by skirmishers and
                    vedettes with my pickets on the three roads on the right leading toward
                    Carlisle, thus establishing a continuous line from the York road, on the extreme
                    right, to the left of the First Brigade, on the Cashtown road. The infantry not
                    having arrived, and the enemy's artillery fire increasing, I was ordered to
                    retire gradually, as they succeeded in getting the range of my position. This I
                    effected in successive formations in line to the rear by regiment, in the face
                    of the enemy, the troops behaving well, and forming with perfect coolness and
                    order.</p>
                <p>About this time, my skirmishers on the right were forced back by the advance of
                    the enemy's line of battle, coming from the direction of Heidlersburg. Knowing
                    the importance of holding that point until the infantry could arrive and be
                    placed in position, I immediately placed the Ninth New York in support, and,
                    dismounting the rest of my available force, succeeded in holding the rebel line
                    in check for two hours, until relieved by the arrival of the Eleventh Corps,
                    when I was ordered to mass my command on the right of the York road and hold
                    that approach. While in that position--immediately in front of the town, the
                    command faced to the front and my pickets on the York road advanced
                    three-quarters of a mile--a heavy fire of shells was opened on us from one of
                    our own batteries on Cemetery Hill, immediately in my rear. The fire becoming
                    very hot and persistent, and many of the shells bursting among us, I was led to
                    suppose for a moment that the enemy had succeeded in gaining that position, and
                    I immediately removed my command into the town, the column being shelled the
                    whole distance. After I had retired, the battery turned its attention to my
                    pickets on the road, and shelled them out. I was then ordered to the Emmitsburg
                    road, where the brigade was formed in line, in rear of the batteries of the
                    division, with its right flank resting on the town.</p>
                <p>The enemy, having gained the York road, entered the town immediately after my
                    pickets retired, and, passing through with their sharpshooters, attacked the
                    flank of the brigade, killing and wounding several men and horses. I immediately
                    dismounted one squadron of the Ninth New York, who, with their carbines, drove
                    them some distance into the town, punishing then severely. The brigade was then
                    ordered to the extreme left, where it bivouacked for the night.</p>
                <p>The next morning, July 2, while I was engaged reconnoitering in rear of the
                    enemy's right, our sharpshooters became engaged with a division of the enemy
                    advancing to feel our lines in front of my position. I immediately dismounted
                    and deployed two squadrons in support of Berdan's Sharpshooters (who were
                    engaged in my front), and formed the brigade into line on the left of the First,
                    with one section of Tidball's battery in position. The enemy not pressing his
                    advance, and the Third Corps coming into position, we were ordered to march to
                    Taneytown, where we bivouacked, and marched the next morning, July 3, to
                    Westminster.</p>
                <p>The brigade was here ordered to refit and shoe their horses, but on the following
                    day (Sunday) we were ordered to march with the division to Frederick. Bivouacked
                    outside of the town that night, and the next day we were ordered with the
                    division to advance by Boonsborough to Williamsport.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>THOS. C. DEVIN, Col., Comdg. Second Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
