<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0069"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0069">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Payne's Farm/Mine Run, 87th Pa. Infantry, Report of Col. Benjamin
                    F. Smith, December 3, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">paynes farm mine run, 87th pa infantry report of col benjamin f smith december 3 1863</title>
        <author>Smith, Benjamin F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0069</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500115</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXI, No. 70 Report of Col. Benjamin F. Smith, One hundred and
                            twenty-sixth Ohio Infantry, commanding Third Brigade.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxi, no 70 report of col benjamin f smith one hundred and twenty sixth ohio infantry commanding third brigade</title>
            <author>Benjamin F. Smith</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 29. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent/>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-03">1863-12-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 87th Pa. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Payne's Farm/Mine Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0069T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. Benjamin F. Smith commanded the Third Brigade of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 87th Pa. Inf. Smith reports that his regiment was not sharply
                    engaged in the battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    BRANDY STATION, VA.
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. J. JOHNSON, Acting Assistant Adjutant-General.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-03">December 3, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>LIEUTENANT</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In compliance with circular of this date from headquarters Third Division, I have
                    respectfully to report the recent operations of this brigade, giving, as
                    directed, any delays or obstacles; also a revised report of casualties* at the
                    close of the report.</p>
                <p>On the 26th of November, the brigade marched at 8 a.m. from Brandy Station, Va.,
                    with the division and corps, to Jacobs' Mills Ford, on the Rapidan River, and
                    crossed, without resistance, at about 5 p.m., and marched some 3 miles along a
                    road through the Wilderness and returned to near the ford and bivouacked for the
                    night.</p>
                <p>November 27, in accordance with circular from headquarters of the division, the
                    brigade marched with the corps soon after sunrise over same road for the greater
                    part of the distance of the day before. The Second Division of the corps, being
                    in the advance, came upon the enemy about noon. This brigade, being in rear of
                    its division, moved slowly along, closed up, with flankers well thrown out, as
                    directed by the general commanding division. At about 4 p.m. the rapidity of the
                    firing and the number of the wounded brought to the rear indicated the enemy in
                    force. I received verbal orders to move forward with the brigade, and met the
                    general commanding division behind and near the line of battle in the woods, and
                    was directed by him to move quickly and take position in line, my right joining
                    the left of General Morris' brigade. In moving through the thick woods I sent
                    two staff officers in different directions to find the brigade of General
                    Morris, as I had no time to reconnoiter the ground over which I was passing.
                    Finding the Second Brigade taking the position indicated for mine, I halted and
                    sent a staff officer to report the general commanding division. I was then
                    ordered, through the assistant adjutant-general of the division, to join my
                    right on the Second Brigade, and connect with the Second Army Corps on my left.</p>
                <p>In marching to this last-mentioned position I came to a clearing of low ground,
                    through which ran a miry creek, on the opposite of which was a matted thicket of
                    considerable extent and depth. As all this ground was covered by the enemy's
                    fire, in order to protect my men as well as possible until I could place them in
                    the position indicated, I filed the left in front of the line under the cover of
                    some irregularly shaped small hills. This done, I directed the left to move back
                    to the line proper, the right having joined with the left of the Second Brigade.
                    In doing this the most of the brigade was thrown in the tangled timber around
                    which on the left flank the enemy was moving in heavy columns, being under a
                    severe fire without being able to accomplish or see anything. The left being in
                    some confusion on account of the character of the country, I found it necessary
                    to reform the brigade in the clearing a short distance in the rear. It then
                    moved to a new line along the crest of the hill a little farther to the left and
                    rear, a good position. After consulting with General Howe, of the Sixth Corps,
                    whom I met there and who was of opinion that the hill should be held at all
                    hazards, I accordingly occupied it and remained there, thus holding the extreme
                    left. A brigade of the Sixth Corps closed the gap on my right. By this movement
                    I prevented the rebels from turning our flank. The Second Corps, with which I
                    was ordered to connect, must have been some miles on our left, as I could not
                    find or communicate with it. During these movements the sun went down and the
                    battle ceased.</p>
                <p>My brigade was not fairly engaged; there was some desultory firing from it, but
                    nothing more. I used every effort to make the best of circumstances. I did not
                    know the ground, and there was no one to give me information. One of my aides is
                    missing, either killed or a prisoner. Another aide did not rejoin me again after
                    I sent him with an order. He reports that he could not find the brigade again.
                    One of my orderlies had his horse disabled by a gunshot wound, therefore I lost
                    his services, and I found myself almost alone most of the time, with but one
                    orderly, who carried the brigade flag. My acting assistant adjutant-general did
                    not fail me, but it became necessary to give my personal attention to all parts
                    of the line, which was extremely difficult, owing to the broken and tangled
                    state of the country. The brigade remained in its position at night on the hill,
                    under arms, with strong pickets thrown out in front and on the left flank.
                    During the movements described the brigade lost slightly in killed, wounded, and
                    missing.</p>
                <p>November 28, at about half past 4 a.m., a staff officer from division
                    headquarters brought me an order to rejoin the division, which I did, with the
                    brigade to the rear, near corps headquarters. At about 8 o'clock marched with
                    corps toward Robertson's Tavern. Passing Robertson's Tavern the command halted
                    about 3:30 p.m., and about 5 o'clock moved forward, and, after a tedious night
                    march of some 2 miles, bivouacked, for the night in the immediate presence of
                    the enemy.</p>
                <p>November 29, before noon, the general commanding division sent for me, and
                    informed me that it was the intention to assault the works of the enemy in our
                    front, and that my brigade was to lead the attack of our division, and gave me
                    directions accordingly. The division was formed for this purpose in the
                    afternoon, but, for some reason unknown to me, the assault was abandoned, and we
                    bivouacked for the night.</p>
                <p>Monday, November 30, the brigade, with the division, marched at 2 a.m. some 2
                    miles and joined the Second Corps, and at daylight was in line of battle for the
                    purpose of assaulting the rebel works, this brigade again in the advance, two
                    regiments in the front line, the One hundred and twenty-sixth Ohio and
                    Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, with a company from each deployed as
                    skirmishers about 300 yards in advance. During the morning, the pickets being
                    drawn in, the rebels closed up in the vacuum and came upon the skirmishers of
                    the Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, when, for a few moments, there was
                    some sharp firing, killing 3 and wounding 4 men, the rebels falling immediately
                    back. For some reason the assault was given up, and at l p.m. the division
                    marched back to its camp of the night before, and bivouacked.</p>
                <p>December 1, at noon, the brigade marched, in accordance with orders, back some 6
                    miles, to the junction of the Orange and Fredericksburg pike and the plank road
                    to Germanna Ford, to support the cavalry and cover the flank while the army
                    moved to the rear. This was done without event, and at 7 a.m., December 2, the
                    brigade moved, with Colonel Taylor's brigade of cavalry and one battery of
                    artillery (myself in command of the whole, by order of General Gregg), and
                    covered the rear of the troops crossing at Culpeper Ford. A few of the rebel
                    cavalry followed and skirmished with the rear cavalry regiments, picking up some
                    few stragglers, but doing no other damage. After seeing all the troops,
                    &amp;, cross Culpeper Ford, I crossed and placed the brigade in position,
                    until the pontoon bridge was taken up and taken away, when I received orders
                    from General Gregg to rejoin my corps, which I did near the ford about 2 p. m.,
                    and marched with it until sunset, when the division bivouacked in the woods.</p>
                <p>Thursday, December 3, at 1 a.m., resumed the march, and reached Brandy Station at
                    sunrise, and re-occupied the old camp of just one week ago.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>[B. F. SMITH], Colonel, Comdg. Third Brig., Third Div., Third Corps.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
