<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0074"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0074">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Payne's Farm/Mine Run, 16th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Brig. Gen.
                    David McM. Gregg, December 4, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">paynes farm mine run, 16th pa cavalry report of brig gen david mcm gregg december 4 1863</title>
        <author>Gregg, David McM.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0074</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500117</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI MINE RUN, VIRGINIA, CAMPAIGN., Report of Brig. Gen. David
                            McM. Gregg, U. S. Army, commanding Second Cavalry Division.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli mine run, virginia campaign report of brig gen david mcm gregg u s army commanding second cavalry division</title>
            <author>David McM. Gregg</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 29. part I, Reports, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 806</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-04">1863-12-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Payne's Farm/Mine Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0074T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. David McM. Gregg commanded the Second Cavalry Division which included
                    the 16th Pa. Cav. Gregg reports on having to contend with enemy cavalry
                attacks.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HEADQUARTERS SECOND CAVALRY DIVISION
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. C. C. SUYDAM, Assistant Adjutant-General. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-04">December 4, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPTAIN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report of the operations of this division
                    since the 24th of November, 1863:</p>
                <p>On the morning of November 24, the Second Division, which had camped the previous
                    night at Morrisville, crossed the Rappahannock at Ellis' Ford, and proceeded to
                    Ely's Ford to cross the Rapidan. The advance guard having crossed the river and
                    taken possession of the heights beyond, [the river?] was recrossed. In pursuance
                    of an order from the major-general commanding Cavalry Corps, the division was
                    withdrawn to Richardsville and Ellis' Ford, and the brigade camped at these
                    points for the night and until the morning of the 26th, when the entire division
                    crossed the Rapidan and advanced upon the left of the army and in the direction
                    of the headwaters of the Po River. Communicating from time to time with the
                    general commanding the advance of the army corps on my right, I endeavored to
                    regulate my march by his. Getting somewhat in advance, about 8 p. m. I halted
                    the division on the head of the Po River, near the road leading from Parker's
                    Store to Spotsylvania. During the day only small parties of the enemy were seen,
                    and these retiring in different directions.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 27th, pursuant to orders from the major general commanding
                    Cavalry Corps, the division moved to Parker's Store, passing on to the Orange
                    plank road in advance of the Fifth Army Corps. At New Hope Meeting House the
                    First Brigade, Col. J. P. Taylor commanding, met the pickets and first line of
                    skirmishers of the enemy's cavalry. Two squadrons of the Third Pennsylvania
                    Cavalry and one of the First Massachusetts Cavalry, dismounted, soon drove back
                    this line. The enemy endeavored to check the advance by discharges of canister
                    and shell from a piece of artillery, but uselessly. A section of Martin's (Sixth
                    New York) battery placed at the meeting house compelled the withdrawal of this
                    piece. Additional squadrons of dismounted men were now moved upon the skirmish
                    line, and the enemy rapidly driven a mile beyond the meeting house. At this
                    point the enemy's cavalry disappeared behind a line of infantry, which advanced
                    to meet the line of the division; a battery of artillery opened from the enemy's
                    right. To check this advance, four regiments, the Third Pennsylvania, First
                    Massachusetts, First Pennsylvania, and First New Jersey, were dismounted and
                    moved to the front, and two sections of Martin's battery placed in position
                    close upon our line. This strong line of dismounted cavalry rushed upon the
                    enemy, firing volleys from their carbines, and drove the infantry line to the
                    cover of a dense woods and there held it at bay. Thirty-four prisoners were
                    brought out and reported themselves as belonging to Hill's corps.</p>
                <p>Major-General Sykes, having joined me at this time, moved forward one of his
                    divisions, and late in the evening my division retired within his lines. In this
                    action, the regiments and battery of the First Brigade behaved most handsomely.</p>
                <p>The entire loss of the First Brigade was 2 officers killed and 5 wounded; 17
                    enlisted men killed and 59 enlisted men wounded, and 1 enlisted man missing.</p>
                <p>On the 28th, the First Brigade was posted at the Wilderness with two regiments at
                    Parker's Store, the Second Brigade at New Hope Meeting House.</p>
                <p>On the 29th, Hampton's division of rebel cavalry made a strong attack at Parker's
                    Store with the view of falling upon the wagon trains of the army. The pickets of
                    the regiments at Parker's Store were rapidly driven in. The regiments engaged in
                    distributing rations were attacked on all sides and compelled to retire toward
                    the Wilderness. But sooner than they expected I moved three regiments of the
                    Second Brigade, with a section of King's battery, Fourth U. S. Artillery, toward
                    Parker's Store. The Second and Sixteenth Pennsylvania, in advance, met the
                    enemy, charged him, releasing prisoners, and compelled the retirement of the
                    enemy. The two regiments at Parker's Store lost a portion of their rations, and
                    1 wagon was burned to prevent its falling into the hands of the enemy.</p>
                <p>On this day, the loss of the division was 4 officers wounded (one since died), 7
                    enlisted men killed and 40 enlisted men wounded, and 1 officer and 54 enlisted
                    men missing. The loss of the enemy in killed and wounded was as great as our
                    own.</p>
                <p>On the 30th, Devin's brigade, of the First Division, having reported to me, it
                    was posted at the Wilderness, and the whole of the First Brigade moved to
                    Parker's Store. The movement of the army across the Rapidan on the night of the
                    1st of December was covered by the Second Division and Devin's brigade, of the
                    First Division, and two brigades of infantry from the Third Army Corps, all
                    under my command.</p>
                <p>The Second Brigade of the Second Division and Blaisdell's brigade of infantry
                    covered the movement on the road to Ely's Ford, the First Brigade, Second
                    Division, and Smith's brigade of infantry that on the road to Culpeper Ford, and
                    Devin's brigade on the road to Germanna Ford. These commands did the duty
                    assigned to them in a very creditable manner.</p>
                <p>The gallantry and good conduct of my entire command on the dates of November 27
                    and 29 is deserving of the highest commendation.</p>
                <p>Accompanying will be found a nominal list of casualties.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>D. McM. GREGG, Brigadier-General of Volunteers, Comdg. Second Div.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
