<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0076"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0076">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Payne's Farm/Mine Run, 17th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Col. Thomas C.
                    Devin, December 3, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">paynes farm mine run, 17th pa cavalry report of col thomas c devin december 3 1863</title>
        <author>Devin, Thomas C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0076</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500118</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI MINE RUN, VIRGINIA, CAMPAIGN., No. 88 Report of Col. Thomas
                            C. Devin, Sixth New York Cavalry, commanding Second Brigade.*</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli mine run, virginia campaign no 88 report of col thomas c devin sixth new york cavalry commanding second brigade</title>
            <author>Thomas C. Devin</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I. , Volume 29. Part I, Reports, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 804</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-03">1863-12-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 17th Pa. Cav.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Payne's Farm/Mine Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0076T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. Thomas C. Devin commanded the Second Brigade of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 17th Pa. Cav. Devin reports on guarding the approaches to
                    Ely's Ford.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. SECOND BRIGADE, FIRST CAVALRY DIVISION
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. T. C. BACON, Assistant Adjutant-General.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-03">December 3, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPTAIN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that on the morning of the 26th ultimo, in pursuance
                    with orders from division headquarters, I left camp on the James City road, and
                    encamped near to and south of Culpeper, occupying the town, and establishing a
                    line of vedettes completely around it, commanding the adjacent country and
                    entirely preventing all egress or ingress. Patrolled to Brandy Station. On the
                    morning of the 27th ultimo, I marched via Stevensburg to a point near
                    Richardsville, where the brigade encamped for the night, picketing toward
                    Stevensburg and Brandy Station.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 29th, I marched to Ely's Ford, with orders to cross the
                    Rapidan and take up a position to cover the approaches to the ford and protect
                    the trains. This I effected by posting a strong force well advanced on the road
                    to Chancellorsville, with one section of artillery in position, and by picketing
                    strongly the wood road leading to the Wilderness. At daylight of the 30th, I was
                    ordered to report to General Gregg at the Wilderness, where I relieved Colonel
                    Taylor's brigade of Gregg's division. Went into position on the crest in the
                    rear of the Lacey House, and west of the intersection of the old turnpike and
                    Germanna road, picketing from Colonel Taylor's left, on the Orange plank road,
                    to General Merritt's right from Ely's.</p>
                <p>On the night of December 1, I received orders from General Gregg to throw a
                    sufficient force on the road from Chancellorsville to Ely's Ford to cover that
                    approach. This I effected by sending Colonel Kellogg, with the Seventeenth
                    Pennsylvania, to occupy that road. I was then ordered to cover the crossing of
                    the infantry at Germanna Ford by holding the approaches until the rear of the
                    column had passed the intersection of that road with the old turnpike, and then
                    cross the river and take up a position on the north side to prevent any crossing
                    of the enemy. The movement I executed as ordered, fording the river in rear of
                    the infantry about 12 m. on the 2d instant, after the bridges were taken up,
                    placing my battery in position on the crest to the right of the ford, and
                    picketing the south bank with a strong supporting force on this side. About 4 p.
                    m. a small party of the enemy's cavalry came toward the ford and engaged the
                    pickets, but were quickly driven off.</p>
                <p>In addition to the above, I would state that, in compliance with orders, I
                    detached 100 men of the Fourth New York Cavalry to report to the officer
                    commanding the Second Corps, for the purpose of keeping open communication
                    between the Third and Fifth Corps. The detachment was engaged in skirmishing
                    with the enemy. The officer commanding it reports his loss to be 1 man killed, 1
                    wounded, 2 taken prisoner, and 2 missing, together with 11 horses killed.</p>
                <p>The balance of this regiment (Fourth New York) was detached, in compliance with
                    orders to report to Captain Graham, commanding the reserve artillery.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 3d instant, I received orders from General Gregg to report
                    to General Merritt, at Culpeper Court-House.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>THOS. C. DEVIN, Colonel, Commanding Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
