<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0088"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R0088">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Spotsylvania Court House, 5th Va. Infantry, Report of Lieut. Gen.
                    Richard S. Ewell, March 20, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">spotsylvania court house, 5th va infantry report of lieut gen richard s ewell march 20 1865</title>
        <author>Ewell, Richard S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">30</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0088</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500128</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII. OPERATIONS IN SE. VA. AND N. C., Report of Lieut. Gen.
                            Richard S. Ewell, C.S. Army, commanding Second Army Corps, of operations
                            May 4-29.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii operations in se va and n c , report of lieut gen richard s ewell c s army commanding second army corps of operations may 4 29</title>
            <author>Richard S. Ewell</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 36. Part I, Reports, Serial No. 67</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-20">1865-03-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 5th Va. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Spotsylvania Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0088T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Gen. Richard S. Ewell commanded the Second Army Corps of the Army of
                    Northern Virginia which included the 5th Va. Inf. Ewell reports battling a
                    numerically superior force.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"> Col. W. H. TAYLOR, Assistant Adjutant-Gen. </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-20">March 20, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">RICHMOND, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>When Gen. Grant crossed the Rapidan, R. D. Johnston's (North Carolina) brigade,
                    of Rodes' division, was at Hanover Junction; the Twenty-first Georgia, of Doles'
                    brigade, same division, and Hoke's (North Carolina) brigade, of Early's
                    division, were in North Carolina. About 13,500 effective infantry and 2,000
                    artillery were present.</p>
                <p>By order of Gen. Lee, his corps and division commanders met him on Monday, May 2,
                    1864, at the signal station on Clark's Mountain. He then gave it as his opinion
                    that the enemy would cross by some of the fords below us, as Germanna or Ely's.
                    They began to do so next day. About noon of the 4th we moved from our camps on
                    the Rapidan toward Locust Grove, on the old turnpike from Orange Court-House to
                    Fredericksburg. Johnson's division and Nelson's battalion of artillery
                    bivouacked 2 miles south of Locust Grove, Rodes just behind them, and Early at
                    Locust Grove. The artillery was close behind Early; Ramseur's brigade, of Rodes'
                    division, with three regiments from each of the other divisions, was left on
                    picket. Next morning I moved down the pike, sending the First North Carolina
                    Cavalry, which I found in my front, on a road that turned to the left toward
                    Germanna Ford. About 8 a.m. I sent Maj. Campbell Brown, of my staff, to Gen. Lee
                    to report my position. In reply he instructed me to regulate my march by Gen. A.
                    P. Hill, whose progress down the plank road I could tell by the firing at the
                    head of his column, and informed me that he preferred not to bring on a general
                    engagement before Gen. Longstreet came up.</p>
                <p>Advancing slowly with John M. Jones' brigade, of Johnson's division, in advance,
                    prepared for action, I came about 11 a.m. in sight of a column of the enemy
                    crossing the pike from Germanna Ford toward the plank road. The Stonewall
                    Brigade (Walker's) had been sent down a left-hand road, driving in the enemy's
                    pickets within 1 1/2 miles of Germanna Ford. Being a good deal ahead of Gen.
                    Hill, I halted and again reported through Lieut.-Col. Pendleton, of my staff,
                    receiving substantially the same instructions as before. Just after they came
                    the enemy demonstrated against Jones' brigade, and I placed Battle's brigade, of
                    Rodes' division, to support it, with Doles' on Battle's right. They were
                    instructed not to allow themselves to become involved, but to fall back slowly
                    if pressed. Some artillery posted near the pike on Jones' front was withdrawn.
                    Soon afterward the enemy fell suddenly upon Jones' right flank and front, broke
                    his brigade, and drove it back upon Battle's, which it disordered. Daniel's
                    brigade, of Rodes' division, and Gordon's, of Early's, were soon brought up and
                    regained the lost ground, the latter capturing, by a dashing charge, several
                    hundred prisoners and reliving Doles, who, though hard pressed, had held his
                    ground. Gen. John M. Jones and his aide-de-camp, Capt. Robert D. Early, fell in
                    a desperate effort to rally their brigade. I placed it in reserve to reorganize;
                    Battle's brigade, which had rallied in time to do good service, taking its place
                    in the line which rallied in time to do good service, taking its place in the
                    line which was now formed on the ground first occupied. The brigades were as
                    follows: From right to left of my line, Daniel's, Doles', Battle's (Rodes'
                    division); George H. Steuart's, The Stonewall (Walker's), Stafford's (Johnson's
                    division); Pegram's, Hays', Gordon's (Early's division). Battle's left and
                    Steuart's right rested on the pike.</p>
                <p>Slight works were at once thrown up and several partial attacks of the enemy
                    repulsed. In a counter attack by Steuart's and Battle's brigades two 24-pounder
                    howitzers, brought up the pike within 800 yards of our works, were captured. The
                    troops were brought back to the works after posting skirmishers to hold the
                    captured pieces till dark, when they were brought off. Gen. Stafford was
                    mortally wounded in a similar attack by his own and the Stonewall brigade late
                    in the afternoon. The fighting closed at dusk with the repulse of a fierce
                    attack on Pegram's brigade. Gen. Pegram was severely wounded, and Col. Hoffham
                    (Thirty-first Virginia) succeeded to the command. This evening Gen. Ramseur came
                    up with the picket regiments, which rejoined their brigades. Ramseur went to the
                    extreme right of my line next morning.</p>
                <p>The 6th of May was occupied in partial assaults on my line (now greatly
                    strengthened) and in efforts to find my flank, which were promptly checked.
                    About 9 a.m. I got word from Gen. Gordon, through Gen. Early in person, that his
                    scouts reported the enemy's right exposed, and he urged turning it, but his
                    views were opposed by Gen. Early, who thought the attempt unsafe. This
                    necessitated a personal examination, which was made as soon as other duties
                    permitted, but in consequence of this delay and other unavoidable causes the
                    movement was not begun until nearly sunset. After examination I ordered the
                    attack, and placed Robert D. Johnston's brigade, of Rodes' division (that
                    morning arrived from Hanover Junction), to support Gordon. Each brigade as its
                    front was cleared was to unite in the attack. Hays was partly moved out of his
                    works to connect with Gordon. The latter attacked vehemently, and when checked
                    by the darkness had captured, with slight loss, a mile of the works held by the
                    Sixth Corps, 600 prisoners, and 2 brigadier-generals-Seymour and Shaler. Of the
                    force encountered not an organized regiment remained and nearly all had thrown
                    away their arms. They made no attempt to recover the lost ground, but threw back
                    their line, so as to give up Germanna Ford entirely. Maj. Daniel, of Gen.
                    Early's staff, joined in Gordon's attack and was desperately wounded and maimed
                    for life while gallantly assisting in this brilliant movement. On May 7 no
                    fighting took place except that in extending to join Gen. Hill's left, Gen.
                    Ramseur came upon a division of the Ninth Corps entrenching. This he put to
                    flight by a sudden attack of his skirmishers, capturing several hundred piled
                    knapsacks and occupying the ground. On the night of the 7th the general
                    commanding sent me word to extend to the right, in conformity to the movements
                    of the troops there, and if at daylight I found no large force in my front to
                    follow Gen. Anderson toward Spotsylvania Court-House. This was done. On the
                    march orders were received placing Gen. Early in command of Hill's corps,
                    transferring Hays' brigade to Johnson's division, and consolidating both
                    Louisiana brigades, under Gen. Hays, and assigning R. D. Johnston's brigade to
                    Early's division, of which Gen. Gordon came in command. After a very distressing
                    march through intense heat and thick dust and smoke from burning woods, my
                    troops reached Spotsylvania Court-House about 5 p.m., just in time for Rodes to
                    repel an attempt to turn Anderson's right, which rested on the----road. Rodes
                    advanced nearly half a mile, when his left, coming upon strong works, was
                    checked and he was forced to halt. Johnson's division formed on his right.
                    Gordon remained in reserve. On the 9th the lines were defined and entrenched.
                    There were two salient-one at Rodes' right brigade (Gen. Doles'), the other at
                    Johnson's center, where I occupied a high open point-which if held by the enemy
                    would enable their artillery to command our line. Johnson's right was connected
                    by skirmishers with Hill's (Early's) left. A second line from Rodes' left center
                    to Hill's left, cutting off the salient, was laid out by the chief engineer and
                    built and occupied by Gordon's division. Heavy skirmishing took place. Gen. Hays
                    was severely wounded. May 10, the enemy's batteries getting an enfilade and
                    reverse fire on Gordon's line, he was withdrawn and placed in rear of Rodes'
                    left and Anderson's right (Kershaw's division), where an attack was expected.
                    About 4 p.m. I learned that Gen. Doles' skirmishers were driven into his works.
                    He was ordered to regain his skirmish line at any cost, but while preparing to
                    do so his lines were attacked and broken, he losing 300 prisoners. The right of
                    Daniel's brigade was exposed and fell back to the second line already mentioned.
                    Battle's brigade and Gordon's division were rapidly brought up, and the former
                    thrown across the head of the enemy's column, while the leading brigade (R. D.
                    Johnston's) of the latter, with them remnants of Doles' and the right of
                    Daniel's brigades, struck them on one flank, and the Stonewall (Walker's), of
                    Johnson's division, on the other. In a short time the enemy was driven from our
                    works, leaving 100 dead within them and a large number in front.</p>
                <p>Our loss, as near as I can tell, was 650, of whom 350 were prisoners. Capt.
                    Thomas T. Turner, my aide-de-camp, was very efficient in rallying the fugitives,
                    and was severely wounded while assisting in recapturing several pieces of
                    artillery of which the enemy had got temporary possession.</p>
                <p>Wednesday, May 11, it rained hard all day and no fighting took place. Toward
                    night the enemy were reported withdrawing from Anderson's front and were heard
                    moving to our right. Scouts stated them to be retiring to Fredericksburg. I
                    received orders to withdraw the artillery, which was done along Johnson's front.
                    Soon after midnight Maj.-Gen. Johnson reported the enemy massing before him, and
                    Gen. Long was directed to return the artillery to the entrenchments, and Gen.
                    Gordon ordered to be ready to support Johnson. Different artillery was sent
                    back, and owing to the darkness and to ignorance of the location it only reached
                    the lines in time to be taken. The enemy attacked in heavy force at earliest
                    dawn, and though gallantly resisted, their numbers and the want of artillery
                    enabled them to break through our lines, capturing Maj. Gen. Edward Johnson,
                    Brig. Gen. G. H. Steuart, about 2,000 men and 20 pieces of artillery. The smoke
                    of the guns and the mist kept the air dark until a comparatively late hour,
                    thereby assisting the enemy, as he was enabled to mass his troops as he chose.
                    They poured through our lines in immense numbers, taking possession to the right
                    and left of the Salient and keeping up a constant fire of artillery and musketry
                    for twenty-four hours.</p>
                <p>Gen. Gordon was heavily engaged-one brigade broken, and its commander (Robert D.
                    Johnston) wounded, but he held his ground, drove out the enemy in his immediate
                    front by a strong effort, and regained a portion of our works to the right of
                    the Salient. Their main effort was evidently against Rodes' position to the left
                    of the Angle, and here the fighting was of the most desperate character. Gen.
                    Rodes moved Daniel's brigade from its works to meet the enemy. Gen. Kershaw
                    extended so as to allow Ramseur to be withdrawn, and as Daniel's right was
                    unprotected Ramseur was sent in there. He retook the works to Daniel's right
                    along his whole brigade front by a charge of unsurpassed gallantry, but the
                    Salient was still held by the enemy, and a most deadly fire poured on his right
                    flank. Accordingly Harris' (Mississippi) brigade, which came to my assistance
                    about 9 a.m., was sent to Ramseur's right, but as it still failed to fill the
                    trenches, McGowan's (South Carolina) brigade, which arrived an hour later, was
                    ordered to the same point. Only part of this brigade succeeded in reaching the
                    trenches and joining Harris' brigade. Spite of the terrible flank fire to which
                    they were yet exposed, the brave troops of these three brigades held their
                    ground till 3 a.m. of May 13, when ordered back to the new line. Gen. Daniel was
                    killed and Gen. Ramseur severely wounded early in the day, but the latter
                    refused to leave the field.</p>
                <p>The nature of the struggle will be apparent from the fact that after the loss of
                    Johnson's division (before sunrise) my force barely numbered 8,000, the
                    re-enforcements about 1,500 more. Gen. Edward Johnson estimated the enemy's
                    force at this part of the field at over 40,000, and I have every reason to
                    believe this a moderate calculation. The engagement was spoken of in Northern
                    papers as a general attack by their army. It was met only by my corps and three
                    brigades sent to my aid, and after lasting with unintermitted vigor from 4.30
                    a.m. till 4 p.m. of May 12, ceased by degrees, leaving us in possession of
                    two-thirds of the works first taken from us and of four of the captured guns,
                    which the enemy had been unable to haul off. These guns were withdrawn by hand
                    to the McCool house, and Gen. Long was directed to send after them at night.
                    Maj. Page, whom he instructed to get them, left the duty to an ordnance
                    sergeant, who failed to find them, and they were again allowed to fall into the
                    enemy's hands.</p>
                <p>As it was unadvisable to continue efforts to retake the Salient with the force at
                    my command, a new line was laid out during the day by Gen. Lee's chief engineer
                    some 800 yards in rear of the first and constructed at night. After midnight my
                    forces were quietly withdrawn to it and artillery placed in position; but his
                    efforts and losses on the 12th seemed to have exhausted the enemy, and all was
                    quiet till May 18, when a strong force advanced past the McCool house toward our
                    new line. When well within range Gen. Long opened upon them with thirty pieces
                    of artillery, which, with the fire of our skirmishers, broke and drove them back
                    with severe loss. We afterward learned that they were two fresh divisions,
                    nearly 10,000 strong just come up from the rear.</p>
                <p>On May 19 Gen. Lee directed me to demonstrate against the enemy in my front, as
                    he believed they were moving to his right and wished to ascertain. As they were
                    strongly entrenched in front I obtained leave to move round their right. After a
                    detour of several miles through roads impassable for my artillery I came on the
                    enemy prepared to receive me. My force was about 6,000, his much larger. His
                    position being developed and my object attained, I was about to retire, when he
                    attacked me. Part of my line was shaken, but Pegram's brigade, of Early's
                    division (Col. Hoffman commanding), and Ramseur's, of Rodes', held their ground
                    so firmly that I maintained my position till night-fall, then withdrew
                    unmolested. My loss was about 900 killed, wounded, and missing.</p>
                <p>Next day Gen. Early returned to his division and Gen. Gordon was put in command
                    of one composed of his own brigade and the remnants of Johnson's division.
                    Hoke's brigade (Col. Lewis commanding) returned to Early's division, and the
                    Twenty-first Georgia Regt. to Doles' brigade. We moved to Hanover Junction,
                    where my corps took the right of the line. After some days' skirmishing we
                    marched toward the Totopotomoy. When we moved I reported to the commanding
                    general that in consequence of a severe attack of diarrhea I would leave Gen.
                    Early in command while the troops were on the march, and on Friday I rode in an
                    ambulance to Mechanicsville, remaining in my tent Saturday and Sunday, May 28
                    and 29.</p>
                <p>On Sunday I reported that I would be ready for duty in two days more, and sent a
                    certificate of Staff Surgeon McGuire to the same effect. The commanding general
                    relieved me on Sunday, placing Gen. Early in temporary command of my corps. I
                    reported for duty on Tuesday, four days after my at tack, and remainder over a
                    week with the army, wishing to place the question of health beyond a doubt, but
                    the change of commanders was made permanent, and on June 14 I was placed in
                    command of the Defenses of Richmond. The losses of my corps from May 4 to 27
                    were, it will be seen, very heavy, and including prisoners amounted to over
                    one-half. Of the 14 generals who began the campaign under me, Gen.'s John M.
                    Jones, L. A. Stafford, and Junius Daniel were killed; Gen.'s John Pegram, Harry
                    T. Hays, James A. Walker, and Robert D. Johnston wounded; Gen.'s Edward Johnson
                    and George H. Steuart, taken prisoners and Gen. Early most of the time detached.
                    Gen. Jones had been twice wounded-at Gettysburg and at Mine Run. I considered
                    his loss an irreparable one to his brigade. Gen. Edward Johnson once said of
                    Gen. Stafford that he was the bravest man he ever saw. Such a compliment from
                    one himself brave almost to a fault and habitually sparing of praise needs no
                    remark. Gen. Daniel's services at Gettysburg, as well as on the bloody field
                    where he fell, were of the most distinguished character. Gen. Walker was wounded
                    in an attempt to stem the attack on his division early on May 12.</p>
                <p>My staff during this campaign consisted of Lieut. Col. A. S. Pendleton and Maj.
                    Campbell Brown, assistant adjutant-general; Col. A. Smead (colonel of
                    artillery), assistant inspector-general; Maj. B. H. Greene, engineer; Lieut.
                    Thomas T. Turner, aide-de-camp; Lieut. Col. William Allan, chief of ordnance;
                    Surg. Hunter McGuire, medical director; Majs. John D. Roges and A. M. Garber,
                    quartermasters (Maj. Harman having been transferred just before the campaign
                    opened); Maj. W. J. Hawks and Capt. J. J. Lock, commissaries of subsistence. All
                    except Maj.'s Brown, Greene, and Rogers and Lieut. Turner, had been of the staff
                    of Lieut.-Gen. Jackson. That officer should be held hardly more remarkable for
                    his brilliant campaigns than for the judgment he almost invariably showed in his
                    sections of men. It would be difficult, without personal knowledge, to
                    appreciate Col. Pendleton's great gallantry; his coolness and clearness of
                    judgment under every trial; his soldier-like and cheerful performance of every
                    duty. On one occasion I expressed a wish to recommend him to a vacant brigade,
                    but he declined, thinking his services more valuable on the staff. Maj. Hawks
                    deserves the highest praise I can give him for his ability and zeal, so
                    impressing me that I have often wished he could have a command in the line if it
                    were possible to fill his place on the staff. It is but simple justice to say
                    that the quiet and efficient manner in which Surgeon McGuire performed the
                    duties of his important department left nothing to be desired, while Col.
                    Allan's abilities were recognized at headquarters by both compliments, and
                    promotion. Maj. Brown had been with me from the first battle of Manassas, and on
                    nearly every field had been intrusted with important duties. On no occasion did
                    I have reason to regret my confidence in his coolness, judgment, and discretion.
                    I also wished to recommend him for promotion to a Tennessee brigade, but he
                    declined. Probably no officer had more distinguished himself by repeated acts of
                    personal bravery and dash than Lieut. T. T. Turner, or with so slight personal
                    advancement. Up to the time when he was wounded at Spotsylvania Court-House, he
                    had constantly been foremost wherever opportunities presented themselves.
                    Lieuts. Harper Carroll and John Taliaferro, acting aides-de-camp, had horses
                    shot under them on May 12, and displayed much personal gallantry.</p>
                <p>My total loss at the Wilderness was 1,250 killed and wounded. The burial parties
                    from two divisions reported interring over 1,100 of the enemy. The third and
                    largest made no report. When we moved probably one-third or more were still
                    unburied of those who were within reach of our lines. At Spotsylvania, though
                    the enemy held the ground for a week, we found on regaining it many of their
                    dead still unburied, while the numerous graves showed their loss to have been
                    immense. It just have exceeded ours in the proportion of at least 6 to 1, taking
                    all the engagements together.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. S. EWELL, Lieut.-Gen.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--Accompanying will be found copies of subordinate
                        reports. None were received from Gen. Rodes up to the time of his death. R.
                        S. E. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
