<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0083"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0083">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Wilderness, 107th Pa. Infantry, Report of Brig. Gen. John C.
                    Robinson, April 25, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">wilderness, 107th pa infantry report of brig gen john c robinson april 25 1866</title>
        <author>Robinson, John C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0083</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500123</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII RAPIDAN TO THE JAMES., No. 119. Report of Brig. Gen.
                            John C. Robinson, U. S. Army, commanding Second Division, of operations
                            May 3-8. Robinson reports heavy fighting in difficult terrain.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii rapidan to the james , no 119 report of brig gen john c robinson u s army commanding second division of operations may 3 8 robinson reports heavy fighting in difficult terrain</title>
            <author>John C. Robinson</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 36. Part I, Reports, Serial No. 67</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 592</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-04-25">1866-04-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 107th Pa. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Wilderness</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0083T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. John C. Robinson commanded the Second Division of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 107th Pa. Inf.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. G. K. WARREN, Late Commander Fifth Army Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-04-25">April 25, 1866.</date>
                        <name type="place">WASHINGTON, D.C.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In compliance with your request I have the honor to submit the following
                    memorandum of the operations of the Second Division, Fifth Army Corps, from
                    Culpeper Court-House to Spotsylvania Court-House in May, 1864:</p>
                <p>The division left its encampment near Culpeper Court-House and Mitchell's Station
                    at midnight on the 3d of May; crossed the Rapidan at Germanna Ford on the 4th,
                    and encamped that night near the Old Wilderness Tavern. On the morning of the
                    5th it started again on the march, taking the dirt road to Parker's Store,
                    preceded by the Third and Fourth Division of the Fifth Corps. The advance of the
                    column having encountered the enemy, my division was halted and formed in column
                    near Lacy's house and held in reserve. The Fourth (Wadsworth's) Division, having
                    been ordered to attack the enemy, I sent my Third Brigade to support it. In this
                    movement the brigade met with considerable loss. Soon after Griffin's (First)
                    division became heavily engaged on the road leading to Robertson's Tavern, and I
                    was directed to go to his support. I moved my First and Second Brigade rapidly
                    out on the road, and at the close of the engagement relieved Griffin's division,
                    which was withdrawn to the rear after suffering heavy loss. My First Brigade,
                    under command of Col. Lyle, Ninetieth Pennsylvania Volunteers, occupied the
                    line, having the Sixth Corps on our right. In the afternoon, Gen. Wadsworth
                    having been directed to take part in the heavy engagement going on our left,
                    with your permission I accompanied him, taking with me my second Brigade,
                    commanded by Brig.-Gen. Baxter. Soon after entering the woods we became engaged
                    with the enemy and drove him steadily before us until dark put an end to the
                    affair, and I returned to the main body of my division. In this engagement my
                    assistant inspector-general, Lieut.-Col. Allen, Twelfth Massachusetts
                    Volunteers, a most worthy and meritorious officer, fell mortally wounded while
                    riding at my side. The command became engaged again the next morning and
                    suffered severely. Gen. Wadsworth was killed and Gen. Baxter wounded. On the
                    evening of the 5th, while my Second Brigade was engaged on the left, the First
                    Brigade on the turnpike road was ordered to advance against the enemy, and the
                    Ninetieth Pennsylvania Volunteers having to cross an open field, was exposed to
                    a terrific fire of musketry and artillery, which nearly destroyed the regiment.
                    For some reason, never explained, the troops on the right of this brigade,
                    although protected by the woods, failed to advance with it. On the afternoon of
                    the 6th I was ordered to send one brigade to the support of Maj.-Gen. Hancock on
                    the Brock road. Soon after I was directed to send another, and went with it
                    myself. I formed these brigades in two lines on the right of the Second Corps,
                    and remained there until the afternoon of the next day.</p>
                <p>After seeing my division well established in this position, and having ordered
                    rifle-pits constructed, I rode to Gen. Hancock's headquarters. He informed me
                    that he had received orders to attack the enemy, and desired me to get ready to
                    assault. I immediately returned to my command, made the necessary dispositions
                    for the movement, and awaited orders. About two hours after I heard sharp
                    musketry on my left, and Maj.-Gen. Birney came to me in great haste, stating
                    that the enemy had broken through our lines and Gen. Hancock was cut off. I
                    asked him what force had broken through, and he replied three or four divisions.
                    I at once faced my second line about and made proper dispositions to received an
                    attack on my left and rear. Gen. Birney then asked my opinion as to the
                    propriety of changing the position of the whole line. I replied, "Before doing
                    that you had better report what has occurred to Gen. Meade." He said he had
                    already done so. While we were conversing on the subject a staff officer came up
                    and informed Gen. Birney that Gen. Hancock desired to see him. I learned soon
                    after that instead of breaking through our lines the enemy had been repulsed,
                    but not until after one division of the Second Corps had been driven from the
                    breast-works.</p>
                <p>At 9 p.m. on the 7th the army commenced the flank movement to the left, the Fifth
                    Corps leading, with my division in advance. Our march was impeded by darkness,
                    bad roads, small streams, and fallen timber; yet, knowing the importance of
                    reaching Spotsylvania Court-House before the enemy, the troops were urged
                    forward as rapidly as possible.</p>
                <p>At daylight on the morning of the 8th I overtook the advance guard of cavalry,
                    which was engaged with the enemy. I immediately deployed two brigades, holding
                    the third in reserve, pushed by the cavalry (commanded by Brig.-Gen. Merritt),
                    and drove the light troops and artillery of the enemy from one position to
                    another, through woods and across open fields for about 3 miles. Coming to
                    another field I could plainly see the enemy's line in the edge of timber beyond.
                    I here halted and reformed the division, and again advanced to the attack. The
                    division was soon checked and it became evident that here was the enemy's main
                    line, but his strength was undeveloped. Knowing that my brave men would followed
                    wherever I led the way, I placed myself at their head and led them forward to
                    the attack. At this moment a part of Griffin's division advanced out of the
                    woods on my right. Cheering my men on, we had arrived within 50 yards of the
                    works when I received a musket-ball in the left knee, resulting in amputation of
                    my left. This unfortunate wound caused the result I feared, for as I was borne
                    off the field I saw that our troops were repulsed and the attack had failed. Our
                    loss this day was heavy, but I have never been able to learn the number of
                    killed and wounded.</p>
                <p>It was my intention to have made a full report of these operations, but having
                    failed to receive the reports of my brigade commanders, I have been unable to do
                    so. This brief statement, made at this late day, is necessarily imperfect, but
                    is correct so far as it goes. I regret exceedingly that I am not able to do full
                    justice to the brave officers and men who served so long and faithfully under my
                    command, and whose gallantry has been conspicuous on many hard-fought fields.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JNO. C. ROBINSON, Brevet Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
