<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0094"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0094">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Spotsylvania Court House, 87th Pa. Infantry, Report of Col.
                    William S. Truex, November 19, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">spotsylvania court house, 87th pa infantry report of col william s truex november 19 1864</title>
        <author>Truex, William S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0094</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500131</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII. RAPIDAN TO THE JAMES., No. 169 Report of Col. William
                            S. Truex, Fourteenth New Jersey Infantry, commanding First Brigade, of
                            operations May 9-June 11.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii rapidan to the james , no 169 report of col william s truex fourteenth new jersey infantry commanding first brigade of operations may 9 june 11</title>
            <author>William S. Truex</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 36. Part I. Reports, Serial No. Serial No. 67.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Page 725</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-11-19">1864-11-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 87th Pa. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Spotsylvania Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0094T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. William S. Truex commanded the First Brigade of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 87th Pa. Inf. Truex details the activities of the brigade
                    during May and June.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. FIRST Brig., THIRD DIV., SIXTH CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. ANDREW J. SMITH, Acting Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-11-19">November 19, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of this brigade
                    from May 4 to July 9, 1864. To cover the first epoch, I inclose a verbatim
                    report+ of Brig. Gen. William H. Morris, who commanded the brigade, and who was
                    wounded early in the morning of the 9th of May, 1864.</p>
                <p>FIRST EPOCH.</p>
                <p>Immediately after the wounding of Brig.-Gen. Morris, Col. Schall, Eighty-seventh
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, senior officer, took command of the brigade. At 6.30
                    p.m. the skirmish line was ordered to advance, and furious cannonading was
                    immediately opened on both sides, with but little effect on the part of the
                    enemy. May 10.--At 10 a.m. heavy cannonading and musketry opened along the whole
                    line. It was reported by prisoners taken that Gen. Longstreet was severely
                    wounded. The cannonading was continued until 8.15 p.m., being the most severe
                    fire we have been under this campaign.</p>
                <p>May 11.--The usual skirmishing was continued this day. Relieved Col. Smith's
                    brigade in the earth-works before dark.</p>
                <p>May 12.--Moved by the left flank at 10 a.m. about 1 1/2 miles and formed line of
                    battle in two lines and almost instantly engaged, the brigade suffering severely
                    in killed and wounded. The command worked all night throwing up works.</p>
                <p>May 13.--Musketry fire was kept up almost incessantly all night. The enemy having
                    been driven from their position, the brigade was ordered to advance and relieve
                    the troops in our front. In the afternoon at 3 p.m. fell back to our original
                    position, and earth-works were erected. On the morning of the 14th moved in the
                    direction of Spotsylvania Court-House. Col. William S. Truex, Fourteenth New
                    Jersey Volunteers, having reported for duty, was ordered to take command,
                    relieving Col. Schall, Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers; crossed the River
                    Po, and bivouacked for the night.</p>
                <p>May 15.--Intrenched ourselves on the hill known as Gayle's Hill, and remained
                    quiet all day.</p>
                <p>May 17.--At 8.45 in the evening moved back across the River Po and reoccupied the
                    position we held the 13th instant, which we reached at 4.30 a.m. The troops very
                    much exhausted. May 18.--Fell back to our old position on Laurel Hill. At 4.30
                    a.m. our brigade advanced over the works, when severe skirmishing immediately
                    commenced. At 2.30 p.m. returned to Gayle's Hill, with orders to be in readiness
                    to move at daylight.</p>
                <p>May 19.--At 5 a.m. moved about 1 1/2 miles to the right and formed line of battle
                    on the extreme left of the Sixth Army Corps, and earthworks thrown up.</p>
                <p>SECOND EPOCH.</p>
                <p>May 21.--At 12 m. we moved again in the direction of Po River; marched all night.</p>
                <p>May 22.--Marched on toward the North Anna River; bivouacked for the night at
                    Harris' Store.</p>
                <p>May 23.--At 9.15 a.m. marched in the direction of Beaver Dam. When within about 2
                    miles of North Anna River halted, and bivouacked. Heavy firing was heard in our
                    front.</p>
                <p>THIRD EPOCH.</p>
                <p>May 24.--Moved forward at 6 a.m. and crossed the North Anna at the town of
                    Jericho. We remained on the south bank until 5.45 p.m., when we moved forward
                    about a mile in line of battle and rested on our arms all night.</p>
                <p>May 25.--Moved forward at 9 a.m. At 9.30 crossed the Virginia Central Railroad at
                    Noel's Station. We followed the railroad for about 2 miles, when we halted and
                    commenced destroying the road, burning the cross-ties and bending the rails.
                    Afterward returned and received orders to connect with our brigade on the right
                    of Gen. Russell's division, and to receive our orders for that night only from
                    Gen. Russell.</p>
                <p>May 26.--At 7.45 p.m. moved forward to Hanovertown, on the Pamunkey; recrossed
                    the North Anna at Jericho on pontoon bridge and marched to Chesterfield Station,
                    which we reached at about 2.30 a.m., after the most fatiguing march of the
                    campaign.</p>
                <p>May 27.--Moved forward at 4 a.m.; marched all day and halted at dark in King
                    William Valley, near the Pamunkey.</p>
                <p>FOURTH EPOCH.</p>
                <p>May 28.--Moved forward at 8 a.m.; crossed the Pamunkey on pontoon bridge near the
                    Widow Nelson's house at 11.30 a.m. We marched about 2 miles south of the river
                    in front of Pollard's mansion, where we formed line of battle and threw up
                    earth-works immediately.</p>
                <p>May 30.--At 4 a.m. moved in the direction of Hanover Court-House. The order was
                    afterward countermanded, and we returned toward Hanovertown, formed line of
                    battle on the hill in front of Hundley's house, on right of Second Corps, and
                    bivouacked for the night.</p>
                <p>May 31.--Drove the enemy from their position in our front and occupied their
                    works. Our loss trifling.</p>
                <p>June 1.--At 12.45 a.m. moved in the direction of Gaines' Mill, by Cold Harbor,
                    which place we reached at 12 m. 5 p.m. we formed line of battle in four lines,
                    and, in connection with the First and Second Divisions of the corps on our left,
                    and the Eighteenth Corps on our right, we charged the enemy in their works. The
                    enemy resisted with great stubbornness, and it was one of the most hotly
                    contested fields of the campaign. The fighting ceased at dark, we having
                    advanced our lines about three-fourths of a mile. Our loss in this battle was
                    very heavy, especially in officers. We captured about 500 prisoners. At the
                    onset Col. Truex, commanding brigade, was wounded, and Lieut.-Col. Hall,
                    Fourteenth New Jersey Volunteers, senior officer, took command. The next morning
                    Gen. Meade issued to our division a congratulatory order, which I herewith
                    append:</p>
                <p>HDQRS. ARMY OF THE POTOMAC, June 1, 1864.</p>
                <p>Maj.-Gen. WRIGHT:</p>
                <p>Please give my thanks to Brig.-Gen. Ricketts and his gallant command for the very
                    handsome manner in which they have conducted themselves to-day. The success
                    attained by them is of great importance, and if followed up will materially
                    advance our operations.</p>
                <p>Very respectfully, yours,</p>
                <p>GEO. G. MEADE,</p>
                <p>Maj.-Gen., Cmdg.</p>
                <p>GEN.: Maj.-Gen. Wright directs me to say that he transmits the within to you with
                    great pleasure.</p>
                <p>Your obedient servant,</p>
                <p>R. F. HALSTED,</p>
                <p>Capt. and Aide-de-Camp.</p>
                <p>June 2.--Col. Schall, commanding Eighty-seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, by
                    virtue of his rank, assumed command of the brigade early in the morning. At 4
                    p.m. received orders to advance our lines at 4 a.m. on the 3d instant.</p>
                <p>June 3.--At the above-named hour the brigade, in connection with the whole corps,
                    advanced about half a mile, when the enemy were met in force. Finding the enemy
                    could not be dislodged, we received orders to throw up earth-works, which was
                    done under a severe artillery fire from the enemy. Our loss was again very
                    heavy, especially in officers. About 10 a.m. Col. Schall, commanding brigade,
                    was severely wounded in the left arm, when the command again devolved on
                    Lieut.-Col. Hall.</p>
                <p>From June 4 until June 11 no movement was made from this position. On the evening
                    of June 7, under a flag of truce, details from both armies were made for the
                    purpose of burying the dead and bringing in the wounded. During this period of
                    seven days our pickets were constantly skirmishing, and at intervals furious
                    cannonading.</p>
                <p>June 11.--In the morning, a little before daylight, moved from our position on
                    the right of the First Division to the left of the same and relieved a division
                    of the Second Corps.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>WM. S. TRUEX, Col., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
