<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0113"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0113">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Petersburg, 184th Pa. Infantry, Report of Lieut. Col. Horace P.
                    Rugg, October 28, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">petersburg, 184th pa infantry report of lieut col horace p rugg october 28 1864</title>
        <author>Rugg, Horace P.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0113</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500141</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LIV. THE RICHMOND CAMPAIGN., No. 49 Reports of Lieut. Col.
                            Horace P. Rugg, Fifty-ninth New York Infantry, commanding First Brigade,
                            of operations August 12-26 and October 26-28.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap liv the richmond campaign , no 49 reports of lieut col horace p rugg fifty ninth new york infantry commanding first brigade of operations august 12 26 and october 26 28</title>
            <author>Horace P. Rugg</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 42. Part I, Reports, Serial No. 87</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 303</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-10-28">1864-10-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 184th Pa. Inf.</term>
                    <term>Battle: Petersburg</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0113T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieutenant Colonel Horace P. Rugg commands the First Brigade of the Army of the
                    Potomac which includes the 184th Pennsylvania Infantry. Rugg reports that the
                    brigade was engaged all day and was driven back until reenforcements
                arrived.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. FIRST Brig., SECOND DIV., SECOND ARMY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. WILLIAM H. GILDER, Acting Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-10-28">October 28, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of operations of this command
                    from the 26th to 28th instant:</p>
                <p>At 2 p.m. on the afternoon of the 26th we left camp, in the rear of Fort Bross,
                    and moved to the Vaughan house, on the Weldon railroad, where we bivouacked for
                    the night. The next morning, at 3.30 o'clock we moved out in the direction of
                    the Boydton plank road, first meeting the enemy at Hatcher's Run, but as they
                    were driven from this position by the Third Brigade, the First Brigade was not
                    engaged. From this point we took the advance, driving the enemy to the Boydton
                    plank road. At this point we formed line of battle across the road, but before
                    getting into position we were opened upon from a battery of the enemy, which was
                    soon after silenced by Beck's battery (C and I), Fifth U. S. Artillery. From
                    this point we advanced in line of battle and took up a position on the left of
                    the plank road, extending from the Burgess house, connecting with the Second
                    Brigade on the right, to a ravine on the left, which was not connected but was
                    protected by the First Minnesota Battalion and Seventh Michigan Volunteers,
                    which I deployed to cover our flank and rear. While in this position the enemy
                    opened upon us from the left with a battery of rifle guns, which enfiladed our
                    lines, and continued firing from them during the remainder of the day, killing
                    and wounding many of our men. Our skirmish line in front was continually engaged
                    with the enemy's lines and at one time was driven by him. We held this position
                    until after the assault by the enemy was made. While in this position the enemy
                    succeeded in obtaining possession of the plank road in our rear, severing for
                    the time our communications, when Maj. Mitchell, of Gen. Hancock's staff,
                    charged down the road with the Thirty-sixth Wisconsin Regiment, capturing many
                    prisoners and one color, as is shown by the special report, accompanying this,
                    of Capt. Fisk, commanding Thirty-sixth Wisconsin Regt. Maj. Mitchell desired me
                    to move my whole brigade in this charge, but I did not do it, for the following
                    reasons: First, I had just received orders, by a staff officer from Gen. Egan,
                    to hold the position I was then in at all hazards; second, the enemy were
                    continually threatening our left flank and front; third, the enemy on the road
                    was not in force, but a disorganized body, and I considered that one good-sized
                    regiment, charging down the road in line, would be as effectual as the whole
                    brigade.</p>
                <p>About 5 p.m. the brigade was moved to the extreme left of the second line, facing
                    to the right and rear, and shortly afterward was again moved to the right and in
                    rear of Col. McAllister's brigade of the Third Division. When moving from our
                    position on the left of the plank road I left the First Minnesota and Seventh
                    Michigan Volunteers in their position in the wood on our left and rear, as they
                    were continually picking up prisoners. After dark the command was moved down and
                    formed in the plank road, connecting on the right with the Third Division, and
                    on the left with Col. McAllister's brigade, throwing out vedettes in front and
                    rear. About 11 p.m. we left this position and moved off with the rest of the
                    column, forming the rear guard. Halting the next morning about 4 o'clock in rear
                    of the Second Division of the Fifth Corps, I received orders from in line of
                    battle, connecting with the Second Brigade on the right and extending to the
                    left. That brigade did not form line, but moved to the rear of the Fifth Corps.
                    As they were the directing brigade I followed them and conformed myself to their
                    movements. Shortly after daylight we took up the line of march (at the head of
                    the division) for our present camp, which were reached about 4 p.m. The First
                    Minnesota and Seventh Michigan Volunteers were left on the skirmish line, as
                    they had changed their position and could not be found when the balance of the
                    brigade left. They remained on the field until the next morning (October 28),
                    when they left at 9.30 o'clock and reached camp at 9 o'clock this morning
                    (October 29). I inclose report of Capt. Farwell.</p>
                <p>Our loss during the operations was 1 officer and 9 enlisted men killed, 34
                    enlisted men wounded, and 95 enlisted men missing; making a total of 1 officer
                    and 138 enlisted men.+ The number missing will probably be reduced by the return
                    of stragglers. The officer killed was Capt. Musson, commanding One hundred and
                    fifty-second New York Volunteers, a brave and able officer. The troops of the
                    command behaved gallantly. Two colors and upward of 400 prisoners were captured,
                    besides a color captured by a man of the Thirty-sixth Wisconsin Volunteers,
                    which was afterward taken from him. I beg leave to mention for especial
                    gallantry my acting staff, Capt. George W. Ryerson, Fifty-ninth New York Veteran
                    Volunteers, acting assistant adjutant-general; Lieut. Ansel L. White, Nineteenth
                    Maine Volunteers, acting aide-de-camp; W. Stone, Nineteenth Massachusetts
                    Volunteers, acting aide-de-camp (each of these officers had his horse shot under
                    him while carrying orders, and my own horse was wounded while rallying one of
                    the brigades of the Third Division); and also Capts. J. C. Farwell, First
                    Minnesota Battalion, and George W. La Point, Seventh Michigan Volunteers, for
                    fighting their way through the enemy's cavalry on the morning of the 28th;
                    Sergt. Alonzo Smith,++ Company C, Seventh Michigan Volunteers, for capturing the
                    colors of the Twenty-Sixth North Carolina (rebel) Regiment, and Sergt. Daniel J.
                    Murphy,++ Nineteenth Massachusetts Volunteers, for capturing the colors of the
                    Forty-seventh North Carolina (rebel) Regt.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>HORACE P. RUGG, Lieut. Col. Fifty-ninth New York Volunteers, Cmdg.
                        Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
