<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0186"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0186">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Sailor's Creek, 17th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Brig. Gen. Thomas C.
                    Devin, [undated]</title>
        <title type="sort">sailors creek, 17th pa cavalry report of brig gen thomas c devin undated</title>
        <author>Devin, Thomas C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0186</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500161</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA. Report of
                            Brig. Gen. Thomas C. Devin, U. S. Army, commanding First Division.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa report of brig gen thomas c devin u s army commanding first division</title>
            <author>Thomas C. Devin</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1125</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value=""/>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 17th Pa. Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Sailor's Creek</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0186T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brig. Gen. Thomas C. Devin commanded the First Division in the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 17th Pennsylvania Cavalry. Devin reports on engaging
                    in an intense cavalry battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <p>Report of Brig. Gen. Thomas C. Devin, U. S. Army, commanding First Division.</p>
                <p>On the morning of April 6 the division marched in the direction of Deatonsville,
                    following Third Division; soon after the enemy's train was reported to be moving
                    upon the road to Rice's Station, on the South Side Railroad, and the division
                    was ordered to cross the country and attack. The country was broken, intersected
                    with ravines and ditches, but in a very few minutes the division struck the
                    flank of the train, only to find it covered by a heavy force of infantry and
                    artillery in position; moving still farther to the left the same result was
                    obtained. Learning that the Third Division had pushed in on the left of the
                    Second, I moved rapidly toward the left of the Third, hoping to strike the train
                    at a vulnerable point. As I was passing to the rear of Third Division I received
                    an urgent message from Gen. Custer, stating that he had struck and captured part
                    of the train and was hard pressed. On joining him I found it necessary to bring
                    up the division on a gallop, and form on his right, in order to hold the ground
                    across Sailor's Creek and secure his captures. The division succeeded in
                    checking the enemy's advance, and was soon after ordered to the extreme left.
                    The division had scarcely reached its new position when it was found necessary
                    to return to the support of the Third Division, which had been forced back. The
                    enemy being checked, the division was again ordered to the extreme left, and
                    succeeded in reaching the road within two miles of Rice's Station. It was now
                    dark, but the command pushed on and soon struck the enemy's rear guard. They
                    were pushed rapidly forward, until, at the crossing of (upper) Sailor's Creek,
                    we found Mahone's division of infantry in position, with artillery covering the
                    crossing. On attempting to force a crossing the enemy opened a heavy fire of
                    musketry, shell, and canister at short range, and, in accordance with
                    instructions, the division was retired one mile, and encamped at 12 p.m.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
