<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0183"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0183">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Hatcher's Run, 210th Pa. Infantry, Report of Bvt. Brig. Gen.
                    James Gwyn, February 14, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">hatchers run, 210th pa infantry report of bvt brig gen james gwyn february 14 1865</title>
        <author>Gwyn, James</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0183</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500158</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., N. 108
                            Report of Bvt. Brig. Gen. James Gwyn, One hundred and eighteenth
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, commanding Third Brigade, of operations February
                            5-7.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa n 108 report of bvt brig gen james gwyn one hundred and eighteenth pennsylvania infantry commanding third brigade of operations february 5 7</title>
            <author>James Gwyn</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 283</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-02-14">1865-02-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 210th Pa. Infantry</term>
                    <term>Brigade: Hatcher's Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0183T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bvt. Brig. Gen. James Gwyn commanded the Third Brigade of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 210th Pa. Infantry. Gwyn reports on the movements of the
                    units in his brigade.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. THIRD BRIGADE, SECOND DIVISION, FIFTH CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Major</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-02-14">February 14, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of operations during the 5th,
                    6th, and 7th instant:</p>
                <p>At 6.30 o'clock on the morning of the 5th of February my command moved, in
                    accordance with circular from corps headquarters, of the 4th instant, left in
                    front, in the following order: First, Two hundred and tenth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, Col. William Sergeant commanding; second, Third Delaware Volunteers,
                    Maj. James E. Baily commanding; third, One hundred and ninety-first Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, Capt. P. L. Norton, commanding; fourth, one hundred and ninetieth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, Capt. R. M. Birkman commanding; fifth, One hundred and
                    fifty-seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, Bvt. Maj. D. H. Kent commanding. The
                    route was along the Halifax road, my brigade being in the advance. The cavalry
                    being unable to overcome the opposition made by the enemy at Rowanty Creek, the
                    One hundred and ninetieth and One hundred and ninety-first Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers were advanced as skirmishers, supported by Fourth Delaware
                    Volunteers, and ordered to take the works beyond the creek. The other regiments
                    of brigade were also brought up. But few men could get across, as the bridge was
                    destroyed. These few, however, succeeded in dislodging the enemy and capturing a
                    few prisoners. After a short delay, to cover the crossing of remainder of
                    division, the brigade again advanced some three or four miles and took up
                    position before dark on the left of Second Brigade. The march was again resumed
                    at 11 o'clock, and continued until reaching the crossing of Vaughan road at
                    Harcher's Run, when the brigade was massed in reserve. During morning of the 6th
                    instant relieved Gen. Winthrop's brigade in the works. In the afternoon moved
                    right in front, following the Second Brigade to the right and in front of the
                    works occupied by the First Division. Then, forming in two lines, moved by the
                    right flank through the woods till the Second Brigade had gained position.*
                    While waiting the order to advance the left of brigade was broken by the
                    stampede of a portion of Gen. Gregg's cavalry, but was afterward rallied and
                    placed in position on left of Second Brigade. I advanced the brigade and engaged
                    the enemy for about two hours; not being supported on either my right or left
                    flank I returned to crest of hill in front of breast-work.</p>
                <p>Tuesday, 7th instant, reoccupied the line of works on left of Second Division.</p>
                <p>I herewith transmit nominal and tabular list of casualties during the engagement.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JAMES GWYN, <lb/> Brevet Brig.-Gen., Cmdg. Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
