<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0180"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0180">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Hatcher's Run, 207th Pa. Infantry, Reports of Bvt. Maj. Gen. John
                    F. Hartranft, February 13, 1865 </title>
        <title type="sort">hatchers run, 207th pa infantry reports of bvt maj gen john f hartranft february 13 1865</title>
        <author>Hartranft, John F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0180</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500155</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., No. 154.
                            Reports of Bvt. Maj. Gen. John F. Hartranft, U. S. Army, commanding
                            Third Division, of operations February 5-10 and March 25.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa no 154 reports of bvt maj gen john f hartranft u s army commanding third division of operations february 5 10 and march 25</title>
            <author>John F. Hartranft</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 344</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-02-13">1865-02-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 207th Pa. Infantry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Hatcher's Run</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0180T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bvt. Maj. Gen. John F. Hartranft commanded the Third Division of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 207th Pa. Hartranft reports that the division did not
                    engage the enemy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. THIRD DIVISION, NINTH ARMY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. P. M. LYDIG, <lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.,
                        Ninth Army Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-02-13">February 13, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the part taken by my command
                    in the late movement on the left, in the vicinity of Hatcher's Run:</p>
                <p>In obedience to orders received near 3 p.m., 5th instant, I moved my command as
                    soon as possible, the whole division being on the march in light order by 4 p.m.
                    At 8 p.m. I reported to Maj.-Gen. Humphreys, commanding Second Army Corps, some
                    two miles down the Vaughan Road from Fort Siebert, with my command in good
                    order, having made the march very rapidly, and, as I believe, without a
                    straggler. Gen. Humphreys placed me in position on his immediate right, with
                    orders to entrench myself during the night; my right rested a few rods in front
                    of the Claypole house, the left on a wide, impenetrable swamp which covered the
                    right of the Second Corps, the general direction of my line being nearly north
                    and south. At daylight on the 6th instant the command had a good line of works
                    1,000 yards in length, joined on the right by a line constructed by the First
                    Division, Sixth Army Corps. Near 10 a.m. I received orders from Gen. Humphreys
                    to send out a regiment on a reconnaissance, with instructions to move by way of
                    the Smith and Hawks houses, and ascertain, if possible, the position and force
                    of the enemy outside of their main works with the view of attacking him in force
                    if found. I ordered out the Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, Lieut.-Col.
                    McCall, commanding, under charge of Capt. Watts, one of my staff officers, who
                    was well acquainted with the various roads in the vicinity as well as the
                    position of the enemy's main line. This officer soon reported that there was no
                    enemy in my front outside of their works, except the usual pickets, who occupied
                    their customary pits, when, in obedience to orders from Gen. Humphreys, the
                    party were ordered to return to the division. At 2 p.m. I received orders to at
                    once relieve Gen. Wheaton's division of the Sixth Corps from the line on my
                    right, and hold the extended works from my present left to the vicinity of Fort
                    Cummings. By placing my reserve regiments on the line, I still had a reasonably
                    strong one. Large details were immediately sent out to slash the timber in
                    front.</p>
                <p>February 7, the slashing was continued with all the available axes. At 1 p.m. I
                    received orders to hold 1,500 men in readiness to move promptly to the support
                    of Maj.-Gen. Warren, Fifth Corps, in the event of its being absolutely
                    necessary. I ordered Col. Diven, commanding a First Brigade, to call in all
                    details and hold his brigade ready to move promptly in answer to such a call,
                    the axes in his possession being transferred to the Second Brigade, which sent
                    out an additional detail to keep them occupied. February 8, 9 and 10 were
                    occupied in opening and building roads. At 7 p.m., 10th instant, I received
                    orders from Gen. Humphreys, relieving my command from duty with the Second Army
                    Corps. The command moved at 8 o'clock, reaching camp between 11 and 12 o'clock
                    the same night.</p>
                <p>Although the command did not become engaged with the enemy, yet they performed
                    all labors and marches with the utmost promptness, each and all seeming willing
                    and anxious to do what was required of them.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, colonel, very respectfully, your obedient
                        servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. F. HARTRANFT, <lb/> Brig.-Gen., Cmdg. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
