<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0191"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0191">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Sailor's Creek, 207th Pa. Infantry, Report of Maj. Gen. John G.
                    Parke, July 10, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">sailors creek, 207th pa infantry report of maj gen john g parke july 10 1865</title>
        <author>Parke, John G.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 17</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0191</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500166</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., No. 153
                            Report of Maj. Gen. John G. Parke, U. S. Army, commanding Ninth Army
                            Corps.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa no 153 report of maj gen john g parke u s army commanding ninth army corps</title>
            <author>John G. Parke</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports, Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1015</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-07-10">1865-07-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 207th Pa. Infantry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Sailor's Creek</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0191T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Maj. Gen. John G. Parke commanded the Ninth Corps of the Army of The Potomac
                    which included the 207th Pennsylvania Infantry. Parke details an attack on the
                    enemy line.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. NINTH ARMY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. GEORGE D. RUGGLES, <lb/> Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen., Army of the Potomac.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-07-10">July 10, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of my command
                    from March 29 to April 19, 1865:</p>
                <p>After the capture and recapture of Fort Stedman, on the 25th of March, the usual
                    state of affairs continual on the line held by this corps, with the exception
                    that the enemy was more than ordinarily active in strengthening his
                    intrenchments. His works from the Appomattox to in front of Fort Sedgwick were
                    part of the old interior line of defenses, which had been so often
                    unsuccessfully attempted by us. At a point in front of Fort Sedgwick an outer
                    line, a kind of spur, struck off from his main line and swept down toward
                    Hatcher's Run in front of the left of our advance. The line held by this corps
                    fronted the whole of this main line and about two miles of the spur. By the
                    orders from headquarters Army of the Potomac, of March 14 and 28, ordering a
                    grand movement of the army on March 29, I was directed to send all surplus
                    baggage and artillery to the rear, and to be prepared to hold with this corps
                    the then line as far as Fort Davis and the rear line from that point. This was
                    accordingly done. I at once placed the Third Division, Brevet Maj.-Gen.
                    Hartranft commanding, at work repairing the rear line, which was much out of
                    order. Under the skillful direction of Gen. Hartranft this line was put in
                    excellent condition.</p>
                <p>At--p.m. on the 30th of March orders were received from army headquarters
                    directing me to make an assault upon the enemy's position in my front at 4
                    o'clock the following morning. The point of attack was left to my decision. I
                    had already decided that the position in front of Ford Sedgwick, on the
                    Jerusalem plank road, was the best one for assault on the front held my this
                    corps. This portion of the line was held by the Second Division, Potter's, and I
                    accordingly concentrated in rear of Fort Sedgwick all of Potter's division, with
                    the exception of pickets and the garrison of the forts, and all of Hartranft's
                    division. But at -- p.m. orders were received from army headquarters suspending
                    the assault, and the troops were returned to their camps. No further movements
                    occurred during March 31 and April 1.</p>
                <p>At 4.50 p.m. April 1 I received orders from army headquarters, through Capt.
                    Worth, directing me to assault together, and, after fully examining the grounds,
                    substantially the same arrangements for the assault were made as had been
                    previously made for the assault ordered for the morning of the 31st. At 9.50
                    p.m. orders were received by telegraph from Gen. Meade directing me to at once
                    open with all the artillery in my front, push forward skirmishers, and follow
                    them with columns of assault. While arrangements were being made to carry out
                    these orders they were modified by further instructions withdrawing the orders
                    for instant attack, and making assault contingent on developments of weakness on
                    the part of the enemy. We opened artillery and threw forward a strong skirmish
                    line along the whole front. The enemy was found prepared and in full force with
                    the exception of in front of the Second Brigade, Second Division, Brig. Gen. S.
                    G. Griffin's, between Forts Hays and Howard, when Gen. Griffin, by a
                    well-planned rush, succeeded in surprising and capturing about half a mile of
                    the enemy's picket-line, taking prisoners 8 officers and 241 men, but further
                    movements disclosed the enemy's main line well manned and on the alert. The
                    demonstration developed no apparent change in the force in our front either of
                    artillery or infantry.</p>
                <p>In accordance with instructions to carry out the original orders to assault at 4
                    a.m. on April 2 the captured line was abandoned. By 1 a.m. the firing had all
                    quieted down, and the concentration of troops for the attack was well under way.
                    To the right of the Jerusalem plank road running through Fort Sedgwick,
                    Hartranft's division was massed in rear of the fort--Willcox's First Brigade,
                    his left one, Col. Samuel Harriman commanding, was massed on Hartranft's right.
                    The Fifty-first Pennsylvania Volunteers being left in the works to hold the
                    brigade line, Col. Harriman was ordered to report to Gen. Hartranft. Potter's
                    (Second) division was massed on Hartranft's left, to the left of the plank road.
                    At 3 a.m. I established my headquarters at Fort Rice, and at the same time
                    Gen.'s Potter and Hartranft formed the assaulting column between our main line
                    and picket-line without alarming the enemy, whose picket-line was in close
                    proximity. The assaulting force was in column of regiments in the following
                    order: On the right of the Jerusalem plank road with left resting on the road,
                    the Third Division, the advance regiments being the Two hundred and seventh
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, Col. Cox commanding; followed by the Two hundred and
                    fifth Pennsylvania Volunteers, Maj. Morrow commanding; the Two hundred and
                    eleventh Pennsylvania, Col. Dodd commanding, and the Two hundred and eighth
                    Pennsylvania, Lieut.-Col. Heintzelman commanding; the two remaining regiments of
                    the division, the Two hundred and Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania, were held
                    as reserve behind the works. On the right of this column was Harriman's brigade
                    of the First Division in the following order: Thirty-eighth Wisconsin, Col.
                    Bintliff commanding; One hundred and ninth New York, Lieut.-Col. Pier
                    commanding, and the Eighth Michigan Volunteers, Maj. Doyle commanding. The
                    remaining regiments of the brigade, the Twenty-seventh Michigan and
                    Thirty-seventh Wisconsin, remained in reserve in rear of the right with
                    Hartranft's division, Potter's division, was formed, Griffin's brigade in the
                    advance, supported by Curtin's brigade. Six regiments from the division were
                    left to garrison the forts on its line. Storming parties, accompanied by
                    pioneers provided with axes to clear away the abatis and chevaux-de-frise,
                    preceded each column. Details of artillery-men to work any guns that might be
                    captured were also in readiness.</p>
                <p>With the view of leading the enemy astray as to the real point of attack I
                    directed Gen. Willcox to make a strong demonstration on his front at 4 a.m. I
                    judged this demonstration would most certainly deceive the enemy from the fact
                    learned from deserters, that our main assault was expected on the Fort Stedman
                    front. Accordingly, about 4 a.m., the artillery opened vigorously along the
                    whole line firing for some minutes. Gen. Willcox then promptly pushed out his
                    skirmishers along his whole front, and was very successful in the object
                    proposed. Col. Bolton, commanding Fifty-first Pennsylvania Volunteers, left to
                    hold Harriman's brigade front, captured some of the enemy's skirmishers near the
                    Crater, and Col. Ely, commanding the brigade next the river, not only carried
                    their picket-line, but even about 200 yards of the main line, but the enemy
                    concentrating upon him he was forced to retire after holding the position some
                    little time. At about 4.30 a.m. the signal was given for the main attack in
                    front of Fort Sedgwick, and the column moved swiftly and steadily forward. In a
                    moment the enemy's picket-line was carried. The stormers and pioneers rushed on
                    and under a most galling fire cut away and made openings in the enemy's abatis
                    and chevaux-de-frise. They, now closely followed by the assaulting columns,
                    which, undeterred by an exceedingly severe fire of cannon, mortar, and musketry
                    from the now aroused main line, pressed gallantly on, capturing the enemy's
                    works in their front with 12 guns,--colors, and 800 prisoners. Col. Harriman's
                    column re-enforced by the two reserve regiments swept up to the right until the
                    whole of what was called by the enemy "Miller's Salient" was in our possession.
                    Potter's column swept down to the left. This part of the enemy's line was
                    heavily traversed, affording him a strong foothold, and he fought from traverse
                    to traverse with great tenacity. We drove him slowly back for about a quarter of
                    a mile when, being re-enforced, and aided by strong positions in the rear, he
                    checked our farther progress in that direction. A most gallant but unsuccessful
                    attempt was made to carry his rear line. The captured guns were at once turned
                    upon the enemy, served at first by infantry volunteers, and them by details from
                    the First Connecticut Heavy Artillery Volunteers from the batteries in the rear.</p>
                <p>Just after we broke through he enemy's lines, and at a most critical time, I was
                    deprived of the valuable services of Brevet Maj.-Gen. Potter, who was severely
                    and dangerously wounded. I directed Brig. Gen. S. G. Griffin to assume command
                    of his division, and by him the division was ably and gallantly commanded during
                    the rest of the day. It being by this time fully daylight no further attempt was
                    made to advance, but attention was turned to securing what we had gained, and
                    restoring the organization of the troops, unavoidably much shattered by the
                    heavy fighting and the advance over broken ground in the darkness. This was
                    rendered the more difficult by the great loss we had sustained in officers,
                    especially field officers, and by my very exposed position occupied by our
                    troops. The captured line was promptly recovered and made tenable as possible,
                    the difficulty being increased by the forts and batteries on that line being
                    open in the rear.</p>
                <p>..</p>
                <p>The other officers were active in the discharge of the duties of their respective
                    departments.</p>
                <p>A tabular statement of losses is annexed.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JNO. G. PARKE,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
