<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0207"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0207">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Fort Stedman, 208th Pa. Infantry, Report of Lieut. Col. Mish T.
                    Heintzelman, March 27, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">fort stedman, 208th pa infantry report of lieut col mish t heintzelman march 27 1865</title>
        <author>Heintzelman, Mish T.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0207</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500178</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. THE RICHMOND CAMPAIGN., No. 157. Report of Lieut. Col.
                            Mish T. Heintzelman, Two hundred and eighth Pennsylvania Infantry, of
                            operations March 25.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii the richmond campaign , no 157 report of lieut col mish t heintzelman two hundred and eighth pennsylvania infantry of operations march 25</title>
            <author>Mish T. Heintzelman</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 352</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-27">1865-03-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 208th Pa. Infantry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Fort Stedman</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0207T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Col. Mish T. Heintzelman commanded the 208th Pennsylvania which was in the
                    Army of the Potomac. Heintzelman reports on the captures made by the
                regiment.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. 208TH REGT. PENNSYLVANIA VOLUNTEERS,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. CHARLES L. BUFFINGTON, <lb/> Acting Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-27">March 27, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In obedience to circular from headquarters Third Division, Ninth Army Corps,
                    dated March 26, 1865, I have the honor to offer the following report relative to
                    the part taken and captures made by my regiment in the engagement near Fort
                    Stedman on the 25th instant:</p>
                <p>When my regiment reached the headquarters of the Third Brigade, First Division,
                    Ninth Army Corps, the enemy had advanced a short distance across the first line
                    of rifle-pits in rear of the main line of our breast-works and still maintained
                    a good line, continuing to advance. On our approach, at the corner of the woods
                    near the top of the hill, the enemy perceived my regiment for the first time,
                    and immediately opened a heavy fire on it. We returned the fire, and merely held
                    our own ground for probably a half hour, during which time I awaited further
                    orders. In the meantime the enemy commenced falling back behind the main line of
                    breast-works, sheltering themselves from our fire and continuing to fire upon my
                    regiment. No orders having reached me yet I ordered the regiment to charge on
                    the enemy, which needed but the word "forward", and the men were off on a
                    double-quick. The enemy began to give way, and in a short time his whole line
                    was under a full and most disorderly retreat. The regiment quickly followed and
                    took possession of the main line, a part entering Battery No. 12 and capturing
                    in the fort alone 100 prisoners, including a colonel, adjutant, and several line
                    officers. On the balance of the line we captured 250 prisoners, making in all
                    350 prisoners captured by my regiment. In the meantime the color bearer of the
                    One hundredth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers entered Battery 12, and took
                    possession of several stand of colors (rebel), which justly belonged to my
                    regiment.</p>
                <p>A large number of enlisted men belonging to the First Division, representing
                    themselves to be provost guards especially detailed for the purpose of escorting
                    to the rear, followed immediately in our rear, picking up large numbers of
                    prisoners taken by my regiment, thereby claiming a credit of prisoners for the
                    First Division.</p>
                <p>Previous to our advancing, the entire line formerly occupied by the One hundredth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers and Fifty-seventh Massachusetts Volunteers, including
                    Batteries Nos.11 and 12, was entirely deserted from Fort Stedman to Fort
                    Haskell. The camps were filled with rebels, who were crowded in so thickly as to
                    render it impossible to deploy my command. My regiment occupied our main line of
                    breast-works from ten to twenty minutes before the order reached me to advance.</p>
                <p>There were gathered up by officers belonging to the First Division in the several
                    batteries at least 500 stand of small-arms belonging to the Third Division.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>M. T. HEINTZELMAN,<lb/> Lieut.-Col., Cmdg. 208th Pennsylvania
                        Volunteers. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
