<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0202"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0202">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Fort Stedman, 208th Pa. Infantry, Reports of Bvt. Maj. Gen. John
                    F. Hartranft, April 14, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">fort stedman, 208th pa infantry reports of bvt maj gen john f hartranft april 14 1865</title>
        <author>Hartranft, John F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 26</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0202</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500175</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., No. 154
                            Reports of Bvt. Maj. Gen. John F. Hartranft, U. S. Army, commanding
                            Third Division, of operations February 5-10 and March 25. Hartranft
                            reports a successful attack on the enemy's lines.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa no 154 reports of bvt maj gen john f hartranft u s army commanding third division of operations february 5 10 and march 25 hartranft reports a successful attack on the enemys lines</title>
            <author>John F. Hartranft</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports. , Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 344</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-04-14">1865-04-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 208th Pa. Infantry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Fort Stedman</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0202T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bvt. Maj. Gen. John F. Hartranft commanded the Third Division of the Army of the
                    Potomac which included the 208th Pennsylvania Infantry.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. THIRD DIVISION, NINTH ARMY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. P. M. LYDIG, <lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.,
                        Ninth Army Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-04-14">April 14, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the part taken by my command
                    in the repulse of the enemy at Fort Stedman on the morning of the 25th of March
                    ultimo:</p>
                <p>Immediately upon hearing the alarm on the right of the line, which was about 4.30
                    a.m., Capt. Dalien, of my staff, who was on duty as staff officer of the day,
                    was sent from my headquarters, which were at the Avery house, to Col. Harriman
                    and Brig.-Gen. McLaughlen, commanding brigades in the First Division, and
                    ascertain the cause of the alarm; at the same time orders were sent to my
                    brigade commanders, and their commands were under arms ready for any emergency.
                    The position of my division, which consists of two brigades, was as follows: One
                    regiment, the Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, near the Dunn House
                    Battery; the Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers, at Meade's Station;
                    the Two hundred and eighth Pennsylvania Volunteers, on the right of the Avery
                    house; the Two hundred and fifth and Two hundred and seventh Regiments
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, on the army line railroad, near Fort Prescott, and the
                    Two hundred and eleventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, near the railroad, about half
                    way between Forts Alex. Hays and Howard. At 5.10 a.m. Capt. Daline returned to
                    headquarters with a dispatch from Gen. McLaughlen's headquarters, and of which
                    the following is a copy:</p>
                <p> HDQRS. THIRD BRIGADE, FIRST DIVISION, NINTH ARMY CORPS,<lb/> March 25, 1865. </p>
                <p>GEN.: The enemy have attacked our lines and carried a portion of its works (from
                    Battery 11 and Stedman to the right). They are now moving towards the
                    Appomattox. Gen. on the lines.</p>
                <p> Very respectfully, your obedient servant, <lb/> CLARKE, <lb/> Acting Assistant
                    Adjutant-Gen. </p>
                <p>A few moments afterward I received dispatch from Maj.-Gen. Parke, of which the
                    following is a copy:</p>
                <p> HDQRS. NINTH ARMY CORPS, <lb/> March 25, 1865--5.15 a.m. <lb/></p>
                <p>GEN.: The general commanding directs that you move the brigade at Meade's Station
                    to re-enforce Gen. Willcox, in order to recapture a battery reported to be taken
                    by the enemy on his front and near Fort Stedman.</p>
                <p> Very respectfully, your obedient servant, <lb/> J. L. VAN BUREN,<lb/> Brevet
                    Col. and Aide-de-Camp. </p>
                <p>I immediately started in person to the right, and at the same time ordered the
                    Two hundred and eighth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers to report to Gen.
                    McLaughlen. I then went to communicate with Maj.-Gen. Willcox, commanding First
                    Division, whose headquarters were at the Friend house. I found the Two hundred
                    and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers moving toward Gen. Willcox's headquarters and
                    the Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers had already moved out of camp and had
                    halted with the right resting near the Dunn House Battery. This was done by the
                    order of Maj.-Gen. Willcox, the regiment having had directions to obey the
                    orders of Gen. Willcox in case of an attack, to avoid delay, the distance to my
                    headquarters being so great owing to the length of the line covered by my
                    command. I asked Gen. Willcox to send one of his staff to direct the Two hundred
                    and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers, and he designated Capt. Brackett,
                    aide-de-camp, to perform this duty, who led the regiment by the flank down the
                    road to the left of the Friend house. It was now sufficiently light to see the
                    enemy's skirmishers advancing from the rear and our right of Fort Stedman toward
                    the ravine and covering the main road leading from Stedman to the Ninth Corps
                    hospitals. Seeing this movement of the enemy's skirmishers, and finding a small
                    party of men from the Fifty-seventh Massachusetts Volunteers in front of the Two
                    hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, under command of a captain, engaging them,
                    and from whom I ascertained that this detachment had been driven its camp and
                    that all that was left of the regiment had been rallied at that point, I ordered
                    his detachment to move forward to its old camp, and I immediately advanced the
                    Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers to the camp of the Fifty-seventh
                    Massachusetts, in rear of Stedman, without sustaining any very serious damage.
                    The enemy's line of skirmishers was broken, but he was in force in the left end
                    of of the Fifty-seventh Massachusetts camp, on the road running in rear of
                    Stedman and in a line of works running about parallel with our line. I sent Maj.
                    Shorkley, of my staff, to bring up the Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers to form a connection on the right of the Two hundred Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, and I immediately attacked with the Two hundredth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, but finding the enemy too strong and my right suffering very much
                    from a heavy fire from Stedman and the troops in the road, the regiment was
                    forced to retire to an old line of works about forty yards in rear of and to the
                    right of the Fifty-seventh Massachusetts camp. The enemy seeing this regiment
                    retire, I feared that he would take advantage of it and attack me, and I
                    therefore attacked a second time and gained quite a good position. I held this
                    position for about twenty minutes, losing very heavily (the loss in this
                    regiment being about 100 at this point), when the line wavered and fell back to
                    and was rallied on the old line of works from which it had advanced the second
                    time. Here the Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers formed a connection
                    on the right of the Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, and with the aid of
                    the fire from Battery 9, which had opened, and the Twentieth Michigan, which
                    garrisoned this battery, and the Second and Seventeenth Michigan, of the First
                    Division, which covered the ground between the right of the Two hundred and
                    ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers and Battery 9, I had a strong line, which I
                    determined could be held and check any farther advance in this direction, and I
                    therefore ordered the troops to act on the defensive.</p>
                <p>I saw that I could accomplish nothing more with the force I had engaged, and
                    having fully satisfied myself that this advance was not a feint on the part of
                    the enemy, but a serious and determined attack, I dispatched an orderly to bring
                    up my Second Brigade, and I went to confer with Gen. Willcox in regard to the
                    situation. On my way to Gen. Willcox's headquarters I saw Col. Loring, of Gen.
                    Parke's staff, through whom I received an order to place my Second Brigade in
                    position on the hill rear of Stedman, and covering Meade's Station. I requested
                    him to communicate with Gen. Willcox, and I proceeded to join my Second Brigade.
                    Two regiments of the Second Brigade, the Two hundred and fifth and Two hundred
                    and seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, had already been moved to the right as far
                    as the Avery house, on the double-quick, by Maj. Bertolette, assistant
                    adjutant-general (who received the order to do so through Col. Van Buren,
                    aide-de-camp on Gen. Parke's staff), and were by him conducted through the
                    ravine on the right of the Avery house to a point on the right of Gen.
                    McLaughlen's headquarters and in the rear of Fort Stedman under cover. I then
                    went to Gen. McLaughlen's headquarters and found the Two hundred and eight
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers in a good position on the right of his headquarters,
                    left resting near Fort Haskell and facing northward. Several small detachments
                    of the Third Brigade, First Division, mostly from the One hundredth Regt.
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, numbering, perhaps, 200 men, were formed on the left of
                    the Two hundred and eighth Pennsylvania Volunteers and between it and Fort
                    Haskell. I also found that the reserves of the First Brigade, First Division,
                    had formed a line on the right of and at right angles with the main line held by
                    that brigade. The Two hundred and fifth and Two hundred and seventh Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers were a short distance to the right of the Two hundred and eighth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, and the distance from the left of the Two hundredth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers to the right of the Second Brigade was probably about
                    300 yards, which distance was not covered by any troops.</p>
                <p>I saw that any further advance on the part of the enemy was impossible under the
                    concentrated infantry fire from the Two hundredth and Two hundred and ninth
                    Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers and Batteries 9 and McGilvery on the right, and
                    the Two hundred and fifth, Two hundred and seventh, and Two hundred and eighth
                    Regiments Pennsylvania Volunteers and Fort Haskell on the left, and from the
                    field artillery in position on the hills in rear of Stedman, the fire of which
                    was concentrated on the fort, and covering the open space in rear. This position
                    being so favorable, I did not move the Two hundred and fifth and Two hundred and
                    seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers, of the Second Brigade, in position on the hills
                    covering Meade's Station, as ordered through Col. Loring, but ordered the Two
                    hundred and eleventh Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers (which hand ot yet arrived on
                    the ground on account of the great distance from its camp on the left to this
                    point) to take this position. It was now about 7.30 a.m., when I received an
                    order from Gen. Parke, through one of his staff, to retake the line. My plan of
                    attack was as follows: Orders were sent out that an assault would be made by my
                    whole division in fifteen minutes, and that the signal for the assault would be
                    the advance of the Two hundred and eleventh Pennsylvania Volunteers from the
                    hill in the rear toward Stedman. Capt. Hodgkins was directed to advance with the
                    Second Brigade under Col. Mathews, Maj. Bertolette with the Two hundredth and
                    Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers on the right, and as soon as the
                    Two hundred and eleventh Pennsylvania Volunteers could be put into position it
                    was advanced toward Stedman, under the direction of Capt. Watts, aide-de-camp,
                    in full view of the enemy. This was done for the purpose of attracting the
                    attention and fire of the enemy, and cover the movement of the balance of the
                    division which was to carry the works. This ruse was a complete success. The
                    enemy, seeing the advance of this regiment, numbering about 600 muskets, in such
                    handsome manner, commenced to waver, when the balance of the division charged
                    with a will, in the most gallant style, and in a moment Stedman, Batteries 11
                    and 12, and the entire line which had been lost, was recaptured with a large
                    number of prisoners, battle-flags, and small-arms. After the troops had
                    commenced moving to make this assault, I received orders not to make it until a
                    division of the Sixth Army Corps, which was on its way to support me, had
                    arrived, but I saw that the enemy had already commenced to waver, and that
                    success was certain. I, therefore, allowed the lines to charged; besides this,
                    it was doubtful whether I could have communicated with the regiments on the
                    flanks in time to countermand the movement.</p>
                <p>From the reports of my subordinate commanders as well as from my own observation,
                    at least 1,500 of the prisoners, and all the battle-flags captured, were taken
                    by and passed to the rear through the lines of my division, but were afterward
                    collected by other troops, while but about 770 prisoners and one battle-flag
                    were credited to my command. The officers and men were so eager to regain the
                    lost ground, and regimental commanders so desirous to maintain their several
                    organizations, which had been somewhat broken after charging through the
                    bomb-proofs and old works around the forts, that little or no attention was paid
                    to the trophies of this brilliant victory.</p>
                <p>The officers and men of my division, composed entirely of new troops, deserve
                    great credit for their promptness in moving forward to the point of attack, to
                    which in a great measure is owing the success of the day, and for their gallant
                    conduct throughout the action.</p>
                <p>The Two hundredth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers, Lieut.-Col. McCall commanding,
                    deserves particular mention. This regiment was put to the severest test, and
                    behaved with the greatest firmness and steadiness. The regiment made two
                    stubborn attacks on the enemy, and when compelled to retire it fell back in good
                    order.</p>
                <p>Among the many officers of this command who did their duty I cannot refrain from
                    noticing especially the conduct of Col. J. A. Mathews, Two hundred and fifth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, commanding Second Brigade, for the promptness in which
                    he moved his command to the scene of action, and for his gallantry in the final
                    assault.</p>
                <p>Col. C. W. Diven, Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, commanding First
                    Brigade, who went early to Gen. McLaughlen's headquarters, for the disposition
                    made by him of the Two hundred and eighth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers, and
                    other troops near Haskell, which checked the farther advance of the enemy toward
                    the left.</p>
                <p>Lieut. Col. W. H. H. McCall, commanding Two hundredth Regt. Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers for his coolness and bravery, and for the skill displayed by him in
                    handling his regiment.</p>
                <p>Lieut. Col. George W. Frederick and Maj. John L. Richery, Two hundred and ninth
                    Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers, who behaved with great gallantry in advancing
                    their regiment and in the final assault.</p>
                <p>Lieut. Col. M. T. Heintzelman and Capt. T. W. Hoffman, Two hundred and eighth
                    Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers, for their promptness in moving their regiment
                    forward, holding the positions they had gained, and for the efficiency of their
                    regiment in the recapture of Batteries 11 and 12.</p>
                <p>Col. R. C. Cox, commanding Two hundred and seventh Regiment Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, Maj. B. M. Morrow, commanding Two hundred and fifth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers, and Capt. W. A. Coulter, commanding Two hundredth and eleventh
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers, for promptness and gallantry in the final assault.</p>
                <p>Capt. F. A. Hoffman, Two hundredth Pennsylvania Volunteers, for his gallantry in
                    attempting to capture a rebel flag, in the act of which he was shot through the
                    hand and knocked down with a musket by the enemy.</p>
                <p>Among the enlisted men who distinguished themselves and deserve particular
                    mention are: Private Levi A. Smith, Company E, Two hundredth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers; Private John J. Levi, Company H, Two hundred and fifth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteers; Sergeants Elbridge Stiles and Edward J. Humphreys, Company C, color
                    bearers, Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers, and Private George Dull,
                    Company F, Two hundred and fifth Pennsylvania Volunteers.</p>
                <p>The following-named enlisted men are reported as having captured colors: Private
                    James Decker, Company D, Two hundred and fifth Pennsylvania Volunteers; Corpl.
                    John Fulton, Company B, Two hundred and seventh Pennsylvania Volunteers; Private
                    Charles H. Keinert, Company F, Two hundred and ninth Pennsylvania Volunteers.
                    Recommendations will be made for medals for these men.</p>
                <p>Brevet Brig.-Gen. Tidball, commanding Artillery Brigade, Ninth Army Corps, was on
                    the ground directing the movements and fire of the artillery.</p>
                <p>Col. Charles G. Loring, Bvt. Col. J. L. Van Buren, Capt. Goddard, and Capt. John
                    C. Youngman, of Gen. Parke's staff, and Capt. L. C. Brackett, aide-de-camp to
                    Maj.-Gen. Willcox, were with me on the field during the action and rendered me
                    valuable services in carrying dispatches.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak too highly of the members of my staff--Bvt. Maj. John D.
                    Bertolette, assistant adjutant-general; Bvt. Maj. George Shorkley (captain
                    Fifty-first Pennsylvania Volunteers), division inspector (who was wounded in the
                    thigh); Capt. William H. Hodgkins, Thirty-sixth Massachusetts Volunteers,
                    assistant commissary of musters; Capt. Richard A. Watts, Seventeenth Michigan
                    Volunteers, aide-de-camp; Capt. Prosper Dalien, Two hundred and eighth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers (who was wounded in the breast); Lieut. Reuben R.
                    Webbert, acting ordnance officer, and Capt. Martin G. Hale, provost-marshal--
                    for the prompt, efficient, and most valuable services rendered during the
                    action.</p>
                <p>A tabular statement of casualties is hereto appended, together with copies of the
                    reports of brigade commanders and regimental commanders of the First Brigade, to
                    which attention is respectfully invited.</p>
                <p>A nominal list of casualties has already been furnished. All of which is
                    respectfully submitted.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>J. F. HARTRANFT,<lb/> Brevet Maj.-Gen. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
