<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0219"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0219">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Appomattox Court House, 16th and 21st Pa. Cavalry, Report of Maj.
                    Gen. George Crook, April 18, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">appomattox court house, 16th and 21st pa cavalry report of maj gen george crook april 18 1865</title>
        <author>Crook, George</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 15</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0219</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500187</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XVIII. N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., No. 208
                            Report of Maj. Gen. George Crook, U. S. Army, commanding Second
                            Division, Army of the Potomac.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa no 208 report of maj gen george crook u s army commanding second division army of the potomac</title>
            <author>George Crook</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports. , Serial No. 95.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1141</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-04-18">1865-04-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cavalry, 21st Pa. Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Appomattox Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0219T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Maj. Gen. George Crook commanded the Second Division of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 16th and 21st Pa. Cavalry. Crook reports on engaging the
                    enemy and capturing both men and equipment.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. SECOND DIVISION, CAVALRY CORPS, ARMY OF THE POTOMAC,
                    <name type="recipient">General</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-04-18">April 18, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report the operations of the Second Cavalry Division, Army of
                    the Potomac, during the campaign which ended with the capitulation of the rebel
                    Army of Northern Virginia on the 9th instant.</p>
                <p>On the 29th ultimo the Second Cavalry Division--composed of three brigades,
                    commanded, respectively, by Brig. Gen. H. E. Davies, Bvt. Brig. Gen. J. I.
                    Gregg, and Bvt. Brig. Gen. Charles H. Smith--left its old encampment in front of
                    Petersburg and marched to Dinwiddie Court-House. Gregg's brigade being in the
                    advance skirmished with small bands of the enemy's cavalry after he crossed the
                    Rowanty Creek until he reached the Court-House. The next day he lay in camp,
                    Davies' brigade going to support Gen. Merritt in the vicinity of Five Forks. The
                    next morning the enemy made a demonstration in Merritt's front, when Smith's
                    brigade was posted at Chamberlain's crossing of Stony Creek, and Davies' brigade
                    at another crossing of the same creek, about one mile above, while Gregg's
                    brigade was held in reserve. At 11 a.m. the enemy made quite a fierce attack on
                    Smith, who repulsed them very handsomely with severe loss. I might here state
                    that the country in the vicinity of the creek was covered with a dense pine
                    thicket, so that cavalry could only fight to advantage on foot. At about 1 p.m.
                    the enemy anticipated our attack on them by their infantry forcing a passage
                    both above and below Davies, cutting him off from Smith. Gregg was now ordered
                    to attack the enemy, which he did very gallantly, causing his temporary falling
                    back up the creek. Davies being compelled to fall back by overwhelming numbers
                    fought his way back stubbornly, eventually working his way around to our right,
                    and joining the division just after night-fall on the Vaughan road. Shortly
                    after the attack on Davies' brigade the enemy made another furious attack on
                    Smith with artillery and cavalry. He very gallantly repelled all their attacks
                    until evening, when his ammunition was exhausted; he was compelled to fall back.
                    Gregg's ammunition being about exhausted was also compelled to fall back in
                    front of their infantry, who were now advancing down the road toward the
                    Court-House. The enemy not advancing farther than the junction of the two roads,
                    the division went into camp for the night on the Vaughan road, some three miles
                    from Dinwiddie. Nothing but occasional skirmishing occurred on the march from
                    Dinwiddie Court-House to Jetersville. We arrived at the latter place on the 4th
                    instant.</p>
                <p>The next morning Davies was ordered to make a reconnaissance to the left. He made
                    a handsome capture of guns, prisoners, &amp;c. (for particulars see his
                    report). I went with the other two brigades to assist in reaching camp with his
                    captives. The enemy attacked his rear guard just beyond Amelia Springs, but was
                    repulsed. Gregg's brigade coming up at this juncture both brigades fell back as
                    soon as the road became clear, Davies' brigade in the advance. Soon it was
                    reported the enemy had attacked the advance guard guarding the captures, when
                    Smith's and Davies' were sent at once to repel this attack, which was done very
                    handsomely, allowing the captures to reach camp safely. The fighting continued
                    all along my front until near night fall, whe the enemy desisted. The division
                    then went into camp for the night at Jetersville, picketing the country in our
                    front.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 6th the division moved on the Pride's Church road for
                    Deatonsville. Ascertained that the enemy were moving through the latter place on
                    the Jamestown road. Attempted to cut their train from the road crossing the
                    Genito road at Atkinson's, but found this road strongly guarded by both infantry
                    and cavalry. Moved across the country and struck the road on which the enemy
                    were moving still farther to the left, and to the left of Gen. Merritt's
                    command. Found the enemy strongly posted on a high eminence, behind temporary
                    breastworks. I sent Gregg's brigade to the left dismounted, who took possession
                    of and held the road. Smith's brigade was also dismounted and on Gregg's right,
                    while Davies' brigade, mounted, was on the field in front of their works. After
                    these arrangements were completed a general assault was made, the dismounted men
                    on the left turning and going over their works, while Davies made one of the
                    finest charges of the war, riding over and capturing their works and its
                    defenders. The enemy on the right, who were thus cut off from retreat,
                    surrendered and were taken by different parties.</p>
                <p>On the 7th moved on the Farmville road; skirmished with enemy's cavalry at
                    different points [on] the road; came in sight of the enemy's rear guard just
                    across the river at Farmville. I crossed the river at this point. Gen. Gregg's
                    brigade, being in the advance, made an attack on the enemy, was repulsed, and
                    Gen. Gregg taken prisoner; the command of this brigade devolved upon Col. S. B.
                    M. Young, Fourth Pennsylvania Cavalry. By instructions we recrossed the river
                    and marched to Prospect Station, where we encamped for the night.</p>
                <p>On the 8th marched to Appomattox Station. Gen. Mackenzie's division was assigned
                    to my command to-day. After dark I was ordered to send a brigade to hold the
                    road leading from Appomattox Court-House to Lynchburg. Smith's brigade was sent;
                    he selected a good position near the Court-House. The enemy made no
                    demonstration during the night, but the next morning, at a very early hour, he
                    moved a very heavy line against him, which he held in check until Gen. Mackenzie
                    got up and went in on Smith's left Davies was sent on a reconnaissance to the
                    left, while Col. Young's brigade was held in reserve. (See accompanying reports
                    of operations during the day.) At about 9 a.m. the enemy made a strong attack on
                    my front and flanks with a large force of infantry, while their cavalry attacked
                    my rear. Mackenzie and Smith were forced to retire by overwhelming numbers,
                    until relieved by the infantry. When we reorganized and were getting ready to go
                    to the front an order for cessation of hostilities reached me. For particulars
                    of the operations of my brigades when acting separately from the division I
                    respectfully refer you to accompanying brigade reports.</p>
                <p>I regret to report the loss of many gallant officers and men. Included in this
                    number, and who came under my personal observation, were Col. H. H. Janeway,
                    First New Jersey Cavalry, who lost his life while heroically rallying his men;
                    also Maj. H. S. Thomas, First Pennsylvania Cavalry, who lost his leg while
                    gallantly leading his regiment in a charge at the battle of Jetersville, on the
                    5th instant. In them the service lost two of its brightest ornaments. For the
                    many acts of gallantry performed that did not come under my personal
                    observation, I would cheerfully indorse the special notices and recommendations
                    of my subordinate commanders.</p>
                <p>I cannot close this report without mentioning the marked good conduct of the
                    command during the whole campaign, and my special indebtedness to my brigade
                    commanders--Brig. Gen. H. E. Davies, Mackenzie, Gregg, and Smith--and to my
                    battery commanders--Lieuts. J. H. Lord and S. H. Kinney--for their gallantry,
                    cordial support, and the skillful manner in which they handled their commands.
                    Also to the members of my staff for their gallantry and valuable assistant
                    commissary of musters, H. E. Tremain, aide-de-camp, C. Taylor, acting assistant
                    inspector-general; Capt.'s Moore, aide-de-camp, William Harper, provost-marshal,
                    A. H. Bibber, acting aide-de-camp; Lieut. C. S. Roberts; and Dr. E. J. Marsh,
                    surgeon-in-chief.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>GEORGE CROOK,<lb/> Maj.-Gen. Volunteers, Cmdg. Second Division. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
