<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0216"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0216">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Appomattox Court House, 11th Pa. Cavalry, Report of Lieut. Col.
                    Franklin A. Stratton, April 29, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">appomattox court house, 11th pa cavalry report of lieut col franklin a stratton april 29 1865</title>
        <author>Stratton, Franklin A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 13</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0216</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500184</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII N. AND SE. VA., N. C., W. VA., MD., AND PA., No. 264
                            Report of Lieut. Col. Franklin A. Stratton, Eleventh Pennsylvania
                            Cavalry.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii n and se va , n c w va md and pa no 264 report of lieut col franklin a stratton eleventh pennsylvania cavalry</title>
            <author>Franklin A. Stratton</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 264</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1255</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-04-29">1865-04-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 11th Pa. Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Appomattox Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0216T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lieut. Col. Franklin A. Stratton commanded the Eleventh Pennsylvania Cavalry of
                    the Army of the Potomac. Stratton reports on skirmishes with the enemy and
                    captures of men and supplies.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ELEVENTH PENNSYLVANIA CAVALRY,
                    <name type="recipient">Sir</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-04-29">April 29, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Richmond, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report of operations of this regiment
                    during the late campaign:</p>
                <p>...</p>
                <p>The regiment moved with the division on the 2d, 3d, and 4th to the vicinity of
                    Amelia Court-House. At Deep Creek we attacked the rebel rear guard, strongly
                    posted, and after half an hour's skirmishing drove them out with considerable
                    loss, having only one man wounded on our side. On the 4th, upon nearing the
                    Court-House, Maj. McFarlan, commanding the advance battalion, met and charged
                    the enemy's cavalry outposts, driving their skirmish line back upon their
                    infantry support. He was followed up in the charge by the remainder of the
                    regiment, which was ordered forward by Col. Evans, commanding the brigade. Only
                    two or three men were lost. The next day I supported the First Maryland Cavalry
                    in its attack on the enemy at the railroad, to the left of the Court-House. Two
                    or three men were slightly wounded in this affair. Moving thence, via
                    Burkeville, to Prince Edward Court-House, on the 7th, we there, in conjunction
                    with Maj. Baker's battalion, captured a considerable number of rebels, including
                    one or two officers. the following day we marched to the vicinity of Appomattox
                    Station, on the South Side Railroad, and on the morning of the 9th moved out to
                    the main road from Appomattox Court-House to Lynchburg, about a mile westerly
                    from the Court-House, this regiment having the advance. Capt. Nimmon's squadron
                    was deployed, dismounted, and pushed across the road to develop the enemy's
                    position. I moved the remainder of the regiment into the wood on the left,
                    dismounting four companies, under Maj. Skelley, holding Capt. Nimmon commenced
                    skirmishing I discovered the enemy pushing out about a brigade of infantry from
                    the wood on our right and moving down the slope at right angles with our line.
                    Changing from to the right, I opened fire with some effect, but receiving orders
                    in a few minutes to fall back retired slowly to deploy again, about 200 yards in
                    front of the road, to protect the left flank, which I did. Capt. Ring's squadron
                    and one squadron under Lieut. Cook were formed in line on the main road to repel
                    the enemy, who were following closely our dismounted men, retiring under their
                    orders to fall back. The enemy's cavalry being reported moving to our left and
                    rear, I sent Maj. McFarlan to move the led horses as his judgment might direct
                    for their safety. This duty he creditably performed, and afterward had the
                    horses ready for mounting as soon as wanted by me.</p>
                <p>While affairs were in this position Davies' brigade, dismounted, aided by our
                    dismounted men, repelled the attack of the enemy on this road. At this moment
                    some of the rebel cavalry dashed in upon our rear, and were met and checked by
                    such men as could be brought up in time. Almost at the same time our infantry, a
                    part of the Twenty-fourth Corps, advanced in line from the woods in our rear,
                    sweeping back the head of the column of rebel cavalry, and pushing beyond us
                    toward the Court-House soon left us in the rear. During this cavalry attack
                    Capt. Ring made a dashing charge on a superior force of cavalry in our rear with
                    some effect, although I had no men at hand mounted to support him. Receiving
                    orders to mount the regiment I did so without delay, and, under orders, moved
                    down the road about a mile westerly to meet the rebel cavalry, there posted
                    across the road. Before any decisive operations were commenced at this point
                    orders to suspend hostilities were received. Although a portion of the
                    engagement was quite sharp this morning I lost but one man killed and three or
                    four wounded.</p>
                <p>From this place, on the evening of the 9th, I detached Capt. Elliott's squadron
                    to search for artillery supposed to be abandoned by the enemy in the vicinity of
                    Red Oak Church. A copy of his report has already been forwarded, from which it
                    will be seen that he captured 60 prisoners, 54 pieces of field artillery, 36 gun
                    carriages and caissons, and 1 battle-flag.</p>
                <p>On the 12th the command marched to Lynchburg and occupied the town about 4 p.m.
                    Upon entering the place I received orders to take command of the troops in the
                    place, consisting of the Eleventh Pennsylvania Cavalry and Maj. Baker's
                    battalion, and to take possession of and destroy all public property. These
                    orders were carried out as far as possible during the evening. The next day I
                    turned over the command and the captured property to Lieut.-Col. Potter, of Gen.
                    Turner's division, of the Twenty-fourth Corps. Very large amounts of military
                    stores were found here, comprising ordnance and ordnance stores of every kind,
                    quartermaster's property, a large amount of subsistence stores, 25 locomotives,
                    many cars, and much other railroad property, and much property of a
                    miscellaneous nature. This property was all turned over by me to Lieut.-Col.
                    Potter as stated. I found here 56 field pieces, 6 heavy guns, 41 mortars, 7
                    forges, 75 caissons and gun carriages, 15,000 muskets, several hundred sabers,
                    and a large quantity of ammunition.</p>
                <p>Including the guns, &amp;c., captured on the 9th, at Red Oak Church, the
                    Eleventh Pennsylvania Cavalry has captured and taken possession of and delivered
                    to the proper officers 110 field pieces, 41 mortars, 6 heavy guns, 111 caissons
                    and carriages, a large amount of ordnance stores, 1 battle-flag, and many
                    prisoners.</p>
                <p>Leaving Lynchburg on the 16th the regiment marched with the brigade to
                    Burkeville, and thence, via Goode's Bridge, to Richmond, at which place it
                    arrived on the 24th instant.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak too highly of the soldierly conduct of both officers and men of
                    the regiment during this brief campaign. I have heretofore recommended several
                    officers for promotion and others as deserving honorable mention, but their
                    service, under the eye of the commanding general, has enabled him to judge of
                    their merits.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>FRANKLIN A. STRATTON, <lb/> Lieut. Col. Eleventh Pennsylvania Cavalry,
                        Cmdg. Regt. </salute>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
