<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0218"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0218">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Appomattox Court House, 16th and 21st Pa. Cavalry, Report of Bvt.
                    Maj. Gen. Wesley Merritt, April 20, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">appomattox court house, 16th and 21st pa cavalry report of bvt maj gen wesley merritt april 20 1865</title>
        <author>Merritt, Wesley</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 11</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0218</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500186</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. THE APPOMATTOX CAMPAIGN., No. 200 Report of Bvt. Maj.
                            Gen. Wesley Merritt, U. S. Army, commanding Cavalry, Army of the
                            Shenandoah.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii the appomattox campaign , no 200 report of bvt maj gen wesley merritt u s army commanding cavalry army of the shenandoah</title>
            <author>Wesley Merritt</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports. , Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1120</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-04-20">1865-04-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cavalry, 21st Pa. Cavalry</term>
                    <term>Battle: Appomattox Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0218T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bvt. Maj. Gen. Wesley Merritt commanded the Cavalry which included the 16th and
                    21st Pa. Cavalries. Merritt reports on blocking the enemy's retreat and engaging
                    him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. CAVALRY OF THE ARMY OF THE SHENANDOAH,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-04-20">April 20, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>...</p>
                <p>April 8, marched at 6 a.m. through Prospect Station toward Appomattox
                    Court-House. The Third Division, in advance, met with no opposition until it
                    arrived near Appomattox Station. Here the enemy's advance column was struck,
                    moving on the Lynchburg road toward Danville. The enemy's army was in force at
                    Appomattox Court-House. Artillery, prisoners, and wagons were here captured by
                    the Third Division, which rushed into the enemy's lines, carrying all before
                    them. Three trains of cars were also taken by this division, loaded with
                    subsistence stores for Lee's army. The First Division was brought up rapidly,
                    and, deploying dismounted on the right of the Third Division, assisted
                    materially in the captures. This division was advanced within a short distance
                    of Appomattox Court-house, being posted across the road on which the enemy was
                    attempting to move, and effectually destroying his chance of making a night's
                    march in retreat, as he intended to do as on former occasions.</p>
                <p>It is impossible to overestimate the value of this day's work. The enemy's
                    supplies were taken, as it were, out of their mouths. A strong force, they knew
                    not how strong, was posted along their line of retreat at a point where they did
                    not expect opposition. Night was upon them; tired, dispirited, and starving they
                    lay at our feet. Their bravest soldiers, their hardiest men, gave way when they
                    heard the noise of battle far in the rear, and the night of despair fell with
                    the night of the 8th of April darkly and terribly on the Army of Northern
                    Virginia.</p>
                <p>April 9, at daylight the command was in readiness to move. Gen. Crook relieved
                    the First Division in the position which it had occupied during the night. This
                    division was ordered to move to the right. The enemy advanced against Gen.
                    Crook's front in heavy force. The cavalry was forced back by overwhelming
                    numbers. Gen. Custer was immediately ordered to move up with his division. The
                    cavalry retired slowly, but of necessity. Soon the Twenty-fourth corps took up
                    Crook's line on the left of the First Division, and the Fifth Corps deployed in
                    rear of Gen. Devin. So soon as the heavy columns of the enemy discovered we had
                    infantry in position he abandoned his evidently formed idea of forcing the road
                    of his retreat, and retired precipitately toward the valley, where his wagon
                    train was parked. The cavalry, now disengaged, was thrown rapidly to the right,
                    taking possession of the high ground on the enemy's left within a short half
                    mile of his camp. There every disposition was made for an attack. The rebel army
                    was at our mercy. The artillery played rapidly for a few moments, when a flag of
                    truce sent from the enemy's line silenced forever the noise of battle between
                    the Union and rebel armies of Virginia.</p>
                <p>April 10, the command marched at 8 a.m. for Burke's Station, under the immediate
                    command of Gen. Custer. The undersigned, having been appointed one of the Union
                    commissioners to arrange the details of surrender, remained at Appomattox
                    Court-House until the 12th instant.</p>
                <p>Thus were concluded the labors of the campaign-a campaign, so far as cavalry in
                    concerned, which has scarcely a parallel in history Never did men behave better;
                    never endure more uncomplainingly the severest of hardships. No task was too
                    severe; no danger too imminent for the cavalry to encounter or overcome. The
                    gallant, daring, and rapid execution of the brave commander of the Third
                    Division, united with the sure, steady, and unchangeable courage and bearing of
                    the commander of the First Division, have accomplished a work which must shed
                    glory on the Union cavalry for all time to come.</p>
                <p>In making up this record it was impossible to enter into details with reference
                    to the different commands or officers without extending it to a very great
                    length. The attention of the major-general commanding is respectfully invited to
                    the reports of division commanders transmitted herewith; they will necessarily
                    enter more largely into particulars. The exceptions to those throughout the
                    command who have given the most complete satisfactory are very few. It is enough
                    glory to be associated with such men--a double glory to have commanded them.</p>
                <p>To my staff I owe especial thanks; one and all, they performed their duties at
                    all times with judgment, energy, and indefatigable zeal. I commend them to the
                    attention of the major-general commanding.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>W. MERRITT,<lb/> Brevet Maj.-Gen., Cmdg. Cavalry. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
