<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R0221"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R0221">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Appomattox Court House, 184th Pa. Regiment, Reports of Col.
                    William A. Olmsted, April 10, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">appomattox court house, 184th pa regiment reports of col william a olmsted april 10 1865</title>
        <author>Olmsted, William A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 9</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R0221</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500189</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. THE APPOMATTOX CAMPAIGN., No. 55 Reports of Col. William
                            A. Olmsted, Fifty-ninth New York Infantry, commanding First Brigade.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii the appomattox campaign , no 55 reports of col william a olmsted fifty ninth new york infantry commanding first brigade</title>
            <author>William A. Olmsted</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series I., Volume 46. Part I, Reports., Serial No. 95.</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 684</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-04-10">1865-04-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 184th Pa. Regiment</term>
                    <term>Battle: Appomattox Court House</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R0221T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Col. William A. Olmsted commanded the First Brigade of the Army of the Potomac
                    which included the 184th Pa. Regiment. Olmsted reports on pursuing the enemy and
                    skirmishing with him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. FIRST BRIGADE,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-04-10">April 10, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>April 4 and 5, we marched to Amelia Station, on Danville road. April 6, Gen. Hays
                    ordered the Seventh Michigan to advance as skirmishers; the brigade followed the
                    division column. Gen. Hays was relieved from command and Gen. Smyth assumed
                    command. Shortly afterward Maj.-Gen. Barlow, having been assigned to the
                    command, ordered the brigade to move; marched in column by ranks of fours in
                    support of Third Brigade, advancing in battalion columns of fours. At Amelia
                    Springs, by order of Gen. Barlow, detailed the One hundred and eighty-fourth
                    Pennsylvania Volunteers to relieve a brigade of First Division, and remain until
                    further orders. The Fifty-ninth New York Veteran Volunteers, commanded by Capt.
                    Ludgate, was thrown out as skirmishers to Third Brigade, at Perkinson's Saw
                    mill, and captured a rebel wagon train.</p>
                <p>April 7, advanced with the brigade, my brigade marching in column on the right
                    flank of the road; arrived near High Bridge, all on Danville road; deployed the
                    Nineteenth Maine; they advanced, and afterward moved to the right and saved the
                    High Bridge, also a smaller bridge for crossing below the bridge; formed line of
                    battle on left of railroad and advanced the Seventh Michigan and Fifty-ninth New
                    York Veteran Volunteers as skirmishers and flankers. Just as the brigade moved I
                    was ordered to move by the right flank, cross the railroad, and march in column
                    in rear of Second Brigade to support Smyth. Advanced about two miles when we met
                    the enemy's the skirmish line moved promptly in advance to within rifle range of
                    Farmville, when part of the skirmish line was captured. After the position was
                    carried was ordered to advance down the railroad to Farmville; after the men had
                    mealed for dinner took the advance and moved to the right, and formed line of
                    battle on the right of First Division; at sundown changed front and formed line
                    facing the enemy. April 8, moved in column by fours, marching them through heavy
                    woods on right of road. April 9, marched in column of fours down Lynchburg road,
                    and participated in the grand and glorious surrender of Lee's Army of Northern
                    Virginia to the Army of the Potomac; went into camp, where we now remain.</p>
                <p>The following is a correct list of casualties, on the days they occurred.</p>
                <p>April 9, all the prisoners captured on the 7th were recaptured and reported to
                    their regiments, and are now doing duty.</p>
                <p>The brigade captured 3 guns (12-pounders, light) at Crow's house, and 18 of all
                    calibers at High Bridge, and about 1,000 prisoners in all.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>WILLIAM A. OLMSTED,<lb/> Col. Fifty-ninth New York Veteran Vols., Cmdg.
                        Brigade. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
