<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11114501"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11114501">
	<teiHeader type="migrated">
		  <fileDesc>
			   <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIII. Confederate Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
					     <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
					     <name/>
					     <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
			   <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
			   <publicationStmt>
				    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
				    <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
				    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
				    <idno type="VCDH">R11114501</idno>
        <!--
				<availability>
					<p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
						University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
					<p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
				</availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
				    <date value="1999">1999</date>
			     <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498587</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
			   <seriesStmt>
				    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
			   </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
			   <notesStmt>
				    <note/>
			   </notesStmt>
			   <sourceDesc>
				    <biblFull>
					     <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIII. Confederate Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
							Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
							       <resp>Translator:</resp>
							       <name/>
						      </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
					     <editionStmt>
						      <p>Series 1, Volume 11, Serial No. 14</p>
					     </editionStmt>
					     <extent>Pages 500-501</extent>
					     <publicationStmt>
						      <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
						      <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
						      <date value="1997">1997</date>
					     </publicationStmt>
					     <seriesStmt>
						      <p/>
					     </seriesStmt>
					     <notesStmt>
						      <note/>
					     </notesStmt>
				    </biblFull>
			   </sourceDesc>
		  </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
		  <profileDesc>
			   <creation>
				    <date value="1862-05-08">1862-05-08</date>
			   </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
			   <textClass>
				    <keywords>
					     <term/>
					     <term/>
				    </keywords>
			   </textClass>
		  </profileDesc>
		  <revisionDesc>
			   <change>
				    <date value=""/>
				    <respStmt>
					     <resp/>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
				    <item/>
			   </change>
		    <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text id="R11114501T">
		<front id="d2">
			<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
				<p>In May 1862, General Joseph E. Johnston commanded the Confederate army facing
					McClellan on the Peninsula. Robert E. Lee functioned as military advisor to
					Jefferson Davis in Richmond. In this letter, Lee informs Johnston of the
					disposition of Confederate forces and notes that Jackson, stationed in Staunton,
					sought to link up with General Edward Johnson's men and attack Federal troops
					under General Robert Milroy at McDowell.</p>
			</div1>
		</front>
		<body id="d4">
			<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
				<head>
					HDQRS.
					<name type="recipient">Gen. JOSEPH E. JOHNSTON,<lb/> Cmdg.,&amp;c.:</name>
				</head>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<date value="1862-05-08">May 8, 1862.</date>
						<name type="place">Richmond, Va.,</name>
					</dateline>
					<salute/>
				</opener>
				<p>Your letter of the 8th has just been received. Those to which you allude as
					having received yesterday were prepared for my signature and being unexpectedly
					called away, and not wishing to detain the messenger, I directed Maj. Taylor to
					affix my signature and send to you. The one referring to the telegram of Gen.
					Loring was merely intended to advise you of the progress of the evacuation of
					Norfolk and what had been done to maintain the posts guarding the communication
					to that place until the evacuation was completed, and which was supposed to be
					in accordance with your general instructions on the subject. Nothing was done to
					interrupt the portion of Gen. Colston's brigade joining him. I consider your
					authority to extend over the troops on both sides of James River, and have
					transmitted as rapidly as I could all the orders sent to me. I do not recollect
					your having requested information relating to the other departments of your
					command to be forwarded by any other means than the usual course of the mails,
					and supposed the commanders were in direct correspondence with you.</p>
				<p>I advised you on the 23d of April of certain troops having been ordered to report
					to Gen. Field, viz, two regiments from this city raised for local defense, two
					light batteries, a brigade from South Carolina, and a brigade from North
					Carolina, making in all about 8,000 men, in addition to those previously there.
					The brigade of Gen. J. R. Anderson having been sent from North Carolina by Gen.
					Holmes, places Gen. Anderson in command of the troops, he being the senior
					officer present. He has taken position about Massaponax, south of
					Fredericksburg, extending his pickets toward Port Royal.</p>
				<p>I understand that the enemy has built a bridge of boats across the Rappahannock
					opposite Fredericksburg, but has not yet occupied the town, his troops occupying
					the hills in Stafford, his left being opposite Port Royal; his strength
					estimated at from 15,000 to 20,000.</p>
				<p>Gen. Ewell at last reports was at Swift Run Gap, a portion of his division being
					at Stanardsville. Gen. Jackson was at Staunton, with a view of uniting with Gen.
					Edward Johnson and attacking Gen. Milroy, who was not far from Buffalo Gap. Gen.
					Banks was reported as having evacuated Harrisonburg and passed down the valley,
					his main body being beyond New Market. It has occurred to me that his object may
					be to form a junction with Gen. McDowell on the Rappahannock. I have telegraphed
					my apprehension to both Gen.'s Jackson and Ewell to place them on their guard.</p>
				<p>Two brigades, one from North Carolina and one from Norfolk, have been directed,
					under the orders of the President, to proceed to Gordonsville, to re-enforce
					that line, which at one time was threatened by a column from Warrenton, the
					advance of which entered Culpeper Court-House. The obstructions of James River
					are progressing as rapidly as possible and batteries in process of erection for
					their defense. I know of no one more competent to direct the construction of
					these works than Maj. Stevenson if not wanted with your army. In reference to
					the obstruction of the Pamunkey, before it was commenced the subject was
					referred to you, and directions were given for the preparation of material
					procuring of pile-driver, &amp;c. The river had been previously examined for
					that purpose, and the best position stated to be about 8 miles below the
					railroad bridge. Capt. Carrington, who understood the work, was directed to
					report to you for instructions and any aid he might require. But from the
					difficulty of communicating with you and the necessity of the case, and being
					only able to use the boats in the river, the work, I fear, has been imperfectly
					done. All the transports, however, were carried above the obstructions, and
					their cargoes I understand are at present secure.</p>
				<p>The quartermaster and commissary departments will be informed as to the point to
					which to send you provisions.</p>
				<p>The President has heard with much pleasure of the handsome manner in which the
					enemy was dislodged on the afternoon of the 6th by a portion of your command,
					and your commendatory remarks on the officers engaged have been reported to him.</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>Most respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
					<signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
				</closer>
			</div1>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI.2>
