<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11114297"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
<!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11114297">
	<teiHeader type="migrated">
		  <fileDesc>
			   <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIII. Union Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Pope, John</author>
        <respStmt>
					     <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
					     <name/>
					     <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
			   <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
			   <publicationStmt>
				    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
				    <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
				    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
				    <idno type="VCDH">R11114297</idno>
        <!--
				<availability>
					<p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
						University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
					<p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
				</availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
				    <date value="1999">1999</date>
			     <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498585</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
			   <seriesStmt>
				    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
			   </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
			   <notesStmt>
				    <note/>
			   </notesStmt>
			   <sourceDesc>
				    <biblFull>
					     <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIII. Union Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
							Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Pope, John</author>
            <respStmt>
							       <resp>Translator:</resp>
							       <name/>
						      </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
					     <editionStmt>
						      <p>Series 1, Volume 11, Serial No. 14</p>
					     </editionStmt>
					     <extent>Pages 295-297</extent>
					     <publicationStmt>
						      <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
						      <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
						      <date value="1997">1997</date>
					     </publicationStmt>
					     <seriesStmt>
						      <p/>
					     </seriesStmt>
					     <notesStmt>
						      <note/>
					     </notesStmt>
				    </biblFull>
			   </sourceDesc>
		  </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
		  <profileDesc>
			   <creation>
				    <date value="1862-07-04">1862-07-04</date>
			   </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
			   <textClass>
				    <keywords>
					     <term/>
					     <term/>
				    </keywords>
			   </textClass>
		  </profileDesc>
		  <revisionDesc>
			   <change>
				    <date value=""/>
				    <respStmt>
					     <resp/>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
				    <item/>
			   </change>
		    <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text id="R11114297T">
		<front id="d2">
			<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
				<p>Operations in the Shenandoah Valley proved difficult for Federal commanders early
					in the war. In July, 1862, in the wake of Stonewall Jackson's victories over the
					combined forces of McDowell, Banks, and Fremont, Lincoln reorganized the army.
					John Pope received command of the Union Army of Virginia, which included troops
					stationed in the Valley area. In this letter, he informs General McClellan of
					his plans, including sending troops to establish communications with Staunton,
					Virginia.</p>
			</div1>
		</front>
		<body id="d4">
			<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
				<head>
					HDQRS. ARMY OF VIRGINIA
					<name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. GEORGE M. McCLELLAN,<lb/> Cmdg. Army of the
						Potomac, on James River:</name>
					</head>
		        <opener>
					<dateline>
						<date value="1862-07-04">July 4, 1862.</date>
						<name type="place">Washington, D. C.</name>
					</dateline>
					<salute>GEN.:</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>As you have doubtless been informed, I was a few days since assigned by the
					President to the command of the forces and departments lately under the command
					of Gen.'s Fremont, Banks, and McDowell.</p>
				<p>I avail myself of the first moment, after ascertaining the strength, positions,
					and condition of the force thus assigned me, to communicate with you. I beg you
					to understand that it is my earnest wish to co-operate in the heartiest and most
					energetic manner with you, and that there is no service, whatever the hazard or
					the labor, which I am not ready to perform with this army to carry out that
					object.</p>
				<p>That you may understand precisely what means are at my disposal for such a
					purpose and what is expected of me I will proceed to give you in detail the
					information which will enable you to understand precisely my situation and the
					power I have to aid your operations. Do not hesitate to suggest frankly and
					freely to me any views and wishes you may entertain in regard to the assistance
					I can give you. Be assured that your suggestions will be received with all
					kindness and as far as possible adopted. I am guided and shall be, by an earnest
					wish to contribute by every possible means within my control to the success of
					your operations.</p>
				<p>You know the history of the late peculiar operations in the Shenandoah Valley,
					and that Gen. Fremont has retired from his command for reasons unnecessary to
					set forth. The forces lately under his command and those of Gen. Banks are
					collected in the neighborhood of Strasburg and Middletown. They are much
					demoralized and broken down, and unfit for active service for the present. Of
					some use they can be, but not much just now. They are scattered at small posts,
					but are now being concentrated. They number about 23,000 men of all arms.The
					army corps of Gen. McDowell's about 19,000 strong, is by far the best, and in
					fact the only reliable portion of my command. One division is at Manassas, the
					other at Fredericksburg.</p>
				<p>Gen. Sturgis in command of the forces within and outside of the intrenchments
					near Washington. They number altogether about 17,000 men, mostly raw recruits
					and fragments of broken regiments, in no condition for service.</p>
				<p>My first object is to concentrate all these forces (except those under Sturgis),
					as far as practicable, in advance of this place, both to put them in condition
					for active operations and to have them in hand. In this arrangement the security
					of the valley of the Shenandoah and of the city of Washington must be held in
					view. I have therefore broken up the depots on the Ohio River and on the
					Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and established my depots and base of operations at
					Alexandria. I am concentrating the two corps of Fremont (now Sigel's) and Banks
					near Luray Gap (Sperryville); Banks' about 5 or 6 miles east of that place.</p>
				<p>The division of McDowell, now at Manassas, has moved forward to Warrenton and
					taken post. His cavalry brigade has advanced to Warrenton Junction, with strong
					cavalry pickets south of the Rappahannock. The division at Fredericksburg
					pickets the country 20 miles in advance of that place. A good stone turnpike
					connects Luray with Warrenton. It was my purpose, before the news of your
					critical situation reached here, to concentrate the two divisions of McDowell at
					Orange Court-House and the corps of Banks and Sigel at Stanardville; thence to
					occupy Gordonsville long enough to destroy entirely the Virginia Central road
					between that place and Hanover Court-House, and to move on Charlottesville, or a
					point east of that place, with my whole force united; to destroy the railroad
					between Lynchburg and Charlotesville, and also, by pushing cavalry in various
					directions toward it, to destroy the railroad from Lynchburg to Richmond; to
					move down to James River at Columbia, and to pursue the north (left) bank of the
					river toward Richmond at least as far as Tuckahoe Creek; to take up a strong
					position behind that creek, and throw bridges over the James River or secure
					those now existing within the proposed lines, so as to be able to throw my whole
					force across to the south side whenever it became necessary. Having secured
					these objects, to aid you in any way in the immediate operations against
					Richmond.</p>
				<p>The occurrences of the last few days have deranged this plan, and I am holding my
					forces at the points I have designated, so as to be able, by marching rapidly on
					Gordonsville and Charlottesville, to cut off any force which may penetrate into
					the valley of the Shenandoah from the direction of Richmond, and at the same
					time be able to concentrate my whole force with little delay in front of
					Washington in case of necessity. These positions I shall hold until some
					well-defined plan of operations and co-operations can be determined on.</p>
				<p>It seems to me that it will not be difficult for the enemy at Richmond to detach
					50,000 men to march rapidly on Washington if it be uncovered by the movement of
					the force under my command in any direction. Much of my cavalry I am keeping in
					the valley of the Shenandoah, and as soon as my forces are established as I have
					designated, they (the cavalry) will be pushed as far south as Swift Run Gap and
					Harrisonburg. I have intrenched a brigade of infantry with one battery at
					Winchester; a somewhat smaller force will be posted in a like manner at Romney.
					The small posts at Clarksburg, Beverly Buckhannon, &amp;c., are placed under
					charge of Gen. Kelley, who has some force also on the railroad. The care and
					protection of the road has been assigned to Gen. Wool, so that I am foot-loose
					in that region.</p>
				<p>I have directed Gen. Cox, who has about 12,000 men in the Kanawha Valley, near
					Lewisburg, to maneuver so as to get Heth and Humphrey Marshall between himself
					and Lexington or Lynchburg, and then follow them through to Lexington by the
					turnpike, and open communication with Staunton or Charlottesville, abandoning
					entirely his line to Point Pleasant, on the Ohio, and calling in his small
					posts. Of course this movement will depend upon whether my operations toward
					Charlottesville and Richmond are carried out.</p>
				<p>You position on James River places the whole of the enemy's force around Richmond
					between yourself and Washington. Were I to move with my command direct on
					Richmond I must fight the whole force of the enemy before I could join you, and
					at so great a distance from you as to be beyond any assistance from your army.
					If my command be embarked and sent to you by James River the enemy would be in
					Washington before it had half accomplished the journey.</p>
				<p>Under these circumstances my position here is difficult and embarrassing. Whilst
					I am very anxious to render you all the assistance in my power, the imperative
					necessity of insuring the safety of the capital must control my operations.</p>
				<p>You now know my position and resources. A movable force of 43,000 men (19,000 in
					good order), posted as I have detailed to you, are all I have, and I am made
					responsible for the security of this city.</p>
				<p>I trust you will communicate you wishes to me, and give me the benefit of any
					views and suggestions which will enable me to aid you. I need not repeat that I
					stand prepared to do all in my power for that purpose.</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>I am, general, respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
					<signed>JNO POPE,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
				</closer>
			</div1>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI.2>
