<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218840"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218840">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11218840</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498657</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 840-841</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-27">1862-03-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11218840T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>General Thomas J. Jackson, commanding Confederates in the Valley, reports to
                    General Joseph E. Johnston in this March, 1862, letter. Jackson details Union
                    troop movements, strengths, and plans. Jackson mentions deceiving Union generals
                    into thinking he has planned a withdrawal to the important railroad town of
                    Staunton to link up with Johnston in the East.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. VALLEY DISTRICT
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. JOSEPH E. JOHNSTON:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-27">March 27, 1862</date>--<time>10 a. m.</time>
                        <name type="place">Near Woodstock,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MY DEAR GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have received your two dispatches of yesterday. The enemy are still at
                    Strasburg, and I see no indication of an advance. Should an advance be made and
                    I fall back beyond New Market, I will move on the Gordonsville road.</p>
                <p>The line of couriers will be re-examined. This end of the line is right and if
                    the other is not soon arranged as it should be please let me know what change is
                    required. I will try and draw the enemy on, but do not except to succeed.</p>
                <p>Yesterday a gentleman who had been with the Northern Army for months joined me,
                    and states that Banks crossed about 22,000 men at Harper's Ferry to this side,
                    and that they moved to the vicinity of Winchester.</p>
                <p>On last Sunday the force at Snicker's Ferry was about 15,000-not over 16,000.
                    This force was part of Bank's old command. At present Shields is under Banks. On
                    last Friday Sedgwick's (late Stone's) division was at Bolivar, and one of the
                    colonels said that they were waiting for the boats to be in readiness either at
                    Annapolis or Washington; that they were going to McClellan. Their destination,
                    or that of McClellan, was supposed to be Aquia Creek or York River. That
                    McClellan had been relieved as commander-in-chief and had gone down the Potomac.
                    His force is not over 85,000 or 90,000, though the enemy estimates it as high as
                    150,000. McClellan has the best troops in the Federal service, and the North
                    expects him to take Richmond; that nothing less will satisfy them, and that
                    Richmond is his proposed destination. My informant saw Banks at Strasburg at 10
                    a.m. yesterday. His force there consists of--</p>
                <p>Col. Kimball's brigade, which is: Fourth Ohio, Sixth Ohio, Sixty-seventh Ohio,
                    and Eighty-fourth Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>Gen. Sullivan's brigade: Fifth Ohio, Sixty-second Ohio, Sixty-sixth Ohio,
                    Thirty-third Iowa, and Thirty-ninth Illinois.</p>
                <p>Gen. Tyler's brigade: Seventh Ohio, Twenty-ninth Ohio, Seventh Iowa, First
                    Virginia, and One hundred and tenth Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>That the regiments probably number 800 for duty on an average, but not more. This
                    give 11,200 infantry.</p>
                <p>Yesterday morning Banks went in the direction of the burnt railroad bridge, which
                    is toward Front Royal, and was inquiring about bridge timber. The railroad agent
                    at Strasburg was with him; I designed arresting the agent, but he eluded me. The
                    Strasburg force is of Shields' and Williams' division. The railroad agent said
                    to Banks that there was some rolling stock in the direction of Alexandria, which
                    had been taken from the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and there was one freight
                    engine and several cars in this direction. The impression produced in the mind
                    of my information was that Banks designed rebuilding the railroad bridge and
                    move by railroad such troops from Strasburg as could be spared. It is understood
                    in the Federal Army that you have instructed me to keep the forces now in this
                    district and not permit them to cross the Blue Ridge, and that this must be done
                    at every hazard, and that for the purpose of effecting this I had made the
                    attack. I have never so much as intimated such a thing to any one. Gen. Gordon's
                    brigade, which was brought back from Snicker's Ferry last Sunday, was still
                    there. The enemy is ignorant of my strength. On the 23d the enemy had
                    twenty-sixth guns. Best's battery, consisting of four or six pieces, was not in
                    the fight. This fives thirty or thirty-two pieces then at Winchester.</p>
                <p>Estimating Banks' command that crossed at Harper's Ferry at 22,000, and the
                    Virginia regiment now at Winchester at 800, and the force at Strasburg at
                    11,200, gives 34,000 infantry. Shields and Williams came from Paw Paw and
                    Hancock.</p>
                <p>The enemy at Strasburg believed that I had fallen back to Staunton en route to
                    join you. I will try and correct this error and them fall back, if necessary. I
                    am much obliged to you for telegraphing respecting Field.</p>
                <p>Shields had an arm fractured by a shell from Ashby's artillery on last Saturday.
                    It is said that amputation has become necessary.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very truly, yours,</salute>
                    <signed>T. J. JACKSON.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
