<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218340"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218340">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Schriver, Ed</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R11218340</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498631</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and Confederate
       Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Schriver, Ed</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 340-341</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-06-05">1862-06-05</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="R11218340T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this dispatch, Ed Schriver updates General James Shields on the supply situation facing
     his division pursuing Jackson southward. He wonders how Shields will reach Staunton despite
     impassable roads beyond Columbia Bridge. He also details foraging procedures.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF THE RAPPAHANNOCK
     <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. JAMES SHIELDS,<lb/> Commanding Division:</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-06-05">June 5, 1862.</date>
      <name type="place">Front Royal, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Gen.:</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your dispatch of the 4th by the hand of Capt.
     Haycock.</p>
    <p>I am intrusted by the major-general commanding to say in reply that subsistence and beef on
     the hoof left here for your division day before yesterday, and must have been received before
     this.</p>
    <p>The floods have carried away the Bull Run Bridge and have done other damage on the line of
     the road, but it is rapidly being restored, and no serious detention in the driving forward of
     supplies to this place is anticipated.</p>
    <p>As far as the means of transportation belonging to your division and the condition of the
     roads will go you can depend on obtaining supplies from this point. In order to do this to the
     full extent of your means your wagons must be employed for that purpose, and your men must
     either carry their knapsacks or do as Jackson's men did, leave them behind them.</p>
    <p>The wagons must not be made to carry anything not absolutely necessary, and a rigid
     inspection must be ordered to see that this rule is observed. We cannot catch a light-footed
     enemy and carry such heavy weights.</p>
    <p>You report the roads beyond Columbia Bridge as being impassable for wagons, and of course for
     artillery. How, then, do you propose at this time to get your division to Staunton?</p>
    <p>The major-general commanding is as anxious as you to accomplish something, even in spite of
     the elements, with your gallant division, and will give it any facility in his power.</p>
    <p>To whatever distance you may, from your better knowledge of the roads and country, feel
     yourself justified in going, the general wishes you to have all your force well in hand, with
     the parts in supporting distance of each other.</p>
    <p>The grass is now of the best, and you must do as we do in Texas and on the plains, graze your
     horses, unless you can get grain in the country. In taking it you will please instruct your
     quartermaster to be governed by the orders on that subject communicated to him through the
     chief quartermaster at department headquarters. Whatever private property is taken you will
     cause the officer taking it to send here immediately a duplicate of the receipt given the party
     from whom the supplies are taken.</p>
    <p>All the bridges across the Shenandoah are swept away.</p>
    <p>Bayard's brigade of cavalry is still with Gen. Fremont. As soon as you get near enough to
     each other the general wishes it to join you. Please to inform him when you have the
     opportunity. Gen. Fremont must now be at or near New Market.</p>
    <p>Part of Ord's division has been caught on the other side of the river and cannot get back. As
     soon as it can move, the larger part of his division will go to Luray, and King's division is
     ordered to-day to Warrenton town. Can the country through which you are operating support more
     than your own division? Please answer immediately as fully as possible on this head.</p>
    <p>When, probably, if the weather continues fine, can you count on the roads being passable for
     artillery beyond Columbia Bridge?</p>
    <p>The Secretary informs us that Maj.-Gen. Pope, at the head of 40,000, pursued Beauregard's
     army beyond Corinth, taking 10,000 prisoners. Beauregard frantic.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute>Very respectfully, &amp; c.,</salute>
     <signed> ED. SCHRIVER,<lb/> Col. and Chief of Staff.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
