<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11216796"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11216796">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Proceedings of a Military Commission.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv proceedings of a military commission</title>
        <author>Noakes, Thomas</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11216796</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498601</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Proceedings of a Military Commission.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv proceedings of a military commission</title>
            <author>Noakes, Thomas</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 16</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 795-796</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value=""/>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11216796T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union scout Thomas Nokes testifies before a military commission on the evacuation
                    of Winchester. He mentions Confederate movements from Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Proceedings of a military commission held at Washington City, D. C.
                </head>
                
                <p>The Commission resumed the investigation in relation to the evacuation of
                    Winchester by Gen. White, and proceeded to the examination of witnesses.</p>
                <p>THOMAS NOAKES, called by Gen. White, and sworn and examined as follows:</p>
                <p>By Gen. WHITE:</p>
                <p>Question. Were you at Winchester during the month of August last, and up to the
                    time of its evacuation?</p>
                <p>Answer. I was not there at the time of its evacuation.</p>
                <p>Question. Were you there shortly prior, during the month of August?</p>
                <p>Answer. Yes, sir; I left a short time before the evacuation.</p>
                <p>Question. What sort of duty were you upon?</p>
                <p>Answer. I was in service for Gen. White and the Government, going to different
                    places.</p>
                <p>Question. As a scout?</p>
                <p>Answer. Yes, sir; as a guide and scout.</p>
                <p>Question. Were you, or not, familiar with the fact that the enemy were constantly
                    in that vicinity?</p>
                <p>Answer. Yes, sir.</p>
                <p>Question. And in greater or less force?</p>
                <p>Answer. Yes, sir; I was familiar with that all the time, and tried to keep you
                    posted.</p>
                <p>Question. Is it your opinion, or not, that there was a sufficient force of the
                    enemy in the immediate vicinity to have taken possession of Winchester upon its
                    evacuation, and whatever property might have been left there?</p>
                <p>Answer. Yes, sir; they were at Newtown and White Post, or the springs west of
                    there. The companies of cavalry at Newtown could come in there without anybody
                    to oppose them at all after the evacuation, and take whatever was there.</p>
                <p>Question. Did you hear anything of a large force of the enemy moving on
                    Winchester at or about that time?</p>
                <p>Answer. I heard of about 1,300 that had struck off from Staunton, and they were
                    to be joined by some 500 guerrillas that were lagging back, and which had formed
                    themselves into companies. I guess I reported that to you. It was a rumor. I did
                    not see them, but that was what I got as being the fact. They intended to attack
                    Winchester on the west side, coming out on the Pughtown road.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
