<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1121849"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1121849">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Banks, Nathaniel P.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1121849</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498642</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Banks, Nathaniel P.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 48-50</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-06">1862-04-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1121849T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this dispatch, Union General Nathaniel P. Banks reports to Adjutant-General
                    Lorenzo Thomas on the situation facing his Corps in the Valley. He mentions
                    possible Confederate plans to concentrate around Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. LORENZO THOMAS, Adjutant-Gen. U. S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-04-06">April 6.</date>
                        <name type="place">WOODSTOCK, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Upon receiving your dispatch announcing the creation of a new military
                    department, embracing the valley of the Shenandoah, for my command, I thought it
                    my duty to make to the Department of War an immediate and full statement of the
                    forces, position, and condition of the Fifth Army Corps.</p>
                <p>The corps consists of two divisions; the first commanded by Gen. A. S. Williams;
                    the second commanded by Brig.-Gen. Shields. The full force of both divisions is
                    now about 23,000 men, including infantry, cavalry, and artillery. Our effective
                    force, however, at this time for operations in the valley of the Shenandoah and
                    vicinity is reduced to 12,600. The accompanying sheet will show the positions of
                    the main force and the various detachments that were necessarily made.</p>
                <p>After the occupation of Winchester by my command I was ordered by Gen. McClellan
                    to move Gen. Williams' division to Manassas for the occupation of the country in
                    front and the reconstruction of the railway in the direction of Strasburg. My
                    impression was that the movement was to be immediate, in order that the
                    embarkation of troops movement to other points might not be delayed and the
                    grand movement of the army embarrassed by a failure here.</p>
                <p>Immediately upon my return to Winchester from Washington I put Williams' division
                    in movement for Manassas, where I had promised it should be on the 25th of
                    March, and, according to my instructions to precede this division, I left
                    Winchester on the 23rd March for Manassas. The battle on that day at Winchester
                    recalled me, and I ordered back all the brigades of the division within my
                    reach. Abercrombie's had advanced too far, and is now at Warrenton Junction, in
                    pursuance of my orders. This reduces my corps 4,500 men. Col. Geary's regiment,
                    with squadron of cavalry, reduced it again 1,800 men, lessening my force in
                    consequence of this movement 6,300 men.</p>
                <p>Our advance from Harper's Ferry has placed under our protection 100 miles of the
                    Baltimore and Ohio Railway, 32 miles of the Winchester Railway, and the towns,
                    villages, highways, and bridges upon a line of 70 miles, over which our trains
                    of supply are constantly passing. In addition to this, the valley we occupy is
                    of such a character that we are compelled to protect our flanks by detachments
                    far in our rear, at the very head of the valley. These military necessities, not
                    to speak of the sick, hospital attendants, &amp;c., have reduced our
                    effective force by a further detachment of 4,000 men, leaving, as I said, but
                    12,633 men for immediate action.</p>
                <p>The enemy has from 6,000 to 8,000 men, is well supplied with both light and heavy
                    artillery, and is supported by a regiment of very superior cavalry. They are
                    likely to be re-enforced to some extent by the rebel forces hitherto at Fort
                    Alleghany, about 26 miles east of Cheat Mountain, 2,600 strong, and from
                    Monterey and one other point, Huntersville, the forces of which I do not know,
                    but believe them not to be large.</p>
                <p>Gen. Fremont telegraphs me they are retreating generally all along his front,
                    with a purpose, he believes, of concentrating at Staunton. This corresponds with
                    our information. We may reasonably look, therefore, for an increase of Jackson's
                    force to this extent, but not much beyond. I do not believe that Johnston can
                    safely strengthen him. Cavalry force is but about 800, mostly inexperienced men
                    and untrained horses. The arrival of Col. Holliday's Vermont cavalry, the use of
                    which I obtained here "for a short time," is demoralized by the suicide of the
                    colonel at Strasburg on Friday. It will not be of value for active service,
                    judging from the representations made to us of the condition of the prominent
                    officers. We have so many mountain valleys to scout and such an extended line to
                    protect that, independent of the necessity of strong cavalry in action, we need
                    a large and efficient cavalry force. We are now greatly inferior to the enemy in
                    this arm of the service, in which we should be stronger.</p>
                <p>Jackson is lying between Mount Jackson and New Market. We hope immediately to
                    strike him an effective blow. Capt. Hunt, of the Engineer Corps, will explain to
                    you more fully than can be written the plans of action, which I hope may meet
                    your approval.</p>
                <p>There are no rebel forces in the mountains between the commands of Gen. Sumner
                    and my own, except perhaps 200 or 300 scouts in different parts of the
                    mountains. Our scouts report no rebel forces at Luray, Washington, or
                    Sperryville, where their troops have been heretofore reported.</p>
                <p>Gen. Johnston we believe to be at Gordonsville-perhaps farther south. Some of the
                    deserters from the enemy report having heard it said in their camp that Johnston
                    was within 15 miles of Richmond. These facts may be of service to Gen. Sumner.</p>
                <p>It is of great importance on this line that we should be informed of every event
                    that transpires on the east in front of Manassas and near Richmond. Pardon this
                    tedious statement; I write amid many interruptions.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>N. P. BANKS,<lb/> Commanding Fifth Army Corps.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
