<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218872"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218872">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11218872</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498668</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 872</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-29">1862-04-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11218872T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In late April, 1862, Confederate General Thomas J. Jackson prepared to launch his
                    Shenandoah Valley campaign. In this letter to Robert E. Lee, commanding all
                    Confederate forces from Richmond, Jackson outlines his plans.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. R. E. LEE,<lb/> Cmdg. C. S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-04-29">April 29, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">SWIFT RUN GAP, </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>As I do not believe that Banks will advance on me in my present position, I am
                    disposed, unless you send me large re-enforcements, to adopt one of three plans,
                    viz, either to leave Gen. Ewell here to threaten Banks' rear in the event of his
                    advancing on Staunton, and move with my command rapidly on the force in front of
                    Gen. Edward Johnson, or else, co-operating with Gen. Ewell, to attack the
                    enemy's detached force between New Market and the Shenandoah, and, if successful
                    in this, then to press forward and get in Banks' rear at New Market, and thus
                    induce him to fall back; the third is to pass down the Shenandoah to
                    Sperryville, and thus threaten Winchester via Front Royal. I believe that this
                    would cause the enemy to fall back. From Sperriville I could move either in the
                    direction of Front Royal, Warrenton, or, if my command should be opposed by too
                    large a Federal force, it could turn off toward Culpeper Court-House. To get in
                    Banks' rear with my present force would be rather a dangerous undertaking, as I
                    would have to cross the river and immediately cross the Massanutten Mountain,
                    during which the enemy would have decidedly the advantage of position. Of the
                    three plans I give the preference to attacking the force west of Staunton, for,
                    if successful, I would afterward only have Banks to contend with, and in doing
                    this would be re-enforced by Gen. Edward Johnson, and by that time you might be
                    able to give me re-enforcements, which, united with the troops now under my
                    control, would enable me to defeat Banks; and if he should be routed and his
                    command destroyed, nearly all our own forces here could, if necessary, cross the
                    Blue Ridge to Warrenton, Fredericksburg, or any other threatened point. I have
                    written to Gen. Edward Johnson to know what force, in addition to his command,
                    would be required for a successful blow in his vicinity. If I receive an answer
                    justifying a move in that direction I may leave here to-morrow via Port
                    Republic.</p>
                <p>Please send me part of Alexander's signal corps, if you can spare it; if not,
                    please send me the system of signals, so that I may have persons instructed.</p>
                <p>The enemy's signals give him a great advantage over me.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>T. J. JACKSON,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
