<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11215470"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11215470">
  <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Report of Major General Thomas J. Jackson.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv report of major general thomas j jackson</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">19</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R11215470</idno>
        <!--
        <availability>
          <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of
            Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
          <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
        </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498595</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Report of Major General Thomas J. Jackson.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and
              Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv report of major general thomas j jackson</title>
            <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 15</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 470-473</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-04-07">1863-04-07</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="R11215470T">
    <front id="d2">
      <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
        <p>On May 8, 1862, Confederate forces under Thomas J. Jackson met and defeated fragments of
          John C. Fremont's Union troops under Robert Milroy at the battle of McDowell. Jackson
          acted to prevent Milroy from linking up with Banks and capturing Staunton, a town which
          Jackson describes as important. In this letter, Jackson reports on the battle. He also
          mentions VMI cadets stationed in Staunton.</p>
      </div1>
    </front>
    <body id="d4">
      <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
        <head>
          HDQRS. SECOND CORPS, ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,
          <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. R.H. CHILTON,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant and
            Inspector-Gen.,<lb/> Headquarters Army of Northern Virginia.</name>
        </head>
        <opener>
          <dateline>
            <date value="1863-03-07">March 7, 1863.</date>
          </dateline>
          <salute>GENERAL: I have the honor herewith to submit to you a report of the operations of
            my command in the battle of McDowell, Highland County, Virginia, on May 8:</salute>
        </opener>
        <p>After the battle of Kernstown I retreated in the direction of Harrisonburg. My rear
          guard--comprising Ashby's cavalry, Capt. Chew's battery, and from time to time other
          forces--was placed under the direction of Col. Turner Ashby, an officer whose judgment,
          coolness, and courage eminently qualified him for the delicate and important trust
          Although pursued by a greatly superior force, under Gen. Banks, we were enabled to halt
          for more than a fortnight in the vicinity of Mount Jackson.</p>
        <p>After reaching Harrisonburg we turned toward the Blue Ridge, and on April 19 crossed the
          South Fork of the Shenandoah, and took position between that river and Swift Run Gap, in
          Elk Run Valley.</p>
        <p>Gen. R.S. Ewell, having been directed to join my command, left the vicinity of
          Gordonsville, and on the 30th arrived with his division west of the Blue Ridge.</p>
        <p>The main body of Gen. Banks' pursuing army did not proceed farther south than the
          vicinity of Harrisonburg; but a considerable force, under my command of Gen. Milroy, was
          moving toward Staunton from the direction of Mounterey, and, as I satisfactorily learned,
          part of it had already crossed to the east of the Shenandoah Mountain, and was encamped
          not far from the Harrisonburg and Warm Springs turnpike. The positions of these two
          Federal armies were now such that if left unmolested they could readily form a junction on
          the road just named and move with their united forces against Staunton.</p>
        <p>At this time Brig. Gen. Edward Johnson, with his troops, was near Buffalo Gap, west of
          Staunton, so that, if the enemy was allowed to effect a junction, it would probably be
          followed not only by the seizure of a point so important as Staunton, but must compel Gen.
          Johnson to abandon his position, and he might succeed in getting between us. To avoid
          these results I determined, if practicable, after strengthening my own division by a union
          with Johnson's first to strike at Milroy and then to concentrate the forces of Ewell and
          Johnson with my own against Banks.</p>
        <p>To carry out my design against Milroy Gen. Ewell was directed to march his division to
          the position which I then occupied, in the Elk Run Valley, with a view to holding Banks in
          check, while I pushed on with my division to Staunton. These movements were made.</p>
        <p>At Staunton I found, according to previous arrangements, Maj.-Gen. Smith, of the Virginia
          Military Institute, with the corps of cadets, ready to co-operate in the defense of that
          portion of the valley. On the morning of May 7 Gen. Johnson, whose familiarity with that
          mountain region and whose high qualities as a soldier admirably fitted him for the
          advance, moved with his command in the direction of the enemy, followed by the brigades of
          Gen. Taliaferro, Col. Campbell, and Gen. Winder, in the order named.</p>
        <p>Encountering the enemy's advance near the point where the Staunton and Parkersburg
          turnpike intersects the Harrisonsburg and Warm Springs turnpike, Gen. Johnson pressed
          forward. The Federals rapidly retreated, abandoning their baggage at Rodgers' and other
          points east of the Shenandoah Mountain. After the advance had reached the western base of
          the Shenandoah Mountain the troops bivouacked for the night.</p>
        <p>On the following morning the march was resumed, Gen. Johnson's brigade still in front.
          The head of the column was halted near the top of Bull Pasture Mountain, and Gen. Johnson,
          accompanied by a party of 30 men and several officers, with a view to a reconnaissance of
          the enemy's position, ascended Setlington's Hill, an isolated spur of the Bull Pasture
          Mountain on the left of the turnpike, and commanding a full view of the village of
          McDowell. From this point the position, and to some extent the strength, of the enemy
          could be seen. In the valley in which McDowell is located was observed a considerable
          force of infantry. To the right, on a height, were two regiment, but too distant for an
          effective fire to that point. Almost a mile in front was a battery supported by infantry.</p>
        <p>The enemy, observing a reconnoitering party, sent out a small body of skirmishers, which
          was promptly met by the men with Gen. Johnson and driven back.</p>
        <p>For the purpose of securing the hill, all of Gen. Johnson's regiments were sent to him.
          The Fifty-second Virginia Regiment, being the first to reach the ground, was posted on the
          left as skirmishers, and it was not long before they were engaged in a brisk encounter
          with the enemy's skirmishers, whom they handsomely repulsed. Soon after this three other
          regiments arrived, and were posted as follows: The Twelfth Georgia on the crest of the
          hill, and forming the center of our line; the Fifty-eighth Virginia on the left, to
          support the Fifty-second, and the Forty-fourth Virginia on the right near a ravine.</p>
        <p>Milroy having during the day been re-enforced by Gen. Schenck, determined to carry the
          hill, if possible, by a direct attack. Advancing in force along its western slope,
          protected in his advance by the character of the ground and the wood interposed in our
          front and driving our skirmishers before him, he emerged from the woods and poured a
          galling fire into our right, which was returned, and a brisk and animated contest was kept
          up for some time, when the two remaining regiments of Johnson's brigade (the Twenty-fifth
          and Thirty-first) coming up, they were posted to the right. The fire was now rapid and
          well sustained on both sides and the conflict fierce and sanguinary.</p>
        <p>In ascending to the crest of the hill from the turnpike the troops had to pass to the
          left through the woods by a narrow and rough route. To prevent the possibility of the
          enemy's advancing along the turnpike and seizing the point where the troops left the road
          to ascend the hill, the Thirty-first Virginia Regiment was posted between that point and
          the town, and when ordered to join its brigade in action its place was supplied by the
          Twenty-first Virginia Regiment. The engagement had now not only become general along the
          entire line, but so intense, that I ordered Gen. Taliaferro to the support of Gen.
          Johnson. Accordingly, the Twenty-third and Thirty-seventh Virginia Regiments were advanced
          to the center of the line, which was then held by the Twelfth Georgia with heroic
          gallantry, and the Tenth Virginia was ordered to support the Fifty-second Virginia, which
          had already driven the enemy from the left and had now advanced to make a flank movement
          on him.</p>
        <p>At this time the Federals were pressing forward in strong force on our extreme right,
          with a view of flanking that position. This movement of the enemy was speedily detected
          and met by Gen. Taliaferro's brigade and the Twelfth Georgia with great promptitude.
          Further to check it, portions of the Twenty-fifth and Thirty-first Virginia Regiments were
          sent to occupy an elevated piece of woodland on our right and rear, so situated as to
          fully command the position of the enemy. The brigade commanded by Col. Campbell coming up
          about this time was, together with the Tenth Virginia, ordered down the ridge into the
          woods to guard against movements against our right flank, which they, in connection with
          the other force, effectually prevented.</p>
        <p>The battle lasted about four hours-from 4.30 in the afternoon until 8.30. Every attempt
          by front or flank movement to attain the crest of the hill, where our line was formed, was
          signally and effectually repulsed. Finally, after dark, their force ceased firing, and the
          enemy retired.</p>
        <p>The enemy's artillery, posted on a hill in our front, was active in throwing shot and
          shell up to the period when the infantry fight commenced, but in consequence of the great
          angle of elevation at which they fired, and our sheltered position, they inflicted no loss
          upon our troops. Our own artillery was not brought up, there being no road to the rear by
          which our guns could be withdrawn in event of disaster, and the prospect of successfully
          using them did not compensate for the risk.</p>
        <p>Gen. Johnson, to whom I had intrusted the management of the troops engaged, proved
          himself eminently worthy of the confidence reposed in him by the skill, gallantry, and
          presence of mind which he displayed on the occasion. Having received a wound near the
          close of the engagement which compelled him to leave the field, he turned over the command
          to Gen. Taliaferro.</p>
        <p>During the night the Federals made a hurried retreat towards Franklin, in Pendleton
          County, leaving their dead upon the field. Before doing so, however, they succeeded in
          destroying most of their ammunition, camp equipage, and commissary stores, which they
          could not remove.</p>
        <p>Official reports show a loss in this action of 71 killed and 390 wounded, making a total
          loss of 461. Among the killed was Col. Gibbons, of the Tenth Virginia Regiment. Col.
          Harman, of the Fifty-second, Col. George H. Smith and Maj. John C. Higginbotham, of the
          Twenty-fifth, and Maj. Campbell, of the Forty-eighth Virginia, were among the wounded.</p>
        <p>To prevent Banks from re-enforcing Milroy, Mr. J. Hotchkiss, who was on topographical
          duty with the army, proceeded with a party to blockade the roads through North River and
          Dry River Gaps, while a detachment of cavalry obstructed the road through Brock's Gap.</p>
        <p>As the Federals continued to fight until night and retreated before morning, but few of
          their number were captured. Besides quartermaster and commissary stores, some arms and
          other ordnance stores fell into our hands.</p>
        <p>Dr. Hunter McGuire, my medical director, managed his department admirably.</p>
        <p>Lieut. Hugh H. Lee, chief of ordnance, rendered valuable assistance in seeing my
          instructions respecting the manner in which the troops should go into action faithfully
          carried out. I regret to say that during the action he was so seriously wounded as to
          render it necessary for him to leave the field.</p>
        <p>First Lieut. A.S. Pendleton, aide-de-camp; First Lieut. J.K. Boswell, chief engineer, and
          Second Lieut. R.K. Meade, assistant chief of ordnance, were actively engaged in
          transmitting orders.</p>
        <p>Previous to the battle the enemy had such complete control of the pass through which our
          artillery would have to pass, if it continued to advance on the direct road to McDowell,
          that I determined to postpone the attack until the morning of the 9th. Owing to the action
          having been brought on by Milroy's advancing to the attack on the 8th, Maj. R.L. Dabney,
          assistant adjutant-general, was not with me during the engagement.</p>
        <p>Maj. J.A. Harman, chief quartermaster, and Maj. W.J. Hawks, chief commissary, had their
          departments in good condition.</p>
        <p>Leaving Lieut. Col. J.T.L. Preston, with a detachment of cadets and a small body of
          cavalry, in charge of the prisoners and public property, the main body of the army,
          preceded by Capt. George Sheetz, with his cavalry, pursued the retreating Federals to the
          vicinity of Franklin, but succeeded in capturing only a few prisoners and stores along the
          line of march.</p>
        <p>The junction between Banks and Milroy having been prevented, and becoming satisfied of
          the impracticability of capturing the defeated enemy, owing to the mountains character of
          the country being favorable for a retreating army to make its escape, I determined, as the
          enemy had made another stand at Franklin, with a prospect of being soon re-enforced, that
          I would not attempt to press farther, but return to the open country of the Shenandoah
          Valley, hoping, through the blessing of Providence, to defeat Banks before he should
          receive re-enforcements.</p>
        <p>On Thursday, the 15th, the army, after divine service, for the purpose of rendering
          thanks to God for the victory with which He had blessed us and to implore His continued
          favor, began to retrace its course.</p>
        <p>Great praise is due the officers and men for their conduct in action and on the march.</p>
        <p>Though Col. Crutchfield, chief of artillery, did not have an opportunity of bringing his
          command into action on the 8th, it was used with effect on several occasions during the
          expedition.</p>
        <p>My special thanks are due Maj. Gen. F.H. Smith for his conduct and patriotic co-operation
          during the expedition.</p>
        <p>Col. T.H. Williamson, of the Engineers, rendered valuable service.</p>
        <p>For further information respecting the engagement and those who distinguished themselves
          I respectfully refer you to the accompanying reports of brigade and other commanders.</p>
        <closer>
          <salute>I am, general, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
          <signed>T.J. JACKSON,<lb/> Lieut.-Gen.</signed>
        </closer>
      </div1>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
