<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1121851"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1121851">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Banks, Nathaniel P.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1121851</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498646</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Banks, Nathaniel P.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 51-52</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-06">1862-04-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1121851T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this April, 1862, letter, Union General Nathaniel P. Banks reports to George
                    B. McClellan on affairs in the Valley. He discusses Staunton as sight of a
                    possible conversion of Confederate forces. Banks also reports that General
                    Thomas J. Jackson has been sending stores and provisions in the direction of
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. GEORGE B. McCLELLAN,<lb/> Commanding Army of
                        the Potomac:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-04-06">April 6, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">WOODSTOCK,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 1st April, probably intended for me at Manassas, I received by
                    special messenger late last night.</p>
                <p>The enemy in front under Jackson is reduced to about 6,000 men. The force is much
                    demoralized by defeat, desertion, and the general depression of spirits resting
                    on the Southern army. His exact position is at Rude's Hill, on the left of the
                    turnpike, about half way between Mount Jackson and New Market. He is not in
                    condition to attack, neither to make strong resistance, and I do not believe he
                    will attempt to make a determined stand there. I do not believe Johnston will
                    re-enforce him. We understand him (Johnston) to be engaged in the direction of
                    Richmond, with a view of concentrating all his forces there. All our reports
                    agree in this. He is now near Gordonsville. On the west we learn from Gen.
                    Fremont that the rebels are retreating from Fort Alleghany, about 2,600 strong,
                    and also from Huntersville, Monterey, and on Fremont front generally. Their
                    purpose is doubtless concentration at Staunton, in which event Jackson will be
                    re-enforced to that extent, and perhaps make a stand at Staunton. He is moving
                    commissary stores, ammunition, &amp;c., in that direction. His alternative
                    will be to join Johnston's movements in the direction of Richmond, and in that
                    view perhaps he is now transferring his stores to Waynesborough.</p>
                <p>Our advance separates us so far from our depot of supplies--Winchester--as to
                    require caution, and the features of the country, hemmed in on both sides by
                    mountain ranges, makes it practicable for the enemy, if in force, to flank our
                    extended line on either side, and the necessity of guarding these lines in all
                    directions has reduced our force of effective men to less than 12,000, not
                    including Abercrombie or Geary, who are at Manassas or vicinity. In the event of
                    a movement we can draw in some detachments not included in our present effective
                    force. If Gen. Blenker arrives soon he will relieve us of this difficulty. Our
                    cavalry is weak in numbers and spirit--much exhausted with night and day work.
                    Good cavalry would help incalculably.</p>
                <p>The movements in contemplation are an attack on Jackson at Rude's Hill, with a
                    view to cut him off, or drive him into the mountain roads, by the way of Luray,
                    Sperryville, &amp;c. This is one of the lines of retreat that he has
                    hitherto contemplated, but a very difficult one. This would prevent a
                    concentration at Staunton. For this movement we are ready at any time. If
                    Jackson retreats on Staunton it will require longer time and the assistance of
                    Gen. Blenker. With his brigades we can bring our force up to about 20,000 men.</p>
                <p>The railway bridges from Front Royal are in progress. The re-establishment of
                    this communication will help us, and I shall hope that we may be able to second
                    your movements upon Richmond at the right time, neither being too early nor too
                    late in ours. I desire most earnestly to be kept well informed of your
                    movements, and shall communicate often with you as to our own and those of the
                    enemy.</p>
                <p>The Secretary of War informed me by telegraph yesterday that a new department was
                    to be created for my command in this valley. If this is effected it will not
                    lessen the importance of our co-operation or the necessity of each being well
                    informed as to the daily progress of events. I shall, in any event, cherish a
                    sincere feeling of satisfaction and pride upon my association with you in the
                    defense of the Potomac, and both work and hope earnestly for the entire success
                    of your long-matured and now daily developing plans.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With much respect, I am, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>N. P. BANKS,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">The death of Col. Holiday was very sudden and very sad.
                        He appeared greatly depressed when here about the condition of his regiment,
                        which was then at Strasburg. He spoke upon no other subject while here. His
                        officers say he had been nearly insane for three weeks, and attribute his
                        depression of spirits to personal disappointments not connected with his
                        profession. I do not know how this may be. His death occurred near
                        Strasburg, while he was near the head of his column. He shot himself in the
                        head, and died without a word. His body has been sent, with appropriate
                        attentions, to his friends in New York.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
