<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R112135"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R112135">
	<teiHeader type="migrated">
		  <fileDesc>
			   <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. General Reports.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv general reports</title>
        <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
        <respStmt>
					     <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
					     <name/>
					     <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
			   <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
			   <publicationStmt>
				    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
				    <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
				    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
				    <idno type="VCDH">R112135</idno>
        <!--
				<availability>
					<p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
						University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
					<p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
				</availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
				    <date value="1999">1999</date>
			     <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498591</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
			   <seriesStmt>
				    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
			   </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
			   <notesStmt>
				    <note/>
			   </notesStmt>
			   <sourceDesc>
				    <biblFull>
					     <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. General Reports.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
							Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv general reports</title>
            <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
            <respStmt>
							       <resp>Translator:</resp>
							       <name/>
						      </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
					     <editionStmt>
						      <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 15</p>
					     </editionStmt>
					     <extent>Pages 234-235</extent>
					     <publicationStmt>
						      <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
						      <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
						      <date value="1997">1997</date>
					     </publicationStmt>
					     <seriesStmt>
						      <p/>
					     </seriesStmt>
					     <notesStmt>
						      <note/>
					     </notesStmt>
				    </biblFull>
			   </sourceDesc>
		  </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
		  <profileDesc>
			   <creation>
				    <date value="1862-04-01">1862-04-01</date>
			   </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
			   <textClass>
				    <keywords>
					     <term/>
					     <term/>
				    </keywords>
			   </textClass>
		  </profileDesc>
		  <revisionDesc>
			   <change>
				    <date value=""/>
				    <respStmt>
					     <resp/>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
				    <item/>
			   </change>
		    <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text id="R112135T">
		<front id="d2">
			<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
				<p>In April, 1862, General George B. McClellan's Army of the Potomac planned an
					advance on Richmond by way of the James River Peninsula. At the same time,
					Nathaniel Banks' Federals, stationed in the Valley, faced Jackson's troops. In
					this letter McClellan writes Banks regarding the plans and situation in the
					Valley. He suggests an advance on Staunton once railroad communications make it
					possible.</p>
			</div1>
		</front>
		<body id="d4">
			<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
				<head>
					<name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. N.P. BANKS,<lb/> Commanding Fifth Corps:</name>
				</head>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<date value="1862-04-01">April 1, 1862.</date>
						<name type="location">HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE POTOMAC,</name>
						<name type="place">On board the Commodore</name>
					</dateline>
					<salute>GENERAL:</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>The change in affairs in the valley of the Shenandoah has rendered necessary a
					corresponding departure--temporarily at least--from the plan we some days since
					agreed upon. In my arrangements I assume that you have with you a force amply
					sufficient to drive Jackson before you, provided he is not re-enforced largely.
					I also assume that you may find it impossible to detach anything toward Manassas
					for some days, probably not until the operations of the main army have drawn all
					the rebel force toward Richmond.</p>
				<p>You are aware that Gen. Sumner has for some days been at Warrenton Junction, with
					two divisions of infantry, six batteries, and two regiments of cavalry, and that
					a reconnaissance to the Rappahannock forced the enemy to destroy the railway
					bridge at Rappahannock Station, on the Orange and Alexandria Railroad. Since
					that time our cavalry have found nothing on this side of the Rappahannock in
					that direction, and it seems clear that we have no reason to fear any return of
					the rebels in that quarter. Their movements near Fredericksburg also indicate a
					final abandonment of that neighborhood. I doubt whether Jonston will now
					re-enforce Jackson with a view to offensive operations; the time has probably
					passed when he could have gained anything by doing so. I have ordered in one of
					Sumner's divisions (that of Richardson, late Sumner's) to Alexandria for
					embarkation. Blenker's has been detached from the Army of the Potomac and
					ordered to report to Gen. Fremont.</p>
				<p>Abercrombie is probably at Warrenton Junction to-day; Geary at White Plains.Two
					regiments of cavalry have been ordered out and are now on the way to relieve the
					two regiments of Sumner.</p>
				<p>Four thousand infantry and one battery leave Washington at once for Manassas;
					some 3,000 more will move in one or two days, and soon after some 3,000
					additional.</p>
				<p>I will order Blenker to march on Strasburg and to report to you for temporary
					duty, so that, should you find a large force in your front, you can avail
					yourself of his aid. As soon as possible please direct him on Winchester, thence
					to report to the Adjutant-Gen. of the Army for orders, but keep him until you
					are sure what you have in front.</p>
				<p>In regard to your own movements the most important thing at present is to throw
					Jackson well back and then to assume such a position as to enable you to prevent
					his return. As soon as the railway communications are re-established it will be
					probably important and advisable to move on Staunton, but this would require
					secure communications and a force of from 25,000 to 30,000 for active
					operations. It should also be nearly coincident with my own move on Richmond; at
					all events not so long before it as to enable the rebels to concentrate on you
					and then return on me. I fear that you cannot be ready in time, although it may
					come in very well, with a force less than that I have mentioned, after the main
					battle near Richmond. When Gen. Sumner leaves Warrenton Junction Gen.
					Abercrombie will be placed in immediate command of Manassas and Warrenton
					Junction under your general orders. Please inform me frequently by telegraph and
					otherwise as to the state of things in your front.</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>I am, very truly, yours,</salute>
					<signed>GEO. B. McCLELLAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding.</signed>
					<seg type="postscript">P.S.--From what I have just learned it would seem that
						the two regiments of cavalry intended for Warrenton Junction have gone to
						Harper's Ferry. Of the four additional regiments placed under your orders
						two should, as promptly as possible, move by the shortest route on Warrenton
						Junction.</seg>
				</closer>
			</div1>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI.2>
