<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218863"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218863">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R11218863</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498665</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and Confederate
       Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 862-863</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-04-23">1862-04-23</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="R11218863T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>General Thomas J. Jackson, commanding Confederate forces in the Shenandoah Valley, reports to
     Robert E. Lee, directing Confederate operations from Richmond. Jackson outlines the situation
     in late April, 1862, and discusses the possibility of Union armies capturing Staunton.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     HDQRS. VALLEY DISTRICT
     <name type="recipient">Gen. R. E. LEE,<lb/> Cmdg. C. S. Army:</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-04-23">April 23, 1862.</date>
      <name type="place">Swift Run Gap,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>GEN.:</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Your letter of the 21st instant has been received.</p>
    <p>Banks' main force is still in the vicinity of New Market, extending from 1 mile below to 3
     above the town. Yesterday he had near 100 wagons 12 miles above New Market, and part of his
     force even entered Harrisonburg, 17 miles from New Market. My object has been to get in his
     rear at New Market or Harrisonburg if he gives me an opportunity, and this would be the case if
     that if I remain quiet a few days with his main body. It appears to me that if I remain quiet a
     few days more he will probably make a move in some direction or send a large force toward
     Harrisonburg, and thus enable me, with the blessing of Providence, to successfully attack his
     advance, and if I am unsuccessful in driving back his entire force he may be induced to move
     forward his command from New Market and attempt to follow me through this gap, where our forces
     would have greatly the advantage.</p>
    <p>Without Gen. Ewell's division Banks can march on to Staunton; though if he attempts it I
     design threading his flank and rear, and this may prevent his reaching Staunton; but without
     doing this he can advance so far as to threaten Gen. Edward Johnson's rear so seriously as to
     make him fall back, and thus let Staunton fall into the hands of the Federal force in his
     front.</p>
    <p>Banks has probably 1,000 men below me on the opposite side of the South Fork of the
     Shenandoah; but should I attack them, the advantage will be on the side of the enemy, in
     consequence of the river separating us and a mountain being in their rear, which would enable
     the enemy to hold me in check until re-enforcements could be brought up from New Market, as it
     is only 4 miles from the top of the mountain and the river is 8 miles from the top. Under all
     the circumstances I will direct Gen. Ewell to move forward to Stanardsville, which will enable
     us in one day to unite all our force at Swift Run Gap or all of his division an my infantry and
     cavalry at Fisher's Gap, should Banks move in the mean time in that direction, of which I think
     there is very little prospect. Should he remain in the position of yesterday I will try and
     seek an opportunity for attacking successfully some part of his army, and, if circumstances
     justify, press forward.</p>
    <p>My instructions from Gen. Johnston were to unite with Gen. Ewell near the top of the Blue
     ridge and give battle. The course I propose would be departing from Gen. Johnston's
     instructions, but I do not believe that Banks will follow me to the Blue Ridge unless I first
     engage him, and I doubt whether he will then.</p>
    <p>I have given you my views respecting things here, but it may be that Gen. Ewell could render
     more service at Fredericksburg, and, if so, I hope that you will direct his movements
     accordingly.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute>I am, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
     <signed>T. J. JACKSON,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
