<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218205"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218205">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Allen, E. J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11218205</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498625</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Allen, E. J.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 204-205</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-05-19">1862-05-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11218205T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter, E. J. Allen reports to Union General John C. Fremont on
                    operations near Callaghan's. He discusses engagements with bushwhackers, the
                    raising of militia, and Union sentiment in Greenbriar County. He mentions his
                    opponent's efforts to get reinforcements by telegraphing Jackson at
                Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. JOHN C. FREMONT:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-05-19">May 19, 1862.<lb/> (Received 10 a. m.)</date>
                        <name type="place">LEWISBURG,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Having received reliable information that Gen. Heth had carried all his stores to
                    Buchanan by way of Covington and boat down James River and was taking them from
                    thence to Bonsack's Station by wagons, that there was a force of about 500 North
                    Carolina troops at Buchanan and about 600 men at Bonsack's--some of the stores
                    were being forwarded to Dublin Depot--it seemed to be the impression among
                    Heth's men that it was the intention to push on a quantity of the stores to
                    Dublin Depot; keep the line of the Tennessee road open in case he desired to
                    fall back toward Lynchburg. With the intention of capturing these stores,
                    transportation, and troops, Col. Crook moved down toward Jackson's River Depot
                    with about 1,000 infantry and 350 cavalry and four mountain howitzers, intending
                    to march rapidly to Buchanan and Bonsack's and return to Lewisburg by way of
                    Fincastle and Sweet Springs. The route by way of Covington to Buchanan, though a
                    greater distance, was chosen partly because as we circulated a report that we
                    were going to Staunton our destination would not be suspected until we passed
                    some 15 miles below Covington, and partly because there was a rendezvous
                    appointed some 8 miles below White Sulphur Springs for a number of Mountain
                    Rangers. Reaching this rendezvous, we prepared an ambush with the infantry and
                    sent the cavalry by another road to drive them in. They had, however, all
                    retreated except their captain, Sprig, a noted character, whom we captured at
                    Callaghan's, in company with a few other bushwhackers of less note. We passed
                    through Covington without resistance, pushed on to the Depot, captured on the
                    way down one of a party of bushwhackers who fired at us as we passed, took
                    possession of the telegraph office at the Depot, and discovered that the
                    provost-marshal of Alleghany County had telegraphed to Gen. Jackson at Staunton
                    for two or three regiments, and was endeavoring to raise the militia of
                    Greenbrier and Monroe. To use his own oppression, "The Greenbrier men had backed
                    down, and there was a great prevalence of Union sentiment." We also discovered
                    that Jackson had telegraphed that he would send a force down by way of Staunton,
                    and Floyd was to send two regiments by way of Sweet Springs. We deemed it
                    proper, both to prevent an immediate advance from Staunton and to protect
                    Lewisburg more completely, to destroy a railroad bridge some 10 miles out on the
                    Central Railroad. Some prominent active secessionists of the county were
                    arrested, and a notice posted on the court-house in Covington warning all
                    secessionists against maltreatment of Union men under penalty of punishment. A
                    numbers of Union men came out in our rear. The effect of the movement has
                    undoubtedly been excellent in that country, and will aid much in the future
                    protection of Union men.</p>
                <p>Our brigade marched back to Callaghan's, intending to send our cavalry down by
                    way of Sweet Springs to Buchanan to effect the original movement, but we were
                    there met by a courier bearing an order from you to fall back to Gauley River.
                    On our entrance into Lewisburg Col. Crook received another dispatch, telling him
                    to remain until further orders. Still another, ordering him down by Palestine
                    road to re-enforce Gen. Cox, which he proceeded to do at daybreak.</p>
                <p>The move to Jackson's River Depot will undoubtedly cause much speculation among
                    the rebels, and they would be for some time after receiving our exaggerated
                    reports of our numbers, in great doubt as to our destination and object. I think
                    in the movement toward Giles that I might be of great service by remaining, as a
                    great portion of that country is personally known to me and I can command the
                    services of persons resident. Shall I remain or shall I report to you?</p>
                <p>Gen. Helt is at or near Dublin with Gen. Floyd, and the greater part of his
                    forces are the militia from Alleghany and the neighboring counties, whom he has
                    forced from their homes against their protests.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>E. J. ALLEN.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
