<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218359"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218359">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Shields, James</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">17</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11218359</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498634</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Shields, James</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 358-361</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-06-08">1862-06-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11218359T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General James Shield's division pursued Stonewall Jackson's Confederates up
                    the Shenandoah Valley in June, 1862. In this letter, Shields reports to Chief of
                    Staff for the Department of the Rappahannock, Edmund Schriver. He describes the
                    obstacles facing his army including the weather and lack of supply. He reports
                    on efforts to meet these problems including bridge building and wheat milling in
                    Luray. Shields also describes Jackson's retreat in the Staunton area, including
                    Confederate desertions and lack of supply.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HEADQUARTERS SHIELDS' DIVISION
                    <name type="recipient"> Col. SCHRIVER,<lb/> C. of S., Hdqrs. Army of the
                        Rappahannock, Front Royal, Va:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-06-08">June 8, 1862.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to state that your dispatch of the 5th instant has been
                    received. Its contents are very satisfactory. I concur fully in the suggestions
                    of the major-general commanding in relation to the remodeling of the department.
                    I beg you will inform the general commanding that I have rigidly enforced his
                    orders in relation to baggage, &amp;c. My command marches with nothing now
                    but arms, ammunition, subsistence, cooking utensils, blankets, and
                    shelter-tents. We found, as I have already had the honor to communicate, all the
                    bridges on the Shenandoah between us and the enemy burned. The incessant rains
                    made every little mountain stream a torrent, and these torrents swelled the
                    South Fork of the Shenandoah to such height that the possibility of crossing in
                    any or by any mode was out of the question. I contrived to push the head of my
                    command as far as Conrad's Store, opposite to Harrisonburg, before this mud road
                    became utterly impassable. Farther no human effort could go. The wheels sunk in
                    the mud to the axle, and the mountain torrents cut between portions of my
                    command and separated them. In this position we commenced building bridges, and
                    soon connected them. Hearing of the failure of the Manassas Railroad, I feared
                    want of supplies, so I put two flour-mills in operation at Luray; collected
                    millers from my command, and Maj. Munn, the provost-marshall at Luray, runs them
                    night and day and furnishes us ample flour to live, but our means of baking are
                    so indifferent that we cannot march without hard bread. There are two other
                    mills near Columbia Bridge which will go into operation as soon as the water
                    falls. We also, in the mean time, constructed a ferry across the Shenandoah at
                    the Columbia Bridge capable of transporting infantry, cavalry, and artillery,
                    and have opened communication with Gen. Fremont.</p>
                <p>On the evening of the 6th instant I sent a party of cavalry and infantry through
                    the Gap to New Market. They found that the enemy had passed the day before and
                    that Fremont had just passed. One was sent to his headquarters, and one of his
                    aides-de-camp to my quarters last night with the communication marked A. He lets
                    me know that on the 6th Jackson was about 9 miles above Harrisonburg, on the way
                    to Staunton, and finding great difficulty in getting along. His men are
                    deserting in hundreds; he crosses and burns the bridges after him. Ashby has
                    infernal activity and ingenuity in this way. Jackson's men appear to be
                    suffering for provisions, he says. The prisoners we take say they have been on
                    half rations. Their supply of ammunition seems by their cautious mode of firing
                    to be nearly exhausted. He is doubtless pushing toward Staunton, and perhaps
                    turning a part of his train toward Port Republic to escape by Waynesborough or
                    Stanardsville.</p>
                <p>The head of Jackson's retreating column may be at Staunton this morning; the head
                    of my column, as you will see by Document B, is in Port Republic. Port Republic
                    is 18 miles from Waynesborough, where I am trying to get. If I get there first,
                    and I think I will, the bridge will be burned and the railroad cut up. This will
                    arrest him and get him between Fremont's command and ours. If his train attempts
                    to go to Stanardsville we will have it, or if to Waynesborough we will have it.
                    I think the head of our column will be in Waynesborough to-night. I am sending
                    information to Gen. Fremont of my exact position, so we may co-operate. I think
                    we have Jackson, but I beg you let the commanding general know that we have to
                    guard our flanks, and this weakens, us.</p>
                <p>Longstreet was between Thornton's Gap and Gordonsville with, say, 8,000 men. This
                    is what brought me back here last night. Our reconnaissance, however, which are
                    still going on, report him as having fallen back. Then there is the turnpike
                    from Harrisonburg to Orange Court-House and thence to Gordonsville, still more
                    dangerous. I have only been able to push forward two brigades against Jackson
                    while Longstreet was in Thornton's Gap, but to-day I am preparing to push
                    forward a third, to hold the road to Stanardsville for the present.</p>
                <p>I repeat, my advance will be in Waynesborough to-night, and this I think will
                    head Jackson, but you will see how extended my line is and what a length of
                    flank I have to defend.</p>
                <p>I wish you would request the commanding general to push forward two brigades to
                    aid me as speedily as possible, one between this and Columbia Bridge, where my
                    Second Brigade is now, to be ready to move either to Luray or Conrad's Store,
                    the other to Luray. This will make everything sure. There is flour here to
                    supply them. I will move my whole command now, relying upon this support. I will
                    need my whole command at Stanardsville (where they say Longstreet has gone),
                    Port Republic, and Waynesborough. The officer who is here from Gen. Fremont says
                    they estimate Jackson's force at 25,000 men. This, I think, is far overrating
                    them, but they must not be despised, and I want my force within supporting
                    distance to act against them. I hope the major-general commanding will be
                    satisfied with my course.</p>
                <p>I venture to keep a few of the Rhode Island cavalry, that I have had shod and put
                    in some condition, until this is over, but if they are required at Front Royal I
                    will send them back at once. We stand in need of salt meat, hard bread, coffee,
                    and sugar. One-third of my command are without shoes, and sans culottes in a
                    literal sense of the word; but we will soon have time to refit. If shoes are in
                    Front Royal, as I hop our quartermaster, Johnson, has some, I want them
                    forwarded to Luray and Conrad's Store. The baggage of all kinds is put in depot
                    here, and the empty wagons are sent back for bread and salt.</p>
                <p>There is one matter I deem it my duty to request you to bring to the notice of
                    the commanding general. In the dispatch to the department announcing the
                    entrance into Front Royal any mention of my division is omitted. The brigade
                    that entered is not named, whereas the Rhode Island cavalry, temporarily
                    attached to this command, is put forward in attractive prominence. Our division
                    is alive to this, because always treated thus in the other department until we
                    got disgusted, and I have constantly assured this command that with Maj.-Gen.
                    McDowell we would be with a soldier who would do us justice. Since they caught
                    sight of the report about Front Royal I regret to say that a feeling is
                    commencing that may lead to the same result. I know it is not possible to give
                    satisfaction of even an allusion to the brigade or division that operated, while
                    the names of others were dilated upon, was something not expected, and creates
                    disappointment.</p>
                <p>For my own part, in my humble way I try to do justice to every portion of my
                    command. When any regiment or company performs a service I mention it. This kind
                    of military justice I deem due to them, and I know the major-general commanding
                    is too generous and just, as well as too experienced a soldier, to act upon the
                    principle of the Shenandoah Department.</p>
                <p>I will act upon the assumption that the general commanding will send down two
                    brigades, one to Luray, one to near Columbia Bridge, immediately. Beg him to
                    save the hard bread for us, as there is an abundance of flour here, and a force
                    in position can use it.</p>
                <p>Three scouts have reached me this moment from Gen. Fremont. They left him at
                    Harrisonburg at 4 p. m. yesterday. They were dressed like rebels, and my pickets
                    detained them last night. They report the following:</p>
                <p>Gen. Fremont is at Harrisonburg; Jackson's rear guard 4 miles on the road to
                    Staunton. The bridge across the North River, on the turnpike, has been burned by
                    some of my cavalry. This has stopped their march on Staunton, and turned them on
                    the road to Port Republic to escape by Waynesborough. The advance of my column
                    near Port Republic report that the enemy's train is on the other side of the
                    river waiting for the water to fall. I have let Gen. Fremont know this, and sent
                    orderlies to keep me informed. Thus you will see he is caught, if these
                    suppositions and dispositions are all right. I hold in my hand an order issued
                    yesterday by B. H. Greene, commissary of subsistence and major in Ewell's
                    division at Stanardsville, directing privates to press horses and picket the
                    mountains while they are removing Government stores. This proves that they are
                    in flight from Stanardsville, either to Charlottesville, by way of Gordonsville,
                    or Waynesborough. I could almost course such rubbish cavalry. One good regiment
                    now would count them up on all sides. My cavalry is an incumbrance. I have to
                    take care of them instead of them taking care of me; but as I need orderlies and
                    scouts, I must use them I keep Capt.? Whipple and a hundred Rhode Island cavalry
                    which I have shod to watch at Luray. These are the only ones here, and I hope
                    the commanding general will sanction this. I go forward myself to-day with the
                    two additional brigades, leaving Luray to be garrisoned by my shoeless men and
                    inefficient until a force can join them from Front Royal. Please let the general
                    know the position at once; he will see the necessity for sending on a few
                    regiments as fast as they can be forwarded. I will keep him constantly advised
                    of our operations. I think we will finish Jackson.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JAS. SHIELDS,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding Division.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
