<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11218376"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11218376">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>McDowell, Irvin</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11218376</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498635</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXIV. Union Correspondence</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>McDowell, Irvin</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 12, Serial No. 18</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 376</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-06-12">1862-06-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11218376T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter, Union General Irvin McDowell reports to Secretary of War Edwin
                    Stanton on the situation in the Valley. He mentions a Confederate telegram from
                    Staunton to Richmond requesting reinforcements.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF THE RAPPAHANNOCK
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. E. M. STANTON,<lb/> Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-06-12">June 12, 1862-</date><time>5 p. m.</time>
                        <name type="place">Manassas,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have received the telegram from Maj.-Gen. McClellan and Maj. Gen. Banks you
                    sent me this morning.</p>
                <p>The enemy's telegram from Staunton to Governor Letcher at Richmond for
                    re-enforcements seems to indicate there was no body of troops between Jackson
                    and Richmond. This is not conclusive, but probable. Gen. McClellan's opinion
                    that some troops left Richmond to join Jackson is strong presumptive evidence
                    that they intend to strengthen their forces in the valley, thought hardly by
                    Longstreet's and Smith's divisions; perhaps it is only to make good Jackson's
                    losses. Gen. Fremont's intention to occupy Mount Jackson and his desire that
                    Gen. Banks should join him there, and the latter's wish to occupy either
                    Middletown or Winchester, and his opinion adverse to occupying Front Royal, see,
                    to indicate that both these commanders intend, or wish, to remain on the west
                    side of the Shenandoah. If they can supply themselves by way of Winchester and
                    Strasburg, and relinquish the road from Manassas to Front Royal town, their plan
                    will have the advantage of having their forces move together in better
                    supporting distance and less liable to attacks in detail; but in that case it
                    seems to me that as all the forces of both these commanders would be on the same
                    line, they might occupy in force a position farther in advance than Mount
                    Jackson, so as to be able to fall on the rear of any force to Washington to
                    enable the President's plan concerning my command to be carried into effect.</p>
                <p>If, under the belief of an advance of a superior force, Gen. Fremont falls back
                    to Mount Jackson, which is within the Massanutten Range, Gen. Shields' division
                    is not safe at Luray, especially since the bridges over the Shenandoah are down
                    and the communication is cut off, and he too far distant to be supported from
                    Catlett's. I have sent to him to know if the has a good defensible position at
                    Luray, and have delayed the movement of Rickett's two brigades from Front Royal
                    to Catlett's, and ordered him to be ready to move to Luray.</p>
                <p>But all this is interfering with the main plan, and if Gens. Fremont and Banks
                    think they can better operate both together west of the Shenandoah, I would
                    recommend that no bridge be rebuilt over the Shenandoah at Front Royal; that
                    Front Royal and the line from Manassas and Front Royal be abandoned, and that I
                    at once bring my forces over to this line. The position now held on the left
                    bank of the Shenandoah near Front Royal by Brig.-Gen. Crawford is strong.
                    Shields' division greatly reduced and broken.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>IRVIN McDOWELL,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Comdg. Department of the Rappahannock.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
