<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928722"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928722">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate General Orders Number 127.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate general orders number 127</title>
        <author>Chilton, Robert H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928722</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498768</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate General Orders Number 127.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate general orders number 127</title>
            <author>Chilton, Robert H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 722</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-14">1862-11-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928722T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee's Adjutant, Robert Chilton, issues General Orders to the army in
                    November, 1862. The orders discuss suppression of gambling and supply
                    speculation by soldiers. It also announces that provost guards will be stationed
                    on trains to inspect soldier's passes. One of the affected routes will be the
                    train running from Richmond to Staunton and back.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    GENERAL ORDERS, No. 127. HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-14">November 14, 1862.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I. The general commanding is pained to learn that the vice of gambling exists,
                    and is becoming common in this army. The regulations expressly prohibit one
                    class of officers from indulging in this evil practice, and it was not supposed
                    that a habit so pernicious and demoralizing would be found among men engaged in
                    a cause, of all others, demanding the highest virtue and purest morality in its
                    supporters. He regards it as wholly inconsistent with the character of a
                    Southern soldier and subversive of good order and discipline in the army. All
                    officers are earnestly enjoined to use every effort to suppress this vice, and
                    the assistance of every soldier having the true interests of the army and of the
                    country at heart is invoked to put an end to a practice which cannot fail to
                    produce those deplorable results which have ever attended its indulgence in any
                    society.</p>
                <p>II. It has also been reported that some men in this army have been so unmindful
                    of their obligations to their comrades, and of their own characters, as to
                    engage in the occupation of purchasing supplies of food and other things, for
                    the purpose of selling them at exorbitant prices to their fellow-soldiers, and
                    it is not surprising that those who have descended to such conduct should be
                    guilty of the crime of imposing on the humane and charitable for the purpose of
                    carrying on their unworthy traffic. A just regard for the reputation of the army
                    requires the immediate suppression of this great evil. It is, therefore, ordered
                    that none but the regular sutlers or citizens having supplies of food or other
                    lawful articles be allowed to engage in barter or trade with the officers and
                    soldiers of this army. Cmdg. officers will give particular attention to the
                    enforcement of this order, and cause every offender to be arrested and brought
                    to trial, that he may receive such punishment as the court may impose.</p>
                <p>III. Hereafter provost guards of an officer and three men will pass daily in the
                    trains from Culpeper Court-House to Gordonsville and back, from Gordonsville to
                    Lynchburg and back, from Richmond to Staunton and back. They will keep order
                    among all military travelers, require from each and all the exhibition of
                    authority upon which they are traveling, arrest all improperly absent from their
                    commands, and turn them over, to be returned to the provost-marshal of the
                    nearest post on the route of travel. The names of individuals arrested, with
                    those of their regiments, companies, &amp;c., with that of the
                    provost-marshal to whom they were turned over, will be reported each trip to
                    these headquarters. No leaves or furloughs to officers or men of this army are
                    valid from this date, unless sanctioned by the commanding general. Staff
                    officers, except those of the general staff attached to the army headquarters,
                    must have the authority of division commanders when traveling on duty. These
                    guards will be detailed by commanding officers at Culpeper Court-House,
                    Gordonsville, and Richmond, and will take charge of all detachments sent from
                    points on their route to this army, preventing delays by the way, and giving
                    them proper directions to their commands. Under no circumstances will such
                    guards interfere with the management of trains, being desired only for duties
                    indicated, and, when called upon, to afford assistance to the conductor.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>By command of Gen. R. E. Lee:</salute>
                    <signed>R. H. CHILTON,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
