<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928697"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928697">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928697</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498756</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 696-697</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-06">1862-11-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928697T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes Thomas J. Jackson on November, 1862, actions in the
                    Shenandoah Valley. He discusses sending a man to Staunton to procure blankets
                    and shoes for the army. He also mentions a group of shoemakers Jackson sent to
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. THOMAS J. JACKSON,<lb/> Cmdg. Corps:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-06">November 6, 1862.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of yesterday from Millwood has been received. The progress of the
                    enemy so far seems to be steadily forward, judging from your reports and those
                    of Gen. Stuart, occupying in his advance the gaps of the Blue Ridge with his
                    right and resting his left on the Orange and Alexandria Railroad. It would seem
                    to be his desire either to detain you in the valley or to get above you, so as
                    to cut you off from a junction with Longstreet, neither of which must you
                    permit. It will be necessary for you to make every arrangement, so that you may
                    move promptly up the valley, that the two corps can be kept in communication
                    with each other and unite when necessary. Gen. George H. Steuart will have to
                    evacuate Winchester before you move higher than Front Royal, and I hope you will
                    be able to bring off all the sick that are able to travel. One of the object of
                    the enemy in proceeding through the counties bordering on the Blue Ridge may be
                    to obtain the forage in that region. You must give the necessary directions to
                    Munford, so that he may regulate his movements by your own. The advantage of the
                    enemy on the eastern slope of the Blue Ridge may be regulated by this force by
                    his force and his facilities for procuring supplies of forage and provision. I
                    do not think he would descend into the valley except with such force as he would
                    think capable of crushing you, still leaving a sufficient force to oppose
                    Longstreet. I have directed Stuart to watch his movements closely, and inform me
                    when he occupies Chester Gap or advances toward Thornton's. In the latter event
                    it will be unwise for the whole of the cavalry to fall back before him to Luray,
                    as that would leave exposed the whole of the country east of the Blue Ridge. I
                    will make inquiries about signal men, and endeavor to establish a line so far as
                    our means will permit. I have heard, however, that one of our signal officers
                    was captured in Loudoun.</p>
                <p>Col. Corley has gone this morning to Staunton to see about blankets and shoes. I
                    hope he will be able to give you a supply. You must keep me advised of your
                    position and of the movements of the enemy against you. I request that will have
                    your divisions as much united as possible, so that you may fall upon any one of
                    the enemy's columns which may expose itself should the opportunity occur to
                    crush it, and that you will endeavor to lead the enemy forward for the purpose.</p>
                <p>You did right in sending the shoemakers to Staunton, and I hope that you placed
                    Col. Davidson on his guard, lest they should turn traitors.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed> R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
