<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928631"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928631">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928631</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498732</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 630-631</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-09-27">1862-09-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928631T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports to Thomas J. Jackson on September, 1862,
                    operations in western Virginia. Imboden reports capturing bandit Captain Bond,
                    some of his gang, and other horse thieves and sending them to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"> Brig. Gen. THOMAS J. JACKSON:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-09-27">September 27, 1862. (Received October 2, 1862.)</date>
                        <name type="place">CAMP LEE, HARDY COUNTY, W. VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was much gratified at the receipt of yours of the 23d, by Mr. Neall, as it once
                    more brigs me in direct communication with you. Your wishes as to Mr. Neall
                    shall be fully carried out.</p>
                <p>My last letter to you from Cheat Mountain advised you of my almost successful
                    attempt to destroy the Cheat River Bridge, which was frustrated by a Union woman
                    riding 25 miles through the woods to alarm the enemy, and give Gen. Kelley time
                    to throw a force of five times my own in my front at Cheat River Bridge. I also
                    informed you of my co-operation with Gen. Jenkins, enabling him to get in the
                    rear of Kelley, and make his brilliant north west dash without pursuit. I then
                    came back from Randolph, through Pocahontas into Highland, where I was joined by
                    several hundred recruits. I then set out with upward of 400 men to capture
                    Romney. I crossed the Shenandoah Mountain at Brock's Gap, and came down Lost
                    River very secretly, and made a night march on Romney, getting within 5 miles
                    before midnight, when I ascertained the enemy had evacuated the place that
                    evening. Unfortunately, 3 soldiers from Winchester, escorting some ladies under
                    a flag of truce, got to Romney the day before. They were wild young fellows, and
                    talked so confidently that Romney would be taken in a day or two, that the
                    commanding officer took fright, telegraphed Gen. Kelly for permission to fall
                    back to the railroad, got it, and left about twelve hours too soon for me. I
                    occupied the place two days, scouted toward the railroad, drew a party of the
                    enemy to Romney by moving out with my whole command 2 miles, as if in retreat,
                    in the night. I ambushed the road below town, and, as I expected, their cavalry
                    came along. We unhorsed 15 of the rascals, wounding several, captured 2 unhurt,
                    8 good fatally, several horses that we did not take away. The next day the
                    commanding officer at Spring River sent a flag of truce to get his wounded and
                    dead. As the skirmish occurred just at dark, and near the woods, they carried
                    off their dead, if any were killed. They reported their lieutenant dead.</p>
                <p>I have about 900 men; only about 600 are armed. As all my wagons and stores were
                    in Highland, I sent for them and moved up the river last week to this point. I
                    have kept Kelley running up and down the railroad with troops for ten days. He
                    has about 2,500 men in all from New Creek to Green Spring. He can move the whole
                    body by rail, and is at Cumberland one day and New Creek the next. He has his
                    headquarters in a car. I have been able to get direct intelligence from him
                    almost every day by means of citizen spies. My object, until all my men are
                    armed, has been to keep the enemy out of this part of the country. I have thus
                    far been successful. There has not been a raid of any kind since I came here. I
                    have tried to restore confidence among our people.</p>
                <p>We have sent off Capt. Bond, the bandit leader of this county, and some four or
                    five of his gang, to Staunton, having been fortunate enough to "bag" them. Most
                    of these desperadoes will be captured, killed or driven off by us. In Pendleton
                    and the eastern aport of Randolph I have restored order in the community; have
                    broken up horse-thieving and plundering by arresting those engaged in it, and
                    sending them to Staunton. One was killed who refused to surrender. He was a
                    deserter from our army, had joined the Yankees, deserted them, and turned
                    here-thief and robber. His name was Mallow, a great scoundrel.</p>
                <p>Gen., I will get down my wagons to-day from Highland. I will at once move down
                    east of Romney and attempt the destruction of the bridge over Little Cacapon
                    River early next week. I will send my cavalry to Romney to threaten the road
                    higher up. If you could send a brigade to Romney, we could take New Creek and
                    Cumberland, beyond a doubt, in a few days, and demolish all their works and the
                    railroad. I am not strong enough to do so myself. The Secretary of War has
                    limited me to ten companies. I have six infantry and four mounted companies,
                    numbering in the aggregate over 900 men-first-rate men. I have had to reject two
                    fine companies within a week because of this restriction. One of them has gone
                    to Floyd, the other left to go to Winchester, and try to get in the cavalry
                    there.</p>
                <p>I am afraid my agreement last June with Dr. Miller, of Lexington, was
                    unfortunate. I don't know of a single company yet raised by him. He is a
                    stranger to the people of the west, and has not been as successful as he
                    expected. This is to be regretted. If my powers had been sufficiently ample, I
                    could probably have had 2,000 men by this time. I shall have to reject another
                    company in a day or two, now on its way to join me, as I learned last night. A
                    very handsome force, say, 3,000 or 4,000 men, can be raised in these mountain
                    counties, if the Government will give the command to some one well known in the
                    west. With my command as a nucleus, and authority to enlist everybody,
                    conscripts, deserters, and all, three regiments can be raised before winter. If
                    the Twenty-fifth and Thirty-first could be sent here I am perfectly certain
                    their ranks can be filled before December 1-800 or 900 men each-provided they
                    are to serve in the west. I wish the Government could be impressed with proper
                    views in regard to the people and their circumstances out here. These mountains
                    swarm with men, and good men, who will do good service if properly managed.</p>
                <p>If possible, I will try and see you one night next week on this very important
                    subject. The new of your glorious achievements has reanimated the whole country
                    here.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most truly, yours,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
