<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11927484"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R11927484">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
        <author>Crawford, Samuel W.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">16</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11927484</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498688</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
            <author>Crawford, Samuel W.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 27</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 484-486</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-21">1862-10-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11927484T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Samuel Crawford writes from Chambersburg in October, 1862, to
                    General Alpheus Williams. Crawford reports on the role his men played in the
                    battle of Antietam, and the wound he sustained there.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 167. Report of Brig. Gen. Samuel W. Crawford, U. S. Army, commanding
                    First Division, of the battle of Antietam.
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. ALPHEUS S. WILLIAMS,<lb/> Comdg. Twelfth Corps,
                        Army of the Potomac.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-21">October 21, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">CHAMBERSBURG, PA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The condition of my health, consequent upon the wound I received at the battle of
                    Antietam on the 17th of September last, has prevented the transmission of an
                    earlier report of the part taken my command in that action. Upon the assigned of
                    Gen. Mansfield to the command of the corps (Twelfth), on the 14th of September,
                    I resumed the command of the First Brigade, of your division (First). My command
                    consisted of the following regiments: Forty-sixth Pennsylvania, Col. J. F.
                    Knipe; Tenth Maine, Col. G. L. Beal; Fifth ;Connecticut, Capt. H. W. Daboll;
                    Twenty-eighty New York, Capt. W. H. H. Mapes commanding; One hundred and
                    twenty-fourth Pennsylvania, Col. J. W. Hawley commanding; One hundred and
                    twenty-fifth Pennsylvania, Col. J. Higgins; One hundred and twenty-eighth
                    Pennsylvania, Col. S. Croasdale. The last three mentioned regiments were new
                    organizations from the nine months' levy, and had seen no field service
                    whatever. The Fifth Connecticut was not in action.</p>
                <p>On the night of September, while lying massed with the army on the Antietam,
                    orders were received to proceed by the Hagerstown and Sharpsburg road toward the
                    position occupied by the corps of Maj.-Gen. Hooker, which had been engaged with
                    the enemy. My brigade led the march of the corps, when, leaving the main road,
                    before daylight we took up a position on Poeffenberger's farm, to the rear and
                    left of Gen. Hooker's force. At early dawn on the 17th my command was moved
                    forward in column of companies still leading the corps. Passing through strips
                    of woods, and open ground and cornfields, we were suddenly halted, and a
                    deployment ordered without delay. While in the act of executing the order I
                    received orders from Gen. Mansfield, in person, to suspend the deployment and
                    again to mass my command, the command was then exposed to an artillery fire. A
                    third to again deploy was brought to me by one of officers of the division
                    staff, and I at once deployed, my command being on the right of the line, which
                    rested on a turnpike, and moved forward thought the woods, and open space,
                    driving before us a thin line of the enemy's skirmishers. The new regiments from
                    Pennsylvania (One hundred and twenty-fourth, One hundred and twenty-fifth, and
                    One hundred and twenty-eighth) moved with great promptness and with the coolness
                    of old troops, although they had not before been under fire. During this
                    movement the One hundred and twenty-fourth Pennsylvania, Col. Hawley, was
                    detached from my brigade by some superior order unknown to me, and sent advance
                    through the woods on our right to Miller's farm, to hold that position.</p>
                <p>The struggle for the skirt of the woods to which the enemy clung, and the open
                    space and corn-fields opposite and along the turnpike on the right, was long and
                    determined. Finally the enemy was driven out of the woods across the fields, and
                    into the opposite woods beyond the rocky ridges, to his supports. There he
                    rallied, and bringing up fresh troops, our lines were exposed not only to a
                    severe fire of his infantry, but also to an effective fire of his artillery on
                    our right. While engaged in the struggle for the corn-field, Col. Croasdale, of
                    the One hundred and twenty-eighth Pennsylvania, was killed, and
                    Lieut.-Col.Hammersley, of the same regiment, severely wounded. The One hundred
                    and twenty-fifth Pennsylvania, Col. Higgins, in the general movement had pushed
                    on into the woods beyond our lines, and had become seriously engaged with the
                    enemy while much exposed, but returned in good order with great loss to our
                    lines.</p>
                <p>Shortly before our movement, Maj.-Gen. Hooker had come to examine my position,
                    and I received orders from him to hold the woods (Miller's) at all hazards, as
                    otherwise the right of the army would be seriously imperiled. Gen. Mansfield,
                    the corps commander, had been mortally wounded, and was borne past my position
                    to the rear. Shortly afterward I received an order from a staff officer of
                    Brig.-Gen. Williams to assume command of the First Division, he having assumed
                    command of the corps. Sending orders to Col. Knipe, of the Forty-sixth
                    Pennsylvania, the senior colonel of my brigade, to assume command at once of the
                    brigade, I rode forward to find the Third Brigade (Gordon's) which had moved
                    into action on the center of our line, and had been gallantly pushing the enemy
                    before it. Our line had driven the enemy from Miller woods across the
                    wheat-fields into the woods beyond the Dunkard Church and Hagerstown road. A
                    line wooden fence which skirted the road had proved a very serious obstacle to
                    our farther advance. The regiments of the Third Brigade had become separated. In
                    the absence of the brigade commander, I ordered Lieut.-Col. Andrews, commanding
                    the Second Massachusetts, to maintain his position until the line could be
                    formed.</p>
                <p>It was nearly 9 o'clock. The enemy had brought up his reserves, and was
                    contesting the possession of the woods around the Dunkard Church and the
                    Hagerstown road, when Maj.-Gen. Sumner arrived on the field with his corps.
                    Immediately the division of Gen. Sedgwick was deployed, and I received orders to
                    withdraw the troops of my division to the woods held in the morning, to rest my
                    troops and replenish their exhausted ammunition. Meantime Sedgwick's division
                    moved forward promptly upon the enemy's position, but, unable to dislodge the
                    enemy gave way under the attack and were falling back, when I received orders
                    from Brig.-Gen. Williams to move forward all my available troops to the support
                    of our troops under Sedgwick. The Third Brigade had received direct orders from
                    the corps commander, and had moved gallantly forward, but under the severe fire
                    had been compelled to fall back. While endeavoring to rally part of this
                    command, I received a gunshot wound in the right thigh, but I did not at the
                    time consider it sufficiently severe to leave my command, and I remained until
                    night.</p>
                <p>Our whole line now retired to the position occupied in the morning and my
                    exhausted command held the woods known as the "Miller woods," the Third Brigade
                    in the rear and left. A section of a battery under Lieut. Thomas, and also
                    Knap's Pennsylvania battery, were stationed at the point of these woods upon a
                    road running across toward the Dunkard Church. The enemy continued his fire upon
                    the woods, and at noon advanced his infantry to take possession of them. Being
                    present with the batteries mentioned, I assumed the control, and sent back a
                    staff officer (Capt. d'Hauteville) to hasten to their support any infantry he
                    might find. Maj. Gen. Franklin arriving with his corps, I indicated to him the
                    position and movement of the enemy, when, by the prompt movement of Maj.-Gen.
                    Smith's command, and the effective fire of the batteries the enemy was repulsed
                    and driven back to his lines, and made no further attempt on the right of our
                    line. In obedience to the orders of the corps commander I directed Brig. Gen.
                    Gordon, commanding Third Brigade, to proceed with his command to the support of
                    Maj.-Gen. Franklin.</p>
                <p>It was now night; the action had ceased; when, exhausted from the loss of blood
                    and the state of my wound, I reported to the general commanding the corps, and
                    left the field. The regiments composing my command did the duty nobly, but it is
                    my duty to call the special attention of the corps commander to the bearing and
                    conduct of the new regiments that had so recently joined the command. Their
                    service in the field were most valuable, and, considering the fact that they
                    were for the first time under fire, their conduct merits the warmest
                    commendation. In my absence the subordinate reports will be made to me
                    successor, and officers and men who have distinguished themselves will be
                    specified, doubtless, by their commanding officers. Brig.-Gen. Gordon,
                    commanding Third Brigade, was active and efficient during the whole day, and his
                    brigade rendered important service. Col. Knipe, of the Forty-sixth Pennsylvania,
                    who commanded my brigade after I had assumed command of the division, will
                    undoubtedly report to you the services of the First Brigade after I left it. Of
                    my staff officers, I desire to mention Capt. Frederick d'Hauteville, my
                    assistant adjutant-general, who was indefatigable in rendering me the most
                    important services on the field; also to Capt. Livingston, aide de-camp; to
                    Lieut. Witman, aide-de-camp, who conveyed my orders most intelligently, and
                    often under circumstances of great personal exposure, from first to last. Our
                    casualties were 1,076 killed, wounded, and missing.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>S. W. CRAWFORD,<lb/> Brig. Gen. U. S. V., late Comdg. 1st Div., 12th
                        Corps, Army of Va.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
