<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928552"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928552">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
        <author>Burnside, Ambrose E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">16</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928552</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498725</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
            <author>Burnside, Ambrose E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 552-554</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-07">1862-11-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928552T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In November, 1862, General Ambrose E. Burnside replaced George B. McClellan as
                    commander of the Army of the Potomac. In this dispatch, he outlines plans for an
                    attack on Fredericksburg. He discusses the need to avoid a Confederate retreat
                    to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF THE POTOMAC.
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. G. W. CULLUM,<lb/> Chief of Staff, Washington, D.
                        C.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-07">November 7, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Warrenton, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In accordance with the order of the Gen.-in-Chief of the 5th instant, I have the
                    honor to make the following report of the movements proposed for this army:</p>
                <p>To concentrate all the forces near this place, and impress upon the enemy a
                    belief that we are to attack Culpeper or Gordonsville, and at the same time
                    accumulate a four or five days' supply for the men and animals; then make a
                    rapid move of the whole force to Fredericksburg, with a view to a movement upon
                    Richmond from that point. The following are my reasons for deciding upon this
                    plan:</p>
                <p>If we move upon Culpeper and Gordonsville, a fight there and a general
                    engagement, even with results in our favor, the enemy will have many lines of
                    retreat for his defeated army, and will, in all likelihood, be able to reach
                    Richmond with enough of his force to render it necessary to fight another battle
                    at that place; and should he leave even one corps, with cavalry, on our right
                    flank, it would render the pursuit very precarious, owing to the great lack of
                    supplies in this country, and the liability to an interruption of our
                    communication with Washington. Should the enemy retreat in the direction of
                    Richmond upon our approach to Culpeper and Gordonsville, we would simply follow
                    a retreating army, well supplied with provisions at least, at depots in his
                    rear, whilst this army would have to rely upon a long line of communication for
                    its supplies, and, as in the other case, a small portion of the enemy's force on
                    our flank might tend to interrupt our communications. It may be well to add
                    here, while on the subject of interrupted communication, that the enemy's
                    sources for gaining information are far superior to our own. The Gen.-in-Chief
                    will readily understand the reason. The difference is more than usual in their
                    favor at present, from the fact that nearly all the negroes are being run south
                    and kept under strict guard.</p>
                <p>Should the enemy retreat before us in the direction of Staunton and Lynchburg,
                    the same difficulty would follow, with the certainty that he would also have a
                    small portion of his force on our left flank. In moving by way of Fredericksburg
                    there is no point up to the time when we should reach that place at which we
                    will not be nearer to Washington than the enemy, and we will all the time be on
                    the shortest route to Richmond, the taking of which, I think, should be the
                    great object of the campaign, as the fall of that place would tend more to
                    cripple the rebel cause than almost any other military event, except the
                    absolute breaking up of their army. The presence of a large army on the
                    Fredericksburg line would render it almost impossible for the enemy to make a
                    successful move upon Washington by any road on this side of the Potomac, and I
                    take it that there are forces enough at Washington and on the line of the
                    Potomac, connected with the fortifications about Washington, to repulse any
                    movement of the enemy on the capital, by way of the Upper Potomac; and it is
                    hardly probable that he would attempt any serious invasion of Pennsylvania at
                    this season of the year, and even if he should make a lodgment in that State of
                    any force that he can spare, the destruction of that force would be the result
                    very soon after winter set in, and the destruction of property by him would be
                    small in comparison with the other expenses of the war. Could the army before
                    Richmond be beaten,and their capital taken, the loss of a half a dozen of our
                    towns and cities in the interior of Pennsylvania could well be afforded. A
                    movement of the enemy upon Baltimore I consider altogether improbable, as an
                    attack on that place would render the destruction of the city certain.</p>
                <p>In connection with this movement in the direction of Fredericksburg, I would
                    suggest that at least thirty canal-boats and barges be at once loaded with
                    commissary stores and forage, and be towed to the neighborhood of Aquia Creek,
                    from which place they can be brought into Belle Plain after the arrival of our
                    force in that vicinity. These should be followed at once by enough stores and
                    forage to subsist the army for thirty days. A great portion of this, I think,
                    could be towed up the Rappahannock, under convoy of light-draught gunboats; but
                    that is a matter for after-consideration.</p>
                <p>It will also be necessary to start at once from Washington or Alexandria by way
                    of Dumfries a quantity of beef cattle and all the wagon-trains that can be
                    spared, filled with small rations, such as bread, salt, coffee, sugar, soap, and
                    candles. This train should be preceded by pontoon trains enough to span the
                    Rappahannock with two tracks; but a small escort of cavalry for this train would
                    be necessary as we would be all the time between the enemy and the train. I
                    will, however, if notified of its departure by telegraph, see that it is
                    protected by my cavalry. During these movements it would be well for Gen. Sigel
                    to remain with his force at Centreville and its neighborhood, holding Manassas
                    Junction, Thoroughfare Gap, Aldie, and Leesburg with forces sufficient to
                    protect them against any light attack, any one of which can fall back on the
                    main body if attacked by too large a force. The main portion of his cavalry can
                    be kept in Loudoun County, where there is an abundance of subsistence and
                    forage. Below Fredericksburg, between the Rappahannock and the Potomac, there
                    must be quite an amount of forage, which could be used for our broken-down
                    animals after we reach Fredericksburg. We will need some fresh horses and mules
                    on our arrival, which can be driven direct from Washington on this side of the
                    Potomac, or from Baltimore direct to Smith's Point, opposite Aquia Creek, from
                    which place they can be brought over in ferry-boats, several of which it would
                    be advisable to send to us. An abundance of horses can also be brought by
                    light-draught vessels from New York and Philadelphia to a point near Belle
                    Plain, where they can be thrown overboard and swim ashore. I cannot impress too
                    strongly upon the Gen.-in-Chief the necessity of furnishing by all these means
                    an abundant supply of horses and mules and beef cattle. These should be sent to
                    Fredericksburg, even at the risk of arriving after we leave.</p>
                <p>After reaching Fredericksburg, our wagon-trains can be organized and filled with
                    at least twelve days' provisions; when a rapid movement can be made direct upon
                    Richmond, by way of such roads as are open to us, and as soon as the army
                    arrives in front of the place an attack should be made at once, with a strong
                    hope of success. The detail of the movement from Fredericksburg I will give you
                    hereafter. A great reason for feeling that the Fredericksburg route is the best,
                    is that if we are detained by the elements, it would be much better for us to be
                    on that route. I hope the Gen.-in-Chief will impress upon the Secretary of War
                    the necessity for sanctioning the changes which I now propose to make in this
                    army:</p>
                <p>1st. To divide it into three parts-right wing, left wing, and center-under
                    command of the three ranking generals present.</p>
                <p>2d. To do away with the very massive and elaborate adjutant-general's office at
                    these headquarters, and require the different commanders of these wings and
                    corps to correspond directly with Washington in reference to all such things as
                    resignations, leaves of absence, discharges, recruiting service, &amp;c.,
                    about which they necessarily know more than I do. I would have to be governed by
                    their suggestions at any rate, and the attention to these matters in detail
                    would surround me with a large number of additional staff officials, and
                    embarrass me with a responsibility which I cannot assume.</p>
                <p>3d. To make Gen. Seth Williams an inspector of the different staff departments of
                    the command, by which means I will ascertain if these duties are properly
                    performed by the persons to whom they are delegated.</p>
                <p>4th. To keep my own adjutant-general, Lieut. Col. L. Richmond, at my
                    headquarters, and to use as far as possible my own staff officers, with
                    promotions necessary to their positions. I shall make as few changes as
                    possible; but I am very anxious to keep my staff as small as may be, and to
                    throw the labor and detail upon the officers immediately in command of the
                    troops.</p>
                <p>With an approval of these suggestions, I will endeavor with all my ability to
                    bring this campaign to a successful issue. If they are not approved, I hope
                    specific instructions will be given, and the Gen.-in-Chief may rely upon a
                    cheerful and implicit obedience. The Gen.-in-Chief will readily comprehend the
                    embarrassments which surround me in taking command of this army, at this place,
                    and at this season of the year. Had I been asked to take it, I should have
                    declined; but being ordered, I cheerfully obey.</p>
                <p>A telegram from you, approving of my plans, will put us to work at once.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>A. E. BURNSIDE.<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg. Army of the Potomac.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
