<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1192829"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R1192829">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
        <author>Wool, John E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1192829</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498704</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
            <author>Wool, John E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 29</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-14">1862-10-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1192829T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General John Wool reports to General-in-Chief Henry Halleck on movements of
                    Confederate Cavalry in Maryland and Pennsylvania during the fall of 1862. Wool
                    mentions the occupation of Chambersburg by Jeb Stuart's Confederates where they
                    allegedly captured Union uniforms and destroyed the railroad depot and other
                    property.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 1. Report of Maj. Gen. John E. Wool, U. S. Army, commanding the Middle
                    Department. HDQRS. EIGHTH ARMY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. H. W. HALLECK,<lb/> Gen.-in-Chief.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-14">October 14, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Baltimore, Md.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>On Friday evening I received (about 10 o'clock) information, by telegraph from
                    Governor Curtin, of Pennsylvania, that the 3,000 rebel cavalry and a section of
                    artillery, under the command of Gen. Stuart, were in possession of Chambersburg.
                    It appears that the town had been surrendered upon the demand of the rebel
                    general. I immediately ordered three regiments and a battery of six pieces to be
                    got ready and proceed at once to Harrisburg; afterward I ordered a fourth
                    regiment.</p>
                <p>The next morning, at 6 o'clock, and as soon as I could obtain a special train. I
                    proceeded to Harrisburg, were I arrived early in the day, and visited Governor
                    Curtin. He appeared quite anxious about the safety of Carlisle. Although I did
                    not agree with him on the subject, yet I proceeded to that place. On the way I
                    received a telegram, informing me that the rebels had gone to Emmittsburg. I
                    returned immediately to Harrisburg and saw Governor Curtin, who had received the
                    same information. I at once proceeded to Hanover Junction, where I arrived about
                    4 a. m., and where I met my troops ordered from Baltimore. These I immediately
                    set in motion for Gettysburg, where they arrived about 1 p. m., and headed off
                    the rebel cavalry, previous to which the advance of the rebels had been attacked
                    by some of the Home Guards, when they retreated, leaving, 5 prisoners in the
                    possession of the Home Guards.</p>
                <p>The rebels went to Emmittsburg, and from there to Waynesborough, and were
                    proceeding toward Boonsborough, when, on being informed of the advance of
                    Pleasonton, they changed their course and proceeded with all haste to the
                    Potomac, in a more easterly direction, and, as I was informed, by telegraph from
                    Maj.-Gen. McClellan, in the following language, viz:</p>
                <p>Gen. Pleasonton, who was in pursuit of the rebel cavalry, reports that they have
                    been driven back, into Virginia, crossing the Potomac near the mouth of the
                    Monacacy, and having marched 90 miles in the previous twenty-four hours, while
                    Pleasonton, in pursuit, marched 78 miles in the same time.</p>
                <p>Col. Cram, under whose direction I placed the troops at Gettysburg, reported to
                    me on Sunday that the rebels had retired to Harbach's Valley.</p>
                <p>On Monday, 2.30 p. m., he reported, by telegram, that a part of the rebels he
                    thought, from information received, were yet in Harbach's Valley. He sent scouts
                    to ascertain, who were to report to him last night or this morning. I think the
                    colonel will find that all the rebel cavalry have returned into Virginia, and
                    have probably escaped altogether the vigilance of Maj.-Gen. McClellan, having,
                    in the mean time, made nearly the whole circle of the army of the
                    Potomac-certainly a bold and daring enterprise, in the execution of which the
                    soldiers at Chambersburg changed the rags which covered them for the uniform
                    clothing of the United States, and supplied themselves on their route with 1,000
                    fresh horses, besides destroying, at Chambersburg, the railroad depot, with all
                    the rolling-stock. They also tore up some of the rails of the road, and
                    destroyed several bridges.</p>
                <p>Myself and staff were in motion from Friday evening until yesterday afternoon at
                    2 o'clock when we returned to Baltimore. During that time we had no rest or
                    sleep, except what little could be taken in the cars.</p>
                <p>From want of cavalry, we could not follow the enemy, as he, from reports made to
                    me, kept continually on the trot, and sometimes even galloped his horses.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JOHN E. WOOL,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
