<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928700"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928700">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R11928700</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498758</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and Confederate
       Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 699-700</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-07">1862-11-07</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="R11928700T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>During the Civil War, the Confederate government had to resort to price fixing and
     confiscation to ease the army's increasingly large supply problem. In this November, 1862,
     letter, General Robert E. Lee writes Secretary of War Randolph concerning procurement of wheat
     in the Shenandoah Valley. He discusses milling, price fixing, and the reportedly higher prices
     charged at Staunton.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
     <name type="recipient">Hon. GEORGE W. RANDOLPH,<lb/> Secretary of War, Richmond, Va.:</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-07">November 7, 1862.</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>SIR:</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>In answer to your dispatch of the 6th instant, in reference to the seizure of flour in
     Rockingham County, I think there must be some misapprehension on the part of the Hon. John B.
     Baldwin as to the facts. I think it, therefore, proper to report to the Department that upon
     the arrival of the army in the Shenandoah Valley, below Winchester, the mills in that section
     of the country that had previously been in a great measure idle, were set to work to supply it
     with flour. After consultation with millers and farmers, the chief commissary placed the price
     of wheat at $1.50 per bushel, making that of flour $8 per barrel. This, I believe, gave entire
     satisfaction at the time, and was considered a fair price, and furnished the only market to the
     farmers for the sale of their wheat, as it was impossible for them to convey it out of the
     valley, for want of teams and laborers that had been by the enemy. The mills above Winchester
     were set to work upon the same terms, and supplies of flour were accumulated in the vicinity of
     Woodstock and Harrisonburg in the event of operations higher up the valley. You must understand
     that the above price was paid at the mills or points where the flour was received, without any
     expense to the proprietors, except in the cases where bags or barrels were furnished by the
     Government, when 40 cents per barrel was deducted. No flour necessary for private consumption
     was taken, and, in many cases, when convenient, wheat was hauled to the mills by the wagons of
     the army, and in some instances was thrashed from the straw. I heard of no dissatisfaction
     until recently, when a higher price was paid for flour at Staunton by some of the agents of the
     Commissary Department not attached to this army. Maj. A. H. Johnston, commissary of
     subsistence, was sent to Harrisonburg to secure the flour in that vicinity for the army. Maj.
     Johnston has dealt with only ten mills in Rockingham, being about two-thirds of the number of
     mills in that county. In only one case that has been reported to me has he been obliged to
     resort to compulsion, and that was at the mill of Mr. Josiah Rollins, on North River, near
     Mount Crawford, where he placed a guard upon receiving information that speculators were
     removing the flour from the mill at from $10 to $12 per barrel, the object of the guard being
     to prevent the flour being carried beyond the reach of the Commissary Department. Harrisborough
     is 20 miles below Staunton, to which point the flour will have to be transported in wagons for
     shipment by railroad. If you prefer to supply the army with flour from Richmond, I will direct
     the chief commissary of the army to cease purchasing it, or to pay for it whatever price you
     may designate. The army must be subsisted, and if millers or owners will not sell their flour
     at a fixed rate, we are obliged to take it. The question will be whether they will take a fair
     price for their flour, or leave it to be seized by the enemy after the army is withdrawn.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute/>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,<signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Indorsement.<lb/> NOVEMBER 11, 1862.<lb/> Inclose copy to Hon. J. B.
      Baldwin. Staunton, and refer to Commissary-Gen. for opinion on the question propounded by Gen.
      Lee.<lb/> G. W. RANDOLPH,<lb/> Secretary of War.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
