<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1192851"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R1192851">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1192851</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498721</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 51</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-14">1862-10-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1192851T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee reports to Secretary of War George Randolph on the results of Jeb
                    Stuart's October, 1862, raid into Pennsylvania and Maryland and ride around the
                    Union army. Lee mentions the capture of Chambersburg along with supplies, and
                    the destruction of some infrastructure.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 16. Report of Gen. Robert E. Lee, C. S. Army, commanding Army of
                    Northern Virginia.
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. GEORGE W. RANDOLPH,<lb/> Secretary of War, Richmond,
                        Va</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-14">October 14, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The expedition, under Gen. Stuart, to Pennsylvania, which crossed the Potomac on
                    the evening of the 9th instant at McCoy's Ford, above Williamsport, will reach
                    their camp to-day. They proceed through Mercersburg to Chambersburg, where they
                    obtained from the United States store-houses such supplies as needed, but were
                    unable to destroy the railroad bridge over the Conococheague in consequence of
                    it being of iron. The shops, &amp;c., of company were, however, destroyed.
                    Thence he proceeded to Emmittsburg, through Liberty, New Market, Hyattstown,
                    Barnesville, to White's Ford, below the mouth of the Monocacy, making a complete
                    circuit of the enemy's position. On approaching the Potomac he was opposed by
                    the enemy's cavalry, under Gen. Stoneman, but drove them back, and put to flight
                    the infantry stationed on the bluff at White's Ford to guard the passage.</p>
                <p>His expedition was eminently successful, and accomplished without other loss than
                    the wounding of 1 man. He obtained many remounts for his cavalry, and deserves
                    much credit for his prudence and enterprise.</p>
                <p>From the information he was able to obtain, I am inclined to believe that Gen.
                    McClellan has detached no part of his army eastward, but, on the contrary, has
                    been receiving re-enforcements. His main army is posted west of the Blue Ridge
                    range, and stretches from Hagerstown to Rockville, the center resting at
                    Harper's Ferry, with detachments guarding the river. They have a large force
                    repairing the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, and I should judge from all I can learn
                    that the operation of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad from Harper's Ferry west
                    is viewed by them as an object of great importance, and that efforts will be
                    made to repair it. I am breaking up the Harper's Ferry and Winchester Railroad
                    to increase the obstacles to their advance up the Shenandoah Valley. The iron
                    would be very useful to the roads farther south, and the flat iron might be used
                    for Government purposes, but I have no means of sending it away.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--I send you a copy of a Harrisburg and Baltimore
                        paper, which may interest you. The former is of that class which the enemy
                        do not permit to come within their lines.<lb/> R. E. L.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
