<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928653"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928653">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Special Orders Number 209.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi special orders number 209</title>
        <author>Chilton, Robert H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928653</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498738</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Special Orders Number 209.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi special orders number 209</title>
            <author>Chilton, Robert H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 652-654</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-04">1862-10-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928653T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>These October, 1862, orders approved by Robert E. Lee, and issued by Robert
                    Chilton, concern reorganization of Confederate Artillery. Among other things,
                    guns are ordered to Staunton, VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    SPECIAL ORDERS, No. 209. HDQRS. ARMY OF THE NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-04">October 4, 1862.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I. The necessity of the service requires an immediate reorganization of the
                    artillery of this army. The combination of the companies hereafter named is to
                    be considered temporary and subject to the order of the Secretary of War. Their
                    selection has been made entirely with a view of the efficiency of the artillery,
                    and implies no blame or degradation to the batteries thus combined. Many of the
                    batteries have served with distinction, and their enfeebled condition is
                    attributable to the dangers and hardships they have encountered. Whenever
                    circumstances will permit, the batteries will again be restored.</p>
                <p>II. Col. Walton, of the Louisiana Washington Artillery, will retain one section
                    of Capt. Miller's battery, with the best guns and horses of that company, and
                    turn over the rejected guns, horses, &amp;c., to the proper departments. The
                    me of Capt. Leake's battery and those of Capt. Anderson's are relieved from duty
                    with the Louisiana Washington Artillery, and will be at once returned to their
                    proper companies.</p>
                <p>III. The ten companies of the First Regt. Virginia Artillery, Col. Brown, will be
                    formed into six. The officers of the batteries of Capt.'s Wyatt, Coke, and
                    Ritter--except First Lieut. Thurmond, of Wyatt's; First Lieut. Robertson, of
                    Ritter's; First Lieut. Pendleton and Second Lieut. Hawes, of Coke's
                    batteries--are relived from duty with their companies, and the men of those
                    batteries will be distributed by Col. Brown among the retained companies. Capt.
                    Young's company, originally belonging to the infantry, will be returned to that
                    arm of the service if it is preferred. Should they wish to continue in the
                    artillery, the officers will be relieved from duty and the men distributed by
                    Col. Brown among the retained companies of his regiment.</p>
                <p>IV. The four companies of Maj. Jones' battalion will be formed into two. The
                    officers of Capt.'s Wimbish's and Turner's batteries are relieved from duty with
                    their companies, and the men will be distributed by Maj. Jones among the
                    retained companies. Capt. Peyton is relieved from duty with his company, and
                    First Lieut. Fry will assume command of it. Lieut. W. A. Deas is assigned to
                    duty as first lieutenant; Acting Lieut. Massie is assigned as junior first
                    lieutenant, and Lieut. Hawas is assigned as second lieutenant, of said battery.
                    First Lieut. John L. Grubbs, of Capt. Page's battery, is also relieved from duty
                    with his company.</p>
                <p>V. The four companies constituting Lieut.-Col. Cutt's battalion will be formed
                    into three. The officers of Capt. Blackshear's battery are relieved from duty
                    with the company, and the men will be distributed as follows: Twenty-two of
                    Capt. Ross, 29 to Capt. Lane, and the remainder to Capt. Patterson.</p>
                <p>VI. The four companies of Maj. Nelson's battalion will be formed into three. The
                    officers of Capt. Ancell's battery are relieved from duty with the company, and
                    the men will be assigned to the two other Virginia companies in suitable
                    proportions, as Maj. Nelson may direct. Capt. Huckstep and Second Lieut. Poats
                    are relieved from duty with their company, and First. Lieut. [John] Livingston
                    Massie is assigned to its command. Lieut. Ancell is retained as first lieutenant
                    of this battery. First Lieut. Maddox, heretofore attached to Capt. Blackshear's
                    battery, is attacked, with his section, to Capt. Milledge's battery. Lieut.
                    Maddox will be the senior first lieutenant of the battery, Lieut. Rogers the
                    junior first lieutenant, and Acting Lieut. Falligant, of Lieut.-Col. Cutts'
                    battalion, is transferred to Milledge's battery as senior second lieutenant.</p>
                <p>VII. The three companies of Maj. Saunders' battalion will be formed into two. The
                    officers of Thompson's battery (late Grimes') are relieved from duty with the
                    company, and the men will be distributed by Maj. Saunders between Moorman's and
                    Huger's batteries.</p>
                <p>VIII. The officers of Capt. Lloyd's battery are relieved from duty with the
                    company, and 55 of the men will be assigned to Capt. Manly's battery, Gen.
                    McLaws' division, and the remainder to Capt. Reily, of Gen. Hood's division.</p>
                <p>IX. The officers of Capt. Chapman's battery, of Gen. Featherston's brigade, are
                    relieved from duty with their company. The men and horses will be assigned to
                    Capt. Pegram's battery.</p>
                <p>X. The officers of Capt. Brown's battery, Wise Artillery, are relieved from duty,
                    and the men and horses are assigned to Col. S. D. Lee's battalion.</p>
                <p>XI. The officers of Capt. G. Washington Nelson's battery are relieved from duty
                    with their company; 20 of his men will be assigned to Capt. Kirkpatrick's
                    company, Maj. Nelson's battalion, and 40 to Capt. Woolfolk's battery, Col. S. D.
                    Lee's battalion.</p>
                <p>XII. The officers of Capt. John R. Johnson's battery are relieved from duty with
                    the company, and the men will be equally divided between Capt. Dearing's and
                    Capt. Stribling's companies.</p>
                <p>XIII. The officers of Capt. Rogers' battery, Loudoun Artillery, are relieved from
                    duty with the company. The men and horses will be assigned to Capt. Stribling's
                    battery.</p>
                <p>XIV. The officers of Capt. Anderson's battery, Thomas Artillery, except the two
                    senior lieutenants, are relieved from duty with the company.The men and horses
                    and the two senior lieutenants are assigned to Capt. Caskie's battery.</p>
                <p>XV. The officers of Capt. Leake's battery are relieved from duty with the
                    company. The men and horses are assigned to Capt. Thomas H. Carter's battery.</p>
                <p>XVI. The officers of Capt. Thomas Jefferson Page's [jr.] battery are relieved
                    from duty with the company. The men and horses will be distributed among the
                    Virginia companies under Col. S. D. Lee, to whom Capt. Page and Lieut. Magruder
                    will report for duty.</p>
                <p>XVII. The officers of Capt. Fleet's battery, Middlesex Artillery, are relieved
                    from duty with the company. The men heretofore temporarily assigned will remain
                    with the batteries where they are now serving. The remainder of the men will be
                    assigned to Capt. M. Johnson's battery.</p>
                <p>XVIII. To insure the speedy and proper reorganization of the artillery as
                    ordered, the chief of artillery will direct Col.'s Brown and S. D. Lee to assist
                    him in the execution of this orders, and will assign to such companies as may
                    not have their complement of officers such of those hereby relieved from duty as
                    he may deem necessary.</p>
                <p>XIX. In every case the best guns, horses, and equipments will be selected for the
                    batteries retained in service. All surplus horses will be turned over to the
                    chief quartermaster of the army, and all rejected guns, equipments, &amp;c.,
                    to the ordnance department. The guns, &amp;c., will be forwarded to Staunton
                    without delay.</p>
                <p>XXV. A board of survey, to consist of Maj. Gen. J. E. B. Stuart, Lieut. Col. J.
                    L. Corley, chief quartermaster, and Lieut. Col. R. G. Cole, chief commissary,
                    will assemble this evening at 5 o'clock to assess the value of the horses
                    equipments captured from Gen. Philip Kearny, U. S. Army.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>By command of Gen. R. E. Lee:</salute>
                    <signed>R. H. CHILTON,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
