<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1192785"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R1192785">
	<teiHeader type="migrated">
		  <fileDesc>
			   <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
        <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
        <respStmt>
					     <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
					     <name/>
					     <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
			   <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent> 
			   <publicationStmt>
				    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
				    <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
				    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
				    <idno type="VCDH">R1192785</idno>
        <!--
				<availability>
					<p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
						University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
					<p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
				</availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
				    <date value="2001">2001</date>
			     <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498689</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
			   <seriesStmt>
				    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
			   </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
			   <notesStmt>
				    <note/>
			   </notesStmt>
			   <sourceDesc>
				    <biblFull>
					     <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
							Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi union correspondence</title>
            <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
            <respStmt>
							       <resp>Translator:</resp>
							       <name/>
						      </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
					     <editionStmt>
						      <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 27</p>
					     </editionStmt>
					     <extent>Pages 85</extent>
					     <publicationStmt>
						      <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
						      <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
						      <date value="1997">1997</date>
					     </publicationStmt>
					     <seriesStmt>
						      <p/>
					     </seriesStmt>
					     <notesStmt>
						      <note/>
					     </notesStmt>
				    </biblFull>
			   </sourceDesc>
		  </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
		  <profileDesc>
			   <creation>
				    <date value="1862-10-29">1862-10-29</date>
			   </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
			   <textClass>
				    <keywords>
					     <term/>
					     <term/>
				    </keywords>
			   </textClass>
		  </profileDesc>
		  <revisionDesc>
			   <change>
				    <date value=""/>
				    <respStmt>
					     <resp/>
					     <name/>
				    </respStmt>
				    <item/>
			   </change>
		    <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text id="R1192785T">
		<front id="d2">
			<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
				<p>Union General George B. McClellan writes General-in-Chief Halleck on the
					positioning of troops after the battle of Antietam in this October, 1862,
					letter. McClellan recommends that additional troops be sent to several towns,
					including Chambersburg.</p>
			</div1>
		</front>
		<body id="d4">
			<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
				<head>
					HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE POTOMAC,
					<name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. HALLECK,<lb/> Gen.-in-Chief, Washington:</name>
				</head>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<date value="1862-10-29">October 29, 1862</date>--<time>1.15 p. m.</time>
					</dateline>
					<salute/>
				</opener>
				<p>On the 25th instant I sent you a dispatch requesting you to decide what steps
					should be taken to guard the line of the Potomac when this army leaves here. To
					this I received your reply that I had been intrusted by the President with
					defeating and driving away the rebel army; that you had given me no orders
					heretofore, did not give me any then, &amp; c. Under these circumstances, I
					have only to make such arrangements for guarding this extended line as the means
					at my disposal will permit, at the same time keeping in view the supreme
					necessity of maintaining the moving army in adequate force to meet the rebel
					army before us.</p>
				<p>The dispositions I have ordered are as follows, viz: Ten thousand men to be left
					at Harper's Ferry; one brigade of infantry in front of Sharpsburg; Kenly's
					brigade of infantry at Williamsport; Kelley's brigade, including Col. Campbell's
					Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Infantry, at Cumberland, and between that point and
					Hancock. I have also left four small cavalry regiments to patrol and watch the
					river and the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad from Cumberland down to Harper's
					Ferry.</p>
				<p>I do not regard this force as sufficient to cover securely this great extent of
					line, but I do not feel justified in detaching any more troops from my moving
					columns. I would therefore recommend that some new regiments of infantry and
					cavalry be sent to strengthen the forces left by me. There should be a brigade
					of infantry and section of artillery in the vicinity of Cherry Run, another
					brigade at Hancock, and additional brigade at Williamsport, one regiment at
					Hagerstown, and one at Chambersburg, with a section of artillery at each place
					if possible. This is on the supposition that the enemy retain a considerable
					cavalry force west of the Blue Ridge. If they go east of it, the occupation of
					the points named in my dispatch of the 25th instant will obviate the necessity
					of keeping many of these troops on the river.</p>
				<p>There are now several hundred of our wounded, including Gen. Richardson, in the
					vicinity of Sharpsburg, that cannot possibly be moved at present.</p>
				<p>I repeat that I do not look upon the forces I have been able to leave from this
					army as sufficient to prevent cavalry raids into Maryland and Pennsylvania, as
					cavalry is the only description of troops adequate to this service, and I am, as
					you are aware, deficient in this arm.</p>
				<closer>
					<salute/>
					<signed>GEO. B. MCCLELLAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding.</signed>
				</closer>
			</div1>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI.2>
