<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928706"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928706">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928706</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498760</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 705-706</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-09">1862-11-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928706T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Thomas J. Jackson's Confederate troops occupied the Shenandoah Valley during
                    November, 1862. In this dispatch, General Robert E. Lee discusses plans in the
                    Valley, and informs Jackson that shoes and blankets from Staunton have been
                    forwarded to his army.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. THOMAS J. JACKSON,<lb/> Cmdg. Left Wing,
                        &amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-09">November 9, 1862</date>--<time>1 p. m.</time>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 7th is at hand. The enemy seems to be massing his troops along
                    the Manassas Railroad in the vicinity of Piedmont, which gives him great
                    facilities for bringing up supplies from Alexandria. It has occurred to me that
                    his object may be to seize upon Strasburg with his main force, to intercept your
                    ascent of the valley. This would oblige you to cross into the Lost River Valley,
                    or west of it, unless you could force a passage through the Blue Ridge; hence my
                    anxiety for your safety. If you can prevent such a movement of the enemy, and
                    operate strongly upon his flank and rear through the gaps of the Blue Ridge, you
                    would certainly, in my opinion, effect the object you propose. A demonstration
                    of crossing into Maryland would serve the same purpose, and might call him back
                    to the Potomac. As my object is to retard and baffle his designs, if it can be
                    accomplished by maneuvering your corps as you propose, it will serve my purpose
                    as well as if effected in any other way. With this understanding, you can use
                    your discretion, which I know I can rely upon, in remaining of advancing upon
                    the valley. But I desire you will take precautions to prevent the enemy's
                    occupying the roads west of the Massanutten Mountains, and your demonstration
                    upon his flank might probably be as well made from a position nearer to
                    Strasburg as from that you now occupy. If the enemy should move into the valley
                    through Thornton's Gap, you must seize the pass through the Massanutten
                    Mountains as soon as you can, while Longstreet will advance through Milman's,
                    which you term Fisher's Gap (on the direct road from Madison Court-House to New
                    Market). But I think his movement upon Front Royal the more probable of the two.</p>
                <p>Keep me advised of your movements and intentions; and you must keep always in
                    view the probability of an attack upon Richmond from either north or south, when
                    a concentration of forces will become necessary. The enemy has made no advance
                    south of the Rappahannock line since 1 last wrote you.</p>
                <p>Col. Corley has just returned from Staunton, and says that he has sent you shoes
                    and blankets, which I hope you will soon receive and find sufficient for the
                    necessities of your command. They may have been stopped at New Market with the
                    expectation of your advancing up the valley; if so, send and get them, and use
                    every exertion to insure the hearth and comfort of your men.</p>
                <p>I am much gratified at the conduct of Maj. White, and I desire you to express to
                    Gen. A. P. Hill my appreciation of his conduct.</p>
                <p>The non-occupation of Martinsburg by the enemy, and his not marching into the
                    valley from his formed base on the Potomac, shows, I think, that his whole force
                    has been drawn from Maryland into Virginia east of the Blue Ridge. His
                    retirement from Snicker's and Ashby's Gaps, and concentration of his force on
                    the railroad in the vicinity of Manassas Gap, must either be for the purpose of
                    supplying it, or for making a descent upon Front Royal and Strasburg. I hope,
                    therefore, you will be on your guard.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed> R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
