<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R11928594"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R11928594">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R11928594</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498729</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxi confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 19, Serial No. 28</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 593-594</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-09-05">1862-09-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R11928594T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In September, 1862, Robert E. Lee planned an invasion of Maryland. In this
                    letter, he informs Jefferson Davis of his plans. Lee suggests sending some
                    supplies through Staunton, VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency President DAVIS, Richmond, Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-09-05">September 5, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Leesburg, Va., </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MR. PRESIDENT:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>As I have already had the honor to inform you, this army is about entering
                    Maryland, with a view of affording the people of that State an opportunity of
                    liberating themselves. Whatever success may attend that effort, I hope, at any
                    rate, to annoy and harass the enemy. The army being transferred to this section,
                    the road to Richmond, through Warrenton, has been abandoned as far back as
                    Culpeper Court-House, and all trains are directed to proceed by way of Luray and
                    Front Royal from Culpeper Court-House to Winchester. I desire that everything
                    coming from Richmond may take that route, or any nearer one turning off before
                    reaching Culpeper Court-House. Notwithstanding the abandonment of the line, as
                    above mentioned, I deem it important that as soon as the bridge over the Rapidan
                    shall be completed, that over the Rappahannock should be constructed as soon as
                    possible, and I have requested the president of the road to have timber prepared
                    for that purpose. My reason for desiring that this bridge shall be repaired is,
                    that in the event of falling back it is my intention to take a position about
                    Warrenton, where, should the enemy attempt an advance on Richmond, I should be
                    on his flank; or, should he attack me, I should have a favorable country to
                    operate in, and, bridges being repaired, should be in full communication with
                    Richmond.</p>
                <p>I have had all the arms taken in the late battles collected as far as possible,
                    and am informed that about 10,000 are now at Gainesville. All empty trains
                    returning to Rapidan are ordered to take in arms at Gainesville to transport to
                    Rapidan. They should be sent at once to Richmond to be put in order, as arms may
                    be needed in Maryland. I desire that Col. Gorgas will send some one to take
                    charge of these arms at once, as the cavalry regiments now on duty in the
                    vicinity of Gainesville will have to be withdrawn.</p>
                <p>We shall supply ourselves with provisions and forage in the country in which we
                    operate, but ammunition must be sent from Richmond. I hope that the Secretary of
                    War will see that the Ordnance Department provides ample supplies of all kinds.
                    In forwarding the ammunition it can be sent in the way above designated for the
                    other trains, or it can be sent to Staunton, and thence by the Valley road to
                    Winchester, which will be my depot. It is not yet certain that the enemy have
                    evacuated the valley, but there are reports to that effect, and I have no doubt
                    that they will leave that section as soon as they learn of the movement across
                    the Potomac. Any officer, however, proceeding toward Winchester with a train
                    will, of course, not move without first ascertaining that the way is clear. I am
                    now more desirous that my suggestion as to Gen. Loring's movements shall be
                    carried into effect as soon as possible, so that with the least delay he may
                    move to the lower end of the valley, about Martinsburg, and guard the approach
                    in that direction. He should first drive the enemy from the Kanawha Valley, if
                    he can, and afterward, or if he finds he cannot accomplish that result, I wish
                    him to move by way of Romney toward Martinsburg and take position in that
                    vicinity.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, with high respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
