<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12131821"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12131821">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxiii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sigel, Franz</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">19</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12131821</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498792</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxiii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sigel, Franz</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 21, Serial No. 31</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 820-823</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-03">1862-12-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12131821T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Franz Sigel forwards a December, 1862, scouting report to General
                    Burnside. The report, made by one Joseph Snyder, describes all manner of
                    Confederate activity. He reports sick being sent to Staunton, gives a
                    description of the industry, hospitals, and defenses of the town, and reports
                    that it forms the only telegraph link between Winchester and Richmond. Snyder
                    also reports on the farming and wheat production of Valley citizens.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ELEVENTH CORPS, ARMY OF THE POTOMAC
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. BURNSIDE,<lb/> Cmdg., &amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-03">December 3, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Fairfax Court-House, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The following is a report of Joseph E. Snyder, one of the best scouts in this
                    corps. He was, as he says, taken prisoner and conveyed to Richmond. His report
                    is full of interesting details and valuable information, and indicates that he
                    is a close and accurate observer of objects and movements. I regard him as a
                    very reliable man, but desire that his report be not published in the
                    newspapers, as he is still a scout, and might be tried as a spy in case he was
                    again made a prisoner.</p>
                <p>I forward it for your examination.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your most obedient servant</salute>
                    <signed>F. SIGEL,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg. Eleventh Corps.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Inclosures.<lb/> Monday, October 27.--Leaving
                        headquarters in the morning, on my way toward Upperville, I was intercepted
                        by a squadron of rebel cavalry, under Maj. Breckinridge, who had been on a
                        scouting expedition toward Bloomfield and Union, the latter place being in
                        possession of our cavalry. My arrival at Upperville seemed to have excited
                        the curiosity of the commander, Gen. Walker, who had but newly taken up his
                        quarters, with two brigades of infantry, one battery, and six companies
                        porary but lengthy examination, in the presence of Gen.'s Ransom, Munford,
                        and a number of other officers, followed. On stating that I was a soldier of
                        Gen. Sigel's corps, the general commanding appeared to be very inquisitive
                        as to the strength and position of his opponent, of whom (according to his
                        own statement) he seemed to have but bare information. Upon the sudden
                        arrival of scouts, I was quickly ordered to return to the guard-house,
                        leaving them rejoicing over the defeat of the Yankee cavalry at Snicker's
                        Gap.<lb/> Tuesday, October 28.--The continued advance of the Yankees from
                        Union caused some uneasiness in camp during the day.<lb/> Wednesday, October
                        29.--Alarm was given at 1 a.m. The cavalry force, soon mounted, was ordered
                        to advance to meet the Yankees, who were, according to the report of scouts,
                        advancing in force upon Upperville. The infantry was soon brought in line to
                        support the cavalry. By daylight the whole wagon train, having been ordered
                        back, arrived at Paris, which was followed by the infantry and artillery by
                        noon, when, to the surprise of the rebels, 27 Yankee cavalry charged through
                        the town of Upperville, taking several prisoners, and among them the
                        provost-marshal (Capt. Jones), but, for cause unknown, abandoned them.<lb/>
                        Thursday, October 30.--Before reaching Berryville, I passed fifteen
                        regiments of infantry, nineteen field pieces, mostly steel rifle, under Maj.
                        Gen. A. P. Hill, destined for Ashby's Gap. Berryville and its vicinity were
                        almost deserted by the rebels, while the forces under Jackson and J. E. B.
                        Stuart occupied positions toward Martinsburg and Charlestown, with pickets
                        at the latter place.<lb/> Friday, October 31.--Longstreet's army corps
                        commenced passing through the street of Winchester yesterday morning, and
                        close to-day. It consisted mostly of infantry, estimated at 50,000 men, no
                        less than sixty field pieces, and a small force of cavalry, en route for
                        Front Royal. Gen. Lee having left for Richmond, Gen. Jackson was in chief
                        command.<lb/> Saturday, November 1.--Great activity is displayed in removing
                        the sick to Staunton. Winchester and its vicinity is garrisoned and picketed
                        by the First Louisiana Brigade, First Regt. Maryland Infantry, and squadron
                        of Maryland Cavalry, with pickets extending north 6 miles.<lb/> The 2d, 3d,
                        4th, 5th, 6th, 7th, and 8th were days of constant arrival of prisoners,
                        stragglers, exchanged prisoners from the Southern capital to join their
                        commands. Newspapers from North and South were received daily. The
                        appearance of Yankee cavalry within 6 miles of the city, by way of Hancock;
                        the continual advance of McClellan's forces toward Warrenton; Sigel on
                        Manassas and Ashby's Gap, and the maneuver of the Yankees at Wardensville,
                        created quite a consternation among the chivalry. A daily evacuation was
                        spoken of; the sick and wounded were more vigorously removed, while all
                        movable conveyances in and about the city were pressed for the immediate use
                        of the army. The fortifications northeast of the town were neither
                        garrisoned nor guarded; they retained the same appearance as when evacuated
                        by the Yankees. The conscript crop has turned out, like at other places
                        South, a failure, several dozen being the gatherings of no less than six
                        counties, and of that number five refused to take up arms under all
                        circumstances, but subjected themselves to close imprisonment for a period
                        of time, but finally yielded.<lb/> Gen. Longstreet's corps, having been
                        encamped on the Front Royal road, 9 miles from Winchester, resumed its march
                        on the 2d and 3d of November, to meet Gen. Lee at Culpeper, who was reported
                        awaiting him, having 15,000 men under his command. The arrival of a report,
                        received on the evening of the 4th, claiming a grand victory over Gen.
                        Sigel, and the utter rout of the Yankees under him by Jackson and Hill,
                        created quite a jubilee among the citizens and soldiers, and their pale
                        countenances displayed the chivalric smile once more. Soon their common brag
                        began to make its rounds--Jackson was again ready to advance and enter
                        Maryland. The cry, "Winchester is not going to be evacuated," was hailed in
                        the streets. Army supplies were arriving slowly, consisting of flour,
                        tobacco, blankets, clothing, and shoes, sufficient to clothe 20 men of each
                        regiment in Jackson's corps. The arrival of 103 Yankee prisoners, captured
                        by White's guerrillas at Snicker's Gap; to buying of Yankee clothing and
                        exchanging Confederate scrip for greenbacks, assumed the appearance of quite
                        a business in and about the prison, while the small-pox did its duty at the
                        hospital. The regular arrival of Northern papers and mail matter was
                        surprising--my authority, a Maryland, and orderly to Gen. George H. Steuart,
                        who had been in the habit of supplying me with his daily Southern gas. I
                        obtained sufficient information to convince me that the business is carried
                        on by Marylanders, not alone citizens, but also by soldiers, by crossing the
                        river a few miles above Williamsport, and 4 miles below Martinsburg.<lb/>
                        Sunday, November 9.--Arriving at Strasburg, leaving about 1,200 head of
                        cattle a mile behind, the division, under Gen. D. H. Hill, consisting of
                        infantry and several batteries of field pieces, just entered the town from
                        Front Royal, under orders to re-enforce Jackson. The commissary department
                        in this place was well supplied with crackers, bacon, and flour.<lb/>
                        Monday, November 10.--D. H. Hill leaves at daybreak for Winchester.<lb/>
                        Tuesday, November 11.--The hospitals at Mount Jackson are filled with the
                        transient custom. No garrison. Commissary stores in abundance. The bridge in
                        town not rebuilt. The one over the Shenandoah, 1 1/2 miles distant from
                        Mount Jackson, is nearly completed, and represents a substantial structure.
                        The abundance of water and grass at this locality seems to have induced the
                        rebels to herd their beef-cattle there, which seem to be equal in abundance
                        to buffaloes on the prairies of Kansas. Meeting wagons, few in number,
                        loaded with blankets, &amp;c., from time to time. Big Spring, situate 9
                        miles from Harrisonburg, is the rendezvous for trains, ordnance, and
                        commissary depot.<lb/> Wednesday, November 12.--The farmers all along the
                        valley are engaged in preparing their gain for the mills, hauling it for the
                        use of the army. Harrisonburg, from appearance, is favored with a provost
                        guard. Many a farmer from the surrounding country leaves it with a smile of
                        his brow, with a full pocket of Confederate scrip, the proceeds of his
                        productions and stock. Mount Crawford, a commissary supply depot, memorable
                        for the unhappy bridge of Gen.'s Fremont and Shields. The bridge is rebuilt,
                        and has every appearance of fine improvement.<lb/> Thursday, November
                        13.--Approaching Staunton from the north side, with the mouths of cannons
                        pointing toward you, one might suppose the rebels were occupying the same in
                        force. Enter, and you feel surprised. The manufactories for boots, shoes,
                        and clothing for army use, the extensive hospital preparations for thousands
                        of sick, the general supply depot, the place of safe-keeping of all the
                        captured Harper's Ferry plunder, is defended by one company of the
                        Sixty-first Virginia Infantry, twenty-four field pieces, and a mixture of
                        cavalry and artillery, although small in number. The estimated number of
                        sick in this place is 2,000, and the report of the Yankees having dashed
                        within 16 miles of the place the previous night, nearly caused the removal
                        of them to Richmond.<lb/> Friday, November 14.--The Virginia Central
                        Railroad has been in fine running condition, and has been the main line of
                        nearly all supplies sent to the Army of Northern Virginia. The only direct
                        telegraphic communication from Winchester to Richmond is via Staunton, along
                        this road. Charlottesville, a pleasant village on the railroad, is partly
                        used as a military hospital, with a provost guard to defend it. The cry of
                        danger was visible here to a greater extent; the fear of an early capture of
                        Staunton, the advance of the Yankees toward Fredericksburg, the slow
                        movements of their generals, were openly discussed, and the Richmond
                        Government not being able to comply with the wishes of the inhabitants by
                        sending re-enforcements, they claimed their situation a most perilous one;
                        so spoke the first Union man in Dixie Gordonsville, the junction of the
                        Orange and Virginia Central Railroads, and place of great newspaper
                        notoriety for military defenses and concentration of forces; a roomy
                        railroad depot, several large frame buildings, newly erected by the
                        Confederates, is nearly all there is of interest. Fortifications were
                        nowhere visible. I endeavored to gain my point by raising questions among
                        those that I came in contact with, but being made to understand that I was
                        not here to take notes, I failed. To the best of my ability I discovered but
                        small camps within the immediate vicinity. The depot, as well as other
                        buildings, contained large army supplies. If there are any least 9 miles
                        north of the junction. The arrival of exchanged soldiers, convalescents, and
                        conscripts was great in number, having been the gatherings for a few days
                        past, and, owing to the unsafely in sending them by way of Staunton up the
                        valley, they were retained here for further orders.<lb/> Wednesday, November
                        19.--The Richmond papers announcing the occupation of Staunton by the
                        Yankees, and their rapid advance upon Charlottesville, urging the
                        authorities to repair immediately to meet the invaders and drive them where
                        they belong before making any further progress.<lb/>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
