<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12131780"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12131780">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxiii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Cluseret, Gustave</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12131780</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498789</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxiii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Cluseret, Gustave</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 21, Serial No. 31</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 779-780</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-19">1862-11-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12131780T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Gustave Cluseret reports to Jacob Cox concerning November, 1862,
                    plans for action in the Shenandoah Valley. Cluseret proposes forcing Thomas J.
                    Jackson to move by threatening the important rail and supply center of Staunton,
                    VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. JACOB D. COX:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-19">November 19, 1862.<lb/> Received at Charleston, W. Va., November
                        20.</date>
                        <name type="place">NEW CREEK,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I do not think there is the least use of our remaining at New Creek. As we told
                    Gen. Kelley, his fears were entirely without foundation. What interest can
                    Jackson possibly have to destroy more of the railroad than he has done, when we
                    reflect on the risk and possible consequences that may arise to him from pushing
                    up into the north-west? The object of destroying a railroad is not so much to
                    capture property as to destroy communication. The latter object Jackson has
                    already attained; further destruction would not advance that object; it would be
                    a piece of folly or deliberate malice, of neither of which Jackson is ever
                    guilty. His position and the disposition of his forces clearly indicate a very
                    different object. Posted on the right flank, and in the rear of the army of
                    Burnside, behind passes by which he can debouch at will to a point between that
                    army and the capital, he is in no standing danger, and can be dislodged from his
                    position only by a battle or by a strategic movement. It is absolutely
                    impossible that he should forego the advantages of such a position to move upon
                    a foolish expedition, which no military man would ever conceive of. What use are
                    we? He, then, absolutely knows that Jackson ought to be dislodged. There are
                    naturally two means of doing this: One by attacking him, which will not probably
                    be done, but which, had I the power, should by all means be done, by a corps
                    detached on the east from Burnside's army and a combination of the troops of
                    Harper's Ferry, Hagerstown, Cumberland, and New Creek from the west, got
                    together in all speed, and by means of the railroad. The other means is by a
                    strategic movement, which I shall point out. Threaten at once Staunton and the
                    railroad of the south. Jackson will then do one of two things-either he will
                    march through the valley to relieve the threatened point, and rejoin the
                    Southern army, in which case he will leave Winchester and the Baltimore and Ohio
                    Railroad open, or he will remain where he is, and we can the destroy a line of
                    communication and a depot of supplies much more important than the dangers
                    occasioned by his position at Winchester.</p>
                <p>Now, Staunton and the railroad can be threatened as follows: First, by reuniting
                    our whole force at Beverly; second, from that point to march upon Warm Springs
                    and fall upon the troops there, or, according to circumstances, pass over to the
                    east of that place and fall suddenly upon Staunton, and destroy the railroad
                    bridges between that place and Charlottesville; but this is a plan that only can
                    be matured on the spot; third, a strong detachment of troops, under Gen. Cox,
                    should make a demonstration against Lewisburg, threatening the railroad of the
                    south.</p>
                <p>In all probability, if the demonstration is well made, the rebels at Warm Springs
                    will unite with those at Lewisburg, and we can profit rapidly of that movement
                    by falling upon Staunton. If, on the contrary, the troops at Lewisburg are left
                    to themselves, we can each move separately, as we are much stronger, and thus
                    open a double way to Staunton and the railroad to the south. For the execution
                    of this plan we need 1,000 cavalry, or a full regiment, which must be had, if
                    only temporarily.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>G. P. CLUSERET,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
