<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1211019"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1211019">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1211019</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498774</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 21, Serial No. 31</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1018-1019</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-18">1862-11-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1211019T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes Thomas J. Jackson on Union and Confederate movements in
                    November, 1862, in preparation for the Fredericksburg campaign. He mentions the
                    situation around Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. THOMAS J. JACKSON,<lb/> Cmdg.,&amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-18">November 18, 1862</date>--<time>2 p.m.</time>

                        <name type="place">Camp near Culpeper Court-House,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 17th is just received. I think there must be some mistake
                    about the enemy's being re-enforced at Harper's Ferry, inasmuch as information
                    from Washington states that nearly all the troops near the city have been
                    advanced into Virginia. I fear I was said to be threatening Staunton had retired
                    beyond at Alleghanies. I therefore have ordered the First South Carolina Cavalry
                    and Stribling's battery to Gordonsville. I think the force there, with Imboden
                    operating in advance, will be sufficient to protect that place, as in a short
                    time the roads in that country will be impassable.</p>
                <p>If the report that the enemy is returning in force to Middleburg is correct, it
                    must be owing to your presence in the valley and the operations of the cavalry;
                    but, in that event, it would appear that they are in great force at all points
                    from Harper's Ferry to Fredericksburg. There must be error somewhere, and it is
                    important to discover it. In a telegraphic dispatch sent you half an hour since
                    I have you in substance the result of my information. I will report more in
                    detail.</p>
                <p>The reports from our cavalry, individual scouts, and citizens, represent that the
                    enemy has abandoned Warrenton, fallen down to the Orange and Alexandria
                    Railroad, and is moving in force to Fredericksburg. Their progress and direction
                    is confirmed by their camp-fires at night, which are said to be plainly visible.
                    A large force was reported yesterday, in addition, at Brentsville;it had come
                    from the direction of Alexandria. The cavalry, with light artillery, reached
                    Falmouth yesterday about 3 p.m. Their infantry were said to have reached
                    Hartwood last night; their camp-fires distinctly visible, extending continuously
                    back toward the railroad. An intelligent scout reports this morning that it was
                    Sumner's corps, and that no other troops had passed up to late yesterday. The
                    enemy's cavalry were prevented from crossing the Rappahannock last evening by
                    our troops in Fredericksburg, nor have I yet heard of its occupation. There are
                    in Fredericksburg a regiment of cavalry, one of infantry, and two additional
                    companies, and two light batteries. McLaws' division marched this morning for
                    that place; also Lee's brigade of cavalry, and Ransom's division from Madison.
                    The rest of Longstreet's corps is prepared to move, and only awaits confirmation
                    of intelligence.</p>
                <p>Stuart, with his cavalry, was directed to cross the Rappahannock to-day, and
                    endeavor to ascertain what was in our front and what movements were being made
                    by the enemy. I presume I shall not hear from him till to-morrow; but unless you
                    think it is advantageous for you to continue longer in the valley, or can
                    accomplish the retention and division of the enemy's forces by so doing, I think
                    it would be advisable to put some of your divisions in motion across the
                    mountains, and advance them at least as Sperryville or Madison Court-House. I
                    telegraphed you to this effect to-day. I learn that there are not transports at
                    Alexandria; nothing but a few gunboats and tugs. I see, therefore, no
                    preparation for the transfer of the enemy's troops south of the James River as
                    yet; nor is there anything to develop their ultimate plan. It is possible that
                    the may attempt to seize Winchester, Culpeper, and Fredericksburg, which would
                    embrace their favorite strategic plan of advancing in three columns, but I think
                    by so doing they will much expose themselves. I hope we may be able to take
                    advantage of it.</p>
                <p>I hope more shoes and blankets have arrived for your men, and that you will be
                    enabled to keep them comfortable and in health.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, most respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
