<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122243"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R122243">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122243</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498818</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 242-243</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-11">1861-07-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122243T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>During July, 1861, General Robert Garnett commanded Confederate forces defending
                    what is now West Virginia. In this dispatch, Robert E. Lee sends orders to
                    Garnett. Lee speculates that Union troops plan to push through West Virginia all
                    the way to Staunton. He orders Garnett to prevent this.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. R. S. GARNETT,<lb/> Commanding, &amp;c.,
                        Laurel Hill, Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-11">July 11, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond, Va.</name> <name type="location">HEADQUARTERS OF THE FORCES,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received to-day your two letters of the 6th instant, and have communicated
                    their contents to the President. Your opinion as to the advantage of giving a
                    more northerly direction to Gen. Wise's column will be communicated to that
                    officer, and it is hoped that he will find himself in a condition to conform to
                    it, and that with your united columns you will be able to fall upon the enemy. I
                    do not think it probable that the enemy will configure himself to that portion
                    of the northwest country which he now holds, but, if he can drive you back, will
                    endeavor to penetrate as far as Staunton. Your object will be to prevent him, if
                    possible, and to restrict his limits within the narrowest range, which, although
                    outnumbered, it is hoped by skill and boldness you will accomplish.</p>
                <p>Your recommendation of the appointment of Mr. G. Thomas Getty a lieutenant in the
                    C. S. Army will be complied with, and also the promotions of Capts. R. G. Cole
                    and Julius A. De Lagnel. Should you feel embarrassed by the present rank of
                    Capt. G. Jackson you will please say so.</p>
                <p>Mr. S. M. Yost will also be appointed assistant quartermaster. The officers whom
                    you state you have found in that region were appointed by the governor, in the
                    hope that their standing and political influence would enable them to organize
                    regiments of volunteers. The appointment of Col. L. Wilson has not been
                    confirmed by the convention. He is, therefore, not in the service. Maj. P. B.
                    Adams is the major of the Thirty-fifth Virginia Regiment, whom you were
                    directed, in a previous letter, to cause to report to Col. Alfred Beckley. W. L.
                    Jackson was appointed lieutenant-colonel of the same Regiment. The regiments
                    commanded by Lieut.-Col. Heck and Lieut.-Col. Jackson, I presume, are the
                    Twenty-fifth, of which G. A. Porterfield is colonel, and the Thirty-first, of
                    which W. J. Willey is colonel. Should I be correct, please number them
                    accordingly, and inform me the field officers which you have attached to them.
                    Should Lieut.-Col. Arnett, Maj. Boston Stewart, Second Lieut. J. Bosworth,
                    Second Lieut. B. Haymond, and Lieut. Norment have no commands with the troops of
                    your army, and be unable to organize any volunteer companies, please let me
                    know. I am glad to hear that the troops and articles forwarded you have reached
                    you in safety. A Georgia regiment, Col. E. Johnson, and a North Carolina
                    regiment, Col. S. Lee, are on their way to join you.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen., Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
