<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122616"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122616">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Patterson, Robert</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122616</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498836</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Patterson, Robert</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 615-616</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-05-01">1861-05-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122616T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Early in the war, Chambersburg served as a staging ground for new Union regiments
                    arriving at the front. In this May, 1861, letter, Union General Robert
                    Patterson, commanding troops in Pennsylvania and Maryland, writes Assistant
                    Adjutant E. D. Townsend to notify him of the location and status of his men. He
                    mentions that he sent two unequipped regiments to camps of instruction in
                    Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. E. D. TOWNSEND,<lb/> Asst. Adjt. Gen., Hdqrs.
                        of the Army, Washington City:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-05-01">May 1, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">PHILADELPHIA, PA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt from the Gen.-in-Chief of two
                    communications, dated April 28 and 29, relating to moving troops upon Baltimore
                    via York and Havre de Grace.</p>
                <p>Anticipating the wishes of the Gen.-in-Chief, I have, since the withdrawal by the
                    President of troops placed at Cockeysville, given attention to the
                    demonstrations designed, and have posted unequipped regiments in camps of
                    instruction at points from which they can be easily withdrawn and distributed on
                    these lines of communication, viz: At York, 6 regiments; Chambersburg, 2;
                    Lancaster, 6; Harrisburg, number unknown, but probably 6; and in this vicinity,
                    6.</p>
                <p>The impoverished condition of the quartermaster's department here in regard to
                    tents, canteens, and other camp and garrison equipage and the depleted arsenals,
                    will prevent the execution at an early day of any plan of operations. The troops
                    are not fully armed, and are very incompletely equipped, having but few
                    cartridge-boxes, no canteens, tents, or cooking utensils. Articles ordered for
                    troops in advance will exhaust the supply for the next three days. I have
                    directed these commands to be drilled and made efficient, and by the time they
                    are equipped I hope to be able to move on Baltimore with an effective force of
                    six thousand men via York and six thousand via Havre de Grace, and have
                    sufficient to guard the road as they advance.</p>
                <p>To effect this I request my requisitions may be filled as rapidly as forwarded,
                    or the depot quartermaster here and the arsenal at Frankfort be directed to fill
                    them direct from me. I will keep you informed of my progress and my probable
                    advance in time for concerted action. I shall lose no time, but for success take
                    care not to be too fast.</p>
                <p>I have authority to draw good volunteers from this State, but I desire, if
                    regular artillery companies are en route to Washington City, to obtain one to
                    serve as artillery with the column from York.</p>
                <p>The railroad companies here, and also via York to Baltimore, are now ready to
                    repair their roads, but the troops cannot advance. As soon as the men are
                    equipped they will be thrown to the front, and in a few days the lines will be
                    in working order. Col. Andrew Porter has gone to York to hasten the organization
                    of that column.</p>
                <p>Maj. Porter, governed by the prospect of being able to use for our purposes the
                    bridges on the Baltimore and Ohio Road, deferred arranging for their
                    destruction, and sent parties to examine the bridges and a portion of the road.
                    He is informed that the large bridges are each guarded by about two hundred men,
                    and so carefully that they cannot be injured. The road, however, will, under his
                    plans, be rendered impassable for our opponents as soon as desired, and he will
                    act when convinced that the present hopes of submission in Maryland prove
                    delusive.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, sir, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. PATTERSON,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
