<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122905"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122905">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Doyle, Robert L.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122905</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498902</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Doyle, Robert L.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 905</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-04">1861-06-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122905T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Captain Robert Doyle reports to General Joseph Johnston in June,
                    1861, on preparations to meet an impending Federal advance into Virginia. He
                    passes on estimates of Union troop strengths in Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brig.-Gen. JOHNSTON:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-04">June 4, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">SHEPHERDSTOWN, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have intelligence from the other side up to 3 p.m. yesterday. No Federal troops
                    at Hagerstown, Boonsborough, or at any other point in the valley. At
                    Chambersburg there are said to be some ten or twelve thousand men, though my
                    important believed that their number was exaggerated.</p>
                <p>A true friend from Maryland, living three miles from this post, came over last
                    night with information that on Sunday a prominent Republican, of Washington
                    County, Maryland, named Cook, accompanied by a Pennsylvanian, in citizen's
                    dress, were at Mercersville, about three and a half miles above this place, and
                    at other points along the canal above that point, engaging boats and scows, to
                    be used in passing the river. Cook said to one of the persons, from whom
                    obtained a ferry-boat, that, in the course of the next week, there would be
                    twenty or twenty-five thousand men thrown into Virginia upon this line; that
                    they proposed to cross the river at three points, viz, Mercersville, Slackwater
                    Dam No. 4, about six miles above this, and at Williamsport; and that the three
                    columns would concentrate at a point on the railroad not far from Kerneysville.
                    There is a great congregation of canal and ferry boats at Slackwater Dam No. 4,
                    with which they could speedily bridge the river at that point. I have a large
                    ferry-boat secured on our side in Dam No. 4, with which I can cross over
                    twenty-five or thirty men at a time. The enemy's boats have no other guard than
                    their hands on board and some canal hands, perhaps one hundred and twenty men in
                    all. I think, with my company, I could, if desirable, destroy all of the boats
                    by crossing the river in the night and burning them.</p>
                <p>I obtained two kegs (twenty-five pounds each) of powder from Maryland on
                    yesterday. I have more of the article now than I have immediate use for. I
                    shall, however, continue to procure all that I can. Please direct me where to
                    send it. If desired, I can forward it to Winchester. There is a good macadamized
                    road from here to that place. If not already known to you, allow me to call your
                    attention to a ford across the river at (just below) the mouth of Antietam
                    Creek, four and a quarter miles below this point. It is a good ford, and is now
                    passable, and the approaches on either side very good. My force of cavalry is
                    too small to enable me to guard it.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>RO. L. DOYLE,<lb/> Capt., Third Virginia Infantry, Commandant of Post.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
