<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122686"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122686">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Porter, Fitz-John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122686</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498866</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Porter, Fitz-John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 685-686</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-14">1861-06-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122686T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Robert Patterson's Adjutant Fitz-John Porter writes to General
                    George Cadwalader in June, 1861. Porter gives Cadwalader orders for a planned
                    advance on Harper's Ferry.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brevet Maj. Gen. GEORGE CADWALADER,<lb/> Commanding First
                        Division, Greencastle, Pa.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-14">June 14, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">CHAMBERSBURG, PA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The commanding general desires me to inform you that in operating against the
                    forces which occupy and surround Harper's Ferry his design is, in general terms,
                    as follows:</p>
                <p>First. To threaten an attack of the Maryland Heights.</p>
                <p>Second. To turn the enemy by their left, through or near Martinsburg, with a
                    strong column of mixed arms of service (cavalry mainly in reserve for critical
                    moments, either to launch upon the enemy, to sustain our columns, or hasten the
                    movements of a retreating enemy), cut their line of communication, and attack
                    them in position.</p>
                <p>Third. To sustain the advance column by a force strong enough to resist an effort
                    to cut off the advance, maintain the line of communication, and give the
                    necessary aid to sustain the movement.</p>
                <p>A reconnaissance of the enemy's position may cause a change in this plan, but it
                    is not likely to any material degree. The commanding general, therefore, desires
                    you, while he is preparing his forces, to mature your plans for executing so
                    much of the design as will fall to the lot of your division, that of taking the
                    advance and breaking the enemy's lines. The commanding general has every reason
                    to believe that a determined stand will be made at Harper's Ferry--a desperate
                    struggle for supremacy; and so momentous are the interests of our country,
                    involved in the undoubted success of our arms, that all plans must be matured
                    with great prudence; the agents selected and so well disciplined as to render
                    victory certain. While in position near Williamsport, the sustaining force being
                    unprepared, the commanding general desires you to avoid bringing on a collision
                    of any extent by entering Virginia, or attempting anything the success of which
                    is doubtful. Many efforts will be made to induce you to cross the river, but
                    heed them not or give them your careful consideration, and, whatever you
                    undertake, move with great caution. When our forces cross the river he does not
                    wish to withdraw, but to be able to sustain them and to advance. This, of
                    course, is not designed to restrict you in regard to parties who may annoy you
                    or be destroying property or the dams or cross the river into Maryland. They
                    must be quickly met by an overpowering force.</p>
                <p>The commanding general will be at Hagerstown on Monday morning, when, if you can
                    leave your post, he will be pleased to see you and receive your impressions and
                    such information as Capt. Newton will have obtained.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>F. J. PORTER,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
