<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122241"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R122241">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Garnett, Robert S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122241</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498817</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Garnett, Robert S.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 240-243</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-06">1861-07-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122241T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Robert Garnett, commanding forces in West Virginia during
                    July, 1861, writes to Assistant Adjutant George Deas concerning the situation
                    facing his troops. Garnett reports his dangerous reliance upon Staunton as his
                    only base of supply. He remarks on the lack of transportation from that
                place.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. GEORGE DEAS,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant and
                        Inspector Gen.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-06">July 6, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp at Laurel Hill, Va.,</name>
                        <name type="location">HDQRS. DEP'T OF NORTHWESTERN VIRGINIA,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In the postscript to a communication which I had the honor to address to you a
                    few days ago, I ventured to suggest the expediency of giving a more northerly
                    direction to Gen. Wise's column, in order to threaten the railroad and county
                    east of Parkersburg, now in possession of the enemy. Some subsequent information
                    has confirmed me in my convictions as to the propriety of such a movement. I
                    learned a day or two since, from sources in my front, that twenty-eight hundred
                    men, who had been put upon light-draught steamers in Pittsburg to operate in the
                    Kanawha Valley, were diverted from that purpose and landed at Parkersburg, from
                    which place they came to Clarksburg and thence to Buckhannon, where, with others
                    from Philippi, to the number, it is said, of three or four thousand, they have
                    now taken up their position, with a supporting force at Weston and at
                    Clarksburg--numbers unknown. This latter point, it is said, they are fortifying,
                    and making of it a place of detention for the secessionists whom they have
                    arrested in the country occupied by their troops, and whom hitherto they have
                    been sending to Ohio. It is my belief that as long as they can be made to
                    apprehend any danger to their possession of the railroad and country in front of
                    me they will not attempt any inroads in the Kanawha Valley, as the movement
                    above reported indicates, and that one of the most effectual means of keeping
                    that valley free of them is to occupy them fully here. I moreover think that if
                    Gen. Wise's column should move from Charleston direct upon Parkersburg, by the
                    road through Jackson, Wirt, and Wood Counties, it would have the effect, not of
                    withdrawing any troops from my front, but of bringing others into Virginia from
                    Ohio and the West, as it could be done with equal facility and rapidity, and
                    greater safety. But if he were to retrace his steps from Charlestown to
                    Summersville, in Nicholas County, and thence go to Bulltown, in Braxton, both of
                    which counties are loyal to our cause, he would be within a day's of Weston, and
                    threaten both it and Buchannon, and the enemy would have to draw from his force
                    in my front to meet him. Communication with me could be had by way of
                    Huttonsville.</p>
                <p>The valley of the Kanawha is comparatively loyal to our cause, and the force
                    under Gen. Floyd would be abundant to meet any force which it is probable the
                    enemy will send into that region for the present.</p>
                <p>The latest, and I believe the most accurate, information which I have yet
                    received from the front is that the enemy has seven regiments of infantry at
                    Philippi--say between five and six thousand men--and twenty pieces of artillery,
                    two of which are mortars. I scarcely think they have as much artillery as that
                    stated. At Grafton, a few days ago, there were only a few hundred; at Clarksburg
                    they are represented as having about three thousand men; at Weston two thousand,
                    and at Cheat River Bridge from two to three thousand. I cannot learn whether
                    they have artillery at this bridge, or whether they are erecting any defenses
                    about it. Gen. McClellan, at last accounts, was at Grafton. Gen. Morris in
                    command at Philippi. Were these numbers correct it would put their force in
                    Northwestern Virginia at about seventeen thousand men, though I hardly think it
                    can amount to that number. The term of service of one of the Indiana regiments
                    at Philippi expired a few days ago, and I learn that they are now kept there by
                    force. I do not now think it probable that the enemy, notwithstanding his
                    superiority of numbers, will attempt to attack my position unless the necessity
                    for his force elsewhere becomes very imperative, for the simple reason that he
                    has as much of northwestern country as he probably wants. He could have
                    possessed himself of more of the country after Col. Porterfield's retreat, if he
                    had desired it, yet refrained from doing so. The onus is upon us to drive him
                    out the country he already holds, if we can. It is impossible for me or any one
                    else, in my judgment, to say what numbers (within our means) are necessary to
                    effect this. The facilities, on the one hand, which they possess at present, of
                    throwing men in my front from other States, and the numbers they have disposable
                    for this purpose, with, on the other hand, the slow process to which we are
                    subjected in re-enforcing our force, will always enable them to exceed our
                    numbers, whatever they may be, to any degree they may deem necessary; for
                    secrecy in the movements of my re-enforcements in this disaffected country is a
                    thing impossible. It then becomes a question which must be decided by the
                    authorities of the Government, whether the mere paralyzation of a superior force
                    of the enemy, in my front, with the hope of seizing the railroad, if an
                    opportunity should offer itself, is a sufficient object to warrant the
                    maintenance of all our available force in this region; for as I have just said,
                    I do not suppose that this force can ever obtain a strength, relative to that of
                    the enemy, which would warrant us in offering him battle wherever we could meet
                    him. I have by no means relinquished or abated my hope of being able, on some
                    favorable occasion, to get at the road. But this is a contingency. The only
                    certain result we can calculate upon is that our presence here will necessarily
                    occupy a considerable force of the enemy, and, to that extent, relieve other
                    points of the State where they might be employed against us. It is not for me to
                    determine what the value of this very negative result is, but I have deemed it
                    my duty to state the case as it presented itself to my judgment. I can only say
                    I shall watch vigilantly, and strike whenever and wherever I can see a
                    reasonable hope of success.</p>
                <p>Col. Starke arrived yesterday, and I am gratified to learn that I am to have an
                    addition to my force, and sufficient supplies to secure the health and
                    efficiency of my command for the present. I am exhausting the country
                    immediately around me of grain and other supplies, and the operation of
                    supplying myself almost exclusively from Staunton is becoming a serious
                    difficulty with me on account of the scarcity of transportation. The corps are
                    backward in this region, and I shall not be able to draw from them earlier than
                    the end of August.</p>
                <p>I stated in my letter of the 1st instant that Col. Heck's regiment had been
                    ordered to take up a position on the Saint George road, and that he had been
                    relieved by Lieut.-Col. Hansborough's battalion of five companies. This
                    arrangement was countermanded in consequence of the appearance of the enemy in
                    force at Buckhannon. Lieut.-Col. Hansborough took the positions on the Saint
                    George road assigned to Lieut.-Col. Heck.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, sir, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. S. GARNETT,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
