<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122705"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122705">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Lockwood, Henry</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122705</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498876</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Lockwood, Henry</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 704-705</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-18">1861-06-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122705T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Colonel Henry H. Lockwood, commanding First Regiment, Delaware Volunteers reports
                    to Fitz-John Porter, Assistant Adjutant for the Department of Pennsylvania,
                    headquartered at Chambersburg in June, 1861. Lockwood describes guarding the
                    Philadelphia and Baltimore Railroad and the Delaware and Chesapeake Canal,
                    comments on the readiness of his troops, and mentions hiring a steamer for
                    communications on the Susquehanna.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. FITZ J. PORTER,<lb/> A. A. G., Dep't of
                        Pennsylvania, Chambersburg, Pa.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-18">June 18, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Havre de Grace, Md., </name><name type="location">HDQRS. FIRST REGIMENT DELAWARE VOLUNTEERS,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that this command occupies the several stations on the
                    Philadelphia and Baltimore Railroad, with one company on the Delaware and
                    Chesapeake Canal. The divided state of the command of course operates greatly
                    against any regular system of instruction. I, however, endeavor to visit the
                    several stations twice a week, and hope that the benefits of my instruction are
                    not entirely lost. The company guarding the canal is divided into two equal
                    parts, and its future efficiency thereby much disturbed. As I do not see the
                    necessity of keeping it there, I respectfully suggest the propriety of placing
                    it either at headquarters or at Elkton. I would likewise offer, very
                    respectfully, the same suggestion respecting the occupation of Northeast and
                    Charlestown. The bridges at Northeast and Charlestown are all of stone, and
                    could not be materially injured before word would reach Perryville or Elkton. I
                    would therefore suggest that two companies be kept at Elkton, two at Perryville,
                    and the rest at this place and below--say two at Bush River and two at
                    Gunpowder. This last place seems to me much more exposed than any other, and as
                    demanding greater protection. I await you orders in these respects. I beg leave
                    to add further that I have not felt easy without some means of constant
                    communication with the other shore of the Susquehanna, and that I have
                    accordingly chartered the steamer Fairy for thirty dollars per day, she finding
                    coal.</p>
                <p>In conclusion, I beg leave to present to the general, as the wish of the officers
                    and men of this command (myself included), that it should be called into more
                    active service at an early day. I would also say that the officers and men of
                    this command have received at all hands the well-merited encomiums of all here,
                    and at all the stations, for their genial society and good conduct. I regard the
                    material favorable for a first-rate regiment.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>HENRY H. LOCKWOOD,<lb/> Col., Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
