<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122198"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R122198">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Union Correspondence. </title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122198</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498810</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>McClellan, George B.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 198-199</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-05">1861-07-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122198T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>George B. McClellan commanded Union forces in what is now West Virginia during
                    the summer of 1861. In this July, 1861, letter he reports to Assistant Adjutant
                    General Edward Townsend on the strategic situation. He reports that the
                    Confederates in the area will soon have to rely for supply solely on Staunton,
                    VA, since all other routes have been cut off.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Col. E. D. TOWNSEND, Assistant Adjutant-Gen.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-05">July 5, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Buckhannon, Va.,</name> <name type="location">HEADQUARTERS DEPARTMENT OF THE OHIO,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>You will probably feel as much regret as I do in finding that I am still here.
                    The cause is the difficulty of getting up supplies and arranging transportation.
                    I hope that to-day's arrivals will enable me to move in the morning. While
                    waiting here I have endeavored to employ out time to advantage.</p>
                <p>You will observe that this is the important strategical position in this region.
                    From it I can cover our base of operations and supplies, and move readily by
                    good roads in any desired direction. I have directed the position on Cheat river
                    at Grafton, Webster, Clarksburg, and Parkersburg to be intrenched, that the
                    necessary garrisons may be reduced as much as possible. The bridges, tunnels,
                    &amp;c., on the two branches of the railroad are now well guarded. The Cheat
                    River, covering the left of our base, is guarded by eleven companies; Grafton,
                    by a regiment; Clarksburg, some eight companies, besides Virginia recruits;
                    Parkersburg, six companies, two regiments of Indiana troops to arrive there
                    to-day, and to be disposable as a reserve where needed. Two other Indiana three
                    years' regiments are en route to Bellaire, to be sent wherever needed. Six
                    companies occupy Wirt County Court-House, where Union men have suffered much.
                    Four companies at Ravenswood repulsed O. J. Wise night before last. I hope that
                    they determined to renew the attempt, as in that case he will have been cut off
                    by a column of twelve hundred men under Col. Norton, that were to reach Ripley
                    from Letart's at 2 p. m. yesterday. I shall not be surprised to learn before
                    this letter is close that he is captured. In consequence of the threatening
                    aspect of affairs in the Great Kanawha Valley I have ordered four regiments
                    there, as explained in my instructions to Gen. J. D. Cox, a copy of which has
                    been forwarded to you.</p>
                <p>Of the troops composing the active army fifty-one companies and one battery are
                    at Philippi, amusing the enemy, who is strongly intrenched with artillery on the
                    Laurel Mountain between that place and Beverly. I have with me here six entire
                    regiments of infantry, six detached companies, two batteries, two companies of
                    cavalry; two more regiments, and some five or six detached companies of infantry
                    will reach here by since, and four companies of the Seventeenth reached
                    Glenville from Parkersburg yesterday. I ordered strong detachments from these
                    commands to move last night on Bulltown, and break up a large force of armed
                    rebels congregating there. I can, if necessary, have them all back with me by
                    to-morrow night.</p>
                <p>I have sent out frequent small parties to break up the collections of rebels. We
                    have them pretty well under now. One of our parties of forty last night broke up
                    two hundred. The morale of our men is excellent-could not be better. It is
                    difficult to get perfectly accurate information, but we are improving in that
                    respect every day. The feeling of the people here is most excellent. We are
                    welcomed wherever our men go. It is wonderful to see how rapidly the minds of
                    many of these people become enlightened when they find we can protect them.</p>
                <p>Fear and ignorance combined have made most of the converts to secession; the
                    reverse process in now going on with great rapidity. I expect to find the enemy
                    in position on Rich Mountain, just this side of Beverly. I shall, if possible,
                    turn the position to the south, and thus occupy the Beverly road in his rear. If
                    possible I will repeat the maneuver of Cerro Gordo.</p>
                <p>Assure the Gen. that no prospect of a brilliant victory shall induce me to depart
                    from my intention of gaining success by maneuvering rather than by fighting. I
                    will not throw these raw men of mine into the teeth of artillery and
                    entrenchments if it is possible to avoid it. Say to the General, too, that I am
                    trying to follow a lesson long ago learned from him; i.e., not to move until I
                    know that everything is ready, and then to move with the utmost rapidity and
                    energy. The delays that I have met with have been irksome to me in the extreme,
                    but I felt that it would be exceedingly foolish to give way to impatience, and
                    advance before everything was prepared. I think the troops are improving
                    decidedly in their performance of guard and outpost duty, and that we are losing
                    nothing in efficiency by the halt at this place.</p>
                <p>From all that I learn the enemy is still uncertain as to where the main attack is
                    to be made, and is committing the error of dividing his army in the face of
                    superior forces. If he abandons the position on Laurel Mountain, the troops at
                    Philippi will press him closely. I shall know to-night with certainty what he
                    has in the pass at Huttonsville. I am told that the has moved all his troops
                    thence towards Beverly. By our present positions we have cut off all his
                    supplies of provisions from this region, so that he must depend almost entirely
                    upon Staunton-a long haul, over a rough mountain road.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>GEO. B. McCLELLAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., U. S. Army, Commanding Department.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
