<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122890"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122890">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Whiting, W. H. C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122890</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498897</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. IX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Whiting, W. H. C.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 890</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-05-28">1861-05-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122890T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Major of Engineers W. H. C. Whiting reports on the defense of
                    Harper's Ferry in May, 1861. He mentions that a Union force is gathering in
                    Chambersburg to move on the town, and discusses the probable route of Federal
                    advance.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-05-28">May 28, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">HARPER'S FERRY, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Consultation on the condition of Harper's Ferry and its defenses reduced to
                    writing.</p>
                <p>The plan of the enemy, indicated by his movements, seems to be a cautious
                    approach to, and entrance of, disaffected district, securing his advance, if
                    possible, by securing the sentiments of the people. In the district to the
                    northwest of Harper's Ferry these tactics will be the best he can follow, on
                    account of known Union proclivities and the vicinity of the frontier.</p>
                <p>Large bodies of troops are gathering at Carlisle and Chambersburg, the number
                    already reported (probably exaggerated) being fifteen thousand. When ready to
                    move they will occupy Martinsburg, crossing at Williamsport and Shepherdstown.
                    Martinsburg is well known to be disaffected. His line, established from
                    Martinsburg towards Shepherdstown, has an excellent base, and communications
                    very difficult to interrupt by the Hagerstown and Cumberland roads, and very
                    seriously threatens, not only Harper's Ferry, with its present forces and
                    conditions, but our whole line of operations. Martinsburg is nearer to
                    Winchester than the Ferry, and access easy. Our holding Winchester is necessary
                    to maintain the Ferry. To hold this post, then, either as a fortress, a point
                    d'appui, or as a condition of the defense of the Virginia Valley, we require a
                    force of from twelve to fifteen thousand men, of which two regiments should be
                    cavalry. The force now at the Ferry (about five thousand effectives) might
                    remain as at present, while the main body should be posted centrally, as at
                    Burns' Ford, on the Opequan, where a strong position might be selected, and, if
                    necessary, defended by lines. The strengthening and re-enforcement of this
                    force, as now constituted, seems to have ceased when most necessary. It is
                    essential that supplies of ammunition (especially of equipments of shoes) should
                    be forwarded in quantity, otherwise, without the arrangement designated, we are
                    so deficient in ammunition that this force must, on the advance of the enemy,
                    move out from the Ferry and maneuver, to prevent being shut up in a cul-de-sac.</p>
                <p>The plan sketched above will absolutely force the enemy to very great delay and
                    vastly extended preparations. It continually (by way of Leesburg and the eastern
                    slope of the ridge) threatens the District of Columbia. If, however, he is
                    beforehand with us (besides the present disastrous results), he gains what may
                    take time, means, and men, on a similar scale, to recover.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>W.H.C. WHITING,<lb/> Maj. of Engineers.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
