<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122647"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122647">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Patterson, Robert</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122647</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498838</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Patterson, Robert</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 646-647</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-05-23">1861-05-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122647T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Robert Patterson writes Colonel Edward D. Townsend in May, 1861,
                    concerning the outfitting and deploying of new regiments. He mentions several
                    regiments located, in varying states of readiness, at Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Col. E. D. TOWNSEND,<lb/> A. A. G., Headquarters of the
                        Army, Washington City:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-05-23">May 23 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Philadelphia, Pa.,  </name><name type="location">HEADQUARTERS DEPARTMENT OF PENNSYLVANIA,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In compliance with verbal intimation from the Gen.-in-Chief, I present for his
                    information in tabular form the locations of the regiments now in this
                    department; the condition of their equipment, accouterments, clothing,
                    &amp;c., and the probable time they can be put in motion, fully equipped.
                    The probable time is based on the accompanying statement from the commander of
                    Frankford Arsenal, to which I respectfully refer. I also call attention to the
                    offer herewith of the quartermaster-general of this State. With his aid six
                    regiments can be thrown into the field as rapidly as the accouterments can be
                    distributed, say Monday. Without his assistance (accepted by telegraph through
                    me) the term of service of some of the regiments will expire before they are
                    equipped, or they will be provided at so distant a day that new shoes and other
                    clothing will have to be issued, unless accouterments are provided outside of
                    this department. Col. Hale offers some four thousand sets. I am anxious to
                    forward the views of the Gen.-in-Chief and to execute his designs, and will be
                    much gratified to have the means of putting in the field regiments well drilled
                    and desirous of seeing service. If desirable, they can be sent forward without
                    accouterments,but without them the men lack confidence in each other and inflict
                    severe injuries.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, sir, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. PATTERSON,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Commanding.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--If Col. Hale's offer be accepted I shall at once
                        equip the Twelfth and Thirteenth Regiments, at York; Eighth and Tenth, at
                        Chambersburg; Fourteenth and Fifteenth, at Lancaster; and Twentieth and
                        Twenty-first, at Philadelphia, from those accouterments, to be supplied the
                        first of next week by Lieut. Treadwell.<lb/> Pennsylvania Volunteers.--One
                        regiment at Woodberry, Md., complete, except tents; two regiments at York,
                        all ready for service; three regiments at York, tents by 27th, no
                        accouterments; three regiments at Chambersburg, tents by 27th, accouterments
                        by 30th; three regiments at Philadelphia, no accouterments, rest ready by
                        25th; two regiments at Lancaster, no accouterments, rest ready by 25th; two
                        regiments at West Chester, no accouterments, rest ready by 25th, except
                        clothing, very deficient; one regiment at Havre de Grace and one at Elkton
                        and Perryville, all ready for service by replacing them at their posts by
                        Delaware Volunteers; one company cavalry at Philadelphia, provided with
                        nothing.<lb/> Delaware Volunteers.--One regiment at Wilmington, deficient in
                        clothing; two companies only with accouterments, in other respects ready.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
