<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R122684"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R122684">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Porter, Fitz-John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R122684</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498864</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Chap. IX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap ix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Porter, Fitz-John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 2, Serial No. 2</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 684</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-14">1861-06-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R122684T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Robert Patterson's Assistant adjutant Fitz-John Porter writes to E.
                    D. Townsend in June, 1861. Porter discusses moving Patterson's command from
                    Chambersburg to Hagerstown. He also talks about the prospect of capturing
                    Harper's Ferry.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Col. TOWNSEND:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-14">June 14, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">CHAMBERSBURG, PA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>DEAR COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>To-morrow morning our force will be in Hagerstown, located as indicated in the
                    accompanying map. Every effort has been made to press forward, and the move
                    to-morrow is a strained one. Every wagon we could get is engaged with the front
                    column, except twelve employed here taking baggage to the trains. We could not
                    hire teams here, and as far as I see here the people are just as willing to be
                    employed by the foe as by us if it would be safe and would pay. Our one-horse
                    railroad does not permit much work. By Sunday night I hope the main work will be
                    over and the force in Hagerstown, and the track open to the trains coming in
                    with supplies.</p>
                <p>To-day many reports have come to us to the effect that the enemy is evacuating
                    Harper's Ferry. Persons sometimes circulate such to induce us to press on to the
                    trap. Our own spies do not confirm them. Though I have been engaged night and
                    day in the office, and have no intelligent assistants in a military point of
                    view or cognizant of the workings of the staff, I have succeeded in inspecting
                    the regiments here, and to so organize the brigades as to make them the most
                    effective. In each are some riflemen, good marksmen, though the regiments are
                    mainly armed with smooth bore muskets. Till I came here I could not get from any
                    one of them the kind of arm in possession, nor the caliber, nor a solitary
                    requisition for anything. I have had to order each individual article generally
                    before I came here, and to push the articles forward. I have had to play
                    ordnance officer, assistant adjutant-general, commander of the forces,
                    inspector, quartermaster-everything. Now all branches have got to working well,
                    except that part of the quartermaster's department embraced in transportation. A
                    kingdom for a few horses or mules would be my cry if I had a kingdom. I do wish
                    our force to be the first to enter Harper's Ferry, but rather than make a false
                    step and lose by it or be checked, I shall be content to be last. Our force is
                    an imposing one to all else outside the ring.</p>
                <p>The heavy battery will probably be here on Sunday night or in Hagerstown. The
                    Fourth Artillery battery has not yet arrived at Carlisle, though believed to be
                    on the way. Harness not heard from or of. By the time that battery reaches
                    Hagerstown we will be ready. Our force will be advanced immediately, and a
                    position assumed which will permit the camps to be abandoned to a guard and the
                    force move on. We will soon have a telegraph established to Hagerstown this way.
                    The one through Frederick cannot be trusted. We will soon see other work.</p>
                <p>Write to Stone to-night, telling him what we will do, and that at the proper time
                    we wish him to move up, according to his judgment and information, either
                    towards Frederick or Leesburg. You think us slow, but if you and the Gen. were
                    here you would think otherwise, and that we have accomplished much. The enemy
                    have cut off all avenues of approach. The deserters give various accounts, and I
                    believe in some cases they have been sent here to deceive. They gained no
                    information.</p>
                <p>I send you sketches of Berkeley County. Cannot get one of Jefferson. The Maryland
                    Heights were re-enforced on Wednesday by about 3,000 men; whether to coerce the
                    Kentuckians or not, can't say, or to cover a movement in rear. They have tried
                    several times to induce us to cross and get whipped.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>F. J. PORTER,<lb/> Maj., and A. A. G.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
