<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12335754"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12335754">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXV. Circular. Quartermaster General's
                    Office.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxv circular quartermaster generals office</title>
        <author>Quartermaster General</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12335754</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498925</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXV. Circular. Quartermaster General's Office.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxv circular quartermaster generals office</title>
            <author>Quartermaster General</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 23, Serial No. 35</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 754</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-03-24">1863-03-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12335754T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This March, 1863, Confederate Quartermaster General's Office Circular establishes
                    a supply depot at Staunton, VA, and sets guidelines for purchasing officers.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    CIRCULAR. QUARTERMASTER-GEN.'S OFFICE
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-03-24">March 24, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>To avoid conflict and competition between the officers of this department in the
                    purchase of army supplies, and, as far as possible, between officers of this
                    department and those of the Ordnance Bureau or Commissary Department, in the
                    purchase of supplies common to both, quartermasters are especially directed to
                    observe the following regulations:</p>
                <p>1. Virginia, Lieut. Col. L. Smith, Richmond.</p>
                <p>2. North Carolina, Maj. W. W. Pierce, Raleigh.</p>
                <p>3. South Carolina, Maj. Hutson Lee, Charleston.</p>
                <p>4. Georgia, Maj. I. T. Winnemore, Augusta.</p>
                <p>5. Alabama, Maj. J. L. Calhoun, Montgomery.</p>
                <p>6. Mississippi, Maj. L. Mims, Jackson.</p>
                <p>7. Florida, Maj. H. R. Teasdale, Lake City.</p>
                <p>8. Louisiana, Maj. G. W. Grice, Alexandria.</p>
                <p>9. Texas, Maj. S. Hart, San Antonio.</p>
                <p>10. Arkansas and Missouri, Maj. J. B. Burton, Little Rock.</p>
                <p>11. Tennessee and Kentucky, Maj. James Glover, Knoxville.</p>
                <p>2d. It shall be the duty of these principal purchasing officers to establish, and
                    from time to time regulate, the prices at which army supplies, are to be bought,
                    and to confer with each other so as to secure, as far as practicable, uniformity
                    therein, making due allowances for differences of locations and other
                    circumstances. They will require from their subordinates monthly reports,
                    showing the quantity of supplies purchased or manufactured by them, what thereof
                    has been issued, and the residue on hand. A summary of these, together with a
                    similar statement of his own operations will be forwarded monthly by the chief
                    officer to the Quartermaster-Gen., and the same will be accompanied by general
                    remarks, showing what supplies, either manufactured or in the raw material, he
                    may have in excess beyond his future wants, so that they may be transferred
                    elsewhere when needed. The average cost of each article of supply will also be
                    stated.</p>
                <p>3d. Quartermaster stationed at the various posts within either of said purchasing
                    districts will be the subordinate purchasing officers therein, and, before
                    buying supplies or contracting thereof, they will confer with the principal
                    officer, and conform to such general or specific instructions as he may give
                    respecting the price, quantity, or quality of the supplies to be bought.</p>
                <p>4th. Main depots of supplies will be established at Richmond and Staunton, Va.,
                    Raleigh, N. C., Columbus, Atlanta, and Augusta, Ga., Huntsville and Montgomery,
                    Ala., Jackson, Miss., Alexandria, La., Little Rock, Ark., Knoxville, Tenn., San
                    Antonio, Tex., or elsewhere, as may hereafter be indicated. These will not be
                    subject to the orders of commanding generals, but will be under the exclusive
                    control of the Quartermaster-Gen., and issues therefrom will be made only on
                    requisitions approved by him. Minor depots may be established by the principal
                    purchasing officers, at such other points within their districts as the
                    necessities of the service may require, and their locations will be reported
                    from time to time to this office.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
