<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12540804"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12540804">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12540804</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498971</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 25, Serial No. 40</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 804-805</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-15">1863-05-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12540804T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Samuel Jones reports to Robert E. Lee on May, 1863, cavalry
                    movements in the Shenandoah Valley. He discusses General Albert Jenkin's
                    progress in gathering troops in and around Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF WESTERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. R. E. LEE,<lb/> Cmdg., &amp;c., Fredericksburg,
                        Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-15">May 15 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Dublin,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received yesterday your letter of the 9th instant. One received at the same
                    time from Brig.-Gen. Jenkins informed me that you had ordered him to collect his
                    brigade at Staunton, or some other suitable point in the Valley, and that it was
                    your intention to put him in command in the Valley, and send W. E. Jones'
                    command east. Eight or ten companies of Jenkins' cavalry ought to be at Staunton
                    now or farther to the east, as they had moved from Rockbridge and August several
                    days since to join Gen. Stuart, as ordered. Two companies of the Sixteenth
                    Virginia Cavalry arrived here to-day, and will proceed on toward Staunton
                    to-morrow. The remainder of that regiment was to have started from
                    Jeffersonville, Tazewell County, yesterday for Staunton. The other part of his
                    command will be some days later in reaching Staunton, as their horses were sent
                    to North and South Carolina to winter, and the grass has been so backward that I
                    could not bring them to this part of the country sooner, having no forage for
                    them.</p>
                <p>One of his battalions (Dunn's) went with Imboden, and, I hear, has been increased
                    to a regiment in Northwestern Virginia. It shall go to the Valley as soon as
                    Imboden has carried out the orders I have given him, and sooner, if you so
                    desire. I telegraphed you yesterday on the subject.</p>
                <p>Brig.-Gen. Jenkins is a bold and gallant soldier, but I do not think him a good
                    administrative officer. I believe he is capable of becoming a fine officer in
                    that respect, but unfortunately many of his men are has constituents, and he has
                    been a politician, and, I believe, still has aspirations that way. I do not know
                    enough of Brig. Gen. W. E. Jones to venture a comparison between him and
                    Jenkins. The latter will, I think, prove quite as daring as you can desire, and
                    that, I think, is a very desirable quality, especially in a cavalry officer.</p>
                <p>You ask when you can get cavalry re-enforcements. I really do not know, general.
                    I sent a battalion, Lieut.-Col. Witcher's, to the Valley in the winter, and it
                    is now with W. E. Jones, and when Jenkins goes with his brigade, I am afraid I
                    will have sent you all I can. I shall be able to answer your question more
                    correctly when I have full reports from Imboden. Col. William L. Jackson has
                    recently organized a regiment of cavalry, the Nineteenth Virginia, in my
                    department. I sent him with Imboden. Before starting, he informed me he had
                    three other cavalry companies, and hoped soon to fill up another regiment. I
                    hope he has done so on this expedition. Imboden informed me on the 3d instant
                    that he expected to bring out 1,500 horses. If he meant that many in addition to
                    what Jones would probably bring out, it would contribute largely toward
                    remounting a part of your cavalry. I am organizing another cavalry regiment at
                    Saltville, and hope to have it ready for service soon. I heard to-day that there
                    is a cavalry company, 160 strong, now in Russell County, without orders, and
                    doing nothing, and wants to come under my command. But that part of Virginia is,
                    since January last, in the Department of East Tennessee, and I presume the
                    company I mention is a part of Brig.-Gen. Marshall's late command, which is
                    represented to me as very much scattered and disorganized. An active and
                    energetic officer could do much good service in that section of country in
                    re-collecting and organizing troops.</p>
                <p>I have written too long a letter to be red by one so busy as you are. Hand it
                    over to one of your staff officers to pick out the points and give them to you.
                    Gen. Stoneman does, indeed, seem, as you say, to be "running wild over the
                    State;" but we are not "ruined," general, whilst we have you and your army.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>SAM. JONES,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
