<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12540854"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12540854">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12540854</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498980</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 25, Serial No. 40</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 853-854</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-06">1863-06-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12540854T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Samuel Jones writes Robert E. Lee regarding June, 1863,
                    supply transfers and troop movements. He reports ordering artillery sent from
                    Richmond to Staunton for General Albert Jenkin's use.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF WESTERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. R. E. LEE.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-06">June 6, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Dublin,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letters of the 1st and 3d instant have been received. Though I have relied
                    on the cattle brought out from Northwestern Virginia by my commissary for the
                    subsistence in part of my own troops, I cannot, with a clear conscience,
                    withhold from your army anything it absolutely needs, and which it is in my
                    power to give; you may, therefore, have the cattle. There are only 1,140
                    remaining now, and I will have them turned over to any one you may designate;
                    but, general, they are in no condition now to be butchered. They are now on fine
                    grass in Greenbrier, and, if allowed to remain there until October, will
                    probably be nearly double in weight what they are now. It would be a great waste
                    to butcher them now. They are yours, however, to be disposed of as you think
                    proper.</p>
                <p>So with the transportation that Imboden's expedition captured and brought out. I
                    shall be obliged to let you have it, or rather that part of it which I thought
                    fully belonged to this department. Indeed, I did not know that any of it would
                    go to your army proper, but supposed Imboden would keep it all and it was no
                    more than he needed.</p>
                <p>I hope you will be able to send the Fiftieth Virginia Regt. back to me soon. My
                    command is smaller, I think, than you imagine, and whilst there is no decided
                    indication that the enemy in my front contemplate an advance soon, it is
                    impossible to tell when they may do so, their facilities for suddenly
                    re-enforcing their troops in the Kanawha Valley are so great. In the meantime
                    there are very decided indications that Burnside is moving on East Tennessee,
                    and if he does, Gen. Buckner will expect me to aid him, and I can do so only to
                    a very limited extent.</p>
                <p>I send with this a copy of a letter from Lieut. Col. W. P. Thompson, of the
                    Nineteenth Virginia Cavalry. It gives information which I think it desirable you
                    should have, especially as Brig.-Gen. Imboden acts directly under your orders. I
                    have only the Nineteenth Virginia Cavalry, a new regiment recently organized in
                    Pocahontas County, near Huntersville. I have no other troops nearer that line
                    than Meadow Bluff.</p>
                <p>Will you please inform me where Jenkins' cavalry is, and where it is intended to
                    operate? I desire to send to him an artillery company which I organized for his
                    brigade. The guns for the company were ordered to be sent from Richmond to
                    Staunton. I understand that Jenkins' cavalry is only temporarily detached from
                    my command.</p>
                <p>I am much obliged for your kind wishes for my success in the summer campaign. In
                    the present reduced condition of my command, the most that I can expect is to
                    guard securely all the country I now occupy.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With great respect and esteem, general, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>SAM. JONES,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
