<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12540526"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12540526">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXVII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxvii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Graham, Michael</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12540526</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498940</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXVII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Graham, Michael</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 25, Serial No. 40</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 525-527</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-26">1863-05-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12540526T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>The Shenandoah Valley proved both important and troublesome to Union efforts
                    throughout most of the war. In this letter, Michael Graham sends strategic
                    suggestions to Secretary of War Edwin M. Stanton for May, 1863, operations in
                    the Valley. Graham discusses sending out cavalry scouting forces to many points
                    in the Valley, including Staunton where they can "break up the post." Also of
                    interest is Graham's assessment of the agricultural importance of the Valley,
                    his suggestions for putting confiscated slaves to work, and for making Valley
                    residents take loyalty oaths. Graham also advises treating citizens well to win
                    back their allegiance, and he suggests enacting policies designed to foster
                    class resentment among Valley residents.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. E. M. STANTON.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-26">May 26, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">WINCHESTER, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Allow me to present you with my views of the state of affairs in the Valley of
                    Virginia.</p>
                <p>This Valley cannot be held unless Gen. Milroy is re-enforced by 20,000 men. He
                    ought to have 15,000 infantry and 5,000 cavalry. With that force he could
                    advance up the Valley to New Market, where he should make his headquarters. From
                    New Market he could throw part of his force into Page Valley, and occupy Luray.</p>
                <p>The Valley at New Market from mountain to mountain is a narrow passage, and
                    easily guarded against surprise. Luray, the county seat of Page County, is a
                    point which ought by all means to be held, because the Valley is narrow and
                    easily defended.</p>
                <p>By holding New Market, you hold Brock's Gap, the passage though the mountains to
                    Moorefield. By holding Luray, you hold the passage through Thornton's Gap. If
                    attacked at New Market by the rebels, you can easily fall back by a good road to
                    Luray. If forced to leave Luray, you could retreat down to Front Royal, and from
                    Front Royal to Berryville, and from Berryville to Harper's Ferry, or else you
                    could retreat from Luray to Sperryville, from Sperryville to Little Washington,
                    from Washington to Sandy Hook, from Sandy Hook to Piedmont, from Piedmont to
                    Thoroughfare Gap, from Thoroghfare Gap to Blackburn's Ford, from Blackburn's
                    Ford to Fairfax Court-House, or else you could retreat from Luray to
                    Sperryville, from Sperryville to Warrenton Springs, from Warrenton follow the
                    Warrenton and Alexandria Railroad.</p>
                <p>By giving Gen. Milroy 20,000 men, infantry, cavalry, and artillery, he will hold
                    the Valley against the enemy, protect the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and
                    deprive the rebels of the coming crop. Your cavalry force will need no hay, they
                    can get pasturage and hay in the Valley. All they will need will be oats and
                    corn, and that can easily be hauled from Martinsburg. By having this force
                    stationed at New Market and Luray, under Gen. Milroy, his cavalry force can
                    scour the Valley from New Market to Staunton, break up the post at that place,
                    and penetrate as far as Lexington, in Rockbridge County. The same cavalry will
                    prevent the rebs from getting their supplies from Greenbrier, Monroe, Highland,
                    and Bath Counties. In one week your cavalry can scout the country from New
                    Market to Staunton and Lexington, and return the same week. The next week they
                    could pass into Page County, through Massanutten Mountain to Luray. From Luray
                    they can scout the country to Port Republic; from Port Republic they can proceed
                    to Charlottesville; from Charlottesville they could retreat to Madison
                    Court-House; from Madison to Luray.</p>
                <p>Five full regiments of cavalry should have seven regiments of horses. One of the
                    extra regiments should be stationed at New Market and one at Luray, so that when
                    a regiment came in with jaded horses, they could leave them to rest and take
                    fresh ones.</p>
                <p>Take all the negroes in the Valley from the loyal as well as disloyal, organize
                    them into companies to tend horses, do duty, or act as guides. Bring farming to
                    a stop. You will find enough wheat in the Valley to bread Milroy's army. Put the
                    negroes at work making hay, preparing roads, and at other laborious occupations.
                    What cannot be employed in this manner, organize into regiments and let them
                    take the field. Encourage all citizens to take the oath of allegiance and go
                    North till the war is over. Let them hunt employment in the workshops and
                    manufactories of the North. Let proclamations be issued assuring the rebel
                    soldiers that the Government will protect them, and will not press them into our
                    service if they desert and come to us, but that they can get profitable
                    employment in the North till the return of peace. Also proclaim to all foreign
                    naturalized citizens who are in arms against the United States that they can
                    have twenty days to return to their allegiance to the Union, with full pardon.
                    Give them to understand that they are not only guilty of treason, but also of
                    perjury, and that, if they do not return under twenty days, they will be hung,
                    shot, or banished, if afterward captured.</p>
                <p>Increase the ill-feeling between the rich and poor in your occupation of all
                    towns in the Valley; inquire into the situation and wants of the people; impress
                    the poor with the idea that the rich are the cause of all their miseries, and
                    divide the wealth of the rich with the poor. Why not send three or four brigades
                    of cavalry from Hooker to Milroy? They could proceed from Stafford Court-House
                    to Rappahannock Station, from there to Fayetteville, from there to Jefferson,
                    from there to Battle Mountain, from there to Sperryville, from Sperryville to
                    Little Washington, from there down along the foot of blue Ridge to Chester Gap,
                    from there to Piedmont, from there to Salem, from there to White Plains, from
                    there to Rectortown, from there to Middleburg, from there to Upperville, from
                    there to Ashby's Gap, from there to Berry's Ferry, from there to Berryville, or
                    they could return from Middleburg to Centreville or Fairfax Court-House. If you
                    make a circuit according to this plan, you will catch Mosby and his guerrilla
                    bands. My opinion is that Gen. Milroy will be attacked in less than ten days
                    unless he is re-enforced. He will be attacked by Jones' cavalry, numbering
                    5,000. They will come via Moorefield, Wardensville, and Cacapon Springs, and
                    push themselves between Winchester and Martinsburg. Simultaneously they will
                    push forward an infantry force from Staunton and New Market down the Valley
                    pike, in front of Winchester. To connect with these, if Hooker's army lies
                    still, Stuart's cavalry will steal a march from Orange Court-House or Culpeper.
                    They will go to Warrenton, from there to Orleans or Salem, from Salem to
                    Springfield or Markham; at these latter points they will be joined by all the
                    guerrilla bands. They will push on between Berryville and Winchester, and
                    connect with Jones, and thus fall upon Milroy whichever road he might retreat
                    on. This information I have gained from different rebels.</p>
                <p>Gen. Milroy is a fighting man, and will render a good account of himself and his
                    army to the American people if he is supplied with this force and the posts
                    above mentioned are occupied-Luray and New Market. It would be securing the
                    Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, also cutting the rebels off from Western Virginia.</p>
                <p>Why not collect your forces at Martinsburg and Harper's Ferry, and throw them up
                    to Gen. Milroy at New Market and Luray? Likewise gather up your forces at New
                    Creek and Romney. Station them at Moorefield or Franklin, or advance them to
                    Harrisonburg. By so doing you render all West Virginia safe. Cut the rebels off
                    from their supplies and hiding-places. Let me again urge it upon you-prevent the
                    rebels from having the benefit of the coming crop.</p>
                <p>Send on all your broken-down horses that you have at Washington, Alexandria, or
                    in Hooker's army, and let them be fed and recruited up in the splendid pasture
                    lands of the rebel farms in the Valley, which are all going to waste. Send
                    agents along, that they may scour the country and gather up all arms and saddles
                    belonging to the United States or so-called Confederate States. Be in earnest,
                    and give them no quarter, for they are determined to break up an destroy the
                    Government if they can. Their whole dependence now is on the expected division
                    in the North-that the Democrats will resist the conscription, and thus assist
                    the South.</p>
                <p>Excuse my boldness in thus addressing you. As to who and what I am, I refer you
                    to Maj.-Gen. Milroy or to Maj.-Gen. Banks or any of his staff.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>You most obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>MICHAEL GRAHAM,<lb/> Mount Jackson, Shenandoah County, Va.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
