<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12540792"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12540792">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12540792</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498969</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXVII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 25, Serial No. 40</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 792</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-11">1863-05-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12540792T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes J. E. B. Stuart on cavalry operations following the battle
                    of Chancellorsville. Lee informs Stuart of his orders to Albert Jenkins to go to
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS.
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. J. E. B. STUART,<lb/> Cmdg. Cavalry:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-11">May 11, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Fredericksburg,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your note of the 9th, and I am glad that the railroad bridge will be
                    so soon completed. When it is done, unless circumstances in your opinion
                    prevent, I request you to move into Culpeper, where you can better observe the
                    enemy. I shall be glad to get your view as to the increase of the cavalry, and I
                    need not assure you that nothing will be wanted on my part to augment it. Do you
                    know how many brigades compose the cavalry divisions of the enemy, and who are
                    the brigade commanders? If you think a visit to Richmond, on your part, will
                    expedite the organization or equipment of your command, I have no objection,
                    but, on the contrary, recommend it. I believe I told you of my wish to place
                    Jenkins' cavalry in the Valley and draw Jones' to you. I thought it would give
                    you a more reliable and larger force, from which you could re-enforce either
                    flank, a necessary. What do you think of it? I have ordered Jenkins to assemble
                    his companies (which have been scattered for forage) at Staunton. Hood is at
                    Fredericksburg Hall. Communicate with him, and keep him advised of movements of
                    enemy. I have directed him, as far as possible, to guard bridges over the North
                    Anna, &amp;c. I hope between you two you may scatter Stoneman. Rhett has
                    been ordered from Gordonsville to Richmond. His troops I think necessary there.</p>
                <p>As regards the closing remarks of your note, I am at a loss to understand their
                    reference or to know what has given rise to them. In the management of the
                    difficult operations at Chancellorsville, which you so promptly undertook and
                    creditably performed, I saw no errors to correct, nor has there been a fitting
                    opportunity to commend your conduct. I prefer your acts to speak for themselves,
                    nor does your character or reputation require bolstering by out-of-place
                    expression of my opinions.</p>
                <p>I regret to inform you that the great and good Jackson is no more. He died
                    yesterday at 3.15 p.m., of pneumonia, calm, serene, and happy May his spirit
                    pervade our whole army; our country will then be secure.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very truly, yours,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--From indications observed yesterday, it seems
                        probable Gen. Hooker is contemplating some new movement. The late Washington
                        papers seem also to indicate something. They claim a great victory. Keep
                        your scouts on the alert.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
