<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1254082"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1254082">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXVII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxvii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Milroy, Robert</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1254082</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498975</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXVII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxvii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Milroy, Robert</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 25, Serial No. 40</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 81-82</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-02-15">1863-02-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1254082T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Robert Milroy writes General Robert Schenck in February, 1863, on a
                    variety of subjects. He reports on a mother and daughter returning to Herkimer,
                    NY, from La Grange, GA, by way of Staunton, VA, and the information they can
                    supply on social conditions in the Confederacy. Milroy complains about prices on
                    the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and the lack of paymasters for his command.
                    Milroy also discusses wheat prices in the Valley.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. MILROY'S DIVISION
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. SCHENCK:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-02-15">February 15, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>This will be handed you by Lieut.-Col. Starr, of the Ninth West Virginia, who
                    goes to Baltimore for the double purpose of obtaining some medical treatment
                    that he cannot obtain here (he having a surgeon's certificate showing its
                    necessity), and of escorting to your headquarters two ladies just from La
                    Grange, Ga., by way of Richmond and Staunton, to this place, by means of a pass
                    from the rebel Secretary of War. Mrs. N. A. Wilson and daughter, Miss G. C.
                    Wilson, are the two ladies referred to. The mother brings her invalid daughter
                    North for the ostensible purpose of procuring medical treatment, but more for
                    the purpose of escaping rebel insults, tyranny, and the increasing misery of the
                    South, they being natives of Herkimer County, New York, to which they are
                    returning, having been residents of La Grange, Ga., for a number of years as
                    milliners and dressmakers. They are destitute of funds, except some Confederate
                    scrip, which is worthless, as they leave Dixie, and I send them on their way as
                    far as Baltimore. Mrs. W. can give you much interesting information about
                    Southern society and the extremity and misery to which they have been reduced by
                    the war. She can also tell what she was heard of their general designs and
                    movements, especially against this place. Col. Starr can post you as to matters
                    here. This place being the first place to be attacked (if rebels west of the
                    Blue Ridge in great force), and the key to the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, I
                    hope you will soon conclude to let me have at least the whole of my command
                    here.</p>
                <p>The letter of L. Th's Prince to you of the 6th instant, referred by indorsements
                    to me, is received. The reports there referred to are reiterated by Mrs. Wilson.
                    I have heard in several different ways that I am to be surrounded and captured .
                    They may come in sufficient numbers to surround me, but they will never capture
                    me. What Mr. Prince said of traitors being employed on the Baltimore and Ohio
                    Railroad I have good reason to believe to be true, as I have heard it from many
                    sources and from reliable Union men. That railroad is at this time costing our
                    Government at least $50,000 per day, and yet it is gutting the Government and
                    the soldiers engaged in its defense in every way and occasion that offers. They
                    take advantage of the necessity of sending a dead soldier's body home to extort
                    four or five prices for fare. A short time ago the body of a soldier of the One
                    hundred and twenty-second Ohio was taken from this place to Martinsburg, to be
                    shipped to Ohio. The brother of the deceased who went with it had but $25 to pay
                    charges on the body, contained in a tight box, but when he applied to know and
                    pay charges in advance, as is always required, he was told that he must pay $50
                    to the Ohio River. Not having the funds, he was obliged to bring the body back
                    to this place for interment. That is the way that the traitor employes of this
                    railroad treat its Union defenders. I understand that many of them are
                    open-mouthed traitors, and that the larger portion of them are secretly
                    sympathizers with the traitors. This Augean stable needs cleaning out badly. I
                    reported a lot of these traitor employes to Gen. Kelley several weeks ago, but
                    the general is one of those good-natured, kind-hearted gentlemen who would much
                    rather at any time meet a traitor with a stick of candy than the sword, and
                    excused them.</p>
                <p>Great God! why can we not have paymasters sent here? They have been everywhere
                    else weeks ago. The tales of anguish and misery that come to me from my poor
                    soldiers, whose helpless families are dependent upon their scanty pay, which has
                    been withheld six and eight months, is truly heart-rending. It is very damaging
                    to the morale of the army, as it is very much impairing confidence in the
                    Government among the soldiers, and is creating deep discontent and hatred of the
                    service, and a strong desire to get out of it on any terms, to go home to their
                    suffering families. This evil should be promptly remedied. Our quartermasters
                    and commissaries, too, are and have for a long time been out of funds. There is
                    a large amount of wheat in this Valley yet, and the farmers are anxious to sell
                    it if they can get the money for it. They have saved by not trashing it. Flour
                    of the best quality can be had here from $6.25 to $6.75, while the Government
                    contractors in Baltimore are paying from $8.50 to $8.75. This should be looked
                    after, as it would cost the Government nothing to deliver flour on the railroad
                    by return trains, and we would be exhausting the enemy's country of supplies.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully yours, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed>R. H. MILROY,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
