<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12743212"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12743212">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>McCreary, William G.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12743212</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498993</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>McCreary, William G.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 211-212</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-20">1863-07-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12743212T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Captain William McCreary reports on the July, 1863, pursuit of Lee's army
                    from Gettysburg. McCreary mentions officers and troops being stationed at
                    Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 20. Report of Capt. William G. McCreary, Signal Officer.
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-20">July 20, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Signal Camp of Instruction,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Captain:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of operations from July 6 to July
                    16, 1863, during the retreat of the rebel forces under General Lee from
                    Maryland:</p>
                <p>I received my orders July 6, and same evening started for Frederick; arrived
                    there on the evening of the 7th instant. On the 8th, the Army of the Potomac
                    being on the move, I started for South Mountain, where our advance line rested.
                    Was ordered back to Middletown by you, to open a station there. Upon my arrival
                    there, I found General Meade had established his headquarters, and Captain
                    Norton agreeing to relieve me with one of his officers, I returned to report to
                    you at the pass. Early next morning, with the advance of our troops, in company
                    with yourself, advanced beyond Boonsborough, when I was directed by you to
                    report to the right, with the right brigade of General Buford's cavalry
                    division, General Merritt commanding, Captain Daniels being in the center and
                    Lieutenant Tuckerman on the left of same division, to keep open communication
                    along the line.</p>
                <p>Soon after taking our positions, an advance was made along the line, and we
                    advanced with them. At the crossing of Beaver Creek, the enemy were established
                    with infantry, cavalry, and artillery, to dispute our advance, but after a
                    severe skirmish were driven back.</p>
                <p>Early next morning, July 10, moved forward, and drove them to Antietam, a
                    distance of 4 miles. During this movement, I was in communication with Captain
                    Daniels, but the rapid movements of our forces prevented sending many messages;
                    but from our points of observation much valuable information was furnished the
                    commanding officers, for which we received their personal thanks.</p>
                <p>On the 11th instant, I was requested by you to proceed to Black Rock, an elevated
                    and naked rock on South Mountain Range, but on my arrival found the valley so
                    covered with fog that I was unable to see anything, and returned to the valley.</p>
                <p>On the 12th, again went to Black Rock, and on that day and the 13th endeavored to
                    get communication, but in vain. On the evening of the 13th, left and went to
                    Funkstown.</p>
                <p>Early on the morning of the 14th, received communication from Captain Daniels
                    that the enemy had vacated their works. This communication you furnished General
                    Howard. About 5.15 a. m., with yourself, rode forward to their works, where
                    Lieutenant Galbraith opened a station. At this point met some citizens who had
                    been impressed by the rebels on the previous night and compelled to act as
                    guides, and when within 2 miles of Williamsport had been permitted to return.
                    Their report that there were no rebels on this side of Williamsport was
                    transmitted to General Meade by you. After consulting you, concluded our best
                    course was to proceed and try to get the same information to General Kelley, at
                    Fairview. On arriving at the junction of the Fairview and Greencastle turnpike,
                    an orderly, Private Voohees, of the Sixth New York Cavalry, who had been
                    assigned me, was sent with dispatches to meet the Pennsylvania troops, said to
                    be coming from Chambersburg. Near Greencastle he met the column under General
                    Dana, who, considering the dispatches important, sent him to General Couch, at
                    Chambersburg. General Couch thanked the signal officer for the timely
                    information (these arrived five hours in advance of the dispatches from General
                    Meade), and caused a rapid movement of these forces.</p>
                <p>At the Conococheague Bridge a Union paroled soldier and a rebel of the Sixth
                    North Carolina Infantry were picked up. The former had been across the Potomac,
                    and reported that the enemy were almost entirely across. The rebel was sent to
                    General Kelley.</p>
                <p>On approaching Clear Spring, met the advance of General Averell's cavalry
                    brigade, cautiously feeling their way. On being informed there was no enemy in
                    their front, they halted until we could inform Generals Averell and Kelley; upon
                    doing so, General Kelley immediately moved his whole division rapidly in the
                    direction of Williamsport.</p>
                <p>After resting our horses, we followed, overtaking the column, and arrived at
                    Williamsport to find the enemy gone, as we had reported. Although the weather
                    was such that but comparatively little could be accomplished by signals, yet I
                    received the personal thanks of Generals Merritt, Kelly, and Averell for much
                    valuable and reliable information furnished them. From this point returned to
                    camp.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
