<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745988"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745988">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745988.sgml</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499153</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 987-988</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-09">1863-07-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745988T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes General John Imboden concerning the July, 1863, situation in
                    the Shenandoah Valley. Lee orders Imboden to do his best to get prisoners to
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Army of Northern Virginia,
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. J. D. Imboden, Comdg., &amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-09">July 9, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of 8 p. m. yesterday was received.</p>
                <p>I hope Col. G. W. Imboden will get correct information as regards the enemy
                    stated by you to be advancing from Hancock. I request you to desire him to sift
                    the reports that may reach him, and report only such as he has reason to believe
                    to be correct.</p>
                <p>It will be necessary for him to keep his cavalry active, and instruct men and
                    officers to be steady, and to oppose vigorously the advance of any parties that
                    may present themselves. I do not believe the force can be large; probably only
                    some cavalry.</p>
                <p>It would be an unwise measure for a small body of infantry to attempt to force
                    its way through this army to join the main body of the enemy, which is certainly
                    beyond South Mountain. I do not think they will attempt it.</p>
                <p>You must turn over this matter to Col. Imboden, and yourself attend to getting
                    the prisoners on to Staunton as soon as possible. I hope you will bend all your
                    energies to this subject, and get them along with as much expedition and comfort
                    as circumstances will permit.</p>
                <p>I have directed Lieut.-Col. Thomas B. Massie to advance a portion of his cavalry
                    from Charlestown to Martinsburg, to give additional security to your movement;
                    so you may look out for him.</p>
                <p>I desire you to organize the companies of which you spoke yesterday, as soon as
                    possible, and collect all your serviceable men, and get back to this army as
                    soon as you can.</p>
                <p>Unless Col. H. B. Davidson can place a guard at the Shenandoah Mountain, you will
                    still have to retain a guard at that point, with directions to report to him.
                    You must take as small a guard from Gen. Pickett's command as you can possible
                    do with, and carry it no farther than Winchester, as we want every man now with
                    this army.</p>
                <p>I presume your battery that operates with your cavalry is mounted as horse
                    artillery. If so, it will require no support but the cavalry itself.</p>
                <p>If they have more guns than they require, the surplus can be sent back to
                    Williamsport.</p>
                <p>It will be necessary for Col. Imboden to picket well out on the road, or he will
                    be of no service whatever. He must throw his pickets well out, and keep his men
                    on the alert, and not suffer them to be surprised or taken. His operations must
                    be conducted with boldness and prudence. I regret to hear that a part of his men
                    deserted some wagons when threatened by the enemy, which, as far as reported to
                    me, was not necessary. I do not know the facts, but mention the report to call
                    the attention of Col. Imboden to it, in order that he may inquire into it, and
                    prevent the repetition of such conduct.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
