<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744230"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12744230">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Yates, Charles</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744230</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499000</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Yates, Charles</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 229-231</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-30">1863-09-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744230T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Charles Yates reports on the role New York State National Guard
                    troops played in the defense of Pennsylvania during the June and July, 1863,
                    Gettysburg campaign, including service in the Chambersburg area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 409. Report of Brig. Gen. Charles Yates, commanding Second Brigade, New
                    York State National Guard, of operations June 18--July 18.
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. Charles W. Sandford,<lb/> Comdg. First Division,
                        New York State Militia.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-30">September 30, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hdqrs. 2d Brig., New York State National Guards,<lb/> New
                            York,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Herewith I transmit the reports of the several commandants of regiments of this
                    brigade, detailing the duties assigned to them while in the service of the
                    United States in June and July last:</p>
                <p>On the 18th of June, I ordered Maj. Gardiner, of my staff, to repair immediately
                    to Harrisburg, to attend to the several regiments on their arrival there. On the
                    20th of June, I arrived at Harrisburg with my staff, and reported immediately to
                    Maj.-Gen. Couch, pursuant to your orders. The Fifth, Twelfth, and Fourth Regt.'s
                    arrived there at about the same time. The day following our arrival, the Fourth
                    was placed on detached service at Camp Curtin and elsewhere, and was not under
                    my command during any portion of the residue of the term of service.</p>
                <p>The Sixth and Eighty-fourth Regt.'s were ordered to report at Baltimore, and the
                    Seventy-first, assigned by your orders to my brigade, was, on its arrival at
                    Harrisburg, also placed on detached service in another command. The reports of
                    the commandants of the above-named regiments will show the fidelity with which
                    they discharged the duties assigned to them.</p>
                <p>The staff organization of my brigade was as follows: Maj. Charles Trumbull White,
                    assistant adjutant-general; Maj. Henry D. Gardiner, brigade quartermaster; Capt.
                    Henry C. Landon, commissary; Capt. J. Hobart Herrick, ordnance officer; Capt.
                    Reginald H. Anthon, aide. Capt. Anthon, having been taken ill in consequence of
                    severe exposure in the discharge of his duties, obtained leave of absence, and
                    Capt. Benjamin S. Church, of the Twelfth Regt., was assigned to his post during
                    the residue of our term of service.</p>
                <p>On the 21st of June, I was directed to proceed with the Fifth and Twelfth
                    Regt.'s, numbering together about 1,000 men, early the next day, to Marysville
                    and Fenwick, at the junction of the Dauphin and Susquehanna Valleys, about 6
                    miles above Harrisburg, to guard two railroad bridges crossing the Susquehanna
                    at that point. The Dauphin Valley runs parallel with the Cumberland Valley,
                    being connected with it by several mountain gaps, the farthest of which is
                    Sterrett's Gap, through which the road to Carlisle passes.</p>
                <p>The enemy being then advancing toward Harrisburg, it was supposed he might make a
                    diversion to the left, pass down the Dauphin Valley, and cross the Susquehanna.
                    Our position, therefore, assumed a very important character, and required very
                    great diligence in checking a movement of that kind. On arriving at the Dauphin
                    Valley, the only force we found there consisted of about 50 or 60 men of the
                    Invalid Corps, stationed at block-houses near the bridges. We immediately
                    commenced constructing such earthworks in front and flank as were deemed
                    necessary, and selected a position to make a determined stand, the left flank of
                    our contemplated line being protected by an obstruction of felled woods, and the
                    narrow pass along the Susquehanna being guarded by such force as could be spared
                    for that purpose.</p>
                <p>Various detachments from time to time were sent with ax-men, to obstruct and
                    guard the mountain gaps. During their service there they were exposed to almost
                    incessant rains, having only their shelter tents to protect them from the
                    inclemency of the weather. These detachments performed the duty assigned to them
                    with alacrity and fidelity. During a portion of the term of service in the
                    Dauphin Valley, we were very materially aided by the Thirteenth and
                    Twenty-eighth New York National Guard, under the command of Brig. Gen. Philip S.
                    Crooke, and three companies of the Twenty-eighth Pennsylvania Militia, under the
                    command of Maj. Jessup. Gen. Crooke and Maj. Jessup, with their officers and
                    men, diligently cooperated with me in the performance of the several duties
                    assigned to them.</p>
                <p>On the 7th of July, we proceeded by rail, with the Fifth and Twelfth Regt.'s, to
                    Carlisle; thence on the 8th and 9th, by march, by way of the turnpike, to
                    Shippensburg. At this place, the Twentieth, Thirty-fifth, and Forty-fifth
                    Pennsylvania Militia were attached to my brigade, then denominated the First
                    Brigade of the Second Division of the Department of the Susquehanna, under the
                    command of Maj.-Gen. Dana, to whom I reported for duty. Under his orders, the
                    brigade was marched to a point 1 mile beyond Chambersburg,where it was further
                    re-enforced by the Twenty-sixth Regt. Pennsylvania Militia and a battery of
                    United States artillery. It then comprised the Fifth and Twelfth New York
                    National Guard and the Twentieth, Twenty-sixth, Thirty-fifth, and Forty-fifth
                    Pennsylvania Militia, and Battery --, Fifth U.S. Artillery, and numbered nearly
                    4,300 officers, non-commissioned officers, and men.</p>
                <p>From Chambersburg our brigade and the other brigades of the Second Division were
                    marched to Greencastle. The whole division comprised about 12,000 men. On the
                    arrival of the division at Greencastle, we learned that Gen. Lee had crossed the
                    Potomac, with the whole rebel army. In consequence of this, and the near
                    expiration of our term of service, I received orders to proceed the next day
                    with the Fifth and Twelfth Regt.'s by march to Shippensburg, and thence by rail
                    to New York, and report to Maj.-Gen. Wool, commanding the Department of the
                    East. We arrived at New York on the evening and night of the 18th, and reported
                    accordingly. The regiments did duty at New York until they were mustered out of
                    service.</p>
                <p>The members of the brigade staff were unremitting in the discharge of the duties
                    of their several departments, and performed them with very great regularity. To
                    them as well as to Col. Burger, commanding the Fifth, and Col. Ward, commanding
                    the Twelfth, and their officers and men, and to the officers and men of the
                    several commands attached to my brigade, my acknowledgments are due for the
                    faithful discharge of the several duties assigned to them.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>CHAS. YATES,<lb/> Brig. Gen., Comdg. 2d Brig., New York State National
                        Guard.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
