<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744220"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12744220">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Smith, William F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">21</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744220</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498999</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Smith, William F.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 220-223</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-18">1863-06-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744220T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General William F. Smith reports on the role played by his troops during
                    the Gettysburg campaign. He discusses the defense of Harrisburg and York, the
                    actions of state militia troops, and the pursuit south of the Army of Northern
                    Virginia. Smith mentions procuring supplies in Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 407. Report of Brig. Gen. William F. Smith, U.S. Army, commanding First
                    Division, of operations June 26-July 15.
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-18">July 18, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hdqrs. First Division, Dept. of the Susquehanna,<lb/>
                            Greencastle, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Maj.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have to report that, in obedience to orders from the general commanding, I
                    assumed command of the troops south of the Susquehanna and in the vicinity of
                    Harrisburg on Friday, June 26, and was busily engaged until Tuesday, 30th, in
                    strengthening the defenses at Bridgeport, opposite the city of Harrisburg, and
                    at Marysville, to protect the bridges of the Pennsylvania and Northern Central
                    Railroads.</p>
                <p>On Sunday, a rebel cavalry force, with a section of artillery, came to our picket
                    line near Oyster Point, and drove in our cavalry pickets, but did not succeed in
                    moving the infantry pickets.</p>
                <p>On Monday, I sent the regular cavalry, under Lieut. Frank Stanwood, on the
                    Carlisle road, and he engaged and drove in the pickets of the enemy, but was
                    obliged to retire under a fire of artillery which was opened on him.</p>
                <p>On Tuesday, learning that the rebel infantry had left Carlisle, the cavalry was
                    ordered forward, and found the enemy at Sporting Hill. Gen. Ewen, New York
                    militia, in command of the Twenty-second and Thirty-seventh New York State
                    Militia, went forward to support Lieut. Stanwood, and a section of Landis'
                    battery, under the direction of Lieut. Muhlenberg, was immediately ordered up.
                    The enemy was found in position, and attacked about 4 p. m. The artillery
                    arrived on the ground about 5 p. m., and soon silenced the fire of the enemy.</p>
                <p>Gen. Ewen's command was ordered forward to occupy Carlisle, but did not march
                    until the next morning. Capt. Boyd, First New York Cavalry, with 120 men, was
                    also ordered by the Trindle Spring road, via Churchtown, to Carlisle. He stopped
                    at Churchtown, and entered Carlisle on the morning of July 1.</p>
                <p>Col. Brisbane, commanding the Pennsylvania Brigade, was ordered to move on
                    Carlisle by the mud road at daylight, but, owing to a want of transportation,
                    did not move until about 9 a. m.</p>
                <p>I visited the headquarters to receive instructions and make arrangements for
                    supplies and transportation, and, recrossing the river, the remainder of the
                    command, under Brig.-Gen. Knipe, U.S. Volunteers, was directed to march as far
                    as practicable and encamp, and to move at an early hour in the morning.</p>
                <p>The Eleventh New York Artillery, under Col. Forbes, refused to march under
                    certain pleas, and the matter was referred to Gen. Couch. This delayed my
                    starting till 3.30 p. m., and finally, leaving orders with Gen. Knipe to carry
                    out the instructions with reference to the refractory regiment, I left to join
                    the advance. Hearing rumors on the road of a large cavalry force in the
                    vicinity, I sent out scouts on the cross-roads, and pushed on, entering Carlisle
                    at sunset.</p>
                <p>Gen. Ewen had passed through the town on the Baltimore turnpike about 1 1/2
                    miles, and, while going on to examine his position, word came from my scouts
                    that a large cavalry force of the enemy was in the immediate vicinity, on the
                    York road, and, turning back, before I entered the village, their guns had
                    opened on us. The road for several miles back of us was filled with stragglers
                    from the brigades of Gen. Ewen and Col. Brisbane, and the men with me were
                    wearied with a long march, to which they were unused.</p>
                <p>Under these circumstances, I determined to content myself till morning with
                    simply holding the town, but before I could get a line of skirmishers out, a
                    summons was sent by Gen. Fitzhugh Lee to surrender the town, or send out the
                    women and children. I sent an answer that the women and children would be
                    notified to leave. In less than half an hour, another message was sent to the
                    purport that, if not surrendered, the town would be burned. The answer was
                    returned that one answer had already been given. I then sent a volunteer aide,
                    Mr. Ward, of Harrisburg, to communicate with Gen. Knipe, and order him to march
                    at 3 a. m., and to report to Gen. Couch the position of affairs. In the meantime
                    the enemy opened a battery on the town, to which, by my orders, our artillery
                    did not reply, as I deemed the fire too inaccurate, and wished to save my
                    ammunition.</p>
                <p>About 11 o'clock I sent another volunteer aide, Mr. James Dougherty, to try and
                    get to Gen. Knipe with orders to move immediately. Mr. Dougherty was captured
                    and his orderly wounded, and about 12 m. a third and last summons came to
                    surrender, to which the reply was given that the message had been twice answered
                    before.</p>
                <p>About 1 o'clock the firing ceased, with the exception of three guns about 3 a.
                    m., soon after which reports came in that the enemy was moving off on a country
                    road which came into the turnpike about 2 1/2 miles from Carlisle, and by
                    daylight there was nothing opposed to us.</p>
                <p>The casualties were 12 wounded, none fatally.</p>
                <p>Thursday, July 2, the entire command was put in near the barracks, which had been
                    burned during the night, and on Friday a train of provisions came up to
                    Carlisle. The supplies which we could draw from the citizens were extremely
                    limited, though every disposition to aid us was manifested.</p>
                <p>Gen. Knipe's command having joined me on Friday, the whole command was put in
                    motion at 6 a. m. on Saturday for Mount Holly, where we were detained for two
                    hours by the arrival of about 2,000 prisoners, paroled on the battle-field, and
                    sent under a flag of truce toward Carlisle. Wishing to prevent the enemy from
                    getting information of our strength, I was forced to accept the prisoners,
                    subject to the decision of the Government, and turn the rebel escort back. The
                    Thirty-seventh New York Militia Regt. was left at Mount Holly to watch the
                    Baltimore road, and the command moved toward Pine Grove.</p>
                <p>A most furious rain-storm set in, which raised the creeks, carried away bridges,
                    and made the march toilsome in the extreme. The command of Gen. Ewen was left at
                    Laurel Forge, to cover the entrance to the narrow valley, and also watch a road
                    leading over the mountain to Bendersville. The remainder of the force was
                    concentrated at Pine Grove Furnace, the Eighth New York State Militia being
                    ordered to hold the pass to Bendersville from Pine Grove.</p>
                <p>On Sunday, Gen. Knipe was ordered with his command to hold the cross-roads from
                    Mount Holly to Cashtown and Pine Grove to Bendersville, while Gen. Ewen crossed
                    the mountain to the Mount Holly and Cashtown road, holding the pass in his rear,
                    and being within a mile of Gen. Knipe's command. Col. Brisbane, with the
                    Pennsylvania Brigade, was holding a by-road from Pine Grove to Cashtown. A
                    cavalry scout, under Lieut. Stanwood, was sent up Mountain Creek Valley, in the
                    direction of the pass from Chambersburg to Gettysburg, through which it was
                    supposed the enemy would send his trains, if he were defeated. Lieut. Stanwood
                    drove in the pickets a couple of miles from the turnpike, but had not sufficient
                    force to press on. Capt. Boyd joined me at Pine Grove, having followed the rear
                    guard of the enemy to Fayetteville, on the Gettysburg and Chambersburg road,
                    capturing prisoners. He was directed to pass by Bendersville, in the direction
                    of Cashtown, to try and ascertain the movements and position of the enemy. He
                    fell in with them, and captured eight wagons and--prisoners. During the day a
                    small provision train came up, which was very acceptable, as it was impossible
                    to subsist the troops from the country. A scout from Gen. Meade also came
                    through, giving the information that the enemy was retiring; and, later in the
                    day, Capt. West, a volunteer aide and assistant on the Coast Survey, returned,
                    having successfully opened communications with Gen. Meade on Saturday from Mount
                    Holly.</p>
                <p>On Monday morning, I marched the brigade by three different roads, concentrating
                    at Newman's Pass behind Cashtown. We were, however, too late to intercept the
                    trains which had gone that route.</p>
                <p>Tuesday morning, I was proposing to enter the Cumberland Valley and follow down
                    the mountains toward Boonsborough, when an order came from Gen. Meade to march
                    to Gettysburg, which order was shortly after countermanded, with permission to
                    do as I had proposed. The command was then marched to Altodale, and an officer
                    sent to Chambersburg, to try and procure supplies, as my trains had failed to
                    overtake me. A small supply being procured, the troops were marched on Wednesday
                    to Waynesborough, where I found Gen. Neill, with a brigade of infantry and one
                    of cavalry, and eight pieces of artillery. Here I was forced to wait for my
                    trains to come up, but sent a cavalry scout to communicate with Gen. Meade, west
                    of South Mountain.</p>
                <p>Thursday was spent in waiting for rations to come up, and for instructions from
                    Gen. Meade.</p>
                <p>On Friday, I was ordered by him to occupy the enemy to the best advantage, and to
                    be ready to join the Army of the Potomac or Gen. Couch, as circumstances might
                    require. Col. McIntosh was at once ordered with his brigade of cavalry and four
                    guns to feel the enemy along the Antietam below Leitersburg, which he did in the
                    most skillful manner, driving his cavalry pickets across the creek upon their
                    infantry and artillery supports. The cavalry was supported in this movement by
                    two regiments of Pennsylvania militia, under Col. Frick, at Ringgold and
                    Smithsburg, and one regiment, Forty-third New York Volunteers, from Gen. Neill's
                    command, posted near Leitersburg.</p>
                <p>On Saturday, hearing that the rebels had ordered a miller on Marsh Run to grind
                    wheat all night for them, Col. Brisbane, with two regiments of Pennsylvania
                    militia, was ordered, if possible, to intercept the wagons going for the flour,
                    and destroy the grain if he could not bring it off. These regiments were
                    supported by the Sixty-first Pennsylvania Volunteers, of Gen. Neill's command.
                    From 2 prisoners captured at the mill, we learned that the enemy had fallen back
                    to Hagerstown.</p>
                <p>Col. Brisbane's command was left at Waynesborough, with orders to march at
                    daylight, and the rest of the troops were moved to Leitersburg, excepting the
                    command of Col. Frick, which was ordered from Ringgold to Chewsville.</p>
                <p>During the night an order came for Gen. Neill to join the Army of the Potomac at
                    once, and, as no instructions were sent to me, I ordered Col. Brisbane to remain
                    at Waynesborough, to guard my communications, and moved with what force I had
                    with me to Cavetown. After posting my troops there, I reported in person to Gen.
                    Meade, and recommended to him to divide my command among the old divisions of
                    the Army of the Potomac before the anticipated battle. Under the supposition
                    that this was to be done, I ordered Col. Brisbane to Hagerstown, and moved with
                    the rest of the command to the Boonsborough turnpike, near Beaver Creek. Gen.
                    Meade declined to distribute the militia, and I remained until Wednesday
                    morning, when I received orders to send the New York State militia home, via
                    Frederick, and the necessary orders were given. The Pennsylvania militia were
                    concentrated at Hagerstown, under Col. Brisbane, who was appointed military
                    governor, with instructions to watch the ford at Williamsport and Falling
                    Waters.</p>
                <p>Before closing, I must call to the remembrance of the general commanding the
                    force that I moved without a quartermaster or commissary, without supply trains,
                    some regiments even being without haversacks, and with no adequate
                    transportation of the cooking utensils of the men, and must pay the proper
                    tribute to the general behavior of the troops during long marches, in rainy
                    weather and without sufficient food. The rugged mountain roads left many of them
                    barefooted, but the greater portion of the command seemed animated by a desire
                    to do all that was required in the service of their country.</p>
                <p>Col. Brisbane deserves special mention for the manner in which he managed and led
                    his command, and I earnestly recommend him to notice.</p>
                <p>Capt. Boyd, First New York Cavalry, also did gallant service with his small
                    force.</p>
                <p>I am much indebted to Capt. M. A. Reno, U.S. Cavalry, who acted as my chief of
                    staff; to Lieut. Muhlenberg, my chief of artillery; to Lieut. Rufus King, Fourth
                    U.S. Artillery, and to Lieut. Johnson, U.S. Cavalry, for their services. To my
                    own aides-Lieut.'s Matthew Berry and Campbell Tucker, and the following
                    gentlemen, who were volunteer aides: Col. McCormick, Capts. P. C. F. West and
                    Lamborn, Lieuts. Samuel Carey, F. Rogers, and--Evans, and Mr. Ward--I am
                    indebted for zealous and indefatigable service.</p>
                <p>Dr. John Neill, medical director of the division, was particularly watchful and
                    efficient in the discharge of his duties.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>WM. F SMITH,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
