<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1274569"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R1274569">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Couch, Darius</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1274569</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499096</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Couch, Darius</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 68-69</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-11">1863-06-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1274569T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>These June, 1863, Union orders create a new military department in Pennsylvania
                    and call for the creation of a volunteer Army Corps of the Susquehanna to defend
                    Pennsylvania from Robert E. Lee's impending invasion. The orders make General
                    Darius Couch commander of the department with headquarters at Chambersburg. The
                    orders also provide regulations for the organization of the volunteer army corps
                    including pay, the commissioning of officers, term of service, and the
                    volunteers' relation to Federal forces.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Gen. Orders No. 1., Hdqrs. Dept. of the Susquehanna
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-11">June 11, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>The undersigned assumes command of this department.</p>
                <p>In view of the danger of invasion now threatening the State of Pennsylvania by
                    the enemies of the Government, a new military department has been made, by
                    direction of the War Department, embracing all the territory of Pennsylvania
                    east of Johnstown and the Laurel Hill range of mountains, headquarters at
                    Chambersburg.</p>
                <p>To prevent serious raids by the enemy, it is deemed necessary to call upon the
                    citizens of Pennsylvania to furnish promptly all the men necessary to organize
                    an army corps of volunteer infantry, artillery, and cavalry, to be designated
                    the Army Corps of the Susquehanna. They will be enrolled and organized in
                    accordance with the regulations of the United States service, for the protection
                    and defense of the public and private property within this department, and will
                    be mustered into the service of the United States, to serve during the pleasure
                    of the President or the continuance of the war.</p>
                <p>The company and field officers of the Departmental Corps will be provisionally
                    commissioned by the President, upon the recommendation of the general
                    commanding.</p>
                <p>They will be armed, uniformed, equipped, and, while in active service, subsisted
                    and supplied as other troops of the United States.</p>
                <p>When not required for active service to defend the department, they will be
                    returned to their homes, subject to the call of the commanding general.</p>
                <p>Cavalry volunteers may furnish their own horses, to be turned over to the United
                    States at their appraised value, or allowance will be made for the time of
                    actual service at the rate authorized by law.</p>
                <p>All able-bodied volunteers between the ages of eighteen and sixty will be
                    enrolled and received into this corps.</p>
                <p>The volunteers for State defense will receive no bounty, but will be paid the
                    same as for like service in the Army of the United States for the time they may
                    be in actual service, as soon as Congress may make an appropriation for that
                    purpose.</p>
                <p>If volunteers belonging to this army corps desire, they can be transferred to the
                    volunteer service for three years, or during the war, when they will be entitled
                    to all the bounties and privileges granted by the acts of Congress.</p>
                <p>The general commanding, in accordance with the foregoing general authority, calls
                    upon all citizens within this department to come forward promptly, to perfect
                    company organizations under United States regulations, to wit: 1 captain, 1
                    first lieutenant, 1 second lieutenant, 64 privates as a minimum and 82 as a
                    maximum standard of each company.</p>
                <p>The general commanding especially desires that citizens of this district recently
                    in the army should volunteer for duty in this army corps, thereby from their
                    experience adding greatly to the efficiency of the force for immediate defensive
                    operations.</p>
                <p>Each company organization to be perfected as soon as possible, and report the
                    name of officer in command, the number of men, and the place of its
                    headquarters, in order that they may be promptly furnished with transportation
                    to the general rendezvous, which will be at Harrisburg.</p>
                <p>Any person who will furnish 40 or more men who will be enrolled, if otherwise
                    unobjectionable, will be entitled to a captaincy; any person who will bring 25
                    or more men, under above condition, will be entitled to a lieutenancy, and any
                    person who will bring 15 or more men, under same conditions, to a second
                    lieutenancy.</p>
                <p>On arriving at the place of rendezvous, they will be formed into regiments so far
                    as practicable, and as may be found consistent with the interests of the public
                    service. Companies from the same locality will be put together in regimental
                    organizations.</p>
                <p>For the present, all communications will be addressed to Harrisburg. Chiefs of
                    the respective departments will report accordingly.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>D. N. COUCH,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Comdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
