<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745916"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745916">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745916</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499142</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 916-917</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-22">1863-06-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745916T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Army of Northern Virginia Medical Director Lafayette Guild writes Confederate
                    Army Surgeon General Samuel P. Moore concerning Guild's efforts to provide for
                    the sick and wounded from the Gettysburg campaign and the June, 1863, battle of
                    Winchester in particular. Guild desires to have all sick and wounded sent to
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Medical Director's Office,
                    <name type="recipient">Dr. S. P. Moore,<lb/> Surgeon-Gen., C. S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-22">June 22, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Berryville, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The First and Third Corps of this army are now concentrated in the vicinity of
                    Berryville and the two Gaps of the Blue Ridge-Ashby's and Snicker's. I have
                    directed that all our sick and wounded be collected at Jordan's Springs
                    preparatory to their removal up the Valley to Staunton.</p>
                <p>The town of Winchester is in such a filthy condition, and low forms of fever so
                    rife, that I deemed it unwise to permit any of our sick and wounded to remain
                    there. The Yankee sick and wounded prisoners I have ordered to be placed in a
                    hospital camp just out of town.</p>
                <p>Jordan's Springs is a very suitable place for a hospital; the patients are very
                    well cared for and are comfortable.</p>
                <p>It will be impossible, however, to feed them here but for a short time. Necessity
                    will compel their removal toward Staunton. I am unable to ascertain definitely
                    whether there are hospitals at Harrisonburg and Mount Jackson, and the capacity
                    for their accommodations. These points would make good by-road hospitals,
                    temporarily, in which the sick and wounded who could not bear a long journey in
                    ambulance wagons might be accommodated. It is very desirable, however, that all,
                    if possible, should be sent to Staunton, as those in the intermediate places
                    might fall into the hands of the enemy, in the event of the army's advance or
                    the abandonment of the Valley. There are between 700 and 800 sick and wounded
                    from every portion of our army at Jordan's Springs, a vast majority of whom are
                    very slightly sick, and will soon rejoin their commands.</p>
                <p>The enemy's sick and wounded at Winchester number about 500. Our loss in the
                    battle of Winchester was very small. The list of casualties has not yet been
                    received. Much property of all kinds was captured.</p>
                <p>The Second Army Corps, who were in advance of the army and fought the battle,
                    appropriated "the spoils." A large quantity of medical and hospital supplies
                    must have fallen into our hands, but Medical Director McGuire and his medical
                    officers left behind them only the odds and ends. Surgeon McGuire has not yet
                    forwarded an inventory of the captured articles. Every preparation is being made
                    to enter the enemy's country, as you will perceive from Gen. Orders, No. 72, a
                    copy of which I herewith inclose. I directed Surgeon Geddings to telegraph to
                    you for funds; however, I believe we can manage to make purchases by giving
                    certified receipts, or by transfer of funds from the Quartermaster's Department
                    to the Medical Department. Col. Corley informs me that this transfer will be
                    made, if necessary.</p>
                <p>If medical officers can be spared from Richmond or other general hospitals, I
                    would respectfully request that 12 or 15 surgeons and assistant surgeons be
                    ordered to report to me, for duty with this army, as soon as practicable.</p>
                <p>Our rapid movements and constant skirmishing with the enemy, and insufficient
                    ambulance, make this demand for additional medical officers necessary. I have
                    ordered to Winchester Surgeon J. E. Claggett, with other medical officers, who
                    have been on duty at the different temporary hospitals along the lines of
                    railroad.</p>
                <p>Surgeon Geddings will establish a purveying depot at Winchester for the present.</p>
                <p>I fear there will be some difficulty in transporting the necessary supplies from
                    Staunton by road wagons.</p>
                <p>The purveying depot needs additional assistant surgeons, which I am unable to
                    detach from regiments.</p>
                <p>I respectfully ask that you assign two officers competent to perform the duties.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, sir, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>L. GUILD,<lb/> Medical Director, Army of Northern Virginia.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
