<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744547"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12744547">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Rodes, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">77</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744546</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499016</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Rodes, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 545-561</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value=""/>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744547T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Robert Rodes reports on the actions of his division during
                    the Gettysburg campaign of June and July, 1863. He describes his advance up the
                    Valley, movements through Pennsylvania, and retreat back to Virginia, including
                    the battle of Gettysburg and skirmishing before and after the battle. He
                    discusses procuring supplies at Chambersburg and other towns, and describes the
                    reaction of civilians to his well-disciplined troops. Rodes makes a point of
                    stressing that his men paid for all supplies procured in Pennsylvania, and
                    mentions setting a guard in Chambersburg to protect the people. He mentions one
                    incident of violence at Greencastle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 506. Report of Maj. Gen. R. E. Rodes, C. S. Army, commanding
                    division.
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. A. S. Pendleton,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.,
                        Second Army Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863">1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hdqrs. Rodes' Division, <lb/>Orange Court-House,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Col.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In compliance with orders, I have the honor herewith to submit a report of the
                    operations of this division during the period which elapsed from the breaking up
                    of camp at Grace Church, in Caroline County, to its return to the Rappahannock
                    waters.</p>
                <p>During this period the division was organized as follows: Daniel's (North
                    Carolina) brigade, commanded by Brig. Gen. Junius Daniel, composed of the
                    following regiments: Thirty-second North Carolina, commanded by Col. E. C.
                    Brabble; Forty-third North Carolina, commanded by Col. Thomas S. Kenan;
                    Forty-fifth North Carolina, commanded by Lieut. Col. S. H. Boyd; Fifty-third
                    North Carolina, commanded by Col. W. A. Owens, and Second North Carolina
                    Battalion, commanded by Lieut. Col. H. L. Andrews. Doles' (Georgia) brigade,
                    commanded by Brig. Gen. George Doles, composed of the Fourth Georgia, commanded
                    by Lieut. Col. D. R. E. Winn; Twelfth Georgia, commanded by Col. Edward Willis;
                    Twenty-first Georgia, commanded by Col. John T. Mercer, and Forty-fourth
                    Georgia, commanded by Col. S. P. Lumpkin. Iverson's (North Carolina) brigade,
                    commanded by Brig. Gen. Alfred Iverson, composed of the Fifth North Carolina,
                    commanded by Capt. S. B. West; Twelfth North Carolina, commanded by Lieut. Col.
                    W. S. Davis; Twentieth North Carolina, commanded by Lieut. Col. N. Slough, and
                    Twenty-third North Carolina, commanded by Col. D. H. Christie. Ramseur's (North
                    Carolina) brigade, commanded by Brig. Gen. S. D. Ramseur, composed of the Second
                    North Carolina, commanded by Maj. D. W. Hurtt; Fourth North Carolina, commanded
                    by Col. Bryan Grimes; Fourteenth North Carolina, commanded by Col. R. T.
                    Bennett, and Thirtieth North Carolina, commanded by Col. F. M. Parker. Rodes'
                    (Alabama) brigade, commanded by Col. E. A. O'Neal, composed of Third Alabama,
                    commanded by Col. C. A. Battle; Fifth Alabama, commanded by Col. J. M. Hall;
                    Sixth Alabama, commanded by Col. J. N. Lightfoot; Twelfth Alabama, commanded by
                    Col. S. B. Pickens, and Twenth-sixth Alabama, commanded by Lieut. Col. J. C.
                    Goodgame. Lieut. Col. Thomas H. Carter's battalion of sixteen pieces of
                    artillery, composed of William P. Carter's, R. C. M. Page's, C. W. Fry's, and
                    William J. Reese's batteries.</p>
                <p>Receiving orders on June 3 to march, the division was put in motion early on the
                    morning of the 4th, and, after marching some 16 miles, bivouacked 2 miles north
                    of Spotsylvania Court-House.</p>
                <p>Next day, after a march of 21 miles, turning to the right at Verdierville, in
                    order to cross the Rapidan at Raccoon or Somerville Ford, we bivouacked near Old
                    Verdierville.</p>
                <p>After marching about 4 miles on the 6th, I received orders to halt, and await
                    further orders.</p>
                <p>Resuming the march on the 7th, we crossed the Rapidan at Somerville Ford, passed
                    through Culpeper Court-House, and bivouacked 4 miles beyond, on the Rixeyville
                    road, having marched about 19 miles.</p>
                <p>On the 8th, finding that a long march was ahead of us, and that the supplies had
                    to be closely looked to, I ordered all the baggage, tents, &amp;c., that
                    could be spared to be sent to the rear. By this means, each brigade was enabled
                    to transport three days' rations in its train, in addition to an equal amount in
                    the division commissary train, the men also carrying three days' rations each in
                    his haversack; hence, when the division resumed its march, it was supplied with
                    fully nine days' rations.</p>
                <p>On the 9th, anticipating an order to do so, I moved the division toward Brandy
                    Station, to the support of Gen. Stuart's cavalry. Halting, under Lieut.-Gen.
                    Ewell's orders, at Botts' place, I subsequently, under orders, advanced to
                    Barbour's house, in advance of the station, but did not get in reach of the
                    enemy, he having apparently been repulsed by the cavalry.</p>
                <p>On the afternoon of the 10th, the division resumed the road, under orders, and,
                    after a 10-mile march, bivouacked on Hazel River, near Gourd Vine Church.</p>
                <p>Next day, the route was resumed at an early hour, and, without exception, on the
                    worst road I have ever seen troops and trains pass over. The route designated
                    for the division led by Newby's Cross-Roads to Washington; but finding the
                    portion of the road between these two points absolutely impracticable, and the
                    men and horses well-nigh exhausted by the severe march to Newby's Cross-Roads, I
                    was compelled to proceed by Gaines' Cross-Roads. Before taking that route,
                    however, I found that the movements of the division were not likely to be
                    discovered by the enemy, and hence that there was no necessity for taking the
                    more tortuous and difficult road by Washington.</p>
                <p>The route via Gaines' Cross-Roads to Flint Hill being a good one, we reached the
                    latter place early in the afternoon, and halted an hour or more to await the
                    passage of Early's division, which I knew was to precede mine, and which was to
                    have entered, at Flint Hill, the turnpike upon which I was marching.
                    Ascertaining that Gen. Early had been compelled to abandon his prescribed line
                    of march by reason of the impracticable character of the Fodderstack road, and
                    acting under orders from Lieut.-Gen. Ewell, I resumed the march, and bivouacked
                    about one mile and a half north of Flint Hill, having marched about 15 miles.</p>
                <p>On June 12, having received orders to proceed in advance of the other divisions
                    of the corps, my command crossed the Blue Ridge through Chester Gap, passed
                    through Front Royal, forded both forks of the Shenandoah River, and halted for a
                    few hours near Cedarville. Here the lieutenant-general fully unfolded his
                    immediate plans of action to me, which was, in brief, as follows, orders being
                    given me to proceed at once and in accordance with this plan to the execution of
                    my part of it: The main features of the plan were the simultaneous attack of
                    Winchester and Berryville, the subsequent attack of Martinsburg, and the
                    immediate entrance into Maryland, via Williamsport or any other point near there
                    which events indicated as best. My division was ordered to take the Berryville
                    road, via Millwood, to attack and seize Berryville; then to advance without
                    delay on Martinsburg, and thence proceed to Maryland, there to await further
                    orders; this while the other two divisions of the corps reduced Winchester.</p>
                <p>To enable me to carry out this plan the better, and to obtain full supplies of
                    fresh meat, &amp;c., as soon as possible after crossing the Potomac, and
                    other purposes not necessary to mention, the cavalry brigade of Gen. A. G.
                    Jenkins, of about 1,600 men, which had just joined the column, was placed under
                    my command.</p>
                <p>In obedience to my instructions, the division was at once moved directly from
                    Cedarville toward Millwood by an unfrequented road, under the guidance of Mr.
                    John McCormack, a most excellent guide and soldier. To conceal the movements of
                    the infantry, the cavalry were ordered to take the road by Nineveh Church and
                    White Post, and a part of it to proceed to Millwood. After a march of 17 miles,
                    the division bivouacked near Stone Bridge.</p>
                <p>BERRYVILLE.</p>
                <p>On the 13th, we moved on toward Berryville, but before reaching Millwood the
                    advance of the infantry was discovered by some of the enemy's cavalry who had
                    come up from Berry's Ferry (apparently en route to Berryville), a result which
                    would have been avoided had Gen. Jenkins occupied Millwood during the night
                    before, as he was ordered to do. Finding our movements discovered, the division
                    was marched with the utmost celerity through Millwood upon Berryville, where
                    Jenkins' brigade, after driving in the enemy's cavalry, was found held at bay by
                    the Federal artillery.</p>
                <p>Arriving on the field, and communicating with Gen. Jenkins, it was apparent that
                    the enemy were preparing to evacuate the place, but still held it, as well as I
                    could judge, with infantry, cavalry, and artillery.</p>
                <p>I immediately determined to surround them, if possible, and ordered Gen. Jenkins
                    to march to the left of the town, to cut off the retreat of the enemy toward
                    Winchester. The infantry, save one brigade, without being halted, were ordered
                    to move to the right and left of the place, to unite in its rear. These
                    movements were begun and executed under cover, but, before their execution was
                    much advanced, it became apparent to me that the enemy was retreating, and I
                    ordered the Alabama brigade, Col. O'Neal commanding, to advance rapidly upon the
                    town, which was done.</p>
                <p>I was mortified to learn that the enemy, abandoning his tents, a few stores,
                    &amp;c., had left his cavalry and artillery to keep our cavalry in check,
                    and had some time before retreated with his infantry toward Charlestown, without
                    being discovered. I found that the approaches to the town were well defended by
                    rifle-pits and earthworks for guns, and that with an adequate force it was
                    capable of being strongly defended. It had, however, been held by a force too
                    small to admit of a successful defense against my command. The enemy's force
                    there consisted of two small regiments of infantry, one of cavalry, and a
                    battery of rifled guns, in all about 1,800 men, under the command of Col. A. T.
                    McReynolds. Neither my troops nor Gen. Jenkins' cavalry suffered any loss, the
                    enemy firing only a few rounds of artillery after my arrival.</p>
                <p>A portion of Gen. Jenkins' men had been skirmishing during the afternoon of the
                    previous day and on the morning of the 13th, and had lost a few men, among them
                    Lieut. Charles Norvell, who was wounded and captured in a gallant charge upon
                    the enemy near Nineveh. After securing such stores as were at all valuable, the
                    division was again put in motion toward Martinsburg. Gen. Jenkins had already
                    proceeded in pursuit of the enemy by a road west of Berryville. One portion of
                    his command, under my orders, pursued him by the Charlestown road.</p>
                <p>Just before reaching the road to Summit Point, I was informed by an officer of
                    the cavalry that the enemy pursued that route, and later that he had gone toward
                    Winchester. I followed him to Summit Point, where we bivouacked, after having
                    marched about 20 miles, not including the wide detours made at Berryville by the
                    brigades of Daniel, Doles, Ramseur, and Iverson, in the effort to surround the
                    enemy.</p>
                <p>Maj. J. W. Sweeney's battalion, of Jenkins' brigade, which had been put in
                    pursuit of the enemy under my direct orders, overtook his rear guard near the
                    Opequon Creek, and made a most gallant charge upon it, capturing a piece of
                    artillery, which they were unable to hold, the enemy being too strong for them.
                    Maj. Sweeney, who acted very gallantly in this affair, was very badly wounded in
                    the charge.</p>
                <p>In the absence of any official report from Gen. Jenkins, I cannot explain why he
                    did not intercept at least a portion of the enemy's force. It seems, however,
                    clear that before the close of the day the general made a fierce attack upon a
                    detachment of cavalry and infantry at Bunker Hill, losing several men in a
                    gallant attack upon a party of the latter, who had thrown themselves into two
                    stone houses, well provided for defense, with loop-holes and barricades fixed
                    for that purpose. He captured here about 75 or 100 prisoners, and drove the
                    balance toward Martinsburg. These facts I learned on the next day.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 14th, it was apparent that during the night the enemy had
                    continued his march to Winchester, whither I ordered the only force of cavalry I
                    could then communicate with (Sweeney's battalion) to follow and annoy him.</p>
                <p>Not having heard anything from Winchester, though I had dispatched several
                    couriers to the lieutenant-general commanding, I hesitated for a few moments
                    between proceeding toward Martinsburg, in accordance with my general
                    instructions, and turning toward Winchester. The reflection that, should my
                    division be needed there, I would that day receive orders to turn back,
                    determined me to push on to Martinsburg as rapidly as possible, which I did,
                    reaching that place late in the afternoon, after a very fatiguing march of 19
                    miles.</p>
                <p>MARTINSBURG.</p>
                <p>Arriving in the field before Martinsburg ahead of the troops, I found Gen.
                    Jenkins with his command before the enemy, skirmishing with him occasionally.
                    The enemy's forces were drawn up in line of battle on the right of the town,
                    exhibiting infantry, cavalry, and artillery. Gen. Jenkins, through Capt. W. A.
                    Harris, of my staff, had summoned the Federal commander to surrender, which he
                    declined doing.</p>
                <p>Before the infantry came up, I ordered Gen. Jenkins to move most of his force to
                    the left of the town, to dismount it, and send it forward as skirmishers, to
                    endeavor to get possession of the town, thus cutting off the enemy's retreat
                    toward Hedgesville and Williamsport, and to report to me what force, if any, he
                    discovered in and to the left of the town. At the same time, Lieut.-Col. Carter
                    was directed to take the best position for his artillery to enable him to
                    silence the opposing battery, which was annoying us.</p>
                <p>Without halting, the infantry was put in a position for a direct attack--the
                    Alabama brigade on the right, supporting the artillery, which had already
                    opened, Ramseur on the left, Doles and Iverson in the center, Daniel in reserve.
                    Before these preparations had been completed, however, the enemy's battery had
                    been nearly silenced, and, fearing he would retreat, I ordered Ramseur's brigade
                    and each of the others in turn to advance with speed upon the enemy's position.</p>
                <p>Notwithstanding their fatiguing march, the troops exhibited great enthusiasm, and
                    rapidly occupied the town and the enemy's position. Ramseur's brigade, being in
                    the lead, pursued the enemy at almost a run for 2 miles beyond the town, but,
                    quick as it was, the dismounted cavalry and a squadron or two on horseback,
                    under Gen. Jenkins, were ahead of them, and, after a few shots, compelled the
                    enemy to abandon all his guns, with perhaps one exception. Five of his pieces,
                    with their caissons and most of their horses, were thus captured.</p>
                <p>Nothing was seen of the Federal infantry after the attack began, nor was it known
                    for some hours after their retreat that it escaped by the Shepherdstown road,
                    while the cavalry and artillery fled by way of Williamsport. This latter fact,
                    together with the darkness, prevented the cavalry from discovering that the
                    force had divided. Could the division have reached the town an hour or two
                    earlier, thus giving me time to seize the principal roads leading into
                    Martinsburg, I feel certain that I would have captured the whole force. Under
                    the circumstances, however, nothing was proper excepting a direct attack, as to
                    have awaited daylight would have lost to us all the artillery and the stores,
                    which we secured by moving ahead without delay.</p>
                <p>Gen. Jenkins continued the pursuit of the enemy that night nearly to the river,
                    capturing many prisoners. Many others were taken in town by the infantry. The
                    enemy endeavored to burn the stores accumulated at Martinsburg, and to a large
                    extent succeeded in doing so, but left in our hands some 6,000 bushels of fine
                    grain, some commissary stores, about 400 rounds of rifled artillery ammunition,
                    and small-arms and ammunition in small quantity. With the artillery were
                    captured two excellent ambulances.</p>
                <p>After recalling Ramseur from the pursuit, and putting a regiment of Doles'
                    brigade in the town as a guard, the appropriate officers were set to work
                    gathering prisoners, who were concealed in the houses of many of the Union
                    families of the town, and taking inventories of the supplies.</p>
                <p>On the 15th, the troops were allowed to rest until after 10 a. m., when, for the
                    first time, I received information as to the progress of events at Winchester,
                    and about the same time learned that Gen. Milroy with his shattered command had
                    passed Smithfield, en route for Harper's Ferry, and had already gotten out of my
                    reach. Gen. Jenkins' gallant brigade, under his impetuous leadership, had
                    already succeeded in crossing the Potomac above Williamsport, and, after driving
                    off the small force at that place, had advanced into Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>Leaving Col. Lightfoot with his regiment (the Sixth Alabama) as a guard at
                    Martinsburg, and ordering the pioneers of the division to continue during that
                    day and the next the destruction of the railroad, I put the division in motion
                    for Williamsport, and arrived there by dark, after the most trying march we had
                    yet had; most trying because of the intense heat, the character of the road, and
                    the increased number of barefooted men in the command.</p>
                <p>Three brigades (Ramseur's, Iverson's, and Doles'), with three batteries of
                    artillery, were ordered across the Potomac at once. It was not until this day
                    that the troops began to exhibit unmistakable signs of exhaustion, and that
                    stragglers could be found in the line of march, and even then none but
                    absolutely worn-out men fell out of line. The whole march from Culpeper
                    Court-House to Williamsport, which was an extremely rapid one, was executed in a
                    manner highly creditable to the officers and men of the division. A halt at
                    Williamsport was absolutely necessary from the condition of the feet of the
                    unshod men. Very many of these gallant fellows were still marching in ranks,
                    with feet bruised, bleeding, and swollen, and withal so cheerfully as to entitle
                    them to be called the heroes of the Pennsylvania campaign. None but the best of
                    soldiers could have made such a march under such circumstances.</p>
                <p>As soon as possible after arriving at Williamsport, a strong guard was placed
                    over it, and the necessary instructions were given to Gen. Jenkins about
                    obtaining supplies of cattle and horses. In obedience to orders, the command
                    remained at Williamsport during the 16th, 17th, and 18th, during which time,
                    with the aid of Gen. Jenkins' cavalry, the commissaries and quartermasters
                    obtained, in a proper manner, large supplies in their respective departments.
                    The pioneers, under Capt. Arthur M. Chichester, were busy during our rest here
                    trying to destroy the aqueduct over the Conococheague. Some 5,000 pounds of
                    leather were bought by Maj. J. G. Paxton at Williamsport, and sent to the rear.
                    At Hagerstown and Williamsport, 35 kegs of powder were purchased and sent back.
                    I may as well mention here that at Williamsport, Hagerstown, Chambersburg,
                    &amp;c., large quantities of such articles as were suitable for Government
                    use were obtained by purchase or certificate, and sent back by Quartermasters
                    Paxton, J. D. Rogers, and J. A. Harman. During the march into Pennsylvania, some
                    2,000 or 3,000 head of cattle were taken, and either appropriated for the
                    command or sent to the rear for the other divisions. Some 1,200 or 1,500 were
                    thus sent back. The horses were almost all seized by the cavalry of Gen.
                    Jenkins, and were rarely accounted for. My best efforts were made to suppress
                    all irregularities, and, being very generally and cheerfully seconded by
                    officers and men, they succeeded satisfactorily. Some few cases of fraud and (at
                    Greencastle) some of violence to property (the latter traceable to the cavalry)
                    were heard of. A few instances of forced purchases were reported, but never
                    established. I believe that one quartermaster seized such articles as velvet,
                    &amp;c., but could not find him out. In all cases of purchase that came
                    before me, the parties were fully paid and satisfied.</p>
                <p>On the 17th or 18th, the lieutenant-general commanding visited my quarters, and
                    gave me additional instructions, to the effect that the division should on the
                    19th resume its march, and move slowly toward Chambersburg until the division of
                    Gen. Johnson had crossed the Potomac.</p>
                <p>Accordingly, on the 19th it was put in motion, and proceeded to Hagerstown,
                    where, in obedience to further instructions, its march was directed toward
                    Boonsborough, as if threatening Harper's Ferry, and halted about 2 miles from
                    hagerstown, on the Boonsborough road.</p>
                <p>Remaining two days near Hagerstown, during which period I received further verbal
                    instructions in a personal interview with Lieut.-Gen. Ewell, on the 22d the
                    division resumed its march, and on that day penetrated into the enemy's country.
                    Iverson's brigade was the first to touch Pennsylvania soil. After a march of 13
                    miles, we bivouacked at Greencastle. During the night, under orders, I reported
                    in person at the headquarters of the lieutenant-general commanding, then at
                    Beaver Creek, between Boonsborough and Hagerstown, and, after an interview with
                    him and Gen. Early, rejoined my command next day, Lieut.-Gen. Ewell accompanying
                    me.</p>
                <p>Gen. Jenkins had in the meantime advanced to Chambersburg, where he was ordered
                    to remain until my division came up, which he failed to do, because of the
                    reported approach of the enemy in strong force. The result was that most of the
                    property in that place which would have been of service to the troops, such as
                    boots, hats, leather, &amp;c., was removed or concealed before it was
                    reoccupied. From this date, Gen. Jenkins was directly under the orders of the
                    lieutenant-general in effect, as the latter was thenceforth constantly with the
                    advance guard of infantry.</p>
                <p>At Greencastle, the orders of Gen. Lee, regulating the conduct of troops and
                    officers of all departments while in the enemy's country, were received, but
                    they had in substance been anticipated by orders first from division and then
                    from corps headquarters. The conduct of the troops of this division was entirely
                    in accordance with those orders, and challenged the admiration of their
                    commanding officers, while it astonished the people along the line of march.
                    These latter very generally expected to be treated by us with the wanton cruelty
                    generally exhibited by their troops when they are upon our soil. As a general
                    rule, they apparently expected to see their houses burned down and all their
                    property carried off or destroyed.</p>
                <p>From June 23, the movements of my command were executed under the immediate
                    supervision of the commander of the corps.</p>
                <p>Resuming its march on the 24th, the division made 14 miles, passing through
                    Chambersburg, which had been reoccupied by Gen. Jenkins that morning, and
                    bivouacked on the Conococheague, 2 1/2 miles beyond the town. The Third Alabama
                    Regt., Col. Battle commanding, was left in the town as a guard for the people,
                    property, &amp;c. At Chambersburg, the division of Gen. Johnson joined mine,
                    and the two, moving on slowly without noteworthy incident, reached Carlisle on
                    the 27th. The brigades of Daniel, Iverson, and Ramseur occupied the United
                    States barracks at this place, that of Gen. Doles bivouacked on the campus of
                    Dickinson College, a portion of his force acting as guard for the town, while
                    the Alabama brigade bivouacked on and picketed the Baltimore turnpike, 1 1/2
                    miles from town.</p>
                <p>Large supplies of cattle, horses, and flour were obtained here and on the march,
                    and in the barracks' stables a large quantity of grain was found. Most of the
                    Government property, excepting the grain, had been removed by the enemy, but
                    musketoons, holsters, tents, and a small quantity of subsistence stores were
                    found in the barracks.</p>
                <p>On our arrival at Carlisle, Jenkins' cavalry advanced toward Harrisburg, and had
                    on the 29th made a thorough reconnaissance of the defenses of the place, with a
                    view to our advance upon it, a step which every man in the division contemplated
                    with eagerness, and which was to have been executed on the 30th; but on the
                    30th, having received orders to move toward the balance of the army, then
                    supposed to be at or near Cashtown, we set out for that place, marching through
                    Petersburg, and bivouacking at Heidlersburg, after a march of at least 22 miles.</p>
                <p>GETTYSBURG.</p>
                <p>On July 1, in pursuance of the order to rejoin the army, the division resumed its
                    march, but upon arriving at Middletown, and hearing that Lieut.-Gen. Hill's
                    corps was moving upon Gettysburg, by order of Gen. Ewell, the head of the column
                    was turned in that direction. When within 4 miles of the town, to my surprise,
                    the presence of the enemy there in force was announced by the sound of a sharp
                    cannonade, and instant preparations for battle were made.</p>
                <p>On arriving on the field, I found that by keeping along the wooded ridge, on the
                    left side of which the town of Gettysburg is situated, I could strike the force
                    of the enemy with which Gen. Hill's troops were engaged upon the flank, and
                    that, besides moving under cover, whenever we struck the enemy we could engage
                    him with the advantage in ground.</p>
                <p>The division was, therefore, moved along the summit of the ridge, with only one
                    brigade deployed at first, and finally, as the enemy's cavalry had discovered us
                    and the ground was of such character as to admit of cover for a large opposing
                    force, with three brigades deployed; Doles on the left, Rodes' (old) brigade,
                    Col. O'Neal commanding, in the center, and Iverson on the right, the artillery
                    and the other two brigades moved up closely to the line of battle. The division
                    had to move nearly a mile before coming in view of the enemy's forces, excepting
                    a few mounted men, and finally arrived at a point--a prominent hill on the
                    ridge--whence the whole of that portion of the force opposing Gen. Hill's troops
                    could be seen. To get at these troops properly, which were still over half a
                    mile from us, it was necessary to move the whole of my command by the right
                    flank, and to change direction to the right.</p>
                <p>While this was being done, Carter's battalion was ordered forward, and soon
                    opened fire upon the enemy, who at this moment, as far as I could see, had no
                    troops facing me at all. He had apparently been surprised; only a desultory fire
                    of artillery was going on between his troops and Gen. Hill's; but before my
                    dispositions were made, the enemy began to show large bodies of men in front of
                    the town, most of which were directed upon the position which I held, and almost
                    at the same time a portion of the force opposed to Gen. Hill changed position so
                    as to occupy the woods on the summit of the same ridge I occupied (I refer to
                    the forest touching the railroad and extending along the summit of the ridge
                    toward my position as far as the Mummasburg road, which crossed the ridge at the
                    base of the hill I held). Either these last troops, or others which had hitherto
                    been unobserved behind the same body of woods, soon made their appearance
                    directly opposite my center.</p>
                <p>Being thus threatened from two directions, I determined to attack with my center
                    and right, holding at bay still another force, then emerging from the town
                    (apparently with the intention of turning my left), with Doles' brigade, which
                    was moved somewhat to the left for this purpose, and trusting to this gallant
                    brigade thus holding them until Gen. Early's division arrived, which I knew
                    would be soon, and which would strike this portion of the enemy's force on the
                    flank before it could overpower Doles.</p>
                <p>At this moment Doles' brigade occupied the open plain between the Middletown road
                    and the foot of the ridge before spoken of. The Alabama brigade, with a wide
                    interval between it and Doles', extended from this plain up the slope of the
                    ridge; Daniel's brigade supported Iverson's, and extended some distance to the
                    right of it; Ramseur was in reserve. All the troops were in the woods excepting
                    Doles' and a portion of Rodes' (O'Neal's) brigades, but all were subjected to
                    some loss or annoyance from the enemy's artillery.</p>
                <p>While making some examination into the position and apparent intentions of the
                    enemy, with the view of attacking him, this artillery fire became so annoying
                    that I ordered the Alabama brigade from the line it had occupied to fall back
                    abreast with Iverson, so as to obtain some little shelter for the troops. The
                    right regiment (Third Alabama) was, under my order, placed on a line with
                    Daniel's brigade, Col. O'Neal being instructed to form the balance of the
                    brigade upon it. These dispositions were but temporary and unimportant, and are
                    mentioned only because they are necessary to a full understanding of Col.
                    O'Neal's report.</p>
                <p>Finding that the enemy was rash enough to come out from the woods to attack me, I
                    determined to meet him when he got to the foot of the hill I occupied, and, as
                    he did so, I caused Iverson's brigade to advance, and at the same moment gave in
                    person to O'Neal the order to attack, indicating to him precisely the point to
                    which he was to direct the left of the four regiments then under his orders, the
                    Fifth Alabama, which formed the extreme left of this brigade, being held in
                    reserve, under my own immediate command, to defend the gap between O'Neal and
                    Doles. Daniel was at the same moment instructed to advance to support Iverson,
                    if necessary; if not, to attack on his right as soon as possible.</p>
                <p>Carter's whole battalion was by this time engaged hotly--a portion from the
                    right, the remainder from the left of the hill--and was subjected to a heavy
                    artillery fire in return. Iverson's brigade attacked handsomely, but suffered
                    very heavily from the enemy's musketry fire from behind a stone wall along the
                    crest of the ridge. The Alabama brigade went into action in some confusion, and
                    with only three of its regiments (the Sixth, Twelfth, and Twenty-sixth), the
                    Fifth having been retained by my order, and, for reasons explained to Col.
                    O'Neal, the Third having been permitted by Col. O'Neal to move with Daniel's
                    brigade.</p>
                <p>The three first-mentioned regiments moved with alacrity (but not in accordance
                    with my orders as to direction) and in confusion into the action. It was soon
                    apparent that we were making no impression upon the enemy, and hence I ordered
                    forward the Fifth Alabama to their support; but, to my surprise, in giving this
                    command to its colonel (Hall), I found that Col. O'Neal, instead of personally
                    superintending the movements of his brigade, had chosen to remain with his
                    reserve regiment. The result was that the whole brigade, with the exception of
                    the Third Alabama (the movements of which will be seen by reference to the
                    reports of Gen.'s Ramseur and Iverson and Col. Battle), was repulsed quickly,
                    and with loss. Upon investigation recently, I find that just as O'Neal's men
                    were about starting, and upon his informing me that he and his staff officers
                    were not mounted, and that he had no mounted men with him, I permitted him to
                    send Lieut. James P. Arrington, of my staff, to Col. Battle, commanding the
                    Third Alabama Regt., with his orders, and that Lieut. Arrington delivered them
                    to Col. Battle.</p>
                <p>Iverson's left being thus exposed, heavy loss was inflicted upon his brigade. His
                    men fought and died like heroes. His dead lay in a distinctly marked line of
                    battle. His left was overpowered, and many of his men, being surrounded, were
                    captured.</p>
                <p>Gen. Daniel's gallant brigade, by a slight change in the direction of Iverson's
                    attack, had been left too far to his right to assist him directly, and had
                    already become engaged. The right of this brigade coming upon the enemy,
                    strongly posted in a railroad cut, was, under its able commander's orders,
                    thrown back skillfully, and the position of the whole brigade was altered so as
                    to enable him to throw a portion of his force across the railroad, enfilade it,
                    and attack to advantage.</p>
                <p>After this change, Gen. Daniel made a most desperate, gallant, and entirely
                    successful charge upon the enemy, driving him at all points, but suffering
                    terribly. The conduct of Gen. Daniel and his brigade in this most desperate
                    engagement elicited the admiration and praise of all who witnessed it. Just as
                    his last effort was made, Ramseur's brigade, which under my orders had been so
                    disposed as to support both Iverson and O'Neal, was ordered forward, and was
                    hurled by its commander with the skill and gallantry for which he is always
                    conspicuous, and with irresistible force, upon the enemy just where he had
                    repulsed O'Neal and checked Iverson's advance.</p>
                <p>In the meantime, Gen. Early's division had been brought into action on my left
                    with great success, and Doles, thus relieved, without waiting for orders, and
                    though greatly outnumbered, boldly attacked the heavy masses of the enemy in his
                    front. After a short but desperate contest, in which his brigade acted with
                    unsurpassed gallantry, he succeeded in driving them before him, thus achieving
                    on the left, and about the same time, a success no less brilliant than that of
                    Ramseur, in the center, and Daniel, on the right.</p>
                <p>In this affair, Doles handled his men with a skill and effect truly admirable,
                    exhibiting marked coolness and courage.</p>
                <p>O'Neal's shattered troops, which had assembled without order on the hill, rushed
                    forward, still without order, but with all their usual courage, into the charge.
                    Fry's battery, by my order, was pushed closely after Ramseur.</p>
                <p>The Twelfth North Carolina, which had been held well in hand by Lieut.-Col.
                    Davis, and the shattered remnants of the other regiments of Iverson's brigade,
                    which had been rallied and organized by Capt. D. P. Halsey, assistant
                    adjutant-general of the brigade, made under his guidance a dashing and effective
                    charge just in time to be of considerable service to Ramseur and Daniel, and
                    with them pressed closely after the enemy.</p>
                <p>These successes were rapidly followed by a successful attack on my right on the
                    part of Gen. A. P. Hill's troops, who renewed their attack in time to put a stop
                    to a murderous enfilade and reverse fire to which, in addition to the heavy
                    direct fire it encountered, Daniel's brigade had been subjected from the time he
                    commenced fairly his final advance.</p>
                <p>The enemy was thus routed at all points. My division followed him closely into
                    and through the town, Doles and Ramseur entering in such close contact with the
                    enemy that the former, who penetrated the heart of the town first of all, had
                    two sharp and successful encounters with the enemy in its streets, and the
                    latter, who entered farther to the right, captured the colors of the One hundred
                    and fiftieth Pennsylvania Regt. in its streets, Lieut. F. M. Harney, of his
                    brigade, tearing them from the hands of the colorbearer, and falling almost
                    immediately thereafter, mortally wounded.</p>
                <p>In the pursuit, the division captured about 2,500 prisoners--so many as to
                    embarrass its movements materially.</p>
                <p>The troops, being greatly exhausted by their march and somewhat disorganized by
                    the hot engagement and rapid pursuit, were halted and prepared for further
                    action. I did not change their position materially, nor order another attack,
                    for the following reasons: 1st, in the midst of the engagement just described,
                    the corps commander informed me, through one of his officers, that the general
                    commanding did not wish a general engagement brought on, and hence, had it been
                    possible to do so then, I would have stopped the attack at once; but this, of
                    course, it was impossible to do then; 2d, before the completion of his defeat
                    before the town, the enemy had begun to establish a line of battle on the
                    heights back of the town, and by the time my line was in a condition to renew
                    the attack, he displayed quite a formidable line of infantry and artillery
                    immediately in my front, extending smartly to my right, and as far as I could
                    see to my left, in front of Early. To have attacked this line with my division
                    alone, diminished as it had been by a loss of 2,500 men, would have been absurd.
                    Seeing no Confederate troops at all on my right; finding that Gen. Early, whom I
                    encountered in the streets of the town within thirty minutes after its
                    occupation by our forces, was awaiting further instructions, and, receiving no
                    orders to advance, though my superiors were upon the ground, I concluded that
                    the order not to bring on a general engagement was still in force, and hence
                    placed my lines and skirmishers in a defensive attitude, and determined to await
                    orders or further movements either on the part of Early or of the troops on my
                    right.</p>
                <p>My skirmishers were promptly thrown out so as to cover more than half the town
                    and the front of the division, which was drawn up in two lines, Doles',
                    Iverson's, and Ramseur's brigades making the front line, and extending from the
                    left of the center of the town along one of its principal streets and out on the
                    road to Fairfield; the second line, composed of the brigades of Daniel and
                    O'Neal, extended along the railroad, about 200 yards in rear and considerably to
                    the right of the first. In this position we remained quietly, but with
                    considerable annoyance from the enemy's sharpshooters and artillery, until the
                    morning of the next day.</p>
                <p>On July 2, nothing of importance transpired in my front. The rest of the men
                    generally was only disturbed by the occasional skirmishing and desultory firing
                    of the opposing sharpshooters; but Daniel's brigade, which had been early in the
                    morning moved by my order so as to connect with Pender's division, on the crest
                    of the ridge before spoken of, was subjected to a galling artillery fire,
                    especially in the afternoon. Late in the afternoon, however, an attack was made
                    upon the enemy's position by some troops of the right wing of the army, which
                    produced some stir among the enemy in my immediate front, and seemed to cause
                    there a diminution of both artillery and infantry.</p>
                <p>Orders given during the afternoon, and after the engagement had opened on the
                    right, required me to co-operate with the attacking force as soon as any
                    opportunity of doing so with good effect was offered. Seeing the stir alluded
                    to, I thought that opportunity had come, and immediately sought Gen. Early, with
                    a view of making an attack in concert with him. He agreed with me as to the
                    propriety of attacking, and made preparations accordingly. I hastened to inform
                    the officer commanding the troops on my right (part of Pender's division) that,
                    in accordance with our plan, I would attack just at dark, and proceeded to make
                    my arrangements; but having to draw my troops out of town by the flank, change
                    the direction of the line of battle, and then to traverse a distance of 1,200 or
                    1,400 yards, while Gen. Early had to move only half that distance without change
                    of front, the result was that, before I drove the enemy's skirmishers in, Gen.
                    Early had attacked and had been compelled to withdraw.</p>
                <p>After driving in the enemy's skirmishers, the advance line was halted by Gen.
                    Ramseur, who commanded the right brigade, to enable him to report to me certain
                    important facts (for statement of which I refer to his report) he had discovered
                    as to the nature of the ground and of the defenses. These facts, together with
                    Early's withdrawal, of which I had been officially informed, and the increased
                    darkness, convinced me that it would be a useless sacrifice of life to go on,
                    and a recall was ordered. But instead of falling back to the original line, I
                    caused the front line to assume a strong position in the plain to the right of
                    the town, along the hollow of an old roadbed. This position was much nearer the
                    enemy, was clear of the town, and was one from which I could readily attack
                    without confusion. The second line was placed in the position originally held by
                    the first. Everything was gotten ready to attack at daylight; but a short time
                    after assuming this new position, I was ordered to send without delay all the
                    troops I could spare without destroying my ability to hold my position, to
                    re-enforce Maj.-Gen. Johnson. As my front line was much more strongly posted
                    than my second, and was fully competent to hold the position, and as the
                    re-enforcements had to be in position before daylight, I was compelled to send
                    to Gen. Johnson the troops of my second line, i. e., the brigades of Daniel and
                    O'Neal (excepting the Fifth Alabama).</p>
                <p>These brigades participated in the engagement on the left, under Gen. Johnson,
                    and remained under his orders until the following night, when our whole corps
                    changed front to rear, so as to extend the line occupied by the other two corps.
                    For a report of their operations on July 3, I have, therefore, to refer
                    respectfully to the report of Gen. Johnson, and to those of Gen. Daniel and Col.
                    O'Neal, herewith filed.</p>
                <p>This order left me powerless to do more than hold my position, unless the enemy
                    should be very much weakened in my front, for I had now remaining but a single
                    thin line, composed of two small brigades, about the third of another, and one
                    regiment (the Fifth Alabama) of O'Neal's brigade (in all, not over 1,800 men),
                    facing what I believed then and now to be the most impregnable portion of the
                    enemy's line of intrenchments.</p>
                <p>The gallant men and officers of this line held their new position all day on July
                    3, under a sharp and incessant fire from the enemy's sharpshooters and an
                    occasional artillery fire. The enemy made during the day several ineffectual
                    efforts, by advancing heavy lines of skirmishers, equal almost, if not fully, to
                    my main line, and using their artillery, to dislodge them from their position.</p>
                <p>On the 3d, my orders were general, and the same as those of the day before, and
                    accordingly, when the heavy cannonade indicated that another attack was made
                    from the right wing of our army, we were on the lookout for another favorable
                    opportunity to co-operate. When the sound of musketry was heard, it became
                    apparent that the enemy in our front was much excited. The favorable opportunity
                    seemed to me close at hand. I sent word to Lieut.-Gen. Ewell by Maj. H. A.
                    Whiting, of my staff, that in a few moments I should attack, and immediately had
                    my handful of men, under Doles, Iverson, and Ramseur, prepared for the onset;
                    but in less than five minutes after Maj. Whiting's departure, before the troops
                    on my immediate right had made any advance or showed any preparation therefore,
                    and just as the order forward was about to be given to my line, it was
                    announced, and was apparent to me, that the attack had already failed.</p>
                <p>This attack was accompanied, preceded, and succeeded by the fiercest and grandest
                    cannonade I have ever witnessed. My troops lay about half way between the
                    artillery of the Second Corps and that of the enemy on Cemetery Hill, and
                    directly under the line of fire of fully 100 guns, a most trying position even
                    when the opposing artillerists confined their attention to each other, and one
                    which became fearfully so when both parties, as they did at short intervals,
                    dropped shells in their midst, while the sharpshooters were constant and
                    skillful in their attentions. They underwent this terrible trial not only
                    without murmuring or faltering, but with great cheerfulness and with the utmost
                    coolness.</p>
                <p>It is proper to mention that during the night of the 2d and on the 3d my troops
                    did not occupy any portion of the town excepting that still held by the
                    sharpshooters of the Alabama brigade, under that promising young officer, Maj.
                    Eugene Blackford, of the Fifth Alabama. These sharpshooters, together with those
                    of Doles', Iverson's, and Ramseur's brigades, annoyed the enemy's artillery and
                    infantry constantly during the period of our occupation of the town, and acted
                    with rare and praiseworthy gallantry.</p>
                <p>During the night of the 3d, my division fell back to the ridge which had been
                    wrested from the enemy in the first day's attack, and, being reunited, was
                    posted so that the railroad divided it about equally.</p>
                <p>Expecting to give battle in this position, it was strengthened early on the
                    morning of the 4th. We were not disturbed, however, in the least during the
                    day--in fact, the enemy exhibited so small a force, entered the town, and
                    followed us at so late an hour, that it was generally believed he had retreated.</p>
                <p>During the day of the 4th, all the wounded who could walk or be transported in
                    wagons and ambulances were sent to the rear (many, as it turned out, to be
                    captured or sacrificed in the effort to escape the enemy's cavalry), but nearly
                    one-half of them, say about 760, were left in the hands of the enemy. This
                    painful result was, of course, unavoidable. Four surgeons, 6 assistants, 3
                    hospital stewards, and 94 attendants were left to attend to the wounded, and
                    with them ten days' supply of such food and medicines as were needed. This was
                    all we could do for them.</p>
                <p>Subsequent to the departure of the wounded, Iverson was detached with his brigade
                    as a guard for the train, but unfortunately too late to overtake it and prevent
                    its partial destruction. By a forced march, he arrived at Hagerstown soon after
                    the passage of the train, and found a heavy force of the enemy's cavalry driving
                    back our cavalry through the streets. Making a hasty but skillful disposition of
                    his troops, he soon routed them, capturing a considerable number. Great credit
                    is due Brig.-Gen. Iverson for the handsome and prompt manner in which this
                    affair was managed.</p>
                <p>On the night of the 4th, we began to fall back toward Hagerstown, by way of
                    Fairfield, bivouacking on the night of the 5th, after a most wearisome march in
                    mud and rain, 2 miles west of Fairfield.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 6th, my division became the rear guard of the army, and
                    early in the morning was attacked by the enemy's skirmishers deployed over a
                    line extending entirely across the Valley, and, therefore, fully 1 1/2 or 2
                    miles long. Later it was attacked from the Emmitsburg road.</p>
                <p>The morning attack was sharply repulsed by Gen. Daniel's skirmishers, on the
                    left, and Gen. Doles', on the right of the road, the Forty-fifth North Carolina
                    (Capt. J. A. Hopkins commanding) having a pretty brisk action on the extreme
                    left, driving the enemy from a commanding position there, in reply to his
                    summons to surrender. Gen. Daniel's loss was only 2 killed, 2 wounded, and 5
                    missing; Gen. Doles', nothing. The other (an extremely feeble attack) was
                    repelled by a few of Gen. Doles' men. The road being entirely clear behind us
                    for 4 or 5 miles, at 3.30 p. m. we resumed the march, and proceeded without
                    annoyance or delay across the mountain, by Monterey Springs, to Waynesborough.</p>
                <p>Reaching Hagerstown next day, the division rested there without serious
                    disturbance until the evening of the 11th, when it was moved through and about a
                    mile and a quarter west of Hagerstown, on the National road. Here, during the
                    13th, 14th, and 15th, battle was again (and eagerly by my division) offered to
                    the enemy. During these three days, my division occupied the extreme left of the
                    line of battle. Nothing of importance occurred here, excepting a brisk attack of
                    the enemy's skirmishers (after being re-enforced) and his cavalry upon Ramseur's
                    sharpshooters. This attack was made late on the afternoon of July 14, after the
                    withdrawal of nearly all the artillery and of all the main line of infantry. The
                    enemy had unquestionably discovered this movement. His advance was so firmly and
                    gallantly met by Ramseur's men and the Second Richmond Howitzers (Capt. David
                    Watson), that he fell back, with the loss of many killed and wounded and about
                    20 of the cavalry captured.</p>
                <p>On the memorable night of July 14, the Second Corps fell back to Williamsport,
                    and forded the river. The artillery, under Lieut.-Col. Carter, I had sent off
                    early in the afternoon, with orders to cross at Falling Waters, 4 miles below
                    Williamsport, on the pontoon bridge which had been placed there. My division
                    waded the river just above the aqueduct over the mouth of the Conococheague; the
                    operation was a perilous one. It was very dark, raining, and excessively muddy.
                    The men had to wade through the aqueduct, down the steep bank of soft and
                    slippery mud, in which numbers lost their shoes and down which many fell. The
                    water was cold, deep, and rising; the lights on either side of the river were
                    dim, just affording enough light to mark the places of entrance and exit; the
                    cartridge-boxes of the men had to be placed around their necks; some small men
                    had to be carried over by their comrades; the water was up to the armpits of a
                    full-sized man. All the circumstances attending this crossing combined to make
                    it an affair not only involving great hardship, but one of great danger to the
                    men and company officers; but be it said to the everlasting honor of these brave
                    fellows, they encountered it not only promptly, but actually with cheers and
                    laughter.</p>
                <p>We crossed without the loss of a single man, but I regret to say with the loss of
                    some 25,000 or 30,000 rounds of ammunition, which were unavoidably wetted and
                    spoiled. After crossing, I marched, by orders, a short distance beyond Falling
                    Waters, and then bivouacked; and there ended the Pennsylvania campaign, so far
                    as this division was concerned.</p>
                <p>I cannot, however, close this portion of my report without expressing my pride
                    and admiration of the conduct of the men and officers of this division from the
                    time it left Grace Church until our return to Virginia. Better marching, less
                    straggling, hardships more cheerfully borne, conduct in an enemy's country more
                    commendable, and more generally marked by gentlemanly and soldierly
                    characteristics, and, finally, better behavior in battle, than was exhibited by
                    this division during that period has not been, and I believe will never be,
                    exhibited by any other troops in the service. By their conduct at Gettysburg, I
                    claim to have won the expression from the general commanding the army, who saw
                    their attack on July 1, "I am proud of your division."</p>
                <p>Earnestly do I wish that the name of each officer and private who distinguished
                    himself during this eventful campaign could with reason be enrolled here, to be
                    transferred to history. I hope it will yet be done in a different manner.</p>
                <p>While I cannot mention all who won distinction during this campaign, it is my
                    duty to record here the names of those officers whose conduct, either from my
                    own observation or from the voluntary testimony of many competent witnesses, I
                    know to have been such as to entitle them to the admiration of brave men and to
                    the gratitude of a good people. First among them are Brig. Gens. Junius Daniel,
                    George Doles, and S. D. Ramseur, Lieut. Col. T. H. Carter, Capt. D. P. Halsey,
                    assistant adjutant-general of Iverson's brigade, Col. D. H. Christie,
                    Twenty-third North Carolina (who has since died from the wounds he received),
                    and Lieut. Harney, Company F, Fourteenth North Carolina, of my division, and
                    Brig. Gen. A. G. Jenkins and Maj. Sweeney, of the cavalry brigade. All the field
                    officers, with one exception, are spoken of highly on all hands for their
                    conduct. Appendix B will show what general, field, and staff officers were under
                    fire during the engagements. Company officers did their duty nobly. The men
                    generally acted in a manner worthy of all praise.</p>
                <p>Many valuable lives were lost during the bloody fight at Gettysburg; among them
                    Col. Christie, already mentioned; Lieut. Col. D. R. E. Winn, Fourth Georgia;
                    Lieut.-Col. Andrews, commanding Second North Carolina Battalion, and many
                    others.</p>
                <p>Among the wounded, I regret to have to record the names of Col. F. M. Parker,
                    Thirtieth North Carolina; Lieut.-Col. Lumpkin, Forty-fourth Georgia, a most
                    valuable and estimable officer, who lost a leg; Lieut. Col. R. D. Johnston and
                    Maj. C. C. Blacknall, Twenty-third North Carolina; Col. J. N. Lightfoot, Sixth
                    Alabama; Col. R. T. Bennett, Fourteenth North Carolina; Capt. Page, commanding
                    battery; Col. Thomas S. Kenan, Forty-third North Carolina; Lieut.-Col. Boyd and
                    Maj. J. R. Winston, Forty-fifth North Carolina; Maj. H. G. Lewis, Thirty-second
                    North Carolina; Maj. J. M. Hancock, Second North Carolina Battalion; Lieut. W.
                    R. Bond and Col. W. J. Green, of Gen. Daniel's staff, besides many valuable and
                    distinguished company officers, whose names will be found in the tabular
                    statements appended to reports of brigade commanders.</p>
                <p>My staff officers--Maj. H. A. Whiting, Maj. Greene Peyton, Capt. W. A. Harris,
                    Capt. M. L. Randolph (the two last-named officers attached to the division as
                    chiefs of ordnance and of the signal corps, respectively, voluntarily serving in
                    the field with distinguished ability and courage), Lieut.'s J. W. Hutchinson and
                    James P. Arrington, Capt. D. D. Peden, acting assistant inspector-general, and
                    Surg. W. S. Mitchell--all did their duty nobly during the whole campaign, and
                    deserve mine and the country's warmest thanks for their services.</p>
                <p>Maj. Julian Mitchell, acting division commissary (Maj. J. M. Adams having been
                    taken sick at Culpeper Court-House), discharged the duties of his arduous
                    position with an energy and capacity I have never seen equaled.</p>
                <p>The appendix marked A will show the strength and the loss of each brigade at
                    Gettysburg. Appendix B will show the general, field, and staff officers who were
                    present in the engagements. In the accompanying reports of brigade commanders
                    will be found an account of the operations of each brigade, and the part borne
                    by each in the campaign, in a more detailed form than my limits will admit of,
                    and to these you are respectfully referred.</p>
                <p>SKIRMISH AT MANASSAS GAP.</p>
                <p>After recrossing the Potomac, with the exception of twenty-four hours spent in an
                    ineffectual effort to strike the Federal force at Hedgesville, the division
                    remained quietly in camp near Darkesville, Berkeley County, until July 22, when
                    it resumed the march up the Valley.</p>
                <p>Bivouacking at Winchester one night, the next afternoon found us, after a march
                    of 23 miles, facing nearly the whole Federal Army in the vicinity of Manassas
                    Gap. My division was ordered there to relieve Wright's brigade (of about 600
                    men), of Anderson's division, but arrived too late to do so. The enemy having
                    already engaged Wright's skirmishers, it was necessary for his whole brigade to
                    deploy, so as to cover strongly and hold the line which he occupied until I
                    could establish my line of battle a little in its rear. I caused this movement
                    to be executed, acting under Gen. Ewell's orders. These precautions were proper,
                    as the enemy were making an apparently determined advance with an extended
                    front, and had full 20,000 troops already in view, while others were coming
                    through the Gap.</p>
                <p>All my sharpshooters (about 250 men) were as soon as possible sent to strengthen
                    Wright's line. Rodes' old brigade, under Col. O'Neal, the first to arrive, was
                    deployed behind Wright's, on a ridge some 300 yards in his rear. The main line
                    was strongly posted on a spur of the mountains which commanded the ridges
                    occupied by Wright and O'Neal.</p>
                <p>The enemy attacked in force, driving the front line of skirmishers back slowly.
                    Wright's men fought obstinately, as did the sharpshooters. After obtaining
                    possession of the ridge occupied by the first line of skirmishers, the enemy
                    attempted to make a farther advance in line of battle, and with a force
                    sufficient to have overwhelmed the first line (which had now rallied at the foot
                    of the ridge), but failed signally, the gallant fellows of that line breaking
                    his solid lines repeatedly.</p>
                <p>His officers acted generally with great gallantry, but the men behaved in a most
                    cowardly manner. A few shots from Carter's artillery and the skirmishers' fire
                    halted them, broke them, and put a stop to the engagement. Only a few shots were
                    fired by my second line of skirmishers. Of course, my main line was not engaged.
                    The fight, if it be worthy that name, took place in full view of the division,
                    and while the conduct of our men, and of Wright's particularly, was the subject
                    of admiration, that of the enemy was decidedly puerile.</p>
                <p>Wright's brigade lost, I believe, about 80 men killed and wounded, including
                    among the latter Col. E. J. Walker, commanding the brigade. My total loss was 15
                    killed, wounded, and missing, including 1 officer of Ramseur's sharpshooters,
                    killed. The enemy's loss was, in my opinion, greater than ours. By a prisoner's
                    statements and from what I saw, the enemy had at least two corps backing his
                    attacking force. Gen. Meade's dispatch from Front Royal next day showed that a
                    very large portion, if not all, of his army was present.</p>
                <p>During the night, the pontoons, baggage, &amp;c., having been safely disposed
                    of, my division fell back on the Luray road, about 2 miles from Front Royal, and
                    bivouacked, Johnson's division remaining at Front Royal as rear guard. This
                    day's work, including a march of 27 miles on one of the hottest of summer days,
                    the excitement of a threatened battle, and the night march of 4 or 5 miles,
                    damaged the division seriously.</p>
                <p>Its marches had been admirable up to the time of reaching Front Royal, but for
                    some days after that the men were broken down, and therefore straggled.
                    Fortunately, the marches during this period were quite short.</p>
                <p>Continuing the march leisurely, resting near Luray a day or two, the division
                    arrived at Madison Court-House, by way of Thornton's Gap and Sperryville, on
                    July 29.</p>
                <p>In concluding what I have to say about this campaign, I beg leave to call
                    attention to the heroes of it; the men who day by day sacrificed self on the
                    altar of freedom; those barefooted North Carolinians, Georgians, and Alabamians,
                    who, with bloody and swollen feet, kept to their ranks day after day for weeks.
                    When the division reached Darkesville, nearly one-half of the men and many
                    officers were barefooted, and fully one-fourth had been so since we crossed the
                    Blue Ridge. These poor fellows had kept up with the column and in ranks during
                    the most rapid march of this war, considering its length, over that worst of
                    roads for footmen, the turnpike, and during the hottest days of summer. These
                    are the heroes of the campaign.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, colonel, yours, very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. RODES,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
