<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745914"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12745914">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745914</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499141</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 914</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-22">1863-06-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745914T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>General Robert E. Lee writes General Richard Ewell in June, 1863, with plans for
                    the invasion of Pennsylvania in what became the Gettysburg campaign. Lee
                    suggests that Ewell follow a route through Chambersburg. He also stresses the
                    importance of procuring supplies from the Pennsylvania countryside.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. R. S. Ewell:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-22">June 22, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hdqrs.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of 6 p. m. yesterday has been received. If you are ready to move, you
                    can do so. I think your best course will be toward the Susquehanna, taking the
                    routes by Emmitsburg, Chambersburg, and McConnellsburg. Your trains had better
                    be, as far as possible, kept on the center route. You must get command of your
                    cavalry, and use it in gathering supplies, obtaining information, and protecting
                    your flanks. If necessary, send a staff officer to remain with Gen. Jenkins. It
                    will depend upon the quantity of supplies obtained in that country whether the
                    rest of the army can follow. There may be enough for your command, but none for
                    the others. Every exertion should, therefore, be made to locate and secure them.
                    Beef we can drive with us, but bread we cannot carry, and must secure it in the
                    country.</p>
                <p>I send you copies of a general order on this subject, which I think is based on
                    rectitude and sound policy, and the spirit of which I wish you to see enforced
                    in your command. I am much gratified at the success which has attended your
                    movements, and feel assured, if they are conducted with the same energy and
                    circumspection, it will continue. Your progress and direction will, of course,
                    depend upon the development of circumstances. If Harrisburg comes within your
                    means, capture it. Gen. A. P. Hill arrived yesterday in the vicinity of
                    Berryville. I shall move him on to-day, if possible. Saturday Longstreet
                    withdrew from the Blue Ridge. Yesterday the enemy pressed our cavalry so hard
                    with infantry and cavalry on the Upperville road that McLaws' division had to be
                    sent back to hold Ashby's Gap. I have not yet heard from there this morning.
                    Gen. Stuart could not ascertain whether it was intended as a real advance toward
                    the Valley or to ascertain our position.</p>
                <p>The pontoons will reach Martinsburg to-day, and will be laid at the point you
                    suggest, 4 or 5 miles below Williamsport, if found suitable. I have not
                    countermanded your order withdrawing the cavalry from Charlestown. I will write
                    you again if I receive information affecting your movements.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Trusting in the guidance of a merciful God, and invoking His protection
                        for your corps, I am, with great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
