<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745864"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745864">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745864</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499129</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 863-864</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-06">1863-06-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745864T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June, 1863, Lee's Army of Northern Virginia moved north to embark on an
                    invasion of Pennsylvania. In this letter, Army of Northern Virginia Medical
                    Director Lafayette Guild writes Surgeon General Samuel Moore concerning
                    preparation of receiving hospitals for the advance. Guild mentions Staunton as a
                    possible receiving area for wounded in the event of a big battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Medical Director's Office
                    <name type="recipient">S. P. Moore,<lb/> Surgeon-Gen., C. S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-06">June 6, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Fredericksburg,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The army is moving. The First and Second Army Corps have marched. The Third
                    Corps, Gen. A. P. Hill, remains here for the present. After our army commenced
                    its movements up the Rappahannock, the enemy made considerable demonstration
                    opposite Fredericksburg, brought down their pontoon train with great flourish,
                    and in the afternoon of yesterday, under the protection of eighteen or twenty
                    pieces of artillery, crossed over quite a force, capturing about 50 of our men
                    in the rifle-pits.</p>
                <p>We are striking our tents, and, if the enemy had not appeared immediately in our
                    front, I should have been on my way to Culpeper Court-House, where I was ordered
                    to join the general. The firing of yesterday stopped the general here, and at
                    present it is impossible to say what movement will be determined upon.</p>
                <p>This morning there has been some little cannonading across the river. I have
                    given preparatory orders for the establishment of receiving hospitals on the
                    Orange and Alexandria Railroad.</p>
                <p>Culpeper Court-House will be one of the first to be organized, provided, of
                    course, the army continues its movement in that direction. Gordonsville will be
                    the most eligible position for a purveying depot, and Surgeon W. H. Geddings has
                    received the necessary instructions. The Central and Orange Railroads will be
                    our direct line of communication.</p>
                <p>In the event of the movement in anticipation, I respectfully ask that ambulance
                    trains (railroad trains) be established and equipped on that line of road
                    similarly to those in use upon the Fredericksburg road, with medical officers,
                    nurses, and all conveniences necessary for the comfort and safe conveyance of
                    the sick and wounded to general hospitals.</p>
                <p>It is the intention to send no more sick to Richmond, if suitable accommodations
                    can be provided for them elsewhere. The difficulty of connecting at Hanover
                    Junction with the Central train going west, together with the impracticability
                    of keeping the sick at that point, has rendered it impossible to direct their
                    conveyance from Richmond.</p>
                <p>Gordonsville will be the point of distribution, and the hospital department at
                    that post should be prepared for the temporary accommodation of several thousand
                    sick and wounded, particularly if an engagement takes place on the Upper
                    Rappahannock or along the railroad to Alexandria.</p>
                <p>I am not informed as to the extent of hospital accommodations at Gordonsville,
                    and do not believe it would be advisable to establish a large permanent hospital
                    there; yet the necessities of the case may demand temporary preparations at that
                    point of great magnitude. Charlottesville, Staunton, Lynchburg, Danville,
                    Farmville, &amp;c., I think might afford ample accommodation. I inclose a
                    circular which I have just issued. It is simply a condensation of orders
                    previously issued from your office and from mine.</p>
                <p>I find it necessary to reiterate orders every few months, or they become
                    obsolete, or rather they are disregarded. Sixteen of the severely wounded, who
                    could not be removed far from the battle-field of Chancellorsville, will be sent
                    to Richmond to-morrow. Thirty will remain at Ellwood hospital, yet in no
                    condition to be moved. I regret to report to you that some of the stumps from
                    amputations will require supplementary operations. Ordinarily the amputations
                    were well done, and I can only attribute the necessity for further surgical
                    interference to the application of improper dressing or no dressing at all, and
                    to sloughing. However, it may be that the bad appearance of these stumps could
                    not have been avoided. Among those still remaining in the hospital are quite a
                    number of fractures of the femur, some in the upper third, reported as doing
                    well.</p>
                <p>If I go to Culpeper, I will take the hospitals in my route, and report to you
                    more particularly their condition. Skirmishing with the enemy continues, and I
                    am unable to inform you what the general has in contemplation. I will telegraph
                    to you, if possible, should anything of great importance transpire.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>L. GUILD,<lb/> Surgeon and Medical Director, Army of Northern Virginia.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
