<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744432"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12744432">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Taylor, O. B.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744432</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499010</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Taylor, O. B.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 431-433</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-03">1863-08-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744432T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Captain O. B. Taylor reports on the role played by his battery during
                    the Gettysburg campaign. He mentions camping near Chambersburg, procuring horses
                    in the area, and living off the land before marching to Gettysburg. He then
                    discusses his role in the battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 465. Report of Capt. Osmond B. Taylor, Virginia battery.
                    <name type="recipient">Col. E. P. Alexander.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-03">August 3, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Orange Court-House, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Col.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In accordance with a circular from your headquarters, issued this morning, I make
                    the following report:</p>
                <p>On or about June 3 last, I left Milford Station, Caroline County, with my
                    battery, in company with the other batteries of your battalion. We proceeded to
                    Culpeper Court-House, near which place we went into camp on June 6. We remained
                    here until the 15th, recruiting our horses, repairing our gun-carriages, wagons,
                    harness, &amp;c., with little else of interest, excepting that when the
                    enemy's cavalry made a dash upon ours, near Brandy Station, our battalion
                    marched out to meet them, but we did not have the pleasure of a meeting. Our
                    cavalry drove them back.</p>
                <p>On June 15, we started for the Valley of Virginia, and arrived at Millwood, in
                    Clarke County, on the 18th, where we remained several days recruiting our stock
                    and resting our men. Here also we met with a disappointment. The enemy
                    endeavored to flank us by crossing the Blue Ridge at Ashby's and other gaps. We
                    went out to meet them as before, but our cavalry left nothing for us to do.</p>
                <p>On the 24th, we left Millwood, passing through Winchester, Darkesville, and
                    Martinsburg.</p>
                <p>We crossed the Potomac on the 25th, at Williamsport; thence proceeding on our
                    route, we passed through Hagerstown, Greencastle, and Chambersburg, and encamped
                    near the latter place for several days, resting our men and horses and living
                    upon the fat of Pennsylvania. Here, too, we obtained several fresh horses.</p>
                <p>On June 30, we broke camp, and started for Gettysburg. We arrived there about 10
                    a. m. July 2. After resting about one hour, we took up the line of march for the
                    left wing of the enemy. About 4 p.m. I was ordered into position within 500
                    yards of the enemy's batteries, and to dislodge them, if possible, from a
                    commanding position which they held. I opened upon the batteries with my four
                    Napoleons, firing canister and spherical case until our infantry, who were
                    present, began their charge. I then ceased firing, limbered to the front, and
                    advanced some 800 or 1,000 yards, and took another position, which I held till
                    after dark, though several attempts were made by the enemy, both with infantry
                    and artillery, to drive me from it.</p>
                <p>I lost at the first position one of my best gunners, Corpl. William P. Ray. He
                    was killed while in the act of sighting his guns. He never spoke after receiving
                    the shot, walked a few steps from his piece, and fell dead. I had also while in
                    this, my first position, the following men wounded: Vincent F. Burford, badly
                    bruised on shoulder; Silas C. Gentry, cut on the wrist; Joseph Moody, cut in the
                    face and bruised on the back; Byrd McCormick, shot through the calf of the leg
                    by a bullet from a spherical case; Edward J. Sheppard, wounded badly in heel,
                    and several others slightly wounded. I had killed in the lane while going to my
                    second position another excellent gunner, Corpl. Joseph T. V. Lantz. He had both
                    legs broken above the knees; lived but a little while. His only words were, "You
                    can do me no good; I am killed; follow your piece." While in my second position,
                    I had two men wounded: Hill Carter Eubank, shot through the leg. Eubank was a
                    very promising youth, about eighteen years of age; left the Military Institute
                    at Lexington, Va., to join the army; was brave and attentive to his duties. The
                    other, Claiborne Y. Atkinson struck on the leg by a piece of shell; seriously
                    wounded.</p>
                <p>About 9 p. m. July 2, I left my position, and retired about 1 mile to the rear,
                    watered and fed my horses, and returned to the same position about 2.30 o'clock
                    the next morning. I remained in this position until after the heavy cannonade of
                    the 3d. I was then ordered by Maj. Huger to report to you or to Gen. Longstreet,
                    about half a mile to my left. While taking my battery to the place indicated, I
                    was halted by Gen. Lee, and directed not to go into position until I saw you. It
                    was a considerable time before I could find you. The main fighting had ceased
                    when you came to where my battery was. About 10 p. m. we left the field, and
                    went into park near the barn used as a hospital.</p>
                <p>All of my men, non-commissioned officers and privates, with one or two
                    exceptions, acted well. They remained by their guns, though hungry and
                    exceedingly fatigued.</p>
                <p>On July 5, we took up our line of march for Hagerstown, Md., where we arrived on
                    the 6th, and went into encampment. We remained in the neighborhood of Hagerstown
                    several days, resting our men and horses, which they very much needed on account
                    of the long marching and arduous duties they had undergone.</p>
                <p>On the 10th, we left our encampment, and were moving over toward the pike leading
                    to Frederick City, when I was ordered to report with my battery to Gen. Kershaw,
                    then holding the enemy in check at Antietam Creek. I did report, and had a
                    position selected for me, but before I had gotten into it, I received further
                    orders to proceed at once to Downsville and rejoin my battalion, which I
                    accomplished about 10 p. m., after a tedious march through the dark.</p>
                <p>On the 11th, we had orders to dig pits for our pieces and prepare for action.
                    Again we met with a disappointment. The enemy did not advance.</p>
                <p>We left our fortifications on the evening of the 13th, and, after a very
                    disagreeable march, occupying the whole night, through mud, rain, and darkness,
                    we recrossed the Potomac on the morning of July 14. Thus ended our second
                    campaign into Maryland and Pennsylvania.</p>
                <p>On the evening of the 16th, we went into camp near Bunker Hill. Here we remained
                    several days, recruiting and getting together our scattered forces.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 20th, we again broke camp, and, after four days' travel, we
                    came in sight of Culpeper Court-House, men and horses nearly broken down, and
                    exhausted from excessive heat and long marching. We had rain nearly every day
                    from the day we entered the Valley until within the last few days. Our men
                    suffered much in consequence; their shoes gave out, and many had to go
                    barefooted. Much of their rest was broken by their not getting dry places to
                    sleep on.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>O. B. TAYLOR,<lb/> Capt., Comdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
