<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744232"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12744232">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Hall, William</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744232</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499001</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Hall, William</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 231-233</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value=""/>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744232T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June and July, 1863, New York State militia were sent to Pennsylvania to help
                    defend the state against Robert E. Lee's invasion in what became the Gettysburg
                    campaign. In this dispatch, William Hall, commander of the Third Brigade, New
                    York State National Guards, reports to New York State Governor Horatio Seymour
                    on the actions of his troops during the Gettysburg campaign. He mentions sending
                    New York State troops to Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 410. Report of Brig. Gen. William Hall, commanding Third Brigade, New
                    York State National Guard, of operations June 15--July 18.
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863">1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report to you the condition of the Third Brigade of the First
                    Division, composed of the Seventh, Eighth, Thirty-seventh, and Fifty-fifth
                    Regt.'s New York State National Guard.</p>
                <p>At the annual inspection held on the 9th, 12th, 14th, and 16th days of October
                    last, 1,929 were reported as present, and 621 as absent, making a total of
                    2,550, which is a large increase in numbers over the last year. The particulars
                    of said inspection are contained in the brigade major's report made heretofore
                    to the adjutant-general, to which Your Excellency is respectfully referred.</p>
                <p>It may not be deemed inappropriate for me to refer somewhat particularly to the
                    services performed by this brigade in the months of June and July last, at a
                    period when a loyal State was invaded by an armed foe, threatening to despoil
                    its citizens, to destroy its towns and cities, and set at defiance the
                    authorities of both the local and general governments.</p>
                <p>On the 15th day of June last, I received from you a telegraphic dispatch, as the
                    commander-in-chief of the militia force of the State of New York, to proceed
                    with my brigade, as speedily as possible,to the defense of the city of
                    Harrisburg, the capital of the State of Pennsylvania. By direction and orders of
                    Maj.-Gen. Sandford, the Seventy-first Regt. of the First Brigade was attached to
                    my command, to participate in the expedition.</p>
                <p>These five regiments promptly responded to Your Excellency's orders. The Seventh,
                    Eighth, Thirty-seventh, and Seventy-first Regt.'s left the city of New York on
                    the 16th, 17th, and 18th days of June; the Fifty-fifth Regt. left on the 24th.</p>
                <p>I reached the place of destination on the morning of the 20th of June, and
                    reported to Gen. Couch, who had command of all the military concentrated at that
                    point, acting under orders from the authorities at Washington.</p>
                <p>On the arrival of the Seventh and Fifty-fifth Regt.'s at the city of
                    Philadelphia, they were met by orders from general headquarters, detaching them
                    from my command. They were, by those orders, attached to the Third Army Corps of
                    the Army of the Potomac.</p>
                <p>On my arrival at Harrisburg, I found that the Eighth and Seventy-first Regt.'s
                    had been placed under the command of Gen. Knipe, of the U.S. Volunteer service,
                    and had been ordered to the front. I was placed immediately in command of all
                    the regiments detailed to the fortifications at Bridgeport, on the opposite side
                    of the Susquehanna River, or rather on the river opposite the city of
                    Harrisburg. In this force was included the Eleventh, Twenty-second, and
                    Thirty-seventh Regt.'s, one company of the Eighth Regt., and two companies of
                    the Fourth Regt. of Artillery, all from the city of New York; also five
                    regiments from the city of Brooklyn. The Eleventh and Twenty-second Regt.'s were
                    commanded by Brig.-Gen. Ewen; those from Brooklyn were under the command of
                    Brig.-Gen.'s Crooke and Smith.</p>
                <p>My first order was to send out pickets to a distance of 5 miles, making a
                    crescent form of 15 miles, to avoid a surprise by the enemy in our rear; this
                    duty was assigned to the Thirty-seventh Regt.</p>
                <p>On the 25th, I received an order to send two regiments to Marysville, about 8
                    miles up the river, to report to Gen. Yates. I sent the Thirteenth and
                    Twenty-eighth, of the Fifth Brigade. On the 26th, Brig.-Gen. Crooke, of that
                    brigade, reported for duty. I directed him to report to Gen. Yates, at
                    Marysville, where his command had been sent.</p>
                <p>On the 28th, Gen. Crooke returned with his brigade, and was quartered in the
                    fort. On the 27th, the Thirty-seventh Regt. was directed to proceed to the
                    front, under the command of Brig. Gen. W. F. Smith, of the U.S. Volunteers, with
                    the Eleventh and Twenty-second Regt.'s, under the command of Brig.-Gen. Ewen.
                    Brig. Gen. J. C. Smith, of Brooklyn, arrived with the Twenty-third,
                    Fifty-second, and Fifty-sixth Regt.'s, reported, and was sent to the front,
                    under the command of Brig. Gen. W. F. Smith.</p>
                <p>During our encampment, the Thirty-seventh, Thirteenth, Twenty-eighth, and several
                    other regiments worked on the defenses in the two forts on the heights, one of
                    which was called Fort Washington, the other named Fort Couch.</p>
                <p>On the 3d day of July, I received a verbal order from Gen. Couch to proceed
                    forthwith to the front with the Fifth Brigade. Accordingly, I directed
                    Brig.-Gen. Crooke to order his brigade to be in readiness to leave immediately.
                    We broke camp about 2 o'clock in the morning, and took the cars for Carlisle,
                    where we arrived at 7 a. m. While preparing to leave for Chambersburg, I
                    received a telegram from Gen. Couch to return and resume my former command. I
                    left the brigade at Carlisle, under the command of Brig.-Gen. Crooke, who
                    proceeded with it to Chambersburg.</p>
                <p>On my return, I found in the forts five companies of New Jersey troops (a very
                    fine body of men), two companies of the Fourth Regt. of Artillery, New York
                    State National Guard, one company of the Eighth Regt., under the command of
                    Capt. Robert Brown, New York State National Guard, and one company from
                    Philadelphia.</p>
                <p>On the 11th day of July, the Sixty-fifth Regt., of Buffalo, reached the forts en
                    route for home. It was detained some days on account of the difficulty then
                    existing to procure transportation. On the 14th, the startling intelligence
                    reached me that the city of New York was in a state of insubordination. Knowing
                    the small military force left to defend that city from internal foes, and
                    believing it important that relief should be sent there at the earliest possible
                    moment, I sought and obtained permission of Gen. Couch to send this regiment
                    there. It accordingly left my headquarters at daylight on the morning of the
                    15th, and arrived in the city of New York at about 4 o'clock in the afternoon of
                    the same day. The alarm produced by continued unfavorable reports in reference
                    to the insecurity of the lives and property of the citizens of the city of New
                    York, induced Gen. Couch to issue a general order directing the speedy return of
                    all the New York and New Jersey regiments. This order was executed on the 18th,
                    and the New York regiments reached the city the same evening.</p>
                <p>I cannot forbear expressing my obligations to Capt. B. Frishmuth, commanding an
                    independent company in the city of Philadelphia, for permission to bring with my
                    command from that city a battery of four guns of artillery, the private property
                    of his company, believing they might be of service in restoring municipal order
                    in the metropolis.</p>
                <p>During my operations in Pennsylvania, I was greatly assisted by Col. Pierson and
                    Col. Cone, both of the city of New York, who volunteered as members of my staff.
                    Their experience and skill in military affairs deserve acknowledgments.</p>
                <p>I herewith have the honor to inclose the reports of the colonels of the Seventh,
                    Eighth, Thirty-seventh, and Fifty-fifth Regt.'s, of their services during the
                    expedition.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>WM. HALL,<lb/> Comdg. Third Brigade, New York State National Guard.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
