<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745609"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745609">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R12745609</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499077</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and Confederate
       Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 609</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-07-08">1863-07-08</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="R12745609T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>After the battle of Gettysburg, the Union Army of the Potomac prepared to follow and attack
     Lee. In this letter, Union railroad expert Herman Haupt writes Quartermaster-General Montgomery
     C. Meigs concerning logistics for the planned advance. Haupt believes that heading Lee's army
     off at Staunton would do the most to force a surrender by depriving it of supplies.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">M. C. Meigs,<lb/> Quartermaster-Gen.:</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-07-08">July 8, 1863.<lb/> (Received 3.40 p. m.)</date>
      <name type="place">Frederick,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute/>
    </opener>
    <p>The difficulty here arose from the detention of twenty trains at Frederick, while fifteen
     more were on the road, bound west. Gen. French should have allowed the first trains to be
     unloaded and sent back, and taken others for troops when he was ready for them. The Cumberland
     Valley road is now becoming an important route. I am needed here no longer. The blockade is
     relieved. Fifteen or more trains have been returned, and I anticipate no further trouble. I
     will return immediately, go to Harrisburg, and push through the line to Hagerstown as fast as
     we can get possession. We should be able to capture many prisoners and take wagons and
     ambulances, and perhaps artillery, before the enemy can cross the river. The late rains and bad
     roads will help us, but I do not believe we can prevent Lee's army from crossing. I could build
     trestle-bridges of round sticks, and floor with fence rails. It is too much to assume that the
     rebels cannot do the same.</p>
    <p>If they get across, we should not follow at their heels, but strike at once for White Plains,
     use the railroad from that point, and head them off at Staunton. It seems to me that every
     effort must be made by the rebels to save Lee by sending him supplies via the Shenandoah
     Valley.</p>
    <p>If we could find force enough to occupy the passes of the Blue Ridge, we could capture supply
     trains, and reduce the rebels to such a state of destitution as would compel a surrender. Our
     course seems to me to be a clear one, and, if you concur in this opinion, I hope you will talk
     it over with Gen. Halleck.</p>
    <p>In making your arrangements, if it becomes necessary to send troops from this vicinity to be
     transported south over the Orange and Alexandria Railroad, much time and confusion will be
     saved by marching to White Plains. They should not be sent through Washington by rail. I have
     mentioned this to Ingalls, and he concurs in the opinion.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>H. HAUPT.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
