<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745865"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745865">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745865</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499130</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 865</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-07">1863-06-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745865T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee instructs General John Imboden to bother the enemy in the
                    Shenandoah Valley during June, 1863. Lee also orders Imboden to cooperate with
                    commissary agents near Staunton in obtaining cattle for the army. Lee also hopes
                    Imboden will have success recruiting soldiers in the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Army of Northern Virginia,
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. J. D. Imboden,<lb/> Comdg. Northwestern
                        Brigade, via Staunton:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-07">June 7, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In view of operations in the Shenandoah Valley, I desire you to attract the
                    enemy's attention in Hampshire County, and to proceed down to Romney, or such
                    other point as you may consider best calculated for the purpose. After leaving a
                    sufficient guard on the Shenandoah Mountain, you can use the rest of your
                    command for the purpose specified. In attracting their attention and detaining
                    whatever force they may have at New Creek, Cumberland, Cacapon, &amp;c., you
                    will, of course, do them all the injury in your power by striking them a
                    damaging blow at any point where opportunity offers, and where you deem most
                    practicable. It will be important, if you can accomplish it, to destroy some of
                    the bridges, so as to prevent communication and the transfer of re-enforcements
                    to Martinsburg. After accomplishing what you can in Hampshire, should you find
                    it practicable or advantageous, you can co-operate with any troops that you may
                    find operating in the Valley. Forward to the commanding officer of the force
                    there any information that you may deem important, and comply with any
                    requisition on his part.</p>
                <p>I desire you to move into Hampshire as soon as possible. Let me know the time of
                    your departure and the time of your expected arrival. In connection with this
                    purpose, it is important that you should obtain, for the use of the army, all
                    the cattle that you can. Communicate with the agents of the Commissary
                    Department you may find purchasing in the country west of Staunton, and let them
                    make arrangements to assist you in purchasing and taking care of the cattle.
                    Maj. B. P. Noland, of that department, is now in that region, making
                    arrangements for cattle. I wish you to communicate with him, if practicable. I
                    hope you will also be able, while in that country, to collect recruits for your
                    brigade, both cavalry and infantry, and bring them out with you.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
