<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12744327"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12744327">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12744327</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499007</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Guild, Lafayette</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 44</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 326-328</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-29">1863-06-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12744327T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In early July, 1863, the Army of Northern Virginia retreated back across the
                    Potomac River after their defeat at Gettysburg. In this letter, Army of Northern
                    Virginia Medical Director Lafayette Guild reports to Surgeon General Samuel P.
                    Moore on attempts to care for the wounded during the retreat from Pennsylvania.
                    Guild reports sending many sick and wounded to Staunton, VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 427. Report of Surg. Lafayette Guild, C. S. Army, Medical Director, with
                    Return of Casualties in the Army of Northern Virginia.<lb/> Medical Director's
                    Office,
                    <name type="recipient">Surg. Gen. S. P. Moore,<lb/> Richmond, Va.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-29">July 29, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Culpeper Court-House,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>At midnight, July 3, after the fiercest and most sanguinary battle ever fought on
                    this continent, the general commanding gave orders for our army to withdraw from
                    Gettysburg and fall back to Hagerstown. I inclose you a copy of my instructions
                    to the corps of medical directors issued on that occasion. Every available means
                    of transportation was called into requisition for removing the wounded from the
                    field infirmaries, and, on the evening of the 4th, our ambulance trains took up
                    their line of march by two routes, guarded as well as could be by our
                    broken-down and inefficient cavalry. One train went by Cashtown, the other by
                    Fairfield. The latter train was attacked by a body of the enemy's cavalry, who
                    destroyed many wagons and paroled the wounded private soldiers, but taking with
                    them all of the officers who fell into their hands. The former train was more
                    fortunate; however, it, too, was attacked by the enemy, and met with some little
                    loss in wagons and prisoners.</p>
                <p>The poor wounded suffered very much indeed in their rapid removal by day and
                    night, over rough roads, through mountain passes, and across streams, toward the
                    Potomac. Those who could be removed from the battle-field and infirmaries were
                    concentrated at Williamsport, and transferred to the Virginia bank of the river,
                    by rafts and ferry-boats, as rapidly as the swollen condition of the stream
                    would permit.</p>
                <p>Since my hasty and imperfect letter of the 10th instant from the vicinity of
                    Hagerstown, Md., I have not had time or opportunity to report to you more fully
                    our movements. At Hagerstown, as I informed you in my last letter, we fully
                    expected another battle, and prepared for it.</p>
                <p>We waited there six long days, nearly every day the two armies engaging in
                    desultory skirmishing. When the enemy made his appearance in force, instead of
                    attacking us, as we expected, he commenced fortifying himself all along our line
                    of battle, his line being little less than a mile from ours.</p>
                <p>Our supplies for both men and animals were being rapidly exhausted, and the enemy
                    declining battle by laying aside his muskets and taking to his picks and
                    shovels, orders were given for us to resume our march toward the Potomac on the
                    13th instant. The army crossed at three points (two fords near Williamsport,
                    very deep and bad fords, the river being swollen, at which quite a number of
                    animals were drowned, and the pontoon bridge at Falling Waters) without
                    molestation from the enemy, who contented himself with picking up stragglers.</p>
                <p>Our crossing the river without annoyance evidently shows that the enemy were very
                    badly crippled, and could not risk another general engagement. The sufferings of
                    the wounded were distressing. Indeed, the healthiest and most robust suffered
                    extremely in crossing the river.</p>
                <p>The head of our column commenced its passage at dark on the 13th instant, and, in
                    the afternoon of the 14th, the rear guard reached the south bank.</p>
                <p>On July 15, we encamped near Bunker Hill, 12 miles north of Winchester, and
                    remained there until the 21st, refreshing the troops and removing to the rear
                    our sick and wounded from Winchester and Jordan Springs, at which place I found
                    about 4,000 sick and wounded, steps for their removal to Staunton being
                    immediately taken. All who could bear transportation were gotten off by the 22d
                    instant, less than 150 remaining at the two places.</p>
                <p>Mount Jackson and Harrisonburg have been used simply as wayside hospitals, where
                    the sick and wounded were refreshed with food, and wounds redressed.</p>
                <p>Medical officers, with supplies of all kinds, being stationed at the two points,
                    on the 22d the army resumed its march, the First and Third Corps taking
                    different routes to Front Royal and Chester Gap, where they were convalesced,
                    and the march continued to this point, where they encamped on the 25th, and are
                    now resting after their arduous night marches through great inclemency of
                    weather. The Second Army Corps crossed the Blue Ridge at Thornton's Gap, south
                    of Chester Gap, and will encamp in our vicinity to-day. Considerable sickness
                    has been the consequence of their fatigue and exposure. Diarrhea, dysentery,
                    continued fever, and rheumatism preponderate.</p>
                <p>I have prohibited the establishment of a hospital at Culpeper Court House, but
                    organized a depot for the sick and wounded who cannot be treated in camp. Those
                    who should go to general hospitals are sent with all dispatch to Gordonsville
                    for distribution. The sick and wounded should, in my opinion, by no means be
                    allowed to accumulate at Gordonsville. It is or may be at any time exposed to
                    cavalry raids, and the inhuman enemy invariably, when an opportunity offers,
                    drag our sick and wounded officers (at the sacrifice of their lives) into their
                    own lines.</p>
                <p>Mount Jackson and Harrisonburg, in the Valley of the Shenandoah, should be
                    abandoned as hospitals, as far as practicable, leaving only those patients whose
                    lives would be endangered by transportation.</p>
                <p>I have ordered Surgeon R. J. Breckinridge, medical inspector of the army, to
                    proceed to the hospitals near the army where our sick and wounded have been sent
                    since the battle of Gettysburg, and to have all who are fit for duty returned to
                    their regiments. I inclose for your information a copy of my letter of
                    instructions to him and order from the general commanding. The list of
                    casualties has been forwarded to my office, and embraces the whole army, with
                    the exception of two brigades, which I have taken steps to have made out.</p>
                <p>Our loss at Gettysburg was very heavy, indeed, numbering about 14,000 killed and
                    wounded. The consolidated list will be furnished you at an early day.</p>
                <p>At the battle of Winchester, fought by Gen. Ewell's corps on June 13, 14, and 15,
                    our loss was comparatively small--42 killed and 210 wounded.</p>
                <p>I will also forward to you very soon the list of casualties, properly prepared.</p>
                <p>Complaints are very frequently made by medical officers and officers of the line
                    that many of the sick and wounded who are sent to general hospital are never
                    heard from, the hospital surgeons failing to report deaths, discharges,
                    furloughs, &amp;c. I would again respectfully request that means be adopted
                    for the correction of this neglect of duty on the part of medical officers in
                    general hospital. I am exceedingly anxious to have a personal interview with you
                    relative to some changes in the organization of our corps in the field,
                    particularly in the purveying department. It is impossible for me to visit
                    Richmond at this time, but hope soon to have an opportunity. My office is
                    exhausted of blank forms. Please have forwarded to me the following, viz.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, sir, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>L. GUILD,<lb/> Medical Director, Army of Northern Virginia.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
