<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745477"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12745477">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745477</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499055</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 476-477</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-01">1863-07-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745477T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union railroad expert Herman Haupt writes General In Chief Henry Halleck on the
                    situation in Pennsylvania in this July 1, 1863, dispatch. Haupt reports on the
                    strengths of Confederate troops occupying Chambersburg, and mentions that Lee
                    was in the square at Chambersburg with his men.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. Halleck,<lb/> Gen.-in-Chief, U.S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-01">July 1, 1863</date>--6 a. m.
                        <name type="place">Harrisburg,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I sent you two telegrams last night, and sent the same to Gen. Schenck.</p>
                <p>Finding the communications cut with Meade's army, I concluded to run to
                    Harrisburg, ascertain the position of affairs, then return to Baltimore, and try
                    to work my way through to Frederick.</p>
                <p>I found that there had been some skirmishing near Harrisburg yesterday; that the
                    forces gathered for the protection of the place amounted to 16,000 men, and that
                    information in regard to the movements, position, and numbers of the enemy, and
                    arrangements for keeping advised of the same, were apparently reliable.</p>
                <p>It appears to have been the intention of the enemy to attack Harrisburg
                    yesterday. Our forces, supposed to be Pleasonton's, were resisting their
                    movements, and, T. A. Scott said, had actually succeeded in retarding the
                    advance on Harrisburg, and compelled a retreat. I thought I saw a much more
                    decisive and important move on the tapis. Lee had received information of the
                    removal of Hooker, and the substitution of Meade. He knew also that Meade's
                    communications were cut by Stuart; that some confusion must exist from the
                    change of commanders; that Meade could not at once get his forces in hand, and
                    that, by suddenly concentrating and falling upon Meade, he could be crushed,
                    when Washington, Baltimore, and Philadelphia would all be at the mercy of the
                    enemy. I mentioned to Scott my opinion, in which he at once concurred, and I
                    immediately sent the telegrams to you and Gen. Schenck last night.</p>
                <p>The most reliable information as to the numbers of the enemy, as given by Scott,
                    is as follows: Ewell, 23,000 men, 48 pieces; Longstreet, 30,000 men, 122 pieces;
                    Hill, 24,000 men, pieces not known; Early, 15,000 men, 26 pieces; total, 92,000
                    men and 236 pieces, exclusive of Hill's. Forces of Ewell were counted in
                    Carlisle, Friday p. m. June 26, as they passed. They left Carlisle by the
                    Baltimore pike, Tuesday June 30, 5 a. m.</p>
                <p>Longstreet's corps passed through Chambersburg on Friday and Saturday 27th, in
                    the direction of Carlisle. In Carlisle Sunday evening; left on Monday afternoon;
                    went through Newville with artillery in full trot, in the direction of
                    Shippensburg, probably to take the Gettysburg road from this point.</p>
                <p>Lee was in the square at Chambersburg at 9 a. m. Saturday, with 8,000 men and 40
                    pieces (part of Hill's). Left, after a conference with Hill, in the direction of
                    Gettysburg.</p>
                <p>Hill's corps commenced leaving Chambersburg at 12 m. Saturday, three hours after
                    Lee, in same direction.</p>
                <p>Early left Gettysburg for York Saturday; entered York Sunday; left York 2 p. m.
                    Tuesday.</p>
                <p>Firing Tuesday for several hours about Dillsburg and Petersburg, on the line
                    between York and Gettysburg.</p>
                <p>I am leaving for Baltimore.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>H. HAUPT.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
