<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12745996"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12745996">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12745996</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499157</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jones, Samuel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 995-996</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-11">1863-07-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12745996T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Samuel Jones writes Secretary of War James Seddon concerning
                    the July, 1863, situation in western Virginia. He reports on troops moving from
                    Dublin to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. James A. Seddon,<lb/> Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-11">July 11, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place"> Salt Sulphur Springs, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>On the 9th instant, I received a dispatch from Col. McCausland, commanding near
                    Raleigh Court-House, informing me that the enemy at Fayetteville had been
                    re-enforced; that he had captured their mail, and he apprehended that he would
                    soon be attacked, and asked for re-enforcements. The only troops I could have
                    sent him were those I had ordered, under instructions from you, to go to the
                    Valley, and I did not think the extent of the re-enforcements he then mentioned
                    the enemy had received sufficient to excite serious apprehension for the safety
                    of the position held by McCausland. About 5 o'clock this morning, however, I
                    received another dispatch from him, informing me that the enemy's troops in the
                    Kanawha Valley had been concentrated at Fayetteville to attack and drive him
                    off; that they had seven regiments of infantry, two regiments of cavalry, and
                    two batteries of artillery, while he had but two regiments of infantry, four
                    companies of cavalry, and two batteries, and lie urges me to send him
                    re-enforcements. I have, therefore, reluctantly stopped the movement of the
                    2,000 infantry from Lewisburg to Winchester, that I might be able to re-enforce
                    Col. McCausland.</p>
                <p>The position he holds I regard as very important, and if my force there were
                    driven away and overwhelmed, the way to the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad
                    would be entirely open to the enemy, and this section of country would have to
                    be temporarily abandoned.</p>
                <p>Under all the circumstances, therefore, I thought it my duty to delay, at least,
                    the movement to Winchester, and telegraphed you this morning that I had done so.
                    I felt the less hesitation in doing so, because, before you ordered away any
                    portion of my troops, the President asked me if any could be spared, and I
                    presume it was on my reply that the order was given, circumstances having so
                    materially changed since I wrote to the President that I could not doubt the
                    propriety of acting according to the dictates of my own judgment, under the
                    altered condition of affairs.</p>
                <p>Col. Wharton was to have started, and I presume did start, from Dublin yesterday
                    evening, with 1,100 infantry by railroad per Lynchburg to Staunton. From thence
                    he will move without unnecessary delay to Winchester. As so small a portion of
                    the force ordered to Winchester is now en route to that place, and the
                    circumstances having so changed as to justify me, I think, in delaying the
                    movement of the others, I shall not go to Winchester myself unless ordered to do
                    so after you receive my telegram of this morning. I have received no orders or
                    instructions in regard to the move to Winchester other than your telegram and
                    one from Gen. Cooper, simply directing me to go with my troops to Winchester,
                    where I would receive orders. If ordered to go to Winchester, I can reach there
                    as soon as Col. Wharton can with his command.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>SAM. JONES,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
