<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R127459862"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R127459862">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence. </title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R127459862</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499152</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 45</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 986</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-09">1863-07-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R127459862T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes George Pickett countermanding his July, 1863, orders that
                    Pickett's Division accompany prisoners to Staunton. Lee apologizes for any
                    damage the assignment may have done to the division's fragile confidence in the
                    wake of Gettysburg. Instead, Lee sent Imboden to Staunton, where he was also
                    instructed to muster in new recruits and shoe his horses.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Army of Northern Virginia,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. George E. Pickett,<lb/> Comdg., &amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-09">July 9, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Gen.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 8th has been received.</p>
                <p>It was with reluctance that I imposed upon your gallant division the duty of
                    conveying prisoners to Staunton. I regretted to assign them to such service, as
                    well as to separate them from the army, though temporarily, with which they have
                    been so long and efficiently associated. Though small in numbers, their worth is
                    not diminished, and I had supposed that the division itself would be loth to
                    part from its comrades at a time when the presence of every man is so essential.
                    I therefore felt gratified to be able to assign to the charge of the prisoners a
                    portion of Gen. Imboden's command, which I thought could be better spared from
                    the army at this time, and enable him to muster into service some newly
                    organized companies that have been completed since he left Staunton, shoe his
                    horses, and return to the army more quickly than an infantry force. It would
                    also spare your division a long and disagreeable march.</p>
                <p>These were the reasons that governed me, and, in my opinion, are the best for the
                    public service. I regret that it has occasioned you and your officers any
                    disappointment. If circumstances permitted, I should be glad to allow your
                    division to move to Winchester, if it would afford any gratification or benefit,
                    but I need not tell you how essential it is not to diminish this army by a
                    single man, if possible. I still have the greatest confidence in your division,
                    and feel assured that with you at its head, it will be able to accomplish any
                    service upon which it may be placed. You can send an efficient officer with a
                    portion of your division that you may assign as a guard to the prisoners, as far
                    as Winchester, with directions there to collect all your convalescents and
                    others, and to return to you as soon as possible.</p>
                <p>In the meantime, I trust you will lend all your energies as well as those of your
                    division to sending off our wounded prisoners and all surplus articles belonging
                    to the army, and having them conveyed beyond Winchester. No time should be lost
                    in accomplishing this, and I rely mainly upon you to effect it.</p>
                <p>No one grieves more than I do at the loss suffered by your noble division in the
                    recent conflict, or honors it more for its bravery and gallantry. It will afford
                    me heartfelt satisfaction, when an opportunity occurs, to do all in my power to
                    recruit its diminished ranks, and to reorganize it in the most efficient manner.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
