<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12743977"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R12743977">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Gregg, J. Irvin</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12743977</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:498996</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XXXIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xxxix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Gregg, J. Irvin</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 27, Serial No. 43</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 976-977</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-05">1863-08-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12743977T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>After the July, 1863, battle of Gettysburg, Robert E. Lee's Army of Northern
                    Virginia withdrew toward the Potomac pursued by some Union cavalry. In this
                    dispatch, J. Irvin Gregg of the Sixteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry reports capturing
                    Confederate soldiers and abandoned ammunition caissons near Marion on the road
                    from Chambersburg to Greencastle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Hdqrs. Third Brig., Second Div., Cavalry Corps
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. H. C. Weir,<lb/> Asst. Adjt. Gen., Second Division,
                        Cavalry Corps.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-05">August 5, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Amissville, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report the following as the part taken by this command in the
                    battle of Gettysburg:</p>
                <p>My command arrived and took up position on the pike leading from Gettysburg to
                    Hanover, about 2 miles distant from Gettysburg and in close proximity to Gen.
                    Ewell's corps, about 11 a. m. on July 2. At this time there were two regiments
                    of infantry a short distance in my front, deployed as skirmishers. These
                    regiments were withdrawn about 3 p. m., and, by order of Gen. Gregg, I threw
                    forward the Tenth New York Cavalry, under command of Maj. Avery, and deployed
                    skirmishers to occupy the ground vacated.</p>
                <p>During the afternoon, my vedettes were considerably annoyed by the enemy's
                    sharpshooters from the hill and woods immediately in my front, and at 6 o'clock
                    I ordered 50 dismounted men to clear the hill and find out what was beyond, but
                    they were driven back by a much superior force, and followed until the enemy
                    were checked and driven back by Col. J. B. McIntosh's command.</p>
                <p>On the morning of July 3, by order of Gen. Gregg, my command took up position on
                    the road leading from Gettysburg to Baltimore, not far distant from the position
                    occupied by Gen. Slocum's corps, but was subsequently moved, and took up a
                    position near the one occupied on July 2.</p>
                <p>My command did not participate in the cavalry fight of July 3, excepting one
                    section of Capt. Randol's battery, under command of Lieut. Chester, which was
                    hotly engaged, and was obliged to retire about 200 yards on account of a portion
                    of Gen. Custer's command giving way. The Fourth Pennsylvania Cavalry, having
                    been sent to report to Gen. Pleasonton, was not with me during July 3, but
                    joined men in the evening of that day, when my command was ordered to move to
                    the front and take up a position on the left, in order to meet a threatened
                    attack from that direction. While remaining in that position, the enemy got my
                    range, and wounded several men in the Tenth New York Cavalry by bursting shells.</p>
                <p>On July 4, 5, and 6, my command was engaged in pursuing the enemy as far as
                    Marion, on the pike leading from Chambersburg to Greencastle, Franklin County.
                    During the pursuit, a large number of prisoners were captured, and the enemy
                    obliged to abandon a number of limbers and caissons filled with ammunition,
                    which were left in condition for immediate use.</p>
                <p>The casualties are as follows: Killed, 4; wounded, 5.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. IRVIN GREGG,<lb/> Col. Sixteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry, Comdg.
                        Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
