<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948548"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948548">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. John D. Imboden.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen john d imboden</title>
        <author>Imboden, John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948548</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499166</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. John D. Imboden.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen john d imboden</title>
            <author>Imboden, John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 547-549</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-11-14">1863-11-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948548T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports from Staunton to Robert Chilton, Lee's
                    Chief of Staff, on November, 1863, efforts to oppose a raid in West Virginia and
                    the Valley by Union cavalry under William Averell. At one point, Imboden felt
                    that Staunton was threatened, and he reports calling out the Augusta Home
                    Guards.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No 22. Report of Brig. Gen. John D. Imboden, C. S. Army, commanding Valley
                    District, of operations November 4-14.
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-11-14">November 14, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">STAUNTON,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>On the evening of the 4th instant, I received a note from Lieutenant Byrd,
                    commanding detachment at Hightown, in Highland County, that the enemy had
                    appeared over 5,000 strong at Camp Barrow, on the east side of Cheat Mountain,
                    and a few hours later another dispatch that he had moved toward Huntersville.</p>
                <p>At daybreak on the 5th, I left my camp, 4 miles from Bridgewater, and moved to
                    Buffalo Gap and encamped. I ordered six days' rations (hard bread and bacon) to
                    be sent on the cars to Goshen Depot, and on the 6th I left Buffalo Gap with my
                    best mounted men (about 600 men) and a section of artillery, without baggage.
                    Halted at Goshen, issued provisions to the men, and encamped at Bratton's, in
                    Bath County.</p>
                <p>Started at dawn on the 7th, and passed the Warm Springs at 1 p. m. on the
                    Huntersville road. There heard that a battle was fought on the 6th between the
                    forces of General Echols and Colonel Jackson and the enemy at Mill Point, in
                    Pocahontas. I resolved to fall upon the enemy's rear if possible and pushed on.
                    At the foot of Back Creek Mountain a courier from Covington brought me a
                    dispatch from Captain Skeen that Echols was badly defeated; had retreated
                    through Lewisburg toward Monroe; that a large column of the enemy had arrived at
                    Lewisburg from Kanawha, making the entire hostile force at that point 15,000
                    strong. Believing it impossible to cross by Huntersville and do any good, I
                    changed my course down Jackson's River toward Covington. That night I received a
                    telegram from General Samuel Jones in cipher, which I could not read, never
                    having been furnished the key.</p>
                <p>On Sunday, the 8th, I pressed on to Covington, where I found more than 100
                    panic-stricken refugees from Colonel Jackson's command, and that night more came
                    in. I placed a company on picket at Callaghan's. A little after dark my picket
                    was attacked. Had one horse shot, but repelled the enemy and held the post.</p>
                <p>When I changed my course down Jackson's River on Saturday I sent an order to the
                    Rockbridge Home Guards and Cadets, who were at Millborough, to go to Clifton
                    Forge, which they did on Sunday, and encamped only 13 miles from me. They
                    numbered about 800 men and had two 6-pounder guns.</p>
                <p>On Monday, the 9th, at dawn, the enemy appeared in force at Callaghan's and
                    attacked my picket. It came in slowly. One and a half miles west of Covington I
                    took position on the crest of a mountain to give battle. The force that drove in
                    my picket was about 400 cavalry. When the head of the column came within about
                    1,200 yards I opened on it with my artillery, and by a few shots repulsed and
                    scattered it, when two companies of my cavalry charged and drove the whole force
                    back at full run to Callaghan's, where they joined the main column, over 3,000
                    strong, and moved off on the Warm Springs road. As soon as apprised of this
                    fact, and that the enemy had seven pieces of artillery along, I felt sure he
                    intended to get in my rear, if possible, by a country road, which I knew was
                    entirely practicable. I at once withdrew to a hill 1 mile east of Covington, and
                    sent to hurry up the Rockbridge forces, intending to give battle at that point
                    (a very strong position) to whatever force might appear. In the meanwhile a part
                    of my cavalry, under Colonel Imboden, were thrown out about 4 or 5 miles to
                    watch the enemy's movements.</p>
                <p>Early in the afternoon it was ascertained that Averell had left the Warm Springs
                    road and gone off toward Huntersville. As it was possible this might be a ruse,
                    and that he would sweep around by the Warm Springs and reach Millborough, I
                    resolved to move, via Clifton Forge, to Goshen as quick as possible, sending
                    scouts to watch Averell and report to me at Goshen. I commenced my march at
                    once, and in a little over twenty-four hours made Goshen, a distance of 40
                    miles, on the 10th. Hearing from my scouts I dismissed the Rockbridge forces. My
                    scouts reported Averell as making for Monterey, up Back Creek, and moving very
                    rapidly.</p>
                <p>On the 11th, I came to Buffalo Gap, where I ascertained beyond a doubt that
                    Mulligan, with a fresh force of 800 men from Petersburg, would form a junction
                    that evening with Averell at Monterey. I then deemed a raid on Staunton highly
                    probable, and to repel it (tired as were my men) I ordered up l50 men to top of
                    Shenandoah Mountain (16 miles distant) that night, and followed in the morning
                    with 750 more and four pieces of artillery, and called out the Augusta Home
                    Guards. Mulligan and Averell did form a junction, making their united force near
                    4,000 men, but made no effort to reach Staunton. They went on toward Hardy.</p>
                <p>Having sent Captain McNeill into Hardy two weeks ago with 200 men, who are still
                    there, I immediately dispatched three couriers to his party to obstruct the
                    roads about and north of Franklin, and take position in the cliffs and bushwhack
                    the enemy as he passed. I also sent 40 fresh cavalry to harass him at different
                    points in the mountains. I expect to hear good accounts from both these parties.
                    The force that accompanied me was much jaded, having marched nearly 200 miles in
                    six days through the mountains and over bad roads. Although I inflicted no
                    appreciable damage on the enemy, I am certain I saved all the furnaces (six or
                    eight in full blast) on the west side of Rockbridge and Botetourt Counties. I
                    have information that leaves no doubt that the column I repulsed at Covington
                    were furnished with several days' rations and ordered to proceed down Jackson's
                    River, burn the depots and bridges, destroy the furnaces, and retreat by
                    Millborough and Warm Springs to the main body.</p>
                <p>I will rest two days, and on Monday move down into the lower end of Rockingham or
                    Shenandoah, and see what further can be done before winter sets in. I am
                    satisfied Averell will seek to winter his cavalry at Moore field. Forage and
                    other supplies are abundant in that rich valley. He has over 3,000 men, Mulligan
                    over 1,000--a force too large for me to drive out. I will harass them all
                    winter, but that is all I can do. To-morrow I start Captain Hill with a company
                    to Barbour County to try and capture a train from Grafton to Beverly. There are
                    but about 500 men left at Beverly.</p>
                <p>I beg leave to add my testimony to the admirable spirit displayed by the people
                    of Rockbridge in coming to my assistance. At 7 p. m. on Thursday, the 6th, the
                    news reached Lexington of this raid. By 7 p. m. the next day 800 men were 12
                    miles on their march to support me. My thanks are especially due Col. J. W.
                    Massie, commanding home guards, and. General F. H. Smith, commanding cadets, for
                    the energy and zeal they manifested and the skill with which they moved their
                    commands so rapidly through the mountains.</p>
                <p>I regret to have to add that of nearly 200 stragglers from Colonel
                    Jackson's--whom I found at Covington and supplied with funds to subsist
                    themselves, and supplied with arms, where they had lost their own, out of some
                    Virginia State arms I found at Covington--a large number ran off to the woods
                    and mountains as soon as my artillery opened on the enemy, although I had
                    organized them into two companies and ordered them to take part in the fight I
                    then expected would occur. A part remained and were willing to fight, but a
                    large number fled most shamefully before the enemy was nearer than 2 miles of
                    where I left them to await orders.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brigadier-General, Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
