<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948972"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948972">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of General Jubal Early.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of general jubal early</title>
        <author>Lee, Fitzhugh</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948972</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499181</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of General Jubal Early.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of general jubal early</title>
            <author>Lee, Fitzhugh</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 971-972</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-24">1863-12-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948972T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Cavalry General Fitzhugh Lee reports on December, 1863, operations
                    around Staunton and in the Valley. Lee's cavalry played a role in opposing a
                    Union raid led by William Averell into West Virginia and the Shenandoah
                Valley.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 14. Report of Maj. Gen. Fitzhugh Lee, C. S. Army, commanding Cavalry
                    Division, Army of Northern Virginia. HEADQUARTERS,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. A. S. PENDLETON,<lb/> Major-General.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-24">December 24, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of recent operations, for the
                    information of the major-general commanding:</p>
                <p>Left the army on the Rapidan, with two brigades of my command, on the 11th
                    instant, for the purpose of going into winter quarters near Charlottesville, my
                    other brigade being left to picket.</p>
                <p>Reached Charlottesville on the 12th, and left on 14th, in obedience to an order
                    from General Stuart to interpose my command between the force threatening
                    Staunton from the lower valley and that place.</p>
                <p>Reached Valley turnpike at Mount Crawford (the lowest place I could cross the
                    Shenandoah), by way of Brown's Gap, on the 15th, and finding all quiet in lower
                    valley, the enemy being at Strasburg with no signs of an advance, I turned up
                    the pike with the purpose of assisting Imboden, who was said to be confronting a
                    superior force of enemy on Shenandoah Mountain, and encamped on night of 15th 6
                    miles from Staunton. The same night Major General Early arrived at Staunton and
                    took command.</p>
                <p>On 16th, my command arrived at same place and was ordered back to lower valley,
                    encamping that night near Mount Crawford. On 17th, in compliance with orders</p>
                
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of recent operations, for the
                    information of the major-general commanding:</p>
                <p>Left the army on the Rapidan, with two brigades of my command, on the 11th
                    instant, for the purpose of going into winter quarters near Charlottesville, my
                    from General Early, retraced my steps, and started in pursuit of Averell,
                    marching day and night in the cold storm, and reaching Lexington on 18th at
                    daylight, and uniting at that point with General Imboden, and the home guards of
                    Rockbridge, under Colonel Massie.</p>
                <p>On night of 18th, encamped at Collierstown, at the foot of North Mountain. It was
                    there that I received a dispatch from the major general commanding inclosing a
                    telegram from General Nicholls, at Lynchburg, to the effect that the enemy were
                    returning to Salem, and expressing the hope that I was on the way to Buchanan.
                    Intelligence that the enemy were back in Salem was soon after brought to me,
                    also, by one of Colonel Massie's scouts. My advance, then (19th) upon top of
                    North Mountain, was halted and countermarched; and that night I encamped between
                    Buchanan and Fincastle. Averell was then encamped at Covington. At Buchanan I
                    first learned the falsity of report, but could not ascertain whether the enemy
                    had gone in the direction of Sweet Springs or Covington.</p>
                <p>Upon my arrival at Fincastle on 20th, learning that the enemy had gone toward
                    Covington, I marched for that place, reaching it two days after him. I still
                    followed on, with the hope that his course might be checked or retarded, giving
                    me time to close up. After passing Callaghan's I learned that there was no other
                    force in his front, so turned off to Warm Springs, striking the Central Railroad
                    at Goshen. Had my march across North Mountain not been changed by dispatches
                    received, and the conviction that if I interposed between the enemy and myself a
                    stream represented as likely to be impassable for some days, I would leave the
                    route by Buchanan open and expose Lexington, or enable him to retire on south of
                    Virginia and Tennessee Railroad, or through Giles and Monroe Counties, without
                    molestation, I should have arrived at Covington three hours ahead of him; or had
                    Colonel Jackson destroyed the bridge over Jackson's River, or interposed any
                    obstructions to his march, Averell's command must have been captured.</p>
                <p>Too much credit cannot be attributed to the cheerfulness with which both the
                    members of General Imboden's command and my own have borne the privations and
                    exposure of a long march in weather of uncommon severity, and the alacrity they
                    evinced to meet the enemy. My own command has marched over 300 miles in twelve
                    days.</p>
                <p>As far as I can learn, Averell's force consisted of the Second, Third, and Eighth
                    Regiments of West Virginia Cavalry; the Fourteenth Pennsylvania, Major Gibson's
                    battalion, and Captain Ewing's battery of six guns--in all about 1,700 men--said
                    to be mostly six-months' volunteers, whose term of service expires in January
                    next. He lost all his wagons, and is reported to have carried but three of six
                    pieces of artillery back past Callaghan's. Colonel Jackson can report the number
                    of prisoners taken.</p>
                <p>My especial thanks are due to General F. H. Smith, of Virginia Military
                    Institute, for the promptness with which he moved his command and the eagerness
                    he evinced for the capture of the enemy; and to Mr. Mann, formerly sheriff of
                    Rockbridge County, for valuable services.</p>
                <p>The casualties of my command are confined to the loss of Private Marmaduke, of
                    the Ninth Virginia Cavalry, who was drowned while fording Jackson's River.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>FITZ. LEE,<lb/> Major-General.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
