<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948197"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948197">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of John Imboden.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of john imboden</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948197</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499159</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of John Imboden.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of john imboden</title>
            <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 197-198</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-01">1863-10-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948197T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports to Robert E. Lee on September, 1863,
                    actions in West Virginia and the Shenandoah Valley. Imboden mentions sending the
                    Baker horses to Staunton. He also discusses the new Union Valley commander
                    McReynold's treatment of civilians.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 2. Report of Brig. Gen. John D. Imboden, C. S. Army, including
                    operations September 24-30,
                    <name type="recipient">General R. E. LEE.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-01">October 1, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">HEADQUARTERS VALLEY DISTRICT,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your order in regard to the Baker horses has been complied with. The residue were
                    started to Staunton day before yesterday. As soon as Major Shumate, my
                    quartermaster, gets his receipts from Major Bell, I will forward to you his
                    official statement of the horses turned over. Although somewhat improved--those
                    that are living--they are still unserviceable for artillery or transportation.</p>
                <p>I sent 250 men to Hampshire, to attempt to break the railroad, under command of
                    Lieutenant-Colonel Beall, Eighteenth Cavalry, a brave and energetic officer, a
                    citizen of Hampshire. If anything can be done he will accomplish it. I also
                    ordered Major Gilmor to try it in the valley above or below Martinsburg. I have
                    but little hope that any considerable damage can be done. The bridges are all
                    too strongly guarded to be destroyed by a small force, and damage elsewhere must
                    be necessarily easily repaired; and with a considerable force stationed at
                    Romney, Martinsburg, and Petersburg, the enemy can render the escape of an
                    attacking party a difficult undertaking. As soon as I hear the result I will
                    communicate it to you.</p>
                <p>My cavalry (Eighteenth Regiment) made a scout last week and this down into
                    Frederick, Jefferson, and Clarke, remaining the greater part of three days below
                    Winchester, hoping to draw the enemy out of Martinsburg and Harper's Ferry, but
                    were unsuccessful, and returned without accomplishing anything beyond gaining
                    information of the enemy's position and strength. The force at Martinsburg is
                    about 1,000 men--infantry, cavalry, and artillery--and at Harper's Ferry 1,200
                    or 1,500, and a small force fortified in the jail at Charlestown. The railroad
                    is most vigilantly watched at all points. The enemy is not harassing the
                    citizens much in the lower valley. McReynolds commands, and he seems to be
                    somewhat of a gentleman in habits, conduct, education, and general bearing, and
                    does not imitate his fiendish predecessor--Milroy.</p>
                <p>I have the honor to report that Maj. D. B. Lang, Sixty-second Virginia Infantry,
                    whom I sent week before last, with 100 men on foot, across the Alleghany, toward
                    Barbour County, has returned safely without the loss of a man.</p>
                <p>On last Thursday night, the 24th, at midnight, he attacked a Yankee camp, 9 miles
                    northeast of Beverly, where the Seneca trace, or road, crosses Cheat River, near
                    what is called the Burnt House, and captured the whole concern and brought them
                    safely out, except 2 so badly wounded they could not travel, and 1 drowned in
                    the river in attempting to escape. His prisoners were Company A, Second West
                    Virginia Infantry (bogus), mounted; part of Averell's command. He brought out 1
                    lieutenant and 36 non-commissioned officers and privates; 38 horses, with new
                    saddles, bridles, and halters; 3 carbines, 31 Minie muskets, 3 swords, 1 pistol,
                    with their accouterments, &amp;c. The whole affair was admirably managed by
                    Major Lang, who was General Edward Johnson's old scout, and one of the best
                    mountain soldiers in the service.</p>
                <p>The enemy has a mounted force of over 3,000 men at Beverly, evidently preparing
                    for a raid toward this valley or Lewisburg (the latter, I think), though I have
                    taken every precaution to be advised of their advance in this direction in time
                    to meet them on Shenandoah Mountain, where the pass is fortified. I have an
                    outpost 60 miles to my front at the base of the Alleghany Mountains, with relays
                    of couriers back to my camp.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brigadier-General.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
