<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948924"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948924">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. William W. Averell.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen william w averell</title>
        <author>Averell, William</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R12948924</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved.</p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499168</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. William W. Averell.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and Confederate
       Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen william w averell</title>
            <author>Averell, William</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 924-925</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-12-21">1863-12-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="R12948924T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Union cavalry general William Averell reports to General in Chief Henry Halleck on a
     December, 1863, raid on the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad. Averell mentions Confederate
     positions at Staunton and points west.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     No. 2. Reports of Brig. Gen. William W. Averell, U. S. Army, commanding expedition to
     Virginia at Tennessee Railroad.
     <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. H. W. HALLECK,<lb/> Gen.-in-Chief.</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-12-21">DECEMBER 21.</date><lb/> Via Beverly, <date value="1863-12-22">December 22, 1863</date>. (Received <time>4.15 p. m.</time>, 23d.)
      <name type="place">EDRAY, POCAHONTAS COUNTY, W. VA.,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>SIR:</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I have the honor to report that I cut the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad at Salem on the
     16th instant, and have arrived safely at this point with my command, consisting of the Second,
     Third, and Eighth West Virginia Mounted Infantry, Fourteenth Pennsylvania, Gibson's battalion
     cavalry, and Ewing's battery.</p>
    <p>At Salem three depots were destroyed, containing 2,000 barrels flour, 10,000 bushels wheat,
     100,000 bushels shelled corn, 50,000 bushels oats, 2,000 barrels meat, several cords leather,
     1,000 sacks salt, 31 boxes clothing, 20 bales cotton, a large amount of harness, shoes, and
     saddles, equipments, tools, oil, tar, and various other stores, and 100 wagons. The telegraph
     wire was cut, coiled, and burned for half a mile. The water-station, turn-table, and 3 cars
     were burned, the track torn up, and the rails heated and destroyed as much as possible in six
     hours. Five bridges and several culverts were destroyed, over an extent of 15 miles. A large
     quantity of bridge timber and repairing materials were also destroyed.</p>
    <p>My march was retarded occasionally by the tempest in the mountains, and the icy roads. I was
     obliged to swim my command and drag my artillery with ropes across Craig's Creek seven times in
     twenty-four hours. On my return I found six separate commands, under Generals Early, Jones,
     Fitz. Lee, Imboden, Jackson, Echols, and McCausland, arranged in a line extending from Staunton
     to Newport upon all the available roads to prevent my return.</p>
    <p>I captured a dispatch from General Jones to General Early, giving me the position, and that
     of Jackson--at Clifton Forge and Covington--was selected to carry. I marched from the front of
     Jones to that of Jackson during the night. His outposts were pressed in at a gallop by the
     Eighth West Virginia Mounted Infantry, and the two bridges across Jackson's River saved,
     although fagots had been piled ready to ignite. My column, about 4 miles long, hastened across
     regardless of the enemy until all but my ambulances, a few wagons, and one regiment had passed,
     when a strong effort was made to retake the first bridge, which did not succeed. The ambulance
     and some sick men were lost, and by the darkness and difficulties the last regiment was
     detained upon the opposite side until morning, when it was ascertained that the enemy seemed
     determined to maintain his position up the cliffs which overlooked the bridge.</p>
    <p>I caused the bridges, which were long and high, to be destroyed, and the enemy immediately
     changed his position to the flank and rear of the detachment which was cut off. I sent orders
     to the remnants to destroy our wagons and come to me across the river or over the mountains.
     They swam the river, with the loss of only 4 men drowned, and joined me. In the meantime,
     forces of the enemy were concentrating upon me at Callaghan's over every available road but
     one, which was deemed impracticable, but by which I crossed over the top of the Alleghanies
     with my command, with the exception of four caissons, which were destroyed in order to increase
     the teams of the pieces.</p>
    <p>My loss is C men drowned, 1 officer and 4 men wounded, and 4 officers and 90 men missing. We
     captured about 200 prisoners, but have retained but 4 officers and 80 men, on account of their
     inability to walk. We took also about 150 horses. My men and horses have subsisted entirely
     upon a very poor country, and the officers and men have suffered cold, hunger, and fatigue with
     remarkable fortitude.</p>
    <p>My command has marched, climbed, slid, and swum 355 miles since the 8th instant.</p>
    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>WM. W. AVERELL,<lb/> Brigadier-General.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
