<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12949800"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12949800">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12949800</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499223</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 49</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 800</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-23">1863-10-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12949800T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>General Robert E. Lee writes Secretary of War James Seddon on various aspects of
                    the October, 1863, strategic situation. Among other things, Lee discusses a
                    possible advance by Union General William Averell in western Virginia, and his
                    attempts to meet it by sending Imboden's cavalry west toward Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. JAMES A. SEDDON, Secretary of War, Richmond:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-23">October 23, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have had the honor to receive your letter of the 20th instant. As soon as your
                    dispatch with reference to Averell's movement reached me, I directed Gen.
                    Imboden, whom I had ordered to the lower valley of the Shenandoah when this army
                    crossed the Rapidan, to return, toward Staunton, ascertain, if possible, the
                    truth of the report, and be prepared to meet Averell's advance. I think there
                    are enough troops in Western Virginia, if properly managed, not only to resist
                    all attacks of the enemy, but to drive them farther from our present positions.
                    The retreating before every advance of the enemy upon the Tennessee Railroad, I
                    fear will entail upon us heavy loss, and the assaults of such troops as they
                    have in that region, home guards and cavalry, could, by proper dispositions, be
                    easily repulsed. I hope you will cause to be investigated the truth of the
                    report which you mention of a force of the enemy being in York River, as another
                    attack upon our railroad from that quarter may be in contemplation.</p>
                <p>I have not been able to ascertain the future movements of Gen. Meade's army. Our
                    scouts report that bridge timber and cross-ties have been brought forward to
                    Broad Run, and that a portion of the enemy's infantry had advanced as far as
                    Catlett's Station on the railway. It is also stated that his cavalry is in
                    Warrenton, and a portion of his infantry on the turnpike leading from that place
                    to Centreville. It may be his intention to advance to Warrenton and bring his
                    supplies to that point by the turnpike until the railroad is reconstructed. Our
                    scouts on the Potomac still report transports with troops ascending that river.
                    A steamer passed up on the 13th instant laden with troops, estimated at 600, and
                    on the 17th, two large ocean steamers passed up, estimated to contain 1,200. I
                    see it stated in the Northern papers that all the volunteers in the State of New
                    York have been ordered to Washington. They are, therefore strengthening
                    themselves on that front.</p>
                <p>I hope you will endeavor to provide the army with shoes, clothing, and blankets,
                    for the season is approaching when the want of these articles will entail great
                    suffering and sickness on the troops, and incapacitate them for military
                    movements.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
