<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948491"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948491">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. John D. Imboden.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen john d imboden</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948491</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499165</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. John D. Imboden.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen john d imboden</title>
            <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 490-492</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-19">1863-10-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948491T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports to Lee's Chief of Staff, Robert Chilton,
                    on the October, 1863, capture of Charlestown, and other action in West Virginia
                    and the northern Valley. Imboden mentions receiving intelligence from Staunton
                    about a possible Federal advance.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 5. Report of Brig. Gen. John D. Imboden, C. S. Army, commanding Valley
                    District, and congratulations from General R. E. Lee.<lb/> HEADQUARTERS VALLEY
                    DISTRICT,
                    <name type="recipient">Col. R. H. CHILTON,<lb/> Chief of Staff, Army of Northern
                        Virginia.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-19">October 19, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Fork of Shenandoah, near Front Royal,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COLONEL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yesterday (Sunday) morning at 2 o'clock I moved from Berryville to surprise and
                    capture the garrison at Charlestown. The surprise was complete, the enemy having
                    no suspicion of our approach until I had the town entirely surrounded. I found
                    the enemy occupying the court-house, jail, and some contiguous buildings in the
                    heart of the town, all loop-holed for musketry, and the court-house yard
                    inclosed by a heavy wall of oak timber. To my demand for a surrender Colonel
                    Simpson requested an hour for consideration. I offered him five minutes, to
                    which he replied, "Take us if you can." I immediately opened on the buildings
                    with artillery at less than 200 yards, and with half a dozen shells drove out
                    the enemy into the streets, when he formed and fled toward Harper's Ferry. At
                    the edge of the town he was met by the Eighteenth Cavalry, Colonel Imboden, and
                    Gilmor's battalion. One volley was exchanged, when the enemy threw down his arms
                    and surrendered unconditionally. The colonel, lieutenant colonel, and three
                    others who were mounted fled at the first fire and ran the gauntlet, and escaped
                    toward Harper's Ferry.</p>
                <p>The force I captured was the Ninth Maryland Regiment, and three companies of
                    cavalry, numbering between 400 and 500 men and officers. I have not had time to
                    have them counted. In wagons, horses, mules, arms, ammunition, medicines, and
                    clothing (the captures) were considerable; all of which I have saved and will
                    have properly accounted for.</p>
                <p>As I expected, the Harper's Ferry forces (infantry, artillery, and cavalry)
                    appeared at Charlestown in less than two hours after I fired the first gun.
                    Having promptly sent off the prisoners and property I was prepared for them. I
                    retired from the town and fell back slowly toward Berryville, fighting the enemy
                    all the way from 10 o'clock till near sunset.</p>
                <p>My loss as far as ascertained is very small, 3 killed, 3 or 4 mortally wounded,
                    and 15 or 20 wounded, more or less. Captain Calmes will lose an arm, and Captain
                    Currence was badly shot in the hip. I think a few (10 or 15) broken-down men who
                    straggled behind were captured.</p>
                <p>We killed and wounded dreadfully several of the enemy in the court-house,
                    including the adjutant of the Ninth Maryland, and in the fight along the road
                    the enemy's loss was considerable, as we ambuscaded them several times with good
                    effect.</p>
                <p>I marched nearly all night, and reached the river here at daybreak. It was quite
                    full, but I have effected a safe crossing of the north branch. The other branch
                    I cannot cross to-day, but I feel safe from farther pursuit. A part of my
                    command marched yesterday and last night 60 miles, and the remainder 48 miles, a
                    part of the latter on foot.</p>
                <p>A gentleman, direct from Martinsburg on Saturday, reports four regiments of
                    infantry and four of cavalry now at that place. There are two small brigades at
                    Harper's Ferry. These forces are so much larger than my own that I cannot remain
                    lower down the valley than Shenandoah County without too much risk, as there is
                    no forage to be had in sufficient quantities, except as low down as Clarke and
                    Jefferson. I shall therefore retire to Shenandoah County for the present.</p>
                <p>If General Lee could spare for a few days a division of cavalry to act in
                    conjunction with me, I am perfectly confident that in six days we could break up
                    all the posts of the enemy from Harper's Ferry to New Creek, and again destroy
                    the railroad and canal.</p>
                <p>Night before last I received a telegram from Colonel Nadenbousch, at Staunton,
                    that Lieutenant Siple, commanding a detachment of my men at Hightown, reported
                    Averell at Huttonsville with 5,000 men on the 15th instant, and everything
                    indicating a purpose to advance. This makes me a little uneasy about the upper
                    valley, and on that account I ought to go up the valley some distance. I move in
                    that direction at 1 p. m. by way of Powell's Fort Valley.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brigadier-General.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--I also captured a very handsome stand of colors.
                        This moment a count of the prisoners is completed. They number 434.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
