<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948921"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948921">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. Benjamin F. Kelley.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen benjamin f kelley</title>
        <author>Kelley, Benjamin F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">21</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948921</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499167</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of Gen. Benjamin F. Kelley.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of gen benjamin f kelley</title>
            <author>Kelley, Benjamin F.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 920-923</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-18">1864-02-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948921T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Benjamin F. Kelley reports to Army Headquarter's Chief of Staff
                    George W. Cullum concerning General William Averell's December, 1863, raid in
                    West Virginia and the Shenandoah Valley. During the raid, Union forces
                    threatened Staunton in order to prevent Confederates from focusing all their
                    strength on Averell.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 1. Report of Brig. Gen. Benjamin F. Kelley, U. S. Army, commanding
                    Department of West Virginia.<lb/> HEADQUARTERS DEPARTMENT OF WEST VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. G. W. CULLUM,<lb/> Chief of Staff, Hdqrs. Army,
                        Washington, D. C.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-18">February 18, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Cumberland, Md.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations in this
                    department during the month of December, 1863, which resulted in the cutting of
                    the enemy's communications, and the destruction of his depots at Salem, on the
                    Virginia and Tennessee Railroad:</p>
                <p>In pursuance of the intimated wishes of the General-in-Chief, on the 5th of
                    December, I ordered Brigadier-General Averell, commanding First Separate
                    Brigade, to move with all his available force, via Petersburg, Franklin, and
                    Monterey, to the line of the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad, at Bonsack's
                    Station, in Botetourt County, or Salem, in Roanoke County, and there destroy the
                    railroad to as great an extent and as thoroughly as practicable. To assist in
                    this movement, Colonel Thoburn, First West Virginia Infantry, commanding
                    brigade, was ordered to report to General Averell with two regiments of infantry
                    and a section of artillery, to be left at some selected point on the route, for
                    the purpose of guarding the forage trains and supporting the return of the
                    expedition. The object of the expedition accomplished, General Averell was
                    ordered to return to any station on the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad between New
                    Creek and Harper's Ferry that might be found most convenient.</p>
                <p>To withdraw the enemy's attention from the movements of the main column, and to
                    prevent his penetrating its real design, it was thought advisable to make double
                    feints on either flank, menacing Staunton and New River Bridge, respectively.</p>
                <p>On the 1st of December, Brigadier-General Scammon, commanding Third Division, was
                    ordered to advance from Kanawha, via Lewisburg and Union, threatening the
                    Virginia and Tennessee Railroad at New River.</p>
                <p>On the 8th of December, Brigadier-General Sullivan, commanding First Division,
                    received orders to send all his cavalry force, with two regiments of infantry
                    and a battery, up the Valley of the Shenandoah, to occupy Harrisonburg, and from
                    thence to threaten Staunton with the cavalry, remaining until the 22d of the
                    month.</p>
                <p>In addition, Colonel Moor, Twenty-eighth Ohio Infantry, with two regiments of
                    infantry, was ordered on the 7th of December to report to General Averell, and
                    to move forward from Beverly to Droop Mountain, for the purpose of seconding the
                    expected attack on Lewisburg by the forces under General Scammon.</p>
                <p>In conformity to orders, Brigadier-General Averell, whose detailed report is
                    herewith submitted, moved from New Creek, on the morning of the 8th of December,
                    with four regiments and a battalion of mounted troops and Ewing's battery. On
                    the 10th, he was joined by Colonel Thoburn at Petersburg, Hardy County, and the
                    united command marched southward until near Monterey, in Highland County. The
                    greater portion of the train was here left in charge of Colonel Thoburn, who,
                    with his force, took the road to McDowell.</p>
                <p>On the 12th, General Averell, with his column, took a secluded road down Back
                    Creek, and during the second day's march fell upon and dispersed the rear guard
                    of the rebel (Jackson's) force, which was retreating before the advance of
                    Colonel Moor, toward Droop Mountain. Four wagons loaded with ammunition and
                    commissary stores were captured and destroyed on this occasion. Upon his arrival
                    at Callaghan's, General Averell was informed of the occupation of Lewisburg by
                    General Scammon's forces, and the consequent retreat of Echols toward Union.
                    After making a false advance toward Covington General Averell moved from
                    Callaghan's by an obscure road up Dunlap's Creek to the Sweet Springs. At this
                    place he learned that General Echols was encamped 4 miles north of Union, and
                    that General Scammon had retired from Lewisburg.</p>
                <p>The capture of a rebel quartermaster in this vicinity assured General Averell
                    that his movements were as yet unsuspected. From the Sweet Springs he marched
                    eastward toward New Castle, halted to feed and rest 12 miles from that place.
                    Having sent a squadron to make a false advance on the Fincastle road, he passed
                    through New Castle during the night, and entered Salem with his advanced guard
                    about 10 o'clock on the morning of the 16th. With such admirable skill and
                    secrecy had this march been conducted, that the appearance of our troops was a
                    complete surprise to the inhabitants of Salem, and General Averell found there
                    large depots of military stores without any guard whatever.</p>
                <p>Shortly after his occupation of the place, he was advised of the approach of a
                    train of cars loaded with troops of the enemy. As the main body of his force was
                    not yet within supporting distance, and his advance guard consisted of only 350
                    men and a section of artillery, he thought it imprudent to permit the nearer
                    approach of this train, and accordingly opened on it with his artillery, and
                    drove it back. When the main force arrived he sent parties 4 miles to the
                    eastward and 12 miles to the westward, who destroyed five important bridges, and
                    damaged the railroad track between those points as extensively as their limited
                    time permitted. Meanwhile, he burned the depot buildings in the town, destroying
                    an immense quantity of commissary, quartermaster, and ordnance stores
                    accumulated for the use of General Longstreet's army.</p>
                <p>Having thus successfully accomplished his mission, at 4 p. m. on the same day
                    General Averell started northward, returning by the same route that he had
                    advanced. As his column had marched the last 80 miles of their journey in thirty
                    hours, both men and animals were much exhausted, and in consequence he encamped
                    for the night 7 miles from Salem. A severe rain-storm commenced the same evening
                    which continued during the ensuing day and night, rendering Craig's Creek (which
                    the column was obliged to cross frequently on the march of the 17th) a dangerous
                    and almost impracticable torrent. By extraordinary exertions, however, the
                    artillery and wagons were saved, and on the evening of the 18th the command
                    reached New Castle, with damaged ammunition and otherwise in bad condition.</p>
                <p>Here General Averell received information that Fitzhugh Lee, with his brigade of
                    cavalry, was at Fincastle, and that Samuel Jones was in force on the Sweet
                    Springs road. At 9 p. m. he made a feint advance toward Fincastle, and then with
                    his column took the Sweet Springs road. In this direction he presently met the
                    enemy's pickets, and drove them 12 miles to the junction of the Sweet Springs
                    and Fincastle turnpike. Here a halt was ordered, camp fires built and left
                    burning, while the column moved northeastward by an unfrequented road leading
                    directly toward Covington.</p>
                <p>At a point 8 miles from Covington our troops encountered the enemy about 300
                    strong, routed him, and pursued so closely that he was prevented from destroying
                    the bridges over Jackson's River, although combustibles had been prepared for
                    that purpose. The possession of these bridges (one 5 miles distant from, and the
                    other immediately at, the town of Covington) was essential to the safety of
                    General Averell's command, as Jackson's River was greatly swollen and covered
                    with floating ice. In this vicinity a dispatch from Maj. Gen. Samuel Jones to
                    Major-General Early was captured, which betrayed the plans, positions, and
                    forces of the enemy, and indicated to General Averell the mode of counteracting
                    them, an advantage which was promptly and successfully used.</p>
                <p>After the main body of our forces had crossed the first bridge, the baggage train
                    was assailed by Colonel Jackson, who captured their ambulances, some sick, and
                    about 100 men. The brigade was then burned by our troops, thus cutting off the
                    regiment which formed the rear guard. The baggage train, which was very small,
                    was destroyed under orders, to prevent its failing into the enemy's hands, and
                    the regiment rejoined the command by swimming the river, losing only 4 or 5 men
                    drowned.</p>
                <p>The following day the command concentrated at Callaghan's, and from thence
                    crossed the Alleghany Ridge, striking Antony's Creek between White Sulphur
                    Springs and Huntersville, and on the 21st, by a very obscure route, reached and
                    crossed the Greenbrier River opposite Hillsborough, encamping that night at the
                    northern base of Droop Mountain. On the 24th, General Averell with his command
                    reached Beverly, after a march of 400 miles, altogether one of the most
                    difficult and hazardous that has been yet accomplished by any troops.</p>
                <p>Brigadier-General Scammon, who was ordered to press the enemy from the west for
                    the purpose of diverting his attention from the movements of General Averell,
                    advanced from the Kanawha and occupied Lewisburg on the 12th, driving out
                    Echols, and capturing a few prisoners. He then fell back to Meadow Bluff with
                    his main body, leaving General Duffie with his cavalry and a section of
                    artillery at Lewisburg. Disturbed by the operations of guerrillas in his rear
                    and rumors of re-enforcements to the enemy in front, he retired with his whole
                    force to the Kanawha earlier than was contemplated in his orders.</p>
                <p>In accordance with the general plan, Colonel Moor with his infantry advanced from
                    Beverly to Droop Mountain, and forwarded a messenger to communicate with General
                    Scammon at Lewisburg. This messenger having been captured by guerrillas, he
                    ordered Lieutenant Adams with 20 cavalry to force his way through. On reaching
                    Lewisburg this officer found the town nearly deserted and could hear nothing
                    definite of General Scammon. He returned to Colonel Moor on the 14th, reported
                    that he had been fired on by the enemy in the outskirts of Lewisburg as he left.
                    Failing to communicate with General Scammon, and perceiving that parties of the
                    enemy were blocking up the road in his rear, he retired, carrying with him our
                    wounded left in the vicinity of Droop Mountain after the battle of November 6,
                    and reached Beverly on the 17th, skirmishing on the march with guerrillas, and
                    capturing 8 prisoners.</p>
                <p>Colonel Thoburn, after separating from General Averell on the 12th, near
                    Monterey, moved to the left, and threatened Staunton by way of McDowell. Having
                    successfully assisted in attracting the enemy's attention to that point, he
                    returned without molestation to his original position at Petersburg, bringing
                    with him General Averell's wagon train, and carrying out his instructions in the
                    most satisfactory manner.</p>
                <p>The column sent by Brigadier-General Sullivan up the Valley of the Shenandoah
                    first encountered the enemy at Strasburg, and drove him back, after sharp
                    skirmishing, in which we took some 30 prisoners. Occupying Harrisonburg
                    according to instructions, Colonel Wells, Thirty-fourth Massachusetts Infantry,
                    commanding, threatened Staunton, completely deceiving the enemy, holding Imboden
                    with 1,200 men on guard, and for several days diverting the forces of Generals
                    Fitzhugh Lee and Early from the movements of Averell.</p>
                <p>The enemy attempted to cut off this detachment by sending Colonel Rosser with a
                    brigade of cavalry to fall upon its rear by way of Front Royal. A counter
                    movement was made by General Meade, by sending General Gregg with a cavalry
                    brigade to Luray. Owing to the swollen condition of the Shenandoah River the
                    movement made by Rosser failed, while General Gregg entered Luray, destroyed
                    some rebel property, and retired without meeting the enemy in force.</p>
                <p>The command of Colonel Wells retired to its original position at Charlestown and
                    Harper's Ferry, arriving on the same day that General Averell reached Beverly
                    (24th), having killed, wounded, and captured a number of the enemy, and having
                    materially assisted in the successful accomplishment of the general plan.</p>
                <p>The results of this combined movement have been highly satisfactory and
                    important, inflicting a loss on the enemy of not less than 400 men, an immense
                    amount of provisions, material, and machinery, and the cutting off for a number
                    of weeks of his most important line of communication.</p>
                <p>The behavior of the troops has been most commendable, and the conduct of the
                    different movements (with some exceptions) all that could have been desired. The
                    brigade of General Averell, to which was assigned the most difficult and
                    hazardous duty, has, in its successful accomplishment of that duty, won unfading
                    laurels, while its admirable good conduct toward the peaceful inhabitants of the
                    country, and its heroic endurance of fatigue and privation, add luster to the
                    glory of its success.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>B. F. KELLEY,<lb/> Brigadier-General, Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
