<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948939"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948939">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli union correspondence</title>
        <author>Wells, George D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12948939</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499171</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli union correspondence</title>
            <author>Wells, George D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 938-939</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-22">1863-12-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12948939T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Colonel George D. Wells reports to Captain William Boone on December, 1863,
                    actions in the Shenandoah Valley in conjunction with General William Averell's
                    raid in West Virginia. Wells mentions the feint against Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HEADQUARTERS VALLEY EXPEDITION
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. WILLIAM M. BOONE, Asst. Adjt. Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-22">December 22, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Strasburg,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPTAIN:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report my arrival at this place to-day. I proceeded up the
                    valley as directed, reaching Sparta on the 19th, and entering Harrisonburg with
                    the cavalry. I reached there the 20th with the infantry. We found nothing in the
                    way but O'Ferrall's battalion, most of which was captured at different times.</p>
                <p>At New Market I found a dispatch from O'Ferrall, directed to General Fitz. Lee,
                    which gave me my first intimation that he was in the valley. Two of the
                    prisoners taken there belonged to General Rosser's brigade. They stated that
                    they had come home on furlough, but that when they left the brigade was under
                    marching orders for the valley. Before reaching Sparta, I received information
                    from various sources leaving no doubt in my mind that the brigade was then near
                    Ashby's Gap, intending to cross in my rear. I relied on the high water to
                    prevent this and kept on.</p>
                <p>On the 20th, two deserters from his brigade came in, who reported the brigade as
                    awaiting for the river to fall. The men swam the river, reported it then too
                    deep for fording, but failing rapidly. On reaching Harrisonburg, I learned that
                    Fitz. Lee had crossed on Friday with his brigade and some additional force, and
                    that he and Imboden were trying to intercept Averell, who it was reported had
                    completed his raid, burning the depot and tearing up the track at Salem, and had
                    made good his return, eluding the forces sent in his pursuit. I also learned
                    that Early's division had been in the valley some days, and was then encamped at
                    Mount Crawford. This state of facts being so different from that contemplated in
                    my instructions, and feeling certain of being intercepted if the river should
                    fall, I consulted with Colonel Boyd, and decided to withdraw the infantry to New
                    Market, leaving the cavalry to mask the movements and continue the feint on
                    Staunton as long as possible. I moved after dark and reached New Market before
                    morning, and the next day Edenburg, thus covering the roads leading to Luray
                    Gap.</p>
                <p>Colonel Boyd joined me at Edenburg. He reported that Early and Lee moved on
                    Harrisonburg on the 21st; that the cavalry advanced with great caution until
                    they reached the place where my artillery had been, evidently supposing me to be
                    still there; that they then closed on him, driving him out of town about noon on
                    the 21st, and followed him closely, with frequent skirmishing, as far as Mount
                    Jackson.</p>
                <p>This morning we have not been molested, except by a small party of guerrillas,
                    who rendezvoused at Mount Jackson. I learned at Edenburg that Rosser, together
                    with considerable infantry and artillery of Ewell's corps, unable to cross at
                    Front Royal, moved, to Thornton's Gap on the 20th, and I am told here that he
                    succeeded in crossing at New Market on the 21st, the same day I passed through.
                    I have certainly out marched any infantry force, if any has followed me, and
                    cavalry alone could do nothing with this command except to delay it. I shall
                    move toward and beyond Winchester to-morrow. The men are in excellent health and
                    spirits, and averse to halting to-day. They want to get home. Some, however, are
                    very foot-sore and many barefooted.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>GEO. D. WELLS,<lb/> Colonel, Commanding.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
