<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12948106"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12948106">
  <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Report of John Imboden.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli report of john imboden</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">R12948106</idno>
        <!--
        <availability>
          <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of
            Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
          <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
        </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499158</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Report of John Imboden.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the Union and
              Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli report of john imboden</title>
            <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>Translator:</resp>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 48</p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>Pages 105-107</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
            <date value="1997">1997</date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-09-13">1863-09-13</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term/>
          <term/>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="R12948106T">
    <front id="d2">
      <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
        <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports to Robert E. Lee on September, 1863, operations
          in western Virginia. Imboden discusses several skirmishes and their results. Imboden also
          mentions hauling iron from Shenandoah to Staunton.</p>
      </div1>
    </front>
    <body id="d4">
      <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
        <head>
          No. 2. Report of Brig. Gen. John D. Imboden, C. S. Army, commanding Valley
          District, including operations September 5-13, and skirmish at Bath, September 7.
          <name type="recipient">General R. E. LEE,<lb/> Commanding Army of Northern Virginia.</name>
        </head>
        <opener>
          <dateline>
            <date value="1863-09-13">September 13, 1863.</date>
            <name type="place"> NEAR BROOKS' GAP,</name>
          </dateline>
          <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
        </opener>
        <p>I have the honor to report the following operations of detachments of troops from my
          command during the past week:</p>
        <p>1. Captain Burke and Lieutenant Wells, of Gilmor's battalion, being on picket below
          Newtown on the 6th (5th?) instant, marched their party of 11 men to Winchester, where they
          were joined by Captain Blackford, who is recruiting in the lower valley, with 15 men,
          making a total of 3 officers and 26 men. The party proceeded to, within 21 miles of Bath
          and spent Sunday, and that night at 2 o'clock surprised the enemy's camp at Bath,
          consisting of two companies Colonel Wynkoop's Pennsylvania cavalry, six-months' men. The
          enemy had about fifteen minutes notice of their approach and were formed, but Captains
          Burke and Blackford charged them and had a fight of ten minutes at close quarters.</p>
        <p>Captain Hebble and 8 or 10 of his men (Yankees) were killed; a number wounded. Only 2 of
          our men wounded. Captains Burke and Blackford captured and brought out safely 23 Yankee
          soldiers and 1 negro. Horses and equipments captured, 50; sabers, 20 pistols, 25. All the
          Yankee officers, including the major commanding, escaped in the darkness, except Captain
          Hebble, killed.</p>
        <p>2. In my last I informed you that I had left Captain Imboden in command of a detachment
          of four companies in Hardy. Captains Scott and White returned to camp. Captains Imboden
          and Hobson, with about 70 men, remaining. Early in the week they had a skirmish with a
          regiment in Patterson's Creek Valley on its way to re-occupy Petersburg, but with no
          important result; 1 man killed on our side, and Captain Jarbo reported mortally wounded on
          the other side by a shot from my brother. On Wednesday they fell back to the South Fork,
          above Moorefield, where their camp was discovered and reported by a Union man to the
          forces at Petersburg, when a plan was formed for their capture, as will be seen by the
          inclosed order, subsequently captured.</p>
        <p>Captain McNeill, with 80 men, left my camp at this place on Wednesday, and joined
          Captains Imboden and Hobson on Thursday evening. That day a force of 300 men, under Major
          Stephens, came down from Petersburg to Moorefield. Captains McNeill, Imboden, and Hobson
          at once resolved to surprise their camp next morning at daybreak. The enemy picketed every
          road leading to their intrenched camp, and deployed about 50 men as skirmishers to remain
          in position all night, several hundred yards from their works, and sent out two companies
          to surprise our camp.</p>
        <p>Our men moved noiselessly in the darkness, flanked the enemy's pickets, and succeeded in
          getting between the line of skirmishers and the camp before daybreak on Friday morning,
          the 11th. Just as dawn appeared they charged the Yankee camp, firing into the tents and
          yelling like savages. Some resistance was made, but in a short time the fight was over.
          About 30 Yankees were killed or too badly wounded to be removed. Lieutenant Welton, of
          McNeill's company, and 2 men were badly wounded; the former, it is feared, mortally.</p>
        <p>The following are the captures made and safely brought to camp:<lb/> Prisoners:</p>
        <p>Captains........................... 3</p>
        <p>Lieutenants........................ 5</p>
        <p>Total officers.................. 8</p>
        <p>Non-commissioned officers and privates.......... 138</p>
        <p>Total number or prisoners....... 146</p>
        <p> Major Stephens escaped. All of whom I will start to Richmond to-morrow.<lb/>
          Wagons............................... 9<lb/> Ambulances........................... 2<lb/>
          Horses............................... 46<lb/> Saddles and bridles.................. 4<lb/>
          Minie muskets (best quality, in ..... 133<lb/> splendid order) Cartridge and cap boxes and
          belts.... 112<lb/> New army pistols..................... 29<lb/> Rounds of fixed
          ammunition........... 10,500<lb/> Sabers............................... 25<lb/> Bayonets
          and scabbards............... 90<lb/> Sets of harness...................... 28<lb/>
          Drums................................ 2<lb/> The cooking utensils tents, blankets,<lb/>
          oil-cloths, commissary stores, &amp;c.,<lb/> of the whole force.</p>
        <p>First at 2 miles and again at 4 miles above Moorefield the parties of the enemy sent out
          from Petersburg and Moorefield in the night to surprise our men attacked them and
          attempted to rescue the prisoners. Sharp fighting ensued, but all were brought off with a
          loss of 8 or 10 men on our side, believed to have been captured, and 1 ambulance, in which
          the team was killed, together with 18 or 20 other horses.</p>
        <p>Information reaching here night before last that the enemy was pursuing, Colonel Smith
          took 400 men and made a forced night march to the head of Lost River to assist in bringing
          in the prisoners, &amp;c., but as it turned out he was not needed, all coming in
          safely to-day.</p>
        <p>I cannot speak too highly of the gallantry of officers and men in this really brilliant
          little affair. They were in the very midst of a largely superior force plotting their
          capture or discomfiture, but completely turned the tables upon them.</p>
        <p>I am so well convinced of the utility of this mode of warfare on the border, that day
          after to-morrow I start out two parties, one of 100 men, under Major Lang, Sixty-second
          Virginia Regiment, to penetrate the country north of Beverly on foot and harass the enemy
          two or three weeks in Barbour and Randolph; the other, a single company, under Captain
          Nelson, to go to the North Fork, in Pendleton, and try and clear out Snyder's gang of
          Union robbers and murderers, known as Swamp Dragoons.</p>
        <p>All remains perfectly quiet in the lower valley. Only a small force of the enemy at
          Martinsburg and Harper's Ferry, and they stick to the railroad very closely. We are again
          hauling iron from Shenandoah to Staunton. A very large proportion of my horses have sore
          tongues and cannot stand much service.</p>
        <p>If you could spare for twenty days 2,500 infantry and a battery, to co-operate with me, I
          believe we could destroy every bridge from Martinsburg to New Creek, break up the canal,
          and burn the coal mines at Cumberland, General Jenkins co-operating in the meantime with
          Colonel Jackson in a raid on Beverly and Grafton. The force of the enemy is too large and
          too easily concentrated for me to undertake it alone.</p>
        <closer>
          <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
          <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brigadier-General.</signed>
        </closer>
      </div1>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
