<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R12949625"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R12949625">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xli confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R12949625</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499202</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLI. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xli confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 29, Serial No. 49</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 625</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-05">1863-08-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R12949625T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes Commissary General Lucius B. Northrop concerning the August,
                    1863, supply situation facing the Confederate army. Lee mentions that Major Bell
                    at Staunton can provide at least 50 teams of wagons for gathering and
                    transporting wheat and other supplies.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">Col. L. B. NORTHROP,<lb/> Commissary-Gen., C. S. Army:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-05">August 5, 1863.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 23d ultimo, and a subsequent one without date, have been
                    received. If it becomes necessary to reduce the soldiers' rations, I shall
                    regret it from the effect I fear it will have upon the army, as I do not think
                    the present allowance more than sufficient to keep the men well and satisfied.
                    If the reduction is made, I think it ought to extend to all the armies, and not
                    to this alone, as was the case last spring.</p>
                <p>When ordered, I shall, of course, conform to it, and do all in my power to render
                    it satisfactory to the troops. In all the operations of this army, I have
                    endeavored to economize the supplies as much as possible, and to obtain as great
                    an amount from the country occupied as could be collected.</p>
                <p>As regards your latter communication, I agree with you that every effort should
                    be made to accumulate subsistence in Richmond. The necessities of this army and
                    the uncertainty of depending upon our railroads render this apparent. Every
                    assistance that I can give with the army transportation in collecting the grain
                    and transporting it to the depots will be afforded, and immediately on the
                    reception of your letter, Col. Corley was directed to furnish to the commissary
                    agents you have named the number of wagons you require, or as many in proportion
                    as could be spared for that purpose. He reports that he cannot find Thomas J.
                    Foster, but that he can place at his disposal thirty four-horse wagons under one
                    of his own quartermasters. He has directed Maj. Bell, at Staunton, to use all
                    his surplus transportation in that district as Mr. Nelson may desire. Maj. Bell
                    answered that Mr. Nelson is unable to say at present how many teams he may need
                    or can use, but that he (Maj. Bell) can furnish him fifty teams, probably one
                    hundred, on condition that he procure teamsters. To collect supplies in the
                    Rappahannock Valley, he can furnish twenty teams. These teams will all be placed
                    in charge of quartermasters, and will be set to work as soon as informed that
                    the grain is ready for transportation. As they from a part of the army
                    transportation, and may be needed for its use at any time, there is an objection
                    to turning them over to the commissary agents, but I desire they shall be used
                    in the way you propose.</p>
                <p>The arrangement you propose for the railroad I think ought to be made, but I have
                    no means of controlling their operations.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
