<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331169"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331169">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Cabell, Henry C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331169</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499241</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Cabell, Henry C.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1169-1170</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-13">1864-02-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331169T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate artillery colonel Henry Cabell writes Artillery Chief William
                    Pendleton concerning the February, 1864, positions and conditions of his forces.
                    Pendleton mentions a gun that had been sent to Staunton to replenish a battery
                    weakened after the battle of Gettysburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. CABELL'S BATTALION,
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. W. N. PENDLETON,<lb/> Chief of Artillery:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your valued note of the 11th
                    instant.</p>
                <p>My batteries are located as follows, vi: Fraser's battery, three guns, at
                    Somerville Ford; Manly's battery, four guns, at Raccoon Ford; McCarthy's
                    battery, four guns, at Morton's Ford; Carlton's battery, three guns, in reserve
                    near the intersection of the roads leading to Raccoon and Morton's Fords, and
                    equidistant from each. My headquarters are in a pine thicket adjacent to Capt.
                    Carlton's battery, and are a few hundred yards from Gen. Rodes' old
                    headquarters. The men are in good huts, the horses under good shelter. The
                    horses are faring well. Scarcely any sickness of any kind in camp.</p>
                <p>I sent a requisition for horses early this month to Gen. Lee's headquarters;
                    unfortunately, it has not been supplied. Yesterday I received information that a
                    Napoleon gun had arrived at Orange Court-House, intended for Capt. Carlton's
                    battery. It would not be prudent to bring it here at present (though much
                    needed) from the want of horses. I would be glad if you would write to Maj.
                    Harman and urge him to supply us with horses immediately. It is bad policy to
                    keep condemned horses here in front. The corn at first sent us was worm-eaten or
                    rotten, and produced scurvy in the horses. Unfortunately, notwithstanding every
                    care, 12 horses died. The forage is now sufficient, and of good quality.</p>
                <p>Capt. Fraser's battery requires another gun. After the Thursday's fight at
                    Gettysburg, this battery having lost 2 officers wounded and a very large number
                    of men and horses, it was thought advisable to turn over one of these guns to
                    the quartermaster to be transported. It was sent to Staunton. The gun was a
                    3-inch rifled gun. I have written to Lieut.-Col. Baldwin, chief of ordnance, on
                    the subject, asking a return of the gun. The gun will require horses and
                    harness. There cannot be a more meritorious case.</p>
                <p>I have written to you in regard to the promotion of First Lieut. Morgan Callaway.
                    It would be a great misfortune to lose him from the battery, and remaining with
                    it he ought to be promoted. I would be very glad if you would give the subject
                    your immediate attention. If he cannot be commissioned as captain of the
                    battery, cannot he be commissioned as captain of artillery, and assigned to the
                    command of this battery?</p>
                <p>You ask me if I "need any more guns." Capt. Manly and Carlton's batteries are
                    both large enough for six-gun batteries. If the guns and horses can be supplied,
                    I would like them to be restored to their former position as six-gun batteries.</p>
                <p>The attack of the enemy was by no means "a small affair." I have no doubt that
                    they acted upon reports of the weakness of our forces and our supposed want of
                    vigilance. Nearly all the pickets were taken prisoners. The preservation of the
                    line and the consequent repulse of the enemy are unquestionably due to that
                    portion of your artillery now with Lieut.-Gen. Ewell's corps. The repulse was
                    complete and the casualties small simply because of the promptness, courage, and
                    energy of these batteries. But for them, instead of being characterized as a
                    small affair, it would have been one of the most disastrous affairs of the war.
                    At the same time it is proper to state that Gen. Ewell appeared on the field
                    with the greatest alacrity, exerted himself in bringing up the infantry
                    promptly, and all his arrangements reflected great credit upon him, and the
                    results show that the tactics, generalship, and admirable discipline of the army
                    are so much improved as to overcome the disadvantages of unavoidable surprises.</p>
                <p>If young Saunders is under eighteen he can be received into the First Howitzers;
                    if older, perhaps an arrangement can be made for bringing him into the company
                    by exchange. Let him apply at once.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>H. C. CABELL,<lb/> Col. of Artillery.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
