<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331099"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331099">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331099</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499234</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1098-1099</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-19">1864-01-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331099T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Procuring shoes proved one of the most serious of the Confederate army's supply
                    problems. In this January, 1864, letter, Robert E. Lee discusses many of the
                    problems involved in maintaining an adequate supply of leather, including
                    speculation and low production resulting from impressment. Lee hopes the needed
                    leather can be purchased with either specie or hides, but he suggests putting
                    the quartermasters at Staunton in charge of impressment, should it prove
                    necessary.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. A. R. LAWTON,<lb/> Quartermaster-Gen.,
                        Richmond, Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-19">January 19, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I desire to state more fully to you my views with reference to procuring a supply
                    of shoes for the army, as I fear that unless great efforts are made the return
                    of the season of active operations will find a large number of the men
                    barefooted.</p>
                <p>It is the opinion of the quartermaster of this army that if we were supplied with
                    tools and materials, from one-third to one-half of the army could be shod by the
                    system of brigade shoemakers, already brought to your attention. I am satisfied
                    that this system can be made an important auxiliary of the department, and am
                    anxious that some measure may be devised to procure leather in sufficient
                    quantities. I caused a requisition for the least amount that we could get along
                    with, viz, 37,500 pounds to be made, of which we have only received 8,000 or
                    9,000 pounds. I hope that the rest will be forthcoming. I think there is
                    leather, and enough, in the country concealed by speculators, of which we never
                    hear until the enemy captures and destroys it. Such was the case at Salem, where
                    Gen. Averell reports that he destroyed cords of it. Such was also the case at
                    Luray and Sperryville. That at Luray, was in the hands of a speculator named
                    Borst, I am informed, who had concealed it there.</p>
                <p>If this leather cannot be had in any other way it should be impressed. But before
                    resorting to impressment I would much prefer to resort to the system of
                    exchanging hides for leather. This approaches nearer to a purchase on a specie
                    basis, and would certainly draw out the leather from its concealment, and not
                    have that tendency to repress production which is one of the worst consequences
                    of impressment. I recommend that the prohibition against such exchanges be
                    removed from this army at least, in view of the vital importance of procuring a
                    prompt supply of leather. The result of the experiment would enable you to judge
                    better of its merits, and afford a better idea of the amount of leather in the
                    country than can be otherwise obtained.</p>
                <p>Should you resort to impressment I advise that good men be selected to regulate
                    it. Maj. Bell, quartermaster at Staunton, or Capt. Philips, assistant
                    quartermaster at the same place, would manage the matter so as to prevent
                    hardship and get as much as can be expected by that system. I think that we
                    could be more expeditiously and certainly supplied by exchange, however.
                    Whatever is to be done must be done without delay, as it is indispensable to the
                    efficiency of the army in the approaching campaign. The leather will be placed
                    in charge of active and vigilant officers in the brigade, who will see that none
                    is wasted and that all is applied to the use of the troops.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
