<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331112"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331112">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331112</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499236</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1111-1112</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-21">1864-01-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331112T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In January, 1864, Confederate Topographical Engineer Jedediah Hotchkiss and his
                    assistants set up office in Staunton, VA, to carry out orders to map the
                    Shenandoah Valley. In this letter to General Jubal Early, Hotchkiss reports on
                    his progress in surveying and mapping Augusta, Bath, Allegheny, and Rockbridge
                    Counties.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. J. A. EARLY,<lb/> Cmdg. Volley District,
                        Harrisonburg, Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-21">January 21, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">STAUNTON, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I last night received your letter of yesterday, giving me instructions. I brought
                    my assistants along with me, with the consent of Gen.'s Ewell and Lee, and I
                    have obtained quarters in Staunton, where I can keep them at work and supervise
                    them once a week at least.</p>
                <p>I have a surveyed map of Rockbridge County, and also a survey of portions of
                    Augusta, Bath, and Allegheny Counties, and I shall have them at once put
                    together by my assistants, and so forward the work assigned me. I am now making
                    tracings of the maps I have to take along with me, that I may verify them; that
                    and other necessary preparations will occupy the rest of this week, and on
                    Monday I shall start, and go first along the line of the North Mountain, by the
                    road nearest to it on the east, and go as far as where the road from the Sweet
                    Springs to Fincastle crossed the same mountain, then come back by the nearest
                    line of parallel roads on the west of the North Mountain, and so back and forth
                    until I reach the Allegheny Mountains, as I suppose by so doing I shall examine
                    all the crossings of the mountains from one parallel valley to another. I think
                    I had better make the main road from Harrisonburg, through Staunton, Lexington,
                    Buchanan, and Fincastle, on the Salem, the limit of the map on the southeast;
                    the road from Dry River Gap to Harrisonburg and the Parkersburg road from
                    Staunton westward the limit on the northeast; the Allegheny Mountains the limit
                    on the southwest, making a section of country 100 miles long and 40 wide, as
                    shown in the inclosed tracing. Such, I understand, is the intention of your
                    orders when you ask for "a map of Augusta and Rockbridge from Staunton and
                    Lexington westward, and the counties adjoining them on the west," and "ascertain
                    the routes from Covington to Lexington, Buchanan, Fincastle, and Salem." All the
                    materials from Staunton northeast to the proposed line are now ready to my hand,
                    and only need reduction. If this boundary is not the one you desire, please
                    specify to me a limit. I need a courier or cavalryman to go along with me; it
                    expedites my observations much to have some one to send to ascertain names of
                    houses, &amp;c., while I am taking notes and sketching topography. A courier
                    of Maj. Allan's (A. D. Moore) desires to accompany me, and Gen. Ewell and Maj.
                    Allan have consented for him to come, but Gen. Lee has referred the matter to
                    you. I will be obliged to you if you will approve it. I have asked Col. Imboden
                    to let one of his men accompany me next week, which will, I hope, meet with your
                    approval. I have always had a courier sent with me when on such duty.</p>
                <p>I propose to construct the map on a scale of 1\160000 or 4\10 of an inch to the
                    mile. My address will be Staunton.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, you obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JED. HOTCHKISS,<lb/> Capt. and Topographical Engineer, Second Corps.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
