<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331142"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331142">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331142</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499237</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1141-1142</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-02">1864-02-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331142T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes General Samuel Jones in February, 1864, concerning the
                    defense of western Virginia and the Shenandoah Valley. Lee discusses mapping the
                    countryside near Staunton, enlisting civilians in the army, and dealing with
                    deserters.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS.,
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. SAMUEL JONES,<lb/> Cmdg., &amp;c.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-02">February 2, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have received your dispatch of the 31st ultimo, reporting indications of
                    another advance of the enemy from the Kanawha, and your opinion that there
                    should be some troops on the railroad. I have no troops to send. The facts had
                    better be reported to the Secretary of War, as your detachment is beyond the
                    limits of my command. Gen. Averell, by the last reports of scouts in the valley,
                    was at Martinsburg, with his success appears to me at this distance to be owing
                    to the terror with which he has inspired the troops. As soon as his approach is
                    announced his progress is neither retarded nor watched.</p>
                <p>A body of select troops should remain constantly in his front, obstructing his
                    advance and reporting his route, that troops might be concentrated at the
                    desired point. I know the difficulty of guarding a long line. You cannot have
                    sufficient force at every vulnerable point, whereas the enemy can select
                    whatever point he pleases. But I think the main passes through the mountains
                    could be so fortified as to be led by a small force, and the minor ones so
                    obstructed as to greatly embarrass their passage. If the home guards or local
                    organizations could be got to hold the fortified passes, it would leave all your
                    make your arrangements such as to enable you to attack them at some vulnerable
                    point and throw them on the defensive it would lighten your labor exceedingly.</p>
                <p>I have sent Capt. Howard, of the engineers of this army, to examine the routes
                    through to Allegheny range south of Staunton.</p>
                <p>He will be joined by some young officers who have been occupied in that country
                    for some time, and I hope a serviceable map of the roads, &amp;c., can be
                    formed by the spring, which may aid in future operations. I would recommend, if
                    not already done, that similar examinations on the ranges west be made. I would
                    recommend also that the people be organized for the defense of the country into
                    the regular service, and that existing organizations be filled rather than new
                    ones created; that all deserters be sent to their proper commands and all
                    cowards punished. I wish I could spare you some troops or aid you in any way,
                    but the enemy in my front is active and increasing and I require all I have.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, with great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
