<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13360698"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13360698">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sullivan, Jeremiah C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13360698</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499270</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sullivan, Jeremiah C.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 697-698</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-18">1864-03-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13360698T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In March, 1864, three refugees from Staunton, Gabriel Hirsch, Lizzie Hirsch, and
                    Lizzie Haggaden, passed into Union lines. Union General Jeremiah Sullivan
                    forwards Captain William Boone's write-up of the information the refugees
                    provided. Boone reports that he was told that Confederate General Thomas Rosser
                    left Staunton, leaving only a provost guard. The refugees also discussed the
                    lack of food in the Confederacy, meat prices, discontent among civilians, and
                    Unionist sentiment in the Shenandoah Valley. The refugees also asserted that
                    Staunton was second in importance only to Richmond because Lee received most of
                    his supplies from the Valley. Boone speculates that capture of the town and
                    disruption of the railroad would deal the Confederacy a major blow.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. FIRST DIV., DEPT. OF WEST VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. T. Melvin,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-18">March 18, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Harper's Ferry, W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The following has been received from Martinsburg, Va., and respectfully forwarded
                    for the information of the general commanding the department:</p>
                <p>HDQRS. SECOND BRIGADE, FIRST DIVISION, DEPT. OF WEST VIRGINIA,<lb/> Martinsburg,
                    Va., March 17, 1864.<lb/> CAPT.: I have the honor to report the arrival to-day
                    of 3 refugees from Staunton. They report that Rosser has gone to Gordonsville to
                    join Lee; that Early is no longer in that region; that there is nothing in
                    Staunton but a provost guard; that Imboden only is in the valley, and with
                    Gilmor and Mosby, has not more than 2,000 men. They say that Staunton is
                    regarded as second in importance only to Richmond, the supply for Lee's army
                    coming in a great measure from the valley, and that if the commissary stores
                    there were seized, the bridge burnt, and railroad torn up, so as to sever
                    communication, it would be fatal. They report a raid contemplated some days
                    since to throw the train containing Kilpatrick's horses off the track; they
                    report great scarcity of provisions. Rebel meat rations are 1 pound to 8 men;
                    forage mostly gone; cattle, what there are, in very bad condition-meat fairly
                    blue after being killed; that the scarcity is so great that Lee's army must
                    break into our lines or starve; that there is much discontent among the soldiers
                    and desire to desert at the first opportunity; that there are very many loyal
                    men in the valley who pray for the Union army to come in; that the force which
                    went up the valley last greatly strengthened the Union sentiment by their good
                    treatment of the inhabitants. They obtained a pass to Strasburg and thence came
                    through without difficulty. They heard Gilmor was wounded, but saw him last
                    night in Winchester on horseback. A supper was given him there that night. He
                    came into Winchester immediately after our forces left. Citizen say Gilmor got
                    no booty this last raid and lost 15 men. It is reported that Imboden has been
                    ordered to report to Lee. Their names are Gabriel Hirsch, Mrs. Lizzie Hirsch,
                    and Lizzie Haggaden. They are very fearful lest their names shall be mentioned,
                    as Mrs. Hirsch leaves three children behind.<lb/> WM. W. BOONE,<lb/> Capt. and
                    Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain, captain, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. C. SULLIVAN,<lb/> Brig.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
