<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331332"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331332">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331332</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499253</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1331-1332</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-30">1864-04-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331332T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In April, 1864, Union forces prepared to move in northern Virginia, the
                    Shenandoah Valley, and the West as part of General Grant's overall strategic
                    plan. In this letter, Robert E. Lee writes Jefferson Davis to inform him of the
                    situation, including his suspicion that Generals Averell and Sigel planned a
                    raid on Staunton or the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JEFFERSON DAVIS,<lb/> President
                        Confederate States:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-30">April 30, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. PRESIDENT:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>My dispatch of 1.45 p.m. to-day announced to you the march of Burnside's forces
                    through Centreville. Citizens report the arrival of his troops at Rappahannock
                    Station. I send you the Philadelphia Inquirer of the 26th, from which you will
                    learn that all their available forces are being advanced to the front. They are
                    also apparently drawing troops from Florida and the southern coast. Lieut.-Col.
                    Mosby, who was within a mile of Centreville on the 28th, the day that Burnside
                    passed through, learned from prisoners that no troops were left at Annapolis
                    except convalescents. I see no evidence of more troops being brought from
                    Tennessee, and it may be inferred from newspapers sent, and from the Washington
                    Chronicle of the 27th, that the Twelfth Corps is still in that department.</p>
                <p>As far as I can judge, although there may be a large force in Tennessee, it seems
                    to occupy an extended line, and is not yet concentrated as if for attack. If
                    Gen. Johnston could be re-enforced from Mobile, or by Gen. Polk, he might be
                    able to penetrate their lines or successfully resist their advance. Our scouts
                    report that the engineer troops, pontoon trains, and all the cavalry of Meade's
                    army have been advanced south of the Rappahannock. The regiments of the old
                    Fifth Corps, which have been guarding the Orange and Alexandria Railroad, have
                    been brought forward and replaced by negro troops. Everything indicates a
                    concentrated attack on this front, which renders me the more anxious to get back
                    the troops belonging to this army, and causes me to suggest, if possible, that
                    others be moved from points at the south, where they can be spared, to Richmond.
                    There will no doubt be a strong demonstration made north of south of the James
                    River, which Beauregard will be able successfully to resist. I judge also, from
                    present indications, that Averell and Sigel will move against the Virginia and
                    Tennessee Railroad or Staunton, to resist which Gen.'s Breckinridge and Imboden
                    should act in concert. I have requested them to do so.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
