<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13360347"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13360347">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Meade, George G.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13360347</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499259</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Meade, George G.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 346-347</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-05">1864-01-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13360347T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Army of the Potomac commander George G. Meade reports to General in Chief Henry
                    Halleck on the disposition of forces in the Shenandoah Valley in January, 1864.
                    Meade reports that Confederates under Early advanced down the Valley to raid the
                    Baltimore and Ohio Railroad while maintaining a line of retreat to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF THE POTOMAC,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. H. W. HALLECK, Gen.-in-Chief:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-05">January 5, 1864--1 p. m.<lb/> (Received 2 p. m.)</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Brandy Station, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Our scouts have returned from the valley, and reported that Early's command,
                    consisting of five brigades of infantry, estimated at 7,000, together with
                    Lee's, Rosser's, Imboden's, and Jenkins' cavalry, and some artillery, passed
                    down the valley about Friday last with the intention of making a raid on the
                    Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, but the main body moved from Woodstock over to
                    Moorefield, intending to attack and cut the railroad at New Creek; that a
                    detachment of infantry --Thomas' (Georgia) brigade--and some cavalry were sent
                    through Strasburg to threaten Martinsburg, as a diversion. This intelligence is
                    deemed reliable, and seems to be confirmed by the movements reported by Gen.
                    Kelley.</p>
                <p>The cavalry sent to Front Royal returned yesterday evening completely exhausted,
                    and reported the roads passed over impassable for any trains. At present, with
                    snow on the ground, the only passable road open to a detachment from this army,
                    viz, the Culpeper and Sperryville pike, is not practicable, from the balling of
                    the snow in the animal's hoofs. I hold the balance of the Sixth Corps, about
                    10,000 men, a division of cavalry, about 4,000, and some artillery, with a
                    bridge train, in readiness for any movement you may order; but I am still of the
                    opinion that the operations against Early, to be effective, should be from the
                    railroad and defensive, and the character of the season and roads, together with
                    the difficulty of procuring supplies, after exhausting those carried with them,
                    will rendered nugatory any effort made from this army to cut off Early's
                    retreat, as he has a road via Franklin to withdraw to Staunton, in addition to
                    the one through Woodstock. Again, to re-enforce Kelley, if necessary, from this
                    army would require a smaller detachment than an independent movement into the
                    valley, thus weakening me proportionately less. Defensive movements also would
                    have roads, and the troops be more readily supplied. Under existing
                    circumstances, I shall await your orders before making any movement.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>GEO. G. MEADE,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
