<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331195"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331195">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Imboden, John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331195</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499242</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Imboden, John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1194-1195</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-22">1864-02-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331195T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General John Imboden reports to General Jubal Early on the February,
                    1864, movements of his cavalry. Imboden discusses plans to move to Augusta
                    County.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. NORTHERN BRIGADE,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. J. A. EARLY,<lb/> Cmdg. Valley District:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-22">February 22, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hays' Creek, Rockbridge County, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of this date has been received. I will send a squadron down the
                    valley to-morrow morning to relieve Gen. Rosser's pickets below Woodstock, as
                    directed. I will also move my camp day after to-morrow to my old camp ground,
                    this side of Swoope's Depot. I would move to-morrow, but all my wagons have been
                    sent out 15 miles from camp to-day in search of forage, and will not be in
                    before to-morrow evening. Until Thomas' and Walker's brigades actually move from
                    Rockingham, I presume there is no necessity for me to move the main body of my
                    command to that county; and till that necessity exists it is of the utmost
                    importance for me to remain as far south as possible, on account of forage. I
                    shall be compelled after I go to Rockingham to haul most of my grain from this
                    (Rockbridge) county; therefore every day that I can remain as far south as, say,
                    Swoope's Depot I will save that much in transportation. I scarcely see how it
                    will be possible for me to subsist my horses in Rockingham, when compelled to go
                    there, with the limited transportation allowed by general orders. You are
                    doubtless aware of the fact that Rockingham is nearly exhausted of forage and
                    grain of all kinds, and that Shenandoah and the country below is so completely
                    exhausted that it is with great difficulty and labor, and constant controversies
                    with the people, that even a small picket force can be supplied. My own horses
                    are as much in need of rest as those of any brigade in the army, and I had hoped
                    that for three or four weeks I could rest and feed them here. As that cannot be,
                    however, I will go down to Augusta day after to-morrow, and hope that by
                    furnishing the mounted picket to relieve Gen. Rosser, you will permit me to
                    remain there until orders are received for the return of Gen.'s Thomas and
                    Walker to the Army of Northern Virginia, when I will at once proceed to take my
                    entire command to Rockingham and support it as best I can. If you will notify me
                    the day before the infantry brigades move, I will move down so as to conceal
                    their movements from the knowledge of the enemy. You are mistaken in supposing
                    that the Staunton and Parkersburg road is open and unguarded. There is a guard
                    at McDowell, stopping all persons on that road, under Lieut. Carpenter,
                    enrolling officer of Highland County, and I have a company besides in the
                    northwestern part of Highland, co-operating with four companies in Pendleton, to
                    clean out the "swamps," arrest deserters, conscripts, and all suspicious
                    parties. These forces cover all the approaches in that direction more
                    effectually than any picket could do where you propose it (east of the
                    Shenandoah Mountain), as there are several routes by which such a picket could
                    be flanked from the valley. When the companies I now have on duty west of the
                    Shenandoah Mountain return next week, I will station a picket permanently on
                    that road, or keep a small force constantly scouting the roads in Highland and
                    Pendleton. I also have four companies on the South Fork and South Branch,
                    scouting, foraging, and gathering up cattle for my own command, sent out from
                    Rockingham before I moved from Mount Crawford. McNeill is also over there, I
                    understand, so that I regard all western outlets from the valley very
                    effectually closed up. If you desire me to move right on to Rockingham, you will
                    find me after to-morrow 7 miles southwest of Staunton, where I was camped last
                    week, near Jacob Baylor's.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
