<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331333"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331333">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331333</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499254</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1332-1333</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-30">1864-04-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331333T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In April, 1864, Confederate forces in the Valley and northern Virginia prepared
                    to meet simultaneous Union advances. In this letter, Confederate General John
                    Imboden writes to General John C. Breckinridge to report on the situation,
                    including Imboden's preparations to defend Staunton and the rest of the
                Valley.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. VALLEY DISTRICT
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. J. C. BRECKINRIDGE,<lb/> Cmdg. Department of
                        Western Virginia:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-30">April 30, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of the 24th was received three days ago, and I have delayed answering
                    it in the hope that further developments of the enemy's plans would be made from
                    day to day, but as yet I have been unable to discover his purpose. I have
                    dispatches from Hampshire this morning of date 28th instant. Considerable bodies
                    of troops from the West have been passing for a week over the Baltimore and Ohio
                    Railroad to re-enforce Grant, reported to be the veteran troops of Grant's old
                    command. Sigel has 800 cavalry in Cumberland and 300 at Springfield in
                    Hampshire, and a considerable body of infantry at New Creek, all under marching
                    orders, and believed to be in readiness to co-operate with Averell, whose
                    precise whereabouts I cannot discover. He was personally present in Cumberland
                    about a week ago in conference with Sigel. Citizens from Martinsburg on
                    yesterday report that he is at that place. I do not believe this last report.
                    The force to my front is small, guarding the railroad, and apparently meditating
                    no advance up this valley, though I believe an advance will be made from New
                    Creek and Cumberland through Hardy, Pendleton, and Highland to co-operate with a
                    movement from Beverly and the Kanawha Valley. I have an effective force of a
                    little over 2,000 men. I am concentrating about 1,500 of these about 20 miles
                    northwest of Staunton; the residue I will leave in Shenandoah and Page as scouts
                    and pickets. With my main body I will have to make the best defense I can of the
                    Virginia Central Railroad and of Staunton and Lexington if menaced or attacked.
                    The great difficulty with me is that I am threatened from two directions, New
                    Creek and Beverly, and possibly from Martinsburg.</p>
                <p>I am much obliged to you for directing Col. Jackson to communicate with me. It
                    may become highly important for Col. Jackson and myself to unite at or about
                    Millborough, if the enemy seeks to penetrate the valley about Lexington. I am
                    therefore taking a position on the Warm Springs and Harrisonburg turnpike, from
                    whence I may move in either direction. I will promptly advise you of any
                    important movement of the enemy as soon as discovered.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. IMBODEN,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
