<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1331166"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1331166">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Early, Jubal A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1331166</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499239</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Early, Jubal A.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 33, Serial No. 60</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1166-1167</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-12">1864-02-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1331166T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In February, 1864, Confederate General Jubal Early commanded troops in the
                    Shenandoah Valley. In this letter, Early writes from Staunton to Robert E. Lee
                    concerning actions and movements in his jurisdiction. Early mentions being in
                    Staunton to oversee his engineers' preparations for defense of western Virginia.
                    Early also mentions his desire to return east to join Lee after a furlough.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">General R. E. LEE,<lb/> Commanding:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-12">February 12, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">STAUNTON,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GENERAL:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Matters are quiet in the valley at present, and I hear of no indications of a
                    movement by the enemy. The enemy has left Hardy County, and there has been no
                    effort to reoccupy Petersburg, and I think there will not be any, at least for
                    this winter.</p>
                <p>The statements published in the Yankee papers that they attacked Rosser and
                    recaptured the prisoners taken at Patterson's Creek and captured and wounded
                    some of our men is an arrant falsehood from beginning to end. When Rosser went
                    to Patterson's Creek he sent a regiment toward Romney to prevent any attempt to
                    get into his rear by a force coming from Martinsburg that way. A lieutenant and
                    5 or 6 men were sent ahead as scouts, and on reaching Romney found a
                    considerable force of cavalry advancing. They were pursued by the enemy, and the
                    lieutenant's horse fell with him in the river and threw him, and he is supposed
                    to have been captured. The regiment (the Seventh) took position in a gap at
                    Mechanicsburg, and there had a skirmish with the advance of the enemy and drove
                    it back, having 2 men wounded. Rosser came back without being attacked at all
                    and without losing any of his men after the fight with the guard for the train.</p>
                <p>The force which came to Moorefield as we were leaving consisted of some 2,000 or
                    3,000 mounted men sent from Martinsburg and Charlestown, and a considerable body
                    of infantry and cavalry sent from New Creek and Green Spring and Cumberland,
                    with twelve pieces of artillery, and perhaps more. It did not attack us and did
                    not attempt to follow us. Only some 600 or 700 of the cattle brought off will do
                    for beef, and they have been started to the army.</p>
                <p>I am here to see the engineers about the defenses to be constructed west of this
                    place, and shall leave in the morning for Buffalo Gap and Millborough. I desire
                    to know how long you expect me to remain here. You will recollect that I have
                    received no definite instructions, and have always regarded my position here as
                    temporary. I have therefore left all my messing arrangements at my division
                    headquarters, and I am badly off for horses here. My division will require my
                    presence for some time before the beginning of the spring campaign to get it
                    into condition. I fear things are getting loose there. I wish you, however, to
                    understand that I am willing to do any service that you think I can do with
                    benefit to the country.</p>
                <p>Upon leaving here I should like to go home for some fifteen or twenty days before
                    taking command of my division, for several considerations, as I have not been at
                    home since the war began except for a very few days, when I was wounded in June,
                    1862. However, as I think all private considerations should give way to the
                    public interests in these times, I shall be contented if you think I had better
                    not go home. If I do go I should like to be at the March term to the court of my
                    county, which takes place on the first Monday of the month, as I am informed
                    there is engendering some discontent with the war and some lukewarmness in the
                    cause, which I am informed I can rectify by my presence.</p>
                <p>I hear there is some danger of Rosser's appointment not being confirmed. I have
                    conceived a very high opinion of him as a cavalry officer, notwithstanding the
                    affair I mentioned to you of his coming here after his wife. He attends to his
                    duties and manages his men well and I should regard it a great loss to the
                    service if he should fail of having his appointment confirmed. He desires in the
                    event of an advance of Meade upon you to cross the mountain and strike the
                    railroad and the enemy's trains in the rear, and I submit whether it would not
                    be well to keep him here with that view.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>J. A. EARLY,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
