<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1366793"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1366793">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Dana, Charles A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1366793</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499284</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Dana, Charles A.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 36, Serial No. 67</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 93</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-09">1864-06-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1366793T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Assistant Secretary of War Charles A. Dana writes Secretary of War Edwin
                    Stanton in June, 1864, with information obtained from a refugee from Richmond.
                    The refugee discussed the poor condition of Richmond, the capture of Staunton,
                    and the death of the Confederate General defending the town.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMIES OF THE UNITED STATES
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. EDWIN M. STANTON, Secretary of War.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-09">June 9, 1864--noon. (Received 1.30 p.m., 10th.)</date>
                        <name type="place">Cold Harbor, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I subjoin a communication just send in from Col. Sharpe, deputy
                    provost-marshal-general, to chief of staff, Army of the Potomac: Among prisoners
                    sent in during the night we have a German refugee from Richmond, a man of weak
                    intellect and not intelligent. His statements, as far as they go, are made with
                    apparent truth and simplicity. He left Richmond on the Brook pike Monday
                    morning, passing Yellow Tavern, thence out, say 15 miles, from Richmond, when he
                    bent his course to the right and came into our cavalry. His statements regarding
                    the condition of the city, absence of troops there, closing of departments and
                    stores, location of the reserve supplies of pork and flour, influx of citizens
                    from the part of the State north of Richmond, of the capture of Staunton, and
                    death of the general commanding there, failure of provisions during time
                    Petersburg and Danville road was lately held or cut by us, are substantially the
                    same as information received from refugee a few days ago, and reported with that
                    received yesterday concerning Hunter. This man in passing up the Brook pike
                    passed no troops after leaving the immediate defenses of Richmond. We have also
                    3 men from Ransom's (North Carolina) brigade (lately belonging to Beauregard's
                    command), who have come to our lines with the avowed purpose of availing
                    themselves of the President's proclamation. One of them is a sergeant, and a man
                    of considerable intelligence. Ransom's brigade came from the Bluff on the 4th
                    instant, passed to the right of Bridge, on the Chickahominy. On arriving there
                    it relieved the Richmond City battalion, which was understood to return within
                    the line of the city defenses. Ransom's brigade consists of five regiments,
                    which has not seen hard service since it left Lee's army in January, 1863, and
                    averages 450 to 500 men to the regiment. Sergeant estimates the brigade at
                    3,000. He knows of Hoke's division (formerly Whiting's) having joined Lee before
                    his brigade left Beauregard. He says it was understood when Ransom left that but
                    one division, of three or four brigades (he does not know which), was left in
                    front of Gen. Butler. He heard his officers generally talk about it, and express
                    themselves to that effect. It is a division known as Bushrod Johnson's. Below
                    position now occupied by Ransom's brigade he says there is nothing but cavalry.
                    Fitzhugh Lee's division is represented to be about 2,500 strong. What above
                    Ransom's he cannot tell. Says during time Butler occupied railroad there was
                    failure of meat in the issues to troops, and great scarcity of flour.</p>
                <p>Principal facts stated above are confirmed by various other evidence, and are
                    most probably correct.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>C. A. DANA.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
