<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13667785"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13667785">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13667785</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499282</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 36, Serial No. 67</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 784-786</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-16">1864-06-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13667785T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Phil Sheridan reports to Army of the Potomac Chief of Staff Andrew
                    Humphreys on June, 1864, cavalry action in the central Virginia. Sheridan
                    mentions Union General David Hunter's operations in the Staunton area, including
                    destruction of the railroad.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. CAVALRY CORPS,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. HUMPHREYS,<lb/> Chief of Staff, Army of the
                        Potomac.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-16">June 16, 1864</date>--<time>2 a. m.</time>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Guiney's Bridge, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report to you the arrival of my command at this point, and
                    also to report it operations since leaving New Ferry:</p>
                <p>I crossed the Pamunkey River on the 7th instant, marching via Aylett's, and
                    encamped on Herring Creek. On the morning of the 8th resumed the march via Pole
                    Cat Station, and encamped 3 miles west of the station. On the 9th marched trough
                    Chilesburg and New Market, encamping on East Northeast Creek, near Young's
                    Bridge. On the 10th marched via Andrews' Tavern and Twyman's Store, crossing
                    both branches of the North Anna, and encamped at Buck Childs', but 3 miles
                    northeast of Trevilian Station. My intention was to break the railroad at this
                    station, march through Mechanicsville, cut the Gordonsville and Charlottesville
                    Railroad near Lyndsay's house, and then to march on Charlottesville, but on
                    arrival at Buck Child's house I found the enemy's cavalry in my immediate front.
                    On the morning of the 11th, Gen. Torbert with his division, and Col. Gregg's
                    brigade, of Gen. Gregg's division, attacked the enemy. After an obstinate
                    contest, drove him from successive lines of breast-works, through an almost
                    impenetrable forest, back on Trevilian Station. In the mean time Gen. Custer was
                    ordered with his brigade to proceed by a country road so as to reach the station
                    in rear of the enemy's cavalry. On his arrival at this point the enemy broke
                    into a complete rout, leaving his dead and nearly all of his wounded in our
                    hands; also 20 officers, 500 men, and 300 horses.</p>
                <p>These operations occupied the whole of the day. At night I encamped at Trevilian
                    Station, and on the morning of the 12th commenced destroying the railroad from
                    this point to Louisa Court-House. This was thoroughly done-ties burned and rails
                    rendered unserviceable. The destruction of the railroad occupied until 3 o'clock
                    of this day.</p>
                <p>I directed Gen. Torbert to advance with his division and Gen. Davies' brigade, of
                    Gen. Gregg's division, in the direction of Gordonsville, and attack the enemy,
                    who had concentrated and been re-enforced by infantry during the night, and had
                    also constructed rifle-pits at a point about 5 miles from Gordonsville. The
                    advance was made, but as the enemy's position was found too strong to assault,
                    no general attack was made. On the extreme right of our lines a portion of the
                    Reserve Brigade carried the enemy's works twice, and was twice driven therefrom
                    by infantry. Night closed the contest. I found on examination of the command
                    that there was not a sufficiency of ammunition left to continue the engagement.
                    The next day trains of cars also came down to where we were engaged with the
                    enemy. The reports of prisoners and citizens were that Pickett's old division,
                    or a portion of it, was coming to prevent the taking of Gordonsville. I,
                    therefore, during the night and next morning, withdrew my command over the North
                    Anna, via Carpenters' Ford, near Minor's Bridge. In addition, the animals were,
                    for the two entire days in which we were engaged, without forage, the
                    surrounding country affording nothing but grazing of a very inferior quality,
                    and generally at such points as were inaccessible to us. Up to this time I could
                    get no definite information as to the position of Gen. Hunter. Report placed him
                    and his command at Staunton, destroying the railroad. I had, therefore, the
                    choice of attempting to join him there, via Orange Court-House and
                    Stanardsville, or retiring, and I resolved on the latter. I had at that time
                    only one day's rations for my men, but very little forage for my animals, and
                    not sufficient ammunition on hand to risk a severe engagement. Living off the
                    country was a failure; very little forage could be obtained or the animals, and
                    to attempt under such circumstances to join Gen. Hunter would have jeopardized
                    my command. I regret my inability to carry out your instructions.</p>
                <p>The cavalry engagement of the 12th was by far the most brilliant one of the
                    present campaign. The enemy's loss was very heavy. They lost the following-named
                    officers in killed and wounded: Col. McAllister, commanding regiment, killed;
                    Brig.-Gen. Rosser, commanding brigade, wounded; Col. Aiken, commanding regiment,
                    wounded; Col. Custer (?), commanding regiment, wounded. My loss in killed and
                    wounded will be about 575. Of this number 490 were wounded. I brought off in my
                    ambulances 377, all that could be transported. The remainder were (with a number
                    of rebel wounded that fell into my hands) left behind. Surgeons and attendants
                    were detailed and remained in charge of them. I captured and have now with me
                    370 prisoners of war, including 20 commissioned officers. My loss in captured
                    will not exceed 160. These were principally in the Fifth Michigan Cavalry. This
                    regiment gallantly charged down the Gordonsville road, capturing 1,500 horses,
                    and about 800 men, but was finally surrounded, and had to give them up. When the
                    enemy broke they hurried between Gen. Custer's command and Col. Gregg's brigade,
                    capturing 5 caissons of Pennington's battery, 3 of which were afterward
                    recaptured,leaving in their hands 2 caissons. A more detailed report will be
                    made hereafter. I have sent staff officers forward to send to me as far as
                    Dunkirk subsistence and forage. It is very essential that it should reach me at
                    that point.</p>
                <p>I will march down the north bank of the Mattapony in the expectation that I may
                    be able to obtain some supplies through the country in that vicinity. None can
                    be obtained south of the Mattapony, between this point and the White House.</p>
                <p>The following troops were sent from Lee's army and Richmond to re-enforce Jones'
                    command in the valley: Breckinridge's corps, 4,000; 2,000 dismounted cavalry to
                    Gordonsville; the rebel cavalry under Hampton and Fitz. Lee, and Pickett's old
                    division, or a part of it. Pickett's troops went either by the canal to
                    Columbia, or by railroad via Lynchburg to Charlottesville.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed> P. H. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
