<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13668959"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13668959">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLVIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlviii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Withers, John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13668959</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499292</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLVIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlviii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Withers, John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 36, Serial No. 68</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 958-959</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-05">1864-05-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13668959T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>These May, 1864, Confederate Special Orders muster Major H. W. Gilmor's partisans
                    into service as cavalry, and send them the Camp Maryland, Staunton, VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    SPECIAL ORDERS, No. 105. ADJT. AND INSP. GEN.'S OFFICE,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-05">May 5, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>VII. Capt. T. H. Bomar will proceed by railroad with his company, now on duty in
                    Department of South Carolina, Georgia, and Florida, to headquarters Army of
                    Northern Virginia, and report to Gen. R. E. Lee, commanding, &amp;c., for
                    assignment to duty with his appropriate regiment, the Thirty-eighth Georgia
                    Infantry.</p>
                <p>VIII. The Ben Hill Artillery, Capt. John B. Higdon commanding, is permanently
                    detached from the Thirty-eighth Regt. Georgia Volunteers, and upon the arrival
                    of Capt. Bomar's company, will proceed by railroad to headquarters Department of
                    South Carolina, Georgia, and Florida, and report to Maj. Gen. Samuel Jones,
                    commanding, for assignment to duty as an unattached.</p>
                <p>IX. The Fifty-ninth North Carolina Regiment, Col. Ferebee, the Sixty-Fifth North
                    Carolina Regiment, Col. Folk, the Sixty-second Georgia Regiment, Col. Griffin,
                    and the Seventh Confederate Cavalry, Col. Taliaferro, will constitute a brigade,
                    to the command of which Brig. Gen. James Dearing, is hereby temporarily
                    assigned.</p>
                <p>XI. Maj. H. W. Gilmor's battalion Partisan Rangers will be immediately mustered
                    into the service of the Confederate States as cavalry. Maj. Gilmor will then
                    proceed by highway with his battalion of cavalry to Camp Maryland, Staunton,
                    Va., and report to Maj. Gen. A. Elzey, commanding Maryland Line, for assignment.
                    Citizens of other States who are enlisted in any company of this battalion may,
                    if they desire it, be transferred to companies from their own States.</p>
                <p>XII. Capt. Kincheloe's company Partisan Rangers will be mustered into the service
                    of the Confederate States as cavalry, and will then be assigned to the Fifteenth
                    Regt. Virginia Cavalry.</p>
                <p>XVI. Capt. Thomas E. Gregg with his battery (Company C, Siege Train), South
                    Carolina Volunteers, will proceed by railroad to headquarters Army of Northern
                    Virginia, and report to Gen. R. E. Lee, commanding, &amp;c., for assignment
                    to Lieut.-Col. Pegram's artillery battalion, to relieve the Pee Dee Artillery,
                    Lieut. W. E. Zimmerman, commanding.</p>
                <p>Lieut. Zimmerman, on being relieved, will proceed with his battery to Charleston,
                    S. C., and report to Maj. Gen. Samuel Jones, commanding, &amp;c., for
                    assignment.</p>
                <p>The horses and guns of each battery will remain in the departments in which they
                    are now.</p>
                <p>XIX. Maj. Gen. J. C. Breckinridge will select two batteries from the Thirteenth
                    Battalion Virginia Artillery, for duty in his department, after which Lieut.
                    Col. J. Floyd King, commanding the battalion, will proceed by railroad with the
                    two remaining batteries to headquarters Army of Northern Virginia, and report to
                    Gen. R. E. Lee, commanding, for assignment to Brig.-Gen. Alexander's artillery
                    corps.</p>
                <p>XXVI. Col. William Butler, First South Carolina Enlisted Men, is relieved from
                    duty in Department of South Carolina, Georgia, and Florida, and will proceed
                    without delay to headquarters Department of Richmond, and report to Maj. Gen. R.
                    Ransom, commanding, &amp;c., for assignment to the command of the artillery
                    defenses of Department of Richmond.</p>
                <p>XXVII. In all matters relating to the command, military police and operations,
                    the Departments of Henrico and Richmond are hereby consolidated.</p>
                <p>Brig. Gen. John H. Winder will report to Maj. Gen. Robert Ransom, jr.</p>
                <p>XXX. The Thomas Legion, North Carolina Volunteers, will proceed by highway from
                    East Tennessee to Western North Carolina. Lieut.-Col. Love, commanding, will
                    report for orders to Col. J. B. Palmer, at Asheville, N. C.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>By command of Secretary of War:</salute>
                    <signed>JNO. WITHERS,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
