<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770342"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R13770342">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix union correspondence</title>
        <author>McLean, H. T.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770342</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499334</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix union correspondence</title>
            <author>McLean, H. T.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 341-342</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-04">1864-08-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770342T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Cavalry officer H. T. McLean reports on his command's attempts to check a
                    Confederate advance under Jubal Early into southern Pennsylvania during July and
                    August, 1864. He mentions movements in and out of Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-04">August 4, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">CARLISLE BARRACKS, PA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that in obedience to orders received July 26 (p. m.) I
                    left Carlisle with one officer and forty four men of the Permanent Company,
                    arriving at Chambersburg July 27 (a. m.). From that place I proceeded with my
                    command, via Greencastle,to Mercersburg, arriving there July 28 (a. m.), at
                    which point my command was employed on picket and scouting duty until July 29
                    (p. m.). I sent Lieut. Jones and fifteen men to Greencastle, who picketed the
                    roads below that place. My pickets extended from Shimpstown to McCoy's Ferry,
                    Clear Spring, and Cherry Run. About 3 p. m. July 29 my pickets were driven in
                    from McCoy's Ferry and Cherry Run to Clear Spring, from which place they were
                    driven back within two miles of Shimpstown, when the enemy took a cross-road to
                    the right leading to the Valley road, on which they advanced. I drew in my
                    pickets from Shimpstown and sent a few men about one mile out on the Valley
                    road, when they met the enemy's advance, and, after holding them in check for a
                    short time, were driven back to the town, keeping up a sharp fire with them. I
                    took my little command out of the town and formed line, but had hardly done so
                    when the enemy charged through the town about 200 strong, driving my pickets
                    before them. I held my position until they were within good range, and gave them
                    a volley from my carbines, which checked them slightly. I then fell back on the
                    Saint Thomas road. The enemy pursued me very rapidly. I checked them several
                    times between Mercersburg and Bridgeport, when darkness coming on, and the enemy
                    not being disposed to advance farther there, I left a picket near the town and
                    went to Saint Thomas with the balance of my command, where I was joined by
                    Lieut. Stanwood, Third U. S. Cavalry. Soon after my arrival at Saint Thomas my
                    picket at Bridgeport was driven in. I was compelled to fall back, keeping up a
                    sharp fire with them until within about two miles of Chambersburg, where I was
                    re-enforced by about forty infantry and one piece of artillery of the First New
                    York Artillery, under command of Lieut. Underhill. I sent some of the infantry
                    to support my men, and held them until I placed the piece in position, when my
                    rear guard, being pressed, fell back. I gave them a charge of canister, which
                    checked them until I could get all the trains out of the town. I fired five
                    shots from the piece, holding the enemy two hours, by which time I found I was
                    being flanked, and drew my command into the town, passing through about 5 a. m.
                    July 30. I fell back in order to cover the trains as far as Shippensburg, where
                    I was joined by Lieut. Jones, with the balance of my company, he having been
                    compelled to fall back from Gen. Averell's command. I remained at Shippensburg
                    until July 31 (a. m.), when I took my command back to Chambersburg, remaining
                    there until August 2 (p. m.), when I left Chambersburg for this post, arriving
                    here August 3 (m.), having been absent eight days.</p>
                <p>My loss is 2 men of the Permanent Company wounded; also 8 horses wounded. The
                    officers and men all behaved very bravely. The enemy acknowledge the killing of
                    3 of their men and wounding 6 between Mercersburg and Chambersburg; also the
                    killing of 1 and wounding of 4 men by a discharge of canister.</p>
                <p>I would respectfully beg leave to mention Lieut. Underhill, First New York
                    Artillery, who, while directing the fire of his piece was subjected to a very
                    sharp fire, acted with great coolness and handled his piece very well.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>H. T. MCLEAN,<lb/> First Lieut., Sixth U. S. Cavalry.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
