<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770369"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770369">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sigel, Franz</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770369</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499337</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sigel, Franz</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 368-369</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-02">1864-05-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770369T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Franz Sigel writes General Grant concerning General Crook's May,
                    1864, plans for the Valley. The plans involve a demonstration at Staunton, where
                    the Confederates threaten to concentrate troops.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. U. S. GRANT:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-02">May 2, 1864</date>--<time>2 a. m.</time>
                        <name type="place">WINCHESTER,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>The following telegram was received from Gen. Crook:<lb/> CHARLESTON, April 30,
                    1864.</p>
                <p>Not having a sufficient mounted infantry force to make two demonstrations
                    (columns). I shall only make a demonstration toward Lewisburg, so as to keep the
                    enemy from leaving there, while I will march with the main body from
                    Fayetteville on the bridge of New River. Gen. Averell, with 2,000 mounted men,
                    will go through Logan County (Court-House) to the vicinity of Saltville, and if
                    circumstances will not justify his attacking that place, to destroy the railroad
                    from that place toward the bridge, so as to prevent troops (re-enforcements)
                    from Tennessee. Should I be successful in taking the bridge, I shall cross the
                    bridge (river) and move toward Lynchburg, destroying the road as far as I deem
                    it prudent, then fall back on Lewisburg. The officer who commands on the
                    Lewisburg line is instructed to watch the enemy's movements well, and if he
                    retreats, to advance, occupy Lewisburg, and collect the supplies of the country.
                    On the contrary, if the enemy should attack him, for him to retreat, delaying
                    the enemy all he can by contesting strong points, blockading the roads,
                    &amp;c.</p>
                <p>This plan of Gen. Crook's may prove successful and may have very important
                    results, but it is not in accordance with my views, because it brings Gen.
                    Averell too far west and out of reach of Gen. Crook. His cavalry will be used
                    up, and therefore cannot assist Gen. Crook in future operations. Secondly,
                    because this movement will allow the enemy to concentrate nearly all his forces
                    which are between Staunton and Lewisburg at Staunton. Thirdly, because it makes
                    all co-operation of forces here with those of Gen. Crook impossible. My
                    understanding was that all the forces of Gen. Crook should operate between the
                    James and New Rivers, and that the movements should end with the demonstration
                    against Staunton with all the forces under Crook, the cavalry included; but I
                    may be wrong and it is too late to interfere. I will therefore say nothing to
                    Gen. Crook, but wish him success, which he so well deserves, as he has done all
                    in his power to be prepared and to act.</p>
                <p>As for me, I would very much like to know what your expectations are. I
                    understand that I am to occupy the line at Cedar Creek, and to advance up the
                    Shenandoah Valley, if circumstances will allow me to do so. To advance beyond
                    Strasburg with my present force is hardly possible, if I cannot at the same time
                    leave a pretty strong force opposite Front Royal to prevent the enemy from
                    marching into my rear or cutting off my line of communication with cavalry. I
                    have only a very vague idea about the position of the Army of the Potomac, and
                    do not know whether there is any force of ours at or near Luray. If I am
                    expected to make energetic and decisive movements, I should have at least 5,000
                    more of good infantry, with which I could march up the Shenandoah Valley. The
                    country here is an open country, in which 50,000 men can maneuver. I would
                    submit that under all circumstances a strong corps of observation should be
                    formed here to maneuver upon the enemy's left flank.</p>
                <p>I do not, however, ask for more troops, but simply state how things are and
                    appear to me. The few troops I have here are excellent, with the exception of
                    the cavalry, but they are too weak and too near the main body of the enemy to be
                    able to venture much, especially as long as nothing is decided in regard to his
                    movement. I also take leave to inform you that by the concentration of nearly
                    all the troops of this department in the Kanawha and Shenandoah Valleys the
                    interior of the State of West Virginia is laid open to guerrillas and bands of
                    raiders. Cannot the States of Pennsylvania and Ohio send a few regiments of
                    militia to the assistance of the people who have sent nearly every available man
                    into the field, and those who are left are too poor and dependent upon their
                    daily labor to organize and defend themselves. I bring this subject to your
                    knowledge because I do not know what military resources the Government has at
                    present and what the people of West Virginia may expect.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>FRANZ SIGEL,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
