<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770118"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770118">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Jacob M. Campbell.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel jacob m campbell</title>
        <author>Campbell, J. M.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770118</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499306</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Jacob M. Campbell.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel jacob m campbell</title>
            <author>Campbell, J. M.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 118-119</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-08">1864-06-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770118T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Colonel Jacob Campbell reports from Staunton on the actions of the
                    Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Infantry in the June, 1864, Battle of Piedmont. The
                    Union victory there resulted in the death of Confederate General William E.
                    Jones, and the capture of Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 5. Report of Col. Jacob M. Campbell, Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Infantry,
                    Second Brigade, of engagement at Piedmont. HDQRS. FIFTY-FOURTH REGT.
                    PENNSYLVANIA VOL. INFTY.,
                    <name type="recipient">Col. JOSEPH THOBURN,<lb/> Cmdg. Second Brigade.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-08">June 8, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the part taken by the
                    Fifty-fourth Regt. Pennsylvania Volunteers in the engagement at Piedmont, Va.,
                    on the 5th instant:</p>
                <p>From the time my regiment arrived on the field, about 10 a. m., it was engaged,
                    under your direction, in reconnoitering the position of the enemy until about 11
                    a. m., when we were drawn up in line of battle on the extreme left of the line,
                    in the woods, and concealed from the view of the enemy. Shortly after gaining
                    this position, and before any order to advance was received, it was discovered
                    that to move forward--as our line was then formed--would expose our left flank
                    to a strongly intrenched position of the enemy. I immediately dispatched a
                    messenger to you informing you of the fact. After a personal inspection of the
                    position by yourself, we were ordered to fall back a few hundred feet farther
                    into the woods, keeping well out our line of skirmishers, and to await further
                    orders. Nothing occurred while we remained in this position, other than the
                    wounding of two of my men by the shells from the enemy's batteries, which
                    continued to shell the woods all the time we occupied it. About 11.30 a. m. I
                    received orders to fall back (leaving my line of skirmishers, Companies B and G,
                    to watch the movements of the enemy in that direction), which we did, and
                    remained in the rear of the battery on the elevated ground beyond the white
                    house. While here I received orders to march to the front to assault the
                    position of the enemy on our right, and to take my position on the left of the
                    line. While advancing, however, this order was changed, placing the
                    Thirty-fourth Massachusetts on my left. In this manner we advanced up to the
                    brow of the hill, where my regiment lay down on the ground, discharging a volley
                    into the enemy, and immediately charged into the woods on the right flank and
                    rear of the enemy's intrenched position. Here for a short time a most desperate
                    struggle took place, bayonets and clubbed guns were used on both sides, and many
                    hand-to-hand encounters took place. So sudden and apparently so unexpected to
                    the enemy was our movement on their flank that they were soon compelled to give
                    way in great confusion, despite all the efforts of their officers to rally them.
                    About 100 yards from the front of the woods was a fence running from the left of
                    the line, and parallel with it, extending along the front of the regiment on my
                    left. Along this fence to protect their flank the enemy had a strong force
                    posted. This appeared to be the key to their position, and they held it most
                    obstinately for some time, partially checking the advance of the regiment in
                    front of them. It was here that Brig.-Gen. Jones commanded in person, and was
                    killed while encouraging and rallying his troops. Seeing the importance of
                    carrying this position as quickly as possible. I hastily detached three
                    companies from the left of my regiment and threw them into line with the
                    Thirty-fourth Massachusetts to aid them in dislodging the enemy--leaving Maj. E.
                    D. Yutzy for the time in command of the right of my regiment. This was soon
                    done, for upon the fall of their chief commander they gave way in utter
                    confusion. Those who were not captured were driven through the woods and down a
                    steep bank into the river. By detaching the three companies on the left of my
                    regiment, my command was somewhat scattered when they arrived on the bluff at
                    the river-bank, but were soon reformed in good order.</p>
                <p>Lieut. R. P. Robison, of Company C, captured Col. Browne, who commanded a
                    Virginia brigade. Lieut. G. W. Camp, of Company I, captured Col. Jones, who
                    commanded a Tennessee brigade, placing him in charge of Private Harry Spencer,
                    of Company G, of the Twelfth Virginia, to take him to the rear. Two colonels of
                    regiments, with other field, staff, and line officers, too numerous to mention,
                    were captured by different members of my regiment. Private Thomas Evans, of
                    Company D, wrested the colors from the color bearer of a Tennessee regiment,
                    sending the color bearer to the rear. So numerous were the captures made of the
                    enemy, that I was compelled to stop taking them to the rear, and simply disarm
                    them and turn them out over the barricade to be taken charge of by the cavalry,
                    who were in the open field on our right and rear.</p>
                <p>The casualties in my regiment were, under the circumstances, surprisingly small,
                    which I attribute to the impetuosity of their charge upon the enemy, who were
                    not given time to rally with anything like order or concert of action in their
                    own defense.</p>
                <p>The number of men of my command in the engagement was 394, Companies B and G
                    having been left in rear of the batteries to keep up the skirmish line on the
                    left and guard against surprise from that direction.</p>
                <p>The only commissioned officer wounded was my adjutant, W. H. Rose, who received a
                    painful but not dangerous wound in the left thigh, while gallantly cheering on
                    the men in front of the position held by Brig.-Gen. Jones.</p>
                <p>Only 2 men of my regiment were killed and 27 wounded, a list of whom accompanies
                    this report. This does not include some 40 whose wounds are so slight that they
                    have not been reported to the hospital. It would be invidious to mention
                    officers or men by name, conspicuous for acts of bravery upon the field. All
                    behaved most gallantly, each did all that could be expected of brave men, and
                    all are equally entitled to the thanks and gratitude of their commanding
                    officers.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. M. CAMPBELL,<lb/> Col. Fifty-fourth Regt. Pennsylvania Vols.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
