<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770146"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770146">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Gen. William W. Averell.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of gen william w averell</title>
        <author>Averell, William W.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770146</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499317</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Gen. William W. Averell.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of gen william w averell</title>
            <author>Averell, William W.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 145-146</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-01">1864-07-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770146T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Cavalry General William Averell reports on June, 1864, cavalry movements in
                    the Shenandoah Valley. Averell reports receiving long-awaited supplies in
                    Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 22. Report of Brig. Gen. William W. Averell, U. S. Army, commanding
                    Second Cavalry Division.<lb/> HDQRS. SECOND CAV. DIV., DEPT. OF WEST
                    VIRGINIA,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-01">July 1, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Charleston W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of the cavalry
                    under my command since the 1st ultimo:</p>
                <p>On the 1st of June my division, consisting of the brigades of Brig.-Gen. Duffie,
                    Col. Schoonmaker, and Col. J. H. Oley, was encamped at Bunger's Mills,
                    Greenbrier County, waiting for supplies from Charleston of horses, shoes,
                    clothing, &amp;c. Crook's division crossed the river on that day, leaving me
                    to bring up my detachments and supplies, which did not arrive.</p>
                <p>On the 2d Mr. David Creigh, a citizen of Lewisburg, was tried by a military
                    commission and found guilty of murdering a Union soldier in November last. The
                    proceedings were subsequently approved and Mr. Creigh was hanged at Belleview on
                    Friday, the 10th of June.</p>
                <p>The detachments and supplies for which we had so long waited failing to arrive, I
                    followed Crook's division on the 3d to White Sulphur Springs with 3,200 mounted
                    and 1,200 dismounted men; 600 men were without shoes, and many other articles of
                    clothing were much needed.</p>
                <p>From the 18th of May until this day we had waited near Lewisburg upon half
                    rations, most of the time for necessary supplies of horse-shoes, nails, and
                    clothing; but owing to the miserable, inadequate, and insufficient
                    transportation furnished from the Kanawha we were obliged to set out again
                    almost as destitute as when we arrived. The march from Sulphur Springs to
                    Staunton was made in five days via Morris' Hill, Warm Springs, Goshen and
                    Middlebrook. My barefooted men suffered terribly, but without complaint on this
                    march. At Staunton the much needed supplies were received.</p>
                <p>On the 9th Brig.-Gen. Duffie was placed in command of the First Cavalry Division
                    and my own was reorganized as follows,viz: First Brigade, Col.
                    Schoonmaker--Fourteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry, Eighth Ohio; Second Brigade, Col.
                    Oley-Seventh West Virginia Cavalry, Thirty-fourth Ohio Volunteer Mounted
                    Infantry, Third West Virginia Cavalry, Fifth West Virginia Cavalry; Third
                    Brigade, Col. Powell--First West Virginia Cavalry, Second West Virginia Cavalry.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
