<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770134"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770134">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Daniel Frost.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel daniel frost</title>
        <author>Frost, Daniel</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770134</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499312</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Daniel Frost.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel daniel frost</title>
            <author>Frost, Daniel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 133-135</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-02">1864-07-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770134T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June, 1864, Union armies advanced up the Shenandoah Valley, through Staunton,
                    and on to Lexington and Lynchburg. In this report, Colonel Daniel Frost recounts
                    the role the Eleventh West Virginia Infantry played in the campaign. He
                    discusses arriving at Staunton, and camping and skirmishing in the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 17. Report of Col. Daniel Frost, Eleventh West Virginia Infantry.
                    HDQRS. ELEVENTH WEST VIRGINIA INFANTRY VOLS.,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. C. W. KIRBY,<lb/> Acting Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Piatt, W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report the following as the part taken by six companies of my
                    regiment in the recent expedition of the forces of this department to Lynchburg:</p>
                <p>Left Bunger's Mills, near Lewisburg, June 1, at 6.30 a. m., and, passing through
                    Lewisburg and across Greenbrier River, encamped near White Sulphur Springs.</p>
                <p>June 2, marched to near Callaghan's Station, Alleghany County.</p>
                <p>June 3, marched across Jackson River to near Hot Springs, Bath County.</p>
                <p>June 4, marched over Warm Springs Mountain to camp near Bath Alum Springs.</p>
                <p>June 5, passed through Panther Gap, where the enemy were posted in some force. A
                    flank movement caused the place to be evacuated, with slight skirmishing, when
                    we moved to Goshen Station, Virginia Central Railroad, and camped.</p>
                <p>June 6, our forces were engaged in destroying the Virginia Central Railroad from
                    Millborough to Craigsville and Pond Gap, which gap was passed June 7, into the
                    Shenandoah Valley, and camped near Middlebrook, within five miles of
                    Waynesborough and eight miles of Staunton.</p>
                <p>June 8, marched to Staunton, where we met the divisions of Gen.'s Sullivan and
                    Stahel, under Gen. Hunter. Here this brigade was reorganized, and Col. Campbell,
                    Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Volunteers, assumed command.</p>
                <p>June 10, marched from Staunton via the Lexington road. Met the enemy under Gen.
                    McCausland, near Staunton. The Eleventh Regt. was ordered to deploy to the right
                    of the road, and throwing forward a line of skirmishers, marched on the right of
                    the road, skirmishing the entire distance to Middlebrook, when we were relieved,
                    and marched in column to Brownsburg, Rockbridge County.</p>
                <p>June 11, left camp at 5 a. m. and marched to within one mile of Lexington, where
                    we engaged the enemy, who, after some resistance, evacuated the place, when our
                    forces took possession.</p>
                <p>Sunday, June 12, the Military Institute, professors' buildings, and Governor
                    Letcher's house were burned.</p>
                <p>June 14, marched from Lexington to Buchanan, twenty-four miles, which place we
                    found occupied by Gen. Averell's division. The bridge across James River had
                    been destroyed by McCausland in his retreat. A large portion of the village was
                    destroyed by taking fire from the burning bridge, and would probably all have
                    been destroyed but for the efforts of our soldiers in subduing the flames.</p>
                <p>June 15, marched by the Peaks of Otter to Fancy Farm, Bedford County, and camped
                    near Liberty, Virginia and Tennessee Railroad.</p>
                <p>June 16, marched through Liberty, filed along the railroad, completely destroying
                    it, by burning ties and bridges and bending rails, to Big Otter Creek, where we
                    encamped.</p>
                <p>June 17, marched to within three miles of Lynchburg, where we engaged the enemy,
                    driving him from his position, and at dark held our advanced position near the
                    principal works of the enemy. Companies B and G of my regiment were thrown
                    forward as skirmishers and advanced past a battery of rebel artillery, the enemy
                    retreating. Finding that our main column had halted, our skirmishers retired
                    with a loss of 3 wounded and 2 missing. Our regiment and brigade held the
                    advance line for an hour, when we were relieved by a brigade of the First
                    Infantry Division; fell back a few rods and slept on our arms until morning.</p>
                <p>June 18, marched three miles to the right, and in the afternoon were ordered
                    again to the front of the enemy's works and were afterward formed in line on our
                    left under a heavy fire of artillery. Our brigade charged the enemy and drove
                    him to his rifle-pits. Here the right giving way, and our brigade being exposed
                    to a cross-fire of musketry, grape, and canister, we were obliged to retire
                    about thirty paces to a new line of battle, which was held until orders were
                    received to fall back. Marched all that night and reached Liberty about 3 p. m.
                    of the 19th.</p>
                <p>Our losses in the second day's engagement were Lieut. James Barr, Company D, and
                    5 enlisted men killed, 16 wounded, and 10 missing. At Liberty our forces were
                    formed in order of battle, with cavalry fighting in the rear.</p>
                <p>Moved at 2 a. m. on the 20th and marched night and day, the men suffering
                    severely from heat, hunger, and fatigue, but bearing all without complaint,
                    through Salem, New Castle, Sweet Springs, White Sulphur Springs, Lewisburg,
                    Meadow Bluff, Gauley Bridge, to this place, where we arrived on the 29th ultimo,
                    having marched a distance of 412 miles, in the heart of the enemy's country,
                    over roads rendered dusty by three weeks of drought, without rations much of the
                    time, and with an enemy constantly in our front and rear.</p>
                <p>The endurance of the men is wonderful, and the spirit of devotion to their cause,
                    which enabled them to bear all the hardships they have seen, is worthy of
                    favorable comment.</p>
                <p>Herewith please find a list of casualties of my command.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed> D. FROST,<lb/> Col. Eleventh West Virginia Infantry Volunteers.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
