<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770355"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R13770355">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Johnston, Bradley</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770355</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499335</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Johnston, Bradley</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 354-356</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-10">1864-08-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770355T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this August, 1864, dispatch, Confederate Cavalry General Bradley Johnson
                    reports on the actions of his men in a July and August raid into Pennsylvania
                    and Maryland, including the capture and burning of Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 85.<lb/> Report of Brig. Gen. Bradley T. Johnston, C. S. Army, of operations
                    July 28--August 3.<lb/> HDQRS. JOHNSTON'S CAVALRY BRIGADE,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. S. S. PENDLETON,<lb/> Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-10">August 10, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Mount Jackson,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In obedience to orders headquarters cavalry, Valley District, on the 28th of July
                    I reported to Brig.-Gen. McCausland with my command, and was by him ordered to
                    cross the Potomac at daylight at McCoy's Ferry. This I did, and marched after
                    crossing the river on Clear Spring. Here there was a small force some 300 or 400
                    strong of Federal cavalry, which Maj. Gilmor, with the First Regiment and Second
                    Battalion Maryland Cavalry, promptly drove five miles toward Hagerstown. Thence
                    we moved on Mercersburg, which place we reached at 5 p. m., Maj. Sweeney,
                    Thirty-sixth Battalion Virginia Cavalry, driving a small force of the enemy's
                    cavalry before him out of the town. The command here fed, and at 9 p. m. we
                    moved on Chambersburg, which place we reached just before day. My advance had
                    skirmished all night with a party in front and on the outskirts of the town,
                    being fired into with canister from a field piece. Our further progress was
                    delayed until broad day disclosed the weakness of the enemy. Brig.-Gen.
                    McCausland ordered me to send in the Twenty-first Virginia, Col. Peters, to
                    occupy the town, the Thirty-sixth Battalion, Maj. Sweeney, having preceded it as
                    skirmishers on foot. After remaining in the town some three hours, he ordered it
                    to be fired, which was done quickly and in many places. As soon as it was fairly
                    burning we moved on McConnellsburg, which place we reached at 5 p. m., this
                    brigade in advance, and went into camp.</p>
                <p>At sunrise next morning, Sunday, July 31, we moved on Hancock, we in rear.
                    Brig.-Gen. McCausland then directed me to send Lieut.-Col. Dunn, Thirty-seventh
                    Virginia Battalion Cavalry, by way of Bedford toward Cumberland, to arrest
                    hostages. I ordered Col. Dunn to make the movement, but returning to
                    McConnellsburg he found it occupied by three regiments of Federal cavalry, and
                    properly returned to his command. I then directed him to remain with me,
                    reporting the facts to Brig.-Gen. McCausland. Reached Hancock about 1 p. m. and
                    stopped to feed, while Brig.-Gen. McCausland demanded of the town authorities a
                    ransom of $30,000 and 5,000 cooked rations. At the request of the authorities,
                    who were known to me to be Southern men, I explained to him that the whole
                    population of the town was only 700 and without moneyed resources, which made
                    that amount absolutely impossible to be collected. At the same time I advised
                    them to get every dollar they could raise and pay it. This, I believe, they
                    proceeded to do, but the enemy coming on us before anything was completed, I was
                    unable to receive the money, as he had directed me to do when he moved off his
                    command on the approach of the enemy. The latter gave us but little trouble and
                    was easily checked. At 3 a. m. we stopped at Bevansville, where we unsaddled and
                    fed, and at sunrise moved on Cumberland, Brig.-Gen. McCausland in advance. He
                    engaged the enemy about 3.30 p. m. Monday, August, 1 two miles and a half
                    southeast of Cumberland, and my opinion being asked I agreed with him that the
                    force displayed, with the position and unknown country, made it inexpedient to
                    attack. We withdrew, and this brigade in advance moved on the Potomac at Old
                    Town. We reached this point about daylight Tuesday morning, August 2, and found
                    the enemy, after burning the canal bridges, had posted himself on a hill between
                    the canal and the Potomac. I immediately attacked in front with the
                    Twenty-seventh Battalion Virginia, Capt. Gibson's, and Eighth Virginia, Col.
                    Corns, while I threw the Twenty-first, Col. Peters; Thirty-sixth Battalion, Maj.
                    Sweeney, and Thirty-seventh Battalion, Lieut.-Col. Dunn, all under charge of
                    Col. Peters, over the canal by means of a quickly built bridge and attacked in
                    flanks, at the same time opening my two pieces of artillery vigorously on the
                    enemy. He was driven across the Potomac at once, where he took position behind
                    the railroad embankment, a strong block-house on his right and an iron-clad
                    train of cars, a battery, three guns in each, covered with railroad iron at each
                    end, and four cars iron-lines and musket-proof between the two. The first shot
                    from my artillery drove through the engine-boiler, the second through a port
                    hole, dismounting a gun, and the third dispersed the men behind the railroad
                    embankment. Closing up on the block-house, I demanded a surrender, and Col.
                    Stough, One hundred and fifty-third Ohio, with 80 men and officers and his
                    regimental colors, surrendered to me. Thence I immediately moved to Springfield,
                    where I camped on the South Branch. Here we rested during the 3d August.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, colonel, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>BRADLEY TO JOHNSTON,<lb/> Brig.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
