<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770153"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770153">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Edwin G.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770153</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499324</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Edwin G.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 152-154</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-17">1864-06-17</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770153T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In early June, 1864, Federal troops under David Hunter launched a large scale
                    raid in the Shenandoah Valley. After defeating the Confederates at the Battle of
                    Piedmont, the Union army captured Staunton, VA. They did not stay long, however.
                    By June 17, Confederate Colonel Edwin Lee returned to Staunton to take command.
                    In this report, Lee, who had taken command at Staunton just prior to the
                    evacuation, discusses the abandonment of the town, and his efforts to rebuild
                    his command upon his return. Lee itemizes and assesses the value of the supplies
                    saved before the retreat, as well as the buildings and goods destroyed by the
                    Federals. He reports how he entrusted a prominent citizen of Staunton with
                    distributing to townspeople goods that could not be saved in the retreat. Lee
                    also discusses the parole of sick and wounded prisoners captured at the Staunton
                    hospital, and efforts to rebuild the railroad with the help of C. R. Mason, a
                    prominent citizen.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS.,
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. S. COOPER,<lb/> Adjutant and Inspector Gen.,
                        Richmond.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-17">17, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Pursuant to your telegram of the 3d instant, I took command of this post on the
                    4th. A few hours after doing so I heard that the enemy were moving on Gen.
                    Jones' flank, toward Port Republic, and fearing a cavalry dash, took the
                    responsibility of getting the heavy stores and official papers here in readiness
                    for moving. I received no orders and no information leading me to think the
                    place in danger until Sunday afternoon, June 5, at 5 p. m., when a note
                    addressed to a gentleman here was handed me. It stated that Gen. Jones was
                    killed, and the "army broken and routed," and general Vaughn retreating toward
                    Fishersville. I immediately strained every nerve to get all stores and supplies
                    away, but time was so limited, and for lack of any warning whatever, the means
                    were so limited also, that it was utterly impossible to remove everything.
                    Another disadvantage was that, having been in command of the post brief a time,
                    I did know what was here, and had no time for inquiries. Nearly all the wagons
                    of the post quartermaster had been taken for the newly arrived troops, who came
                    unfurnished with transportation. The precautionary measures of Saturday enabled
                    us to get off 900 sacks of salt, a large lot of leather, &amp;c. All the
                    ammunition was saved, all the bacon, and most of the quartermaster's stores. At
                    11 p. m. June 5 I got an order from Brig.-Gen. Vaughn, in reply to a
                    communication of mine, returning to Waynesborough. This is the only order of any
                    description, the only warning or notice I received from any one.</p>
                <p>I inclose a report, which is as accurate as I am to make, of what was left here.
                    I did not destroy what was left, because I could not do so without destroying
                    the buildings, unless I moved the things out, for which I had no time, but the
                    enemy carried nothing off; they destroyed all. I gave a trusty gentleman of the
                    town authority to give to citizens, before the enemy got in, what they wanted.
                    He distributed all the commissary and some of the quartermaster's stores, and
                    saved, by claiming it as his own, about a hogshead of sugar. The depot, woolen
                    factory, Government stables, steam-mill, wagon shops, and store-houses for tax
                    in kind, were burned. The quartermaster's, commissary, and ordnance buildings
                    were not burned, being private property. The railroad was effectually destroyed
                    for three miles, and partially for three more. The bridge at Christian's Creek,
                    about fifty feet long, was burned. The telegraph destroyed for six miles; that I
                    have repaired. The hands are slowly at work on the railroad. At the rate they
                    are moving it will take a month or more to repair it. I would respectfully
                    suggest that the railroad company be requested to employ C. R. Mason, of this
                    place, as the most suitable person to undertake the repairs of this road.</p>
                <p>Having no instructions, I had to use own judgment about the time of leaving, and
                    the direction the trains should be sent. Such things as could be gotten on the
                    cars was sent to Lynchburg; the commissary supplies I sent to Gen. Vaughan, and
                    all the other wagon trains across the Blue Ridge, at Tye River Gap, into Nelson
                    County, not wishing to encumber the army with a train it could not use. I
                    regarded that as a point safe from every attack, at least until the
                    quartermaster could receive orders from the brigadier-general commanding. With
                    these I sent the surplus hospital train, the convalescents, negroes, &amp;c.</p>
                <p>I left at daylight on Monday morning, after everything was gone. The enemy on the
                    10th captured a small portion of the quartermaster's train, which unfortunately
                    had with it the quartermaster and commissary official papers, all of which were
                    burned. Our sick and wounded at the hospital, with attendants, were paroled by
                    the enemy. They left 300 wounded and forty nurses here of their own, with one
                    assistant surgeon. Upon arriving on the 12th I had no guard, and did not know
                    whether we would hold the place or not, so to be at least even with the Yankees
                    I paroled all of them. I inclose a copy of the parole, the last clause added
                    because being entirely alone here, I wished to keep those who were able to do so
                    from running off before I could get a guard. I have only a provost guard now. I
                    have not yet given a copy of the parole to the surgeon, and I shall not do so
                    until I hear from Judge Ould, to whom I have written for instructions.</p>
                <p>I obeyed that part of your order in reference to organizing a local force, and
                    doing all in my power to aid in the defense of the valley. Before it was
                    received over 700 reserve, and 800 others, convalescents, detailed men,
                    furloughed soldier, &amp;c., had been collected and sent to the field, where
                    they still are.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>E. G. LEE,<lb/> Col., Cmdg. Post.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Inclosure.<lb/> Memorandum of property abandoned upon
                        evacuation of post at Staunton, Va., on 6th June, 1864.<lb/> Commissary
                        stores: Twenty barrels four (mostly broken), 10 barrels corn meal (mostly
                        broken), 600 sacks salt, 2 hogsheads sugar (1 of these saved by a citizen),
                        5,000 empty sacks (in bad order), 5 bales cotton cloth (to be exchanged for
                        supplies), 8 bales cotton yarn (to be exchanged for supplies), and tables,
                        desks, safe, &amp;c.<lb/> Ordnance stores: 1,000 damaged small-arms, 150
                        pairs spurs and straps (common), 200 pounds horseshoes, 20 condemned
                        saddles, 150 new saddles of Richmond Arsenal, one 12-pounder Napoleon,
                        dismounted, which had been captured from the enemy; 2 howitzers, iron
                        (32-pounders), of which they only broke the trunnions; 1 howitzer, iron
                        (12-pounder), in same condition.<lb/> Quartermaster's stores: 1,000 wooden
                        buckets, 8 or 10 boxes deceased soldiers' clothing, 2 or 3 boxes new
                        clothing, 40 or 50 good wagons, large number of picks and shovels, small lot
                        of harness (not much value), and sundry other things of no great value or
                        importance, together with office furniture.<lb/> In addition to the
                        foregoing, there was a considerable quantity of provisions belonging to or
                        intended for the Ordnance department in Richmond. The agent in charge of
                        them estimates their value at $400,000.<lb/> This report is only
                        approximate, the loss of official papers by capture preventing an accurate
                        one. All these stores were destroyed by the enemy, save what were given to
                        citizens during a brief period of the morning of the 6th instant.<lb/>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
