<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770120"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770120">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of General George Crook.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of general george crook</title>
        <author>Crook, George</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770120</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499307</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of General George Crook.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of general george crook</title>
            <author>Crook, George</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 119-122</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-07">1864-07-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770120T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General George Crook reports on his June, 1864, advance in the Shenandoah
                    Valley. Crook reports moving to make a demonstration against Staunton, fighting
                    Confederate skirmishers and guerrillas all the way. He also mentions getting
                    shoes for his troops upon arrival at Staunton. Crook also discusses burning
                    bridges and destroying railroad tracks.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 6. Report of Brig. Gen. George Crook, U. S. Army, commanding Second
                    Infantry Division. HDQRS. SECOND DIV., OF INFTY., DEPT. OF W. VA.,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Col. CHARLES G. HALPINE,<lb/> Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-07">July 7, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Charleston, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that on my arrival at Meadow Bluff, May 19, from the
                    New River expedition, I received a dispatch from Maj.-Gen. Sigel, then
                    commanding the department, to make a demonstration on Staunton as soon as
                    possible. Being out of provision and many of my men barefoot, I was compelled to
                    lay over here until such supplies could be brought up from Gauley Bridge, but
                    owing to the miserable transportation furnished by the quartermaster's
                    department (many of the animals thus furnished being not two years old), I was
                    compelled to lie here eleven days instead of five, and then I was compelled to
                    leave on the 30th (31st), with many of my men barefoot and scantily supplied
                    with rations.</p>
                <p>I marched via Callaghan's, Warm Springs, Goshen Depot, Pond Gap, and Middlebrook
                    to Staunton, arriving at the latter place on the morning of the 8th of June.
                    During the march we kept up almost a continued skirmish with the enemy's scouts,
                    guerrillas, and found Millborough Depot, with McCausland's and Jenkins'
                    brigades, who would occupy the strong positions in my advance in order to impede
                    my march, but without avail. My loss in killed, wounded, and missing was very
                    slight, inflicting a much heavier loss on the enemy. We burned Calf Pasture
                    bridge, besides some lesser bridges and culverts, and tore up some three or four
                    miles of the track on the Virginia Central Railroad. Gen. Averell left the
                    vicinity of Lewisburg some two days after me. (For particulars see his report).
                    At Staunton we were fortunate enough to get shoes for our barefoot men.</p>
                <p>Col. Campbell reported to me on the 9th with the Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania
                    Volunteer Infantry, and was assigned the command of the Third Brigade.</p>
                <p>I marched on the morning of the 10th, per instructions from the major-general
                    commanding, on the Lexington road via Middlebrook; met McCausland's brigade,
                    some 1,500 strong, a couple of miles from Staunton. By skirmishing with my
                    advance and occupying strong positions along the road ahead of me, he endeavored
                    to retard my march, but his loss of killed and wounded that fell into my hands
                    was more than double mine. We marched twenty-four miles and encamped at
                    Brownsburg. Gen. Averell encamped some two miles to my right.</p>
                <p>On my approach to Lexington next morning the enemy fled across the river, burned
                    the bridges, and occupied the cliff on the opposite bank of the river and in the
                    edge of Lexington, opening on me with artillery and musketry. I occupied their
                    attention in front while I sent the Second Brigade, Col. White commanding, to
                    ford the river about two miles above. Gen. Averell had also crossed the river
                    several miles above town, and on the approach of Gen. Averell's and Col. White's
                    commands, the enemy fled toward Buchanan. The advance guard of the First Brigade
                    entered town on the heels of the enemy and were first in town. Lay at Lexington
                    two days.</p>
                <p>Marched to Buchanan the 14th, a distance of twenty-six miles.</p>
                <p>Next day crossed the mountains by Peaks of Otter, and hearing and rear, I halted
                    at Fancy Farm and requested Gen. Averell also to await until the remainder of
                    the command came up.</p>
                <p>Next morning moved to Liberty, seven miles. My division thoroughly destroyed the
                    railroad from Liberty to Big Otter Creek by tearing up the track, burning the
                    ties, and bending the rails. Encamped near Big Otter on the Forest road.</p>
                <p>Received dispatch from the major-general commanding just before daylight next
                    morning to march across to the main road at New London-that Gen. Averell
                    reported the enemy in force there. Arrived on this road, eight miles from
                    Lynchburg, next morning at 10 o'clock, marching eleven miles. Learning that the
                    enemy had retreated toward Lynchburg, halted here until 4 p. m. for Gen.
                    Sullivan's division, when we moved on the main road to Lynchburg, my division in
                    front. Gen. Averell's division moved on a road to the right, which intersected
                    the main road some four miles from Lynchburg, which caused the enemy to fall
                    back beyond the intersection of these roads. When I arrived at these cross-roads
                    Gen. Averell had already passed and was engaging the enemy at the church on the
                    hill beyond. Upon my arrival at the church the enemy began to show themselves in
                    considerable force and were pressing back our skirmish line. At Gen. Averell's
                    request I sent a brigade of infantry to support his line; also sent the third
                    Brigade, Col. Campbell commanding, to our left to clear a skirt of woods of the
                    enemy. The Second Brigade of my division that I had sent to the right to support
                    Gen. Averell, soon checked the enemy's advance and started them in the opposite
                    direction and drove them over a mile, capturing 4 pieces of artillery, but by
                    mistake only 1 piece was brought off the field. Part of this brigade had already
                    turned the enemy's works, but by this time it had become so dark and not knowing
                    the ground the pursuit was discontinued. Gen. Sullivan soon came up with his
                    division and relieved mine, when I fell back, replenished my cartridge-boxes,
                    and went into camp for the night.</p>
                <p>Next morning I was sent to the right with my division to make a reconnaissance
                    for the purpose of turning the enemy's left. Found it impracticable after
                    marching some three or four miles, and just returned with my division and got it
                    in position to support Gen. Sullivan's division when the enemy made an attack on
                    our lines. On the retreat this evening my division brought up the rear. When I
                    reached Liberty I found Gen. Averell had gone into camp in the edge of town; the
                    infantry were going into camp some mile and a half farther on. Just as my
                    division was passing through town the enemy were reported on the Lynchburg road.
                    Gen. Averell desired me to leave part of my division to support his cavalry, but
                    as my men had marched all night and day, with scarcely any rest, I was anxious
                    to put them in camp as soon as possible, and also being well satisfied that
                    nothing but the enemy's cavalry could have had time to reach Liberty, and also
                    that our cavalry was superior in numbers to theirs, I declined unless the enemy
                    should develop a sufficient force to warrant the harassing of my tired men. The
                    enemy, however, only developed some 1,500 or 2,000 cavalry, and had an
                    engagement with Gen. Averell's cavalry.</p>
                <p>Left camp at 2 o'clock next morning; arrived at Buford's Gap at about 1 p. m.
                    Early's corps reached the gap about 3 or 4 p. m. and endeavored to flank us out
                    of the gap, but failed. We resumed the march at 9 p. m. I have no evidence that
                    the enemy's infantry followed us farther than to this point. Their cavalry,
                    however, followed us to the eastern slope of the Catawba Mountain. From here on
                    to the Kanawha Valley no enemy made his appearance except an occasional
                    bushwhacker. The division became a little straitened for provisions, but came in
                    in good shape.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak too highly of both officers and men of the division for their
                    uniform good behavior and cheerful and prompt obedience to orders, and the
                    uncomplaining fortitude with which they endured the hardships and privations
                    incident to the march.</p>
                <p>My losses during the whole expedition are as follows, viz:<lb/> Command. K W M
                    T<lb/> First Brigade..... 11 49 16 76<lb/> Second Brigade.... 17 58 4 79<lb/>
                    Third Brigade..... 29 134 27 190<lb/> Total*...... 57 241 47 345<lb/> K=Killed.
                    W=Wounded. M=Missing. T=Total.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>GEO. CROOK,<lb/> Brig.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
