<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770767"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770767">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770767</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499441</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 766-767</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-26">1864-06-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770767T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes Jefferson Davis in June, 1864, to discuss the overall
                    strategic situation. He mentions plans for the Valley, including Early's actions
                    in Staunton and the lower Valley. Lee expresses fear about his army's supply
                    situation as it faces Grant's Federals. Also of interest is Lee's opinion of the
                    Union's African American troops.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA,
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JEFFERSON DAVIS,<lb/> President
                        Confederate States:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-26">June 26, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. PRESIDENT:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your letter of the 25th instant.
                    Gen. Hunter has escaped Early, and will make good his retreat, as far as I can
                    understand, to Lewisburg. Although his expedition has been partially
                    interrupted, I fear he has not been much punished, except by the demoralization
                    of his troops and the loss of some artillery. From his present position he can
                    easily be reorganized and re-equipped, and unless we have sufficient force to
                    resist him will repeat his expedition. This would necessitate the return of
                    Early at Staunton. I think it better that he should move down the Valley, if he
                    can obtain provisions, which would draw Hunter after him, and may enable him to
                    strike Pope before he can effect a junction with Hunter. If circumstances favor,
                    I should also recommend his crossing the Potomac. I think I can maintain our
                    lines here against Gen. Grant. He does not seem disposed to attack, and has
                    thrown himself strictly on the defensive.</p>
                <p>I am less uneasy about holding our position than about our ability to procure
                    supplies for the army. A fear the latter difficulty will oblige me to attack
                    Gen. Grant in his intrenchments, which I should not hesitate to do but for the
                    loss it will inevitably entail. A want of success would in my opinion be almost
                    fatal, and this causes me to hesitate in the hope that some relief may be
                    procured without running such great hazard. I should like much to have the
                    benefit of Your Excellency good judgment and views upon this subject.</p>
                <p>Great benefit might be drawn from the release of our prisoners at Point Lookout
                    if it can be accomplished. The number of men employed for this purpose would
                    necessarily be small, as the whole would have to be transported secretly across
                    the Potomac where it is very broad, the means of doing which must first be
                    procured. I can devote to this purpose the whole of the Marylanders of this
                    army, which would afford a sufficient number of men of excellent material and
                    much experience, but I am at a loss where to find a proper leader. As he would
                    command Maryland troops and operate upon Maryland soil it would be well that he
                    should be a Marylander. Of those connected with this army I consider Col.
                    Bradley T. Johnson the most suitable. He is bold and intelligent, ardent and
                    true, and yet I am unable to say whether he possesses all the requisite
                    qualities. Everything in an expedition of the kind would depend upon the leader.</p>
                <p>I have understood that most of the garrison at Point Lookout was composed of
                    negroes. I should suppose that the commander of such troops would be poor and
                    feeble. A stubborn resistance, therefore, may not reasonably be expected. By
                    taking a company of the Maryland artillery, armed as infantry, the dismounted
                    cavalry and their infantry organization, as many men would be supplied as
                    transportation could be procured for. By throwing them suddenly on the beach
                    with some concert of action among the prisoners, I think the guard might be
                    overpowered, the prisoners liberated and organized, and marched immediately on
                    the route to Washington.</p>
                <p>The artillery company could operate the guns captured at the Point. The
                    dismounted cavalry with the released prisoners of that arm could mount
                    themselves on the march, and the infantry would form a respectable force. Such a
                    body of men under an able leader, although they might not be able without
                    assistance to capture Washington, could march around it and cross the upper
                    Potomac where fordable. I do not think they could cross the river in a body at
                    any point below Washington, unless possibly at Alexandria. Provisions,
                    &amp;c., would have to be collected in the country through which they pass.
                    The operations on the river must be confided to an able naval officer, who I
                    know will be found in Col. Wood. The subject is one worthy of consideration, and
                    can only be matured by reflection.</p>
                <p>The sooner it is put in execution the better, if it be deemed practicable. At
                    this time, as far as I can learn, all the troops in the control of the United
                    States are being sent to Grant, and little or no opposition could be made by
                    those at Washington. With relation to the project of Marshal Kane, if the matter
                    can be kept secret, which I fear is impossible, should Gen. Early cross the
                    Potomac, he might be sent to join him.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, Your Excellency's obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
