<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770123"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770123">
     <teiHeader type="migrated">
          <fileDesc>
               <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Rutherford B.
                         Hayes.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel rutherford b hayes</title>
        <author>Hayes, Rutherford B.</author>
        <respStmt>
                         <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                         <name/>
                         <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                         <name/>
                    </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
               <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
               <publicationStmt>
                    <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                    <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                    <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                    <idno type="VCDH">R13770123</idno>
        <!--
                    <availability>
                         <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                              University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                         <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                    <date value="1999">1999</date>
               <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499308</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
               <seriesStmt>
                    <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
               </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                    <note/>
               </notesStmt>
               <sourceDesc>
                    <biblFull>
                         <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Rutherford B. Hayes.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of
                                   the Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel rutherford b hayes</title>
            <author>Hayes, Rutherford B.</author>
            <respStmt>
                                   <resp>Translator:</resp>
                                   <name/>
                              </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                         <editionStmt>
                              <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                         </editionStmt>
                         <extent>Pages 122-123</extent>
                         <publicationStmt>
                              <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                              <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                              <date value="1997">1997</date>
                         </publicationStmt>
                         <seriesStmt>
                              <p/>
                         </seriesStmt>
                         <notesStmt>
                              <note/>
                         </notesStmt>
                    </biblFull>
               </sourceDesc>
          </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
          <profileDesc>
               <creation>
                    <date value="1864-07-04">1864-07-04</date>
               </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
               <textClass>
                    <keywords>
                         <term/>
                         <term/>
                    </keywords>
               </textClass>
          </profileDesc>
          <revisionDesc>
               <change>
                    <date value=""/>
                    <respStmt>
                         <resp/>
                         <name/>
                    </respStmt>
                    <item/>
               </change>
          <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
     </teiHeader>
     <text id="R13770123T">
          <front id="d2">
               <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                    <p>Union Colonel Rutherford B. Hayes reports on the role played by the
                         Twenty-third Ohio Infantry in the June, 1864, advance on Staunton,
                         Lynchburg, and Lexington. Hayes reports skirmishing outside Staunton, as
                         well as sending home volunteers whose terms of enlistment had expired.</p>
               </div1>
          </front>
          <body id="d4">
               <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                    <head>
                         No. 7. Report of Col. Rutherford B. Hayes, Twenty-third Ohio Infantry,
                         commanding First Brigade. HDQRS. FIRST BRIGADE, ARMY OF THE
                         KANAWHA,
                         <name type="recipient">Capt. J. L. BOTSFORD,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.,
                              Army of the Kanawha.</name>
                    </head>
                    <opener>
                         <dateline>
                              <date value="1864-07-04">July 4, 1864.</date>
                              <name type="place">Camp Crook, W. Va.,</name>
                         </dateline>
                         <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <p>I have the honor to submit a brief report of the part taken by the First
                         Brigade, Second Infantry Division, Department of West Virginia, in the late
                         campaign against Staunton and Lynchburg.</p>
                    <p>The brigade left Meadow Bluff May 31 with 2,433 men and officers, viz:
                         Twenty-third Ohio Veteran Volunteer Infantry, under Lieut. Col. J. M.
                         Comly, 534; Thirty-sixth Ohio Veteran Volunteer Infantry, Col. H. F. Devol,
                         553; Fifth West Virginia Volunteer Infantry, Col. A. A. Tomlinson, 572;
                         Thirteenth West Virginia Volunteer Infantry, Col. William R. Brown, 774;
                         total, 2,433.</p>
                    <p>We reached Staunton June 8 without loss, the enemy frequently appearing in
                         our front and making several ineffectual efforts to delay or stop our
                         progress. At Staunton 9 officers and 160 men of Twenty-third Ohio Volunteer
                         Infantry, whose term of service had expired, were sent to Ohio to be
                         mustered out of service.</p>
                    <p>On the 10th day of June we started via Lexington and Buchanan toward
                         Lynchburg, reaching the vicinity of that city June 17, after a march of
                         about 100 miles and a delay of two days at Lexington. On this march the
                         First Brigade led the column on the day we reached Lexington and the
                         greater part of the day before, and during both days was engaged in several
                         brisk skirmishes with the enemy. On the day before reaching Lexington, June
                         10, an advance guard, composed of four companies of the Fifth West Virginia
                         Infantry, under Lieut.-Col. Enochs, engaged the enemy twice, driving them
                         rapidly, with some loss. In one of these skirmishes at Newport Lieut.
                         Miller, Fifth West Virginia Volunteer Infantry, was killed at the head of
                         his command.</p>
                    <p>On the 11th, during the attack on Lexington, the Thirty-sixth Ohio Veteran
                         Volunteer Infantry, under Col. Devol, led the column, and pushing rapidly
                         up to the enemy's position near the town, occupied their attention until a
                         part of our forces crossing the river above town compelled its evacuation.
                         In this advance and attack Lieut. J. M. Hamlin, Thirty-sixth Ohio Volunteer
                         Infantry, was severely wounded, and of the same regiment 3 men were killed
                         and 7 wounded.</p>
                    <p>At Lynchburg, on the 18th, the brigade was formed to repel what was deemed at
                         the time an assault of our position by the enemy in force. A line was
                         formed with the greatest promptness, the Fifth West Virginia Infantry
                         having formed in a part of the line, when the enemy, after a sudden
                         approach, hastily withdrew. Pursued the retreating rebels and drove them
                         from their rifle-pits to the protection of their main works. The works
                         being too strong to be carried by the force there before them, the regiment
                         retired in some disorder, but was promptly reformed before reaching our own
                         lines. I regret to state that in this charge Lieut. D. J. Thomas fell
                         mortally wounded.</p>
                    <p>After leaving Lynchburg the officers and men of the First Brigade sustained
                         themselves through the hardships and privations of the retreat like good
                         soldiers. No words of praise could do more than justice to their good
                         conduct throughout the campaign.</p>
                    <p>We reached Charleston July 1, after a march from Meadow Bluff of almost 500
                         miles.</p>
                    <p>Our loss was as follows:<lb/> Command. K W M T<lb/> 23d Ohio Veteran
                         Volunteer Infantry...... .. 3 6 9<lb/> 36th Ohio Veteran Volunteer
                         Infantry..... 3 11 3 17<lb/> 5th West Virginia Volunteer Infantry..... 8 27
                         6 41<lb/> 13th West Virginia Volunteer Infantry.... .. 8 1 9<lb/>
                         Total*.............................. 11 49 16 76<lb/> K=Killed. W=Wounded.
                         M=Missing. T=Total.</p>
                    <p>I herewith transmit copies of the reports of regimental commanders.</p>
                    <closer>
                         <salute>I am, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                         <signed>R. B. HAYES,<lb/> Col., Cmdg.</signed>
                    </closer>
               </div1>
          </body>
     </text>
</TEI.2>
