<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770125"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770125">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel William R. Brown.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel william r brown</title>
        <author>Brown, William R.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770125</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499309</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel William R. Brown.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel william r brown</title>
            <author>Brown, William R.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 124-125</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-02">1864-07-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770125T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Colonel William R. Brown recounts the role played by the Thirteenth West
                    Virginia Infantry during the June, 1864, Union advance in the Shenandoah Valley.
                    Brown reports arriving at Staunton on the 8th, and encountering skirmishing in
                    the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 9. Report of Col. William R. Brown, Thirteenth West Virginia
                    Infantry. HDQRS. 13TH Regt. WEST VIRGINIA, VOL. INFTY.,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. R. HASTINGS,<lb/> Acting Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Charleston, W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In compliance with orders received July 1 instant, requiring a "full report of
                    the action taken by your regiment since leaving Meadow Bluff, embracing the
                    number of men at your departure, loss in killed, wounded, and missing," I have
                    the honor to submit the following report:</p>
                <p>On Monday, May 30, orders were received to march at 8 a. m. the 31st in the
                    following order: Twenty-third Ohio Volunteer Infantry, Thirteenth Virginia,
                    Thirty-sixth Ohio Volunteer Infantry, and Fifth Virginia. At the time of
                    departure this regiment numbered 720 men.</p>
                <p>Passed through Lewisburg, W. Va., June 1, at 8 a. m.</p>
                <p>Crossed the main Alleghanies June 2.</p>
                <p>Passed the Hot Springs June 4, at 6.30 a. m. Part of this regiment was deployed
                    as skirmishers at Warm Springs Mountain, at which place the rebels appeared in
                    some force on the top of the mountain. Camped at Goshen, on the Virginia Central
                    Railroad, in the evening of June 5.</p>
                <p>June 6 was devoted to destroying the railroad.</p>
                <p>June 7, after crossing the mountain at Pond Gap, part of this regiment was
                    deployed as skirmishers; past the village of Middlebrook to a rebel camp, which
                    was found deserted. Arrived at Staunton June 8.</p>
                <p>June 10, Privates William L. Harris and Taylor N. Hogg, of Company B, were
                    wounded near the village of Newport, on the Staunton and Lexington road.</p>
                <p>June 11, this regiment was present at the battle of Lexington, and entered the
                    town at 6 p. m. by the burnt bridge.</p>
                <p>Crossed the James River at Buchanan at 6 p. m. June 14.</p>
                <p>Crossed the Blue Ridge and passed near the foot of the Peaks of Otter June 15.</p>
                <p>Arrived at Liberty, county seat of Bedford, at 9 a. m. June 16. The remaining
                    part of the day was devoted to destroying the Virginia and Tennessee Railroad.</p>
                <p>June 17, at 10 p. m. this regiment was assigned its place in line of battle for
                    the following day before Lynchburg.</p>
                <p>June 18, at sunrise the enemy opened heavily with artillery. During the morning
                    this regiment was deployed to the right of the town; at noon the force was
                    concentrated at the center. This regiment was deployed in line of battle in
                    front of brigade at 1 p. m., and slowly advanced under a heavy artillery and
                    musketry fire toward the enemy's works, and remained before the works until 8 p.
                    m., when this regiment received orders to march one mile beyond the village of
                    New London. Loss in wounded in this day's battle Company D, 2, F. Ohlinger and
                    L. C. Johnson; G., 3, M. W. Maybee, W. J. Dillon, and S. H. Clendenen; G, 1, A.
                    J. Harper (missing in action); total, 6. G should read K. Correction from
                    General Index.</p>
                <p>June 20, reached Buford's Gap at 2 p. m., at which place this regiment was
                    deployed as skirmishers until sunset. Philip Wintz, Company A, wounded severely.</p>
                <p>Recrossed the Alleghany Mountains in the evening of June 24.</p>
                <p>Camped at Meadow Bluff June 25.</p>
                <p>Crossed Gauley River at 11.30 June 28.</p>
                <p>Encamped below Elk River at 1 p. m. July 1.</p>
                <p>Distance marched since May 30, 480 miles.</p>
                <p>Loss in wounded, 8; missing in action, 1; total, 9.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>WM. R. BROWN,<lb/> Col. Thirteenth Regt. West Virginia Vol. Infty.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
