<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1377095"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1377095">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Maj. Gen. David Hunter.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of maj gen david hunter</title>
        <author>Hunter, David</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1377095</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499444</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Maj. Gen. David Hunter.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of maj gen david hunter</title>
            <author>Hunter, David</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 94-95</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-08">1864-06-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1377095T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June, 1864, Union troops under General David Hunter advanced up the Shenandoah
                    Valley. In this report, Hunter discusses his advance, his victory at Piedmont,
                    and the capture of Staunton. Hunter reports capturing and paroling sick and
                    wounded Confederates, capturing supplies, burning buildings, and destroying
                    railroads in town.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 1. Reports of Maj. Gen. David Hunter, U. S. Army, commanding Department
                    of West Virginia, including operations June 2-July 14.<lb/> HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF WEST VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">ADJUTANT-GEN. U. S. ARMY.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-08">June 8, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Staunton, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that on my arrival at Harrisonburg, on the afternoon
                    of the 2d instant, I found the enemy occupying a strong intrenched position at
                    Mount Crawford, on the North River, where it is crossed by the Valley turnpike,
                    his right at Rockland Mills, and his left at Bridgewater.</p>
                <p>I spent the following day in ascertaining the enemy's force and position, and
                    early on the morning of the 4th, after sending a force crossed the Shenandoah at
                    port Republic. This movement was so little expected that we found a large supply
                    train of the enemy at this place, and our advance cavalry captured a part of it,
                    with supplies and horses.</p>
                <p>I encamped about one mile south of Port Republic, and on the morning of the 5th,
                    at an early hour, advanced on the Staunton road. At 6 a. m. my advanced cavalry
                    met that of the enemy, and after a sharp skirmish drove them, with a loss of 75
                    men killed, wounded, and missing. At the village of Piedmont, seven miles
                    southwest of Port Republic, I found the enemy in force advantageously posted.
                    The battle opened with artillery at 9 a. m.,the enemy using several guns of long
                    range and heavy caliber. At 10 o'clock the First Brigade of Infantry, under Col.
                    Moor, advanced on our right and drove the enemy from his advanced position in a
                    wood behind his line of defenses constructed of fallen timber and fence rails.
                    Col. Thoburn, with the Second Brigade of Infantry, took position on elevated
                    ground on our left, supporting the batteries and ready for action where most
                    needed. At 11.30 the fine practice of our artillery had silenced the enemy's
                    batteries, and the cavalry, under Maj.-Gen. Stahel, was massed in rear of the
                    infantry on our right. At 1 o'clock the First Brigade attacked the enemy's line
                    in front, but failed to carry it, and fell back after a spirited contest. At
                    1.30 the enemy was observed to be massing his force on our right, opposite the
                    First Brigade, and orders were immediately sent to Col. Thoburn to move his
                    brigade across the open valley between, and attack the enemy's position in
                    flank. At 2 p. m. the enemy made a determined attack on the First Brigade, which
                    gallantly sustained itself, assisted by Von Kleiser's battery and a cross-fire
                    from Morton's and Carlin's batteries on our left. Meanwhile Thoburn's brigade,
                    having crossed the valley, fell upon the enemy's exposed flank with decisive
                    effect, crushing his whole line and driving a portion of his force over the
                    steep bank into the river, which covered his left. Simultaneously Col. Moor's
                    brigade rushed over the works in front, and a brigade of cavalry, under Col.
                    Wynkoop, charged upon his right flank and rear. The enemy fled in confusion,
                    leaving over 1,000 prisoners in our hands, including 60 officers. The killed and
                    wounded are estimated at 600 men. Brig. Gen. William E. Jones, commanding
                    forces, was killed on the field and his body fell into our hands. From papers
                    found upon his person it is ascertained that the enemy's force was between 6,000
                    and 7,000 men, and 16 guns, among them two 20-pounder Parrotts, and one
                    24-pounder howitzer. In addition to his loss upon the field, the enemy in his
                    precipitate retreat lost an equal number at least by straggling and desertion.
                    Gen. Vaughn, upon whom the command devolved, fell back upon Waynesborough with
                    the wreck of his army.</p>
                <p>On the next day, June 6, I occupied Staunton without opposition, capturing 400
                    sick and wounded, who were paroled, and large quantities of commissary and
                    ordnance stores, which were destroyed or distributed among the troops. All the
                    railroad bridges and depots, and public workshops and factories in the town and
                    vicinity, were also destroyed. A rebel force under Gen. McCausland and Col.
                    William L. Jackson, stationed at Buffalo Gap, to oppose the advance of Gen.
                    Crook, on hearing of our occupation of Staunton, fell back precipitately and
                    escaped southward. Gen. Crook, with his whole command in fine condition, joined
                    me to-day, having brushed away the enemy's corps of observation and destroyed
                    the Virginia Central Railroad west of this place.</p>
                <p>These results have been accomplished with a loss to this command of less than 500
                    men in killed and wounded. On the march and in action the troops have behaved
                    admirably. The combined force, now in fine spirits and condition, will move day
                    after to-morrow to the accomplishment of its mission.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, very respectfully, your most obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed> D. HUNTER,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
