<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770130"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770130">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Jacob Campbell.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel jacob campbell</title>
        <author>Campbell, Jacob</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770130</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499310</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Colonel Jacob Campbell.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of colonel jacob campbell</title>
            <author>Campbell, Jacob</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 129-131</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-02">1864-07-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770130T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>On June 9, 1864, the Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Infantry left Staunton for
                    Lexington to join the Union advance up the Shenandoah Valley. In this report,
                    Colonel Jacob Campbell recounts the events of the campaign.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 15. Report of Col. Jacob M. Campbell, Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania
                    Infantry,commanding Third Brigade.<lb/> HDQRS. 3d Brig., 2d INFTY. DIV., DEPT.
                    OF W. VA.,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. JAMES L. BOTSFORD,<lb/> Asst. Adjt. Gen., Second
                        Infty. Div., Dept. of West Va.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Piatt, W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I would most respectfully submit the following report of the part taken by the
                    Third Brigade in the recent operations of the division on the march from
                    Staunton to Lynchburg, and from Lynchburg to this place:</p>
                <p>On the 9th day of June I was ordered to the command of the brigade, and on the
                    following morning the command left Staunton, by way of Middlebrook and
                    Brownsburg, for Lexington, skirmishing with the enemy the greater part of the
                    way.</p>
                <p>We arrived in the immediate vicinity of Lexington on the 11th about noon, where
                    the enemy made a stand, but were soon driven from the town, which was
                    immediately occupied by our troops.</p>
                <p>We remained in camp at Lexington until the morning of the 14th, when we left that
                    place for Liberty, Bedford County, by way of Buchanan, and Peaks of Otter,
                    occasionally encountering the enemy's skirmishers.</p>
                <p>We arrived at Liberty at 9 a. m. on the 16th and immediately proceeded to destroy
                    the shops and tear up the track of the Virginia and East Tennessee Railroad as
                    far as the South Fork of Otter River, about eight miles east from Liberty.</p>
                <p>On the 17th we left the South Fork of Otter River and marched in the direction of
                    Lynchburg and arrived within four miles of that place at 5.30 p. m., where we
                    encountered the enemy in force. My brigade was soon ordered to the front and
                    formed in line of battle on the left of, and at right angle with, the turnpike.
                    After forming we advanced upon the enemy, driving them into their intrenchments,
                    distant about one mile and a half from where we first encountered their line.
                    Darkness having overtaken us, we ceased to press the enemy farther and merely
                    maintained the position we had gained. We were relieved about 9 p. m. by the
                    First Brigade, of the First Division, and fell back about 400 yards, where we
                    remained for the night.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 18th we were ordered to move to the right for the purpose
                    of flanking the enemy's position, but this being found impracticable we were
                    ordered to return to the front. Before we were able properly to form in line of
                    battle the division in our front, which was then engaged with the enemy, was
                    somewhat broken and retiring in some confusion, the enemy advancing against it.
                    In accordance with the general's instructions, we advanced as quickly as
                    possible for the purpose of checking the enemy before they should gain the crest
                    of the hill, which would enable them to get a clear view of our position. In
                    doing so we were for some time exposed to the enemy's batteries, which were well
                    served with grape and canister. We succeeded, however, in driving the enemy down
                    the hill and across a deep ravine, and from there to their intrenchments on the
                    elevated ground beyond, at the same time gaining a position for ourselves
                    comparatively sheltered from the enemy. My line having become somewhat broken by
                    passing through the thick underbrush and in crossing a deep ditch at the bottom
                    of the ravine, I halted my command. I reformed it and again advanced upon the
                    enemy, pressing close upon their works, but were met with such a storm of grape
                    and canister that we were compelled to fall back to the spot where I had
                    reformed my command.</p>
                <p>We remained in this position, keeping the enemy in their intrenchments, with
                    occasional firing between sharpshooters and skirmishers, until 8.30 p. m., when
                    we were ordered to withdraw, which was done in good order, and we took up our
                    line of march for Liberty, by was of New London, which latter place we passed
                    through at daybreak on the morning of the 19th. Continuing our march, we arrived
                    at Liberty at 6 p. m., were we encamped for the night.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 20th we left Liberty, taking the road to Salem, by way of
                    Buford's Gap and Coyner's Springs. At Buford's Gap we halted for a few hours,
                    during which time we had considerable skirmishing with the enemy. Leaving the
                    gap at 8 p. m., we arrived at Salem on the morning of the 21st. Here we had some
                    skirmishing with the enemy, but met with no serious resistance. After a few
                    hours' halt, we left Salem about 11 a. m. and arrived at Catawba Mountain about
                    4 p. m., where we remained until 9 p. m. Here we had some skirmishing with the
                    enemy, and marched to Craig's Creek and encamped for the night.</p>
                <p>On the 22d we resumed our march by way of New Castle, Red Sweet Springs, and
                    White Sulphur Springs, and passed through Lewisburg on the 25th and encamped for
                    the night at Meadow Bluff.</p>
                <p>On the 26th we left Meadow Bluff for Camp Piatt, where we arrived on the 29th,
                    having traveled a distance of 322 miles from the time of leaving Staunton on the
                    10th instant.</p>
                <p> A list of the casualties in my brigade accompanies this report, the aggregate of
                    which is: Killed, 29; wounded, 134; missing 27; total, 190, and is distributed
                    among the different organizations in the brigade as follows:<lb/> Command. K W M
                    T<lb/> 11th West Virginia Volunteer Infantry.... 6 20 6 32<lb/> 15th West
                    Virginia Volunteer Infantry.... 6 54 13 73<lb/> 54th Pennsylvania Volunteer
                    Infantry..... 11 37 7 55<lb/> Dismounted cavalry....................... 6 23 1
                    30<lb/> 29 134 27 190<lb/> K=Killed. W=Wounded. M=Missing. T=Total.</p>
                <p>The conduct of the officers and men before the enemy and during the long and
                    tiresome march was all that could be expected of brave and gallant men. Many of
                    the men are somewhat broken down and foot-sore, and some few have suffered for
                    the want of proper food, which could not be obtained in the country through
                    which we passed during the last few days of our march, but all are in excellent
                    spirits, and will be ready for action again in a short time.</p>
                <p>I have as yet received no official report from the battalion of the Third and
                    Fourth Regiments Pennsylvania Reserve Volunteer Corps, but am informed by Capt.
                    Sweet, commanding, that no casualties occurred in that command.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, captain, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. M. CAMPBELL,<lb/> Col., Cmdg. Third Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
