<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R13770132"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R13770132">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XLIX. Report of Major Enoch Yutzy.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xlix report of major enoch yutzy</title>
        <author>Yutzy, Enoch</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R13770132</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499311</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XLIX. Report of Major Enoch Yutzy.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xlix report of major enoch yutzy</title>
            <author>Yutzy, Enoch</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 37, Serial No. 70</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 131-133</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-07-02">1864-07-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R13770132T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June, 1864, the Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Infantry left Staunton to join the
                    Union advance on Lexington and Lynchburg. In this dispatch, Major Enoch D. Yutzy
                    reports on the role his regiment played in the campaign.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 16. Report of Maj. Enoch D. Yutzy, Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania
                    Infantry. HDQRS. FIFTY-FOURTH PENNSYLVANIA VOL. INFTRY.,
                    <name type="recipient">Col. J. M. CAMPBELL,<lb/> Cmdg. Third Brigade, Second
                        Division.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Piatt, W. Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the part taken by the
                    Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Volunteer Infantry in the late raid through Virginia
                    since joining your brigade at Staunton, Va., on the 9th ultimo, including the
                    engagements near Lynchburg, Va., on the 17th and 18th of June, 1864:</p>
                <p>The regiment was annexed to the Third Brigade, Second Infantry Division, on the
                    9th of June, 1864, by Special Orders, No. 112, headquarters Department of West
                    Virginia, and left Staunton, Va., on the 10th ultimo, at 4 o'clock in the
                    morning, in company with the rest of the brigade and division, and arrived at
                    Lexington about noon next day, a distance of thirty-six miles.</p>
                <p>Encamped until the morning of the 14th, when we marched to Buchanan, arriving at
                    6 p. m.; distance of twenty-four miles.</p>
                <p>Left Buchanan on the morning of the 15th; crossed the Blue Ridge, my regiment
                    leading the advance and skirmishing with the enemy, losing 1 man wounded.</p>
                <p>Passed through Liberty on the 16th, at 11 a. m., and encamped on Otter Creek,
                    eight miles from Liberty, until the morning of the 17th, 5 o'clock (marching
                    thirty miles on the 15th and 16th), when we marched within about three miles of
                    Lynchburg, where we were confronted by the enemy in force.</p>
                <p>BATTLE OF LYNCHBURG.</p>
                <p>Immediately upon the arrival of the regiment in front of the enemy, within three
                    miles of Lynchburg, and after a march of eleven miles without rest, I was
                    ordered to form the regiment on the left, of, and at right angle with, the
                    turnpike road leading to Lynchburg, the regiment occupying the extreme left of
                    the brigade, Company B, of the regiment, being deployed as skirmishers on our
                    left. We advanced in this order until we gained the crest of the hill, the first
                    line of the enemy's barricade, a distance of about half a mile. Here, by your
                    direction, I took a position with the regiment still farther to the left to
                    cover the left flank of the line, and again advanced down over the hill through
                    the woods, steadily driving the enemy before us, until we reached the foot of
                    the hill. Night overtaking us, the advance was discontinued, and the action
                    closed for the day, the regiment resting in line for about an hour, when our
                    brigade was relieved by a brigade of the First Infantry Division, and we took a
                    position, by your direction, about one-quarter of a mile to the rear of the
                    line, and rested upon our arms until daylight next morning, when we accompanied
                    the brigade in a reconnaissance of the enemy's extreme left, marching a distance
                    of about four miles. We returned at about 11 a. m. and formed in line near the
                    ground on which we rested the previous night, my regiment occupying the extreme
                    left, doubled by wing. Immediately upon the formation of the line I received
                    your order to move forward, and we advanced over the crest of the hill (some 300
                    yards to the left of our line of direction the evening before) and down through
                    an open field, the regiment being exposed to a heavy artillery fire of shell,
                    grape, and canister, for a distance of about 800 yards. At the foot of the hill
                    I found the enemy strongly posted in a deep ditch, concealed by thick weeds and
                    underbrush, lining both banks. Upon this discovery, we immediately charged the
                    enemy and drove him in confusion from his position. Having now gained a line
                    somewhat sheltered from the enemy's fire by the rising ground in our front, in
                    order to reform the line, which had become somewhat broken in consequence of
                    crossing a deep ditch running diagonally through the field, over which we had
                    charged, as well as to give the men a moment's rest before making the final
                    assault, I halted the regiment for about three minutes, after which I ordered
                    another charge upon the enemy, who had taken shelter behind a stone wall, rail
                    breast-works, and an old dwelling-house, stable, and ice-house, about 200 yards
                    in our front. Simultaneously with the order, both the officers and men gallantly
                    rushed forward with a shout, and drove the enemy from their shelter in utter
                    confusion. Here we received the hottest musketry fire of the day, and it was
                    here that most of our comrades fell. Both officers and men behaved with their
                    usual gallantry and bravery. No hesitating or faltering in the face of the
                    enemy's fire; all discharged their duty faithfully and cheerfully. I took 420
                    men into the engagement. Previous battles, sickness, hard marching, and exposure
                    had materially reduced the strength of the regiment. Capt. John Cole, Company B,
                    was the only officer severely wounded. The regiment lost 11 killed, 37 wounded
                    who were not sent to the hospital, among them 3 officers.</p>
                <p>The entire line having come to a halt, we held our position until we were ordered
                    to reform on the ground from which we had made the last charge, and rested there
                    unmolested, except by an occasional shot from the enemy's sharpshooters, until
                    about 9 p. m., when we were ordered to withdraw, and by 10 o'clock took up the
                    line of march with the entire column, and continued a long and fatiguing march
                    for ten days, passing through Liberty, Salem, Rocky Gap, New Castle, Sweet
                    Sulphur Springs, White Sulphur Springs, Meadow Bluff, Lewisburg, Hawk's Nest,
                    Loup Creek, and Gauley Bridge, arriving here in the afternoon of the 28th,
                    having marched a distance of 215 miles since leaving Lynchburg.</p>
                <p>Depending entirely upon the country over which we marched for supplies, a great
                    portion of our line of march being but sparsely settled and supplies scarce, and
                    what little they had, shipped to the mountains on hearing of our approach; in
                    consequence of which, to our suffering from hard, fatiguing marches, loss of
                    sleep, and a burning sun, was added a fair prospect of starvation. During the
                    last four or five days many of my best men dropped out of the ranks, completely
                    exhausted by hunger and fatigue; but supplies having been sent out to meet them,
                    the most of them have since come into camp. Notwithstanding the many hardships
                    endured and the terrible suffering of the men, there is a general expression of
                    satisfaction of the work that was performed during this important expedition.</p>
                <p>Since going into camp much sickness prevails among both officers and men, the
                    sanitary condition of the regiment being worse now than I ever knew it to be
                    since entering the service, more than one-quarter of the regiment being unfit
                    for duty.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>E. D. YUTZY,<lb/> Maj., Cmdg. Fifty-fourth Pennsylvania Vol. Infty.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
