<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1421271"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1421271">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Peyton, H. E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">38</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1421271</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499564</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Peyton, H. E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 42, Serial No. 88</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1270-1278</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-09-23">1864-09-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1421271T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>H. E. Peyton, Inspector General for the Army of Northern Virginia, reports to
                    Adjutant General Samuel Cooper in September, 1864, on the state of the army.
                    Peyton discusses the Army of Northern Virginia's condition in detail including
                    strength, health, morale, discipline, and supply situation. He mentions
                    information lost when General Jubal Early left Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    INSPECTOR-GEN.'S OFFICE,<lb/> ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. S. COOPER,<lb/> Adjutant and Inspector Gen.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-09-23">September 23, 1864.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to transmit the inclosed inspection reports for the month of
                    August, and in doing so would respectfully submit a statement of facts
                    explaining the delay as well as the incompleteness of the reports:</p>
                <p>After the commencement of active operations, Col. Murray, then chief inspector of
                    the army, wrote to the Department in Richmond that it was impracticable to make
                    inspections as prescribed by Gen. Orders, No. 42, Adjutant and Inspector Gen.'s
                    Office, during the constant movements of a campaign, and that he would
                    discontinue them unless otherwise directed. No answer being made to his letter
                    the silence was accepted as an acquiescence in his suggestion and no inspections
                    were made. On the 3d of August an order was addressed to Col. Murray, requiring
                    a resumption of the inspections and a transmittal of the reports as heretofore
                    required. Col. M. being absent sick, I issued the inclosed circular to the corps
                    inspectors in accordance with instructions contained in the order. Many causes
                    have operated to prevent a prompt and satisfactory execution of this order. From
                    Gen. Early's command the reports are necessarily meager, owing to the fact that
                    that corps has been constantly on the march or in line of battle. Col. Smead,
                    the inspector of that army, whose position and opportunities enable him to
                    present a general view of the condition of the corps, makes no report and
                    conveys no information of any sort. He neither indorses nor comments upon the
                    brigade and division reports. The reports for the last of the month have not
                    been forwarded. I have delayed the transmittal of my own report, hoping to
                    receive these. It will be seen that there is general complaint throughout this
                    command of the indifferent clothing of the troops, including shoes. There are no
                    indorsements of the quartermasters except in one or two cases, showing the cause
                    of this deficiency, nor does Col. Smead throw any light on the subject. His
                    attention has been called to this omission.</p>
                <p>It is a matter of congratulation that the health of this command is universally
                    good. There is an abundance of medicines and ordnance stores, secured in great
                    part from battle-fields. The inspectors have made no return of captured
                    property, as required by circular of instructions from Adjutant and Inspector
                    Gen.'s Office, Richmond. The discipline is represented as a general thing lax;
                    not more so, perhaps, than could be expected under the circumstances. Attention
                    is called to the remarks of Maj. Moore, inspector of Gornod's division, from
                    which it will appear that that command had performed "from the 13th of June to
                    the 20th of August 800 miles of route marching, independent of movements in the
                    presence of the enemy, and been engaged in seventeen battles and skirmishes,
                    some of which have lasted through two and three days." It will be seen that none
                    of the reports are made according to the instructions at the bottom of the third
                    page of the form. Desks containing the records having been left behind when Gen.
                    Early moved from Staunton, it was not practicable to obtain the data necessary
                    to fill up all the columns and thereby perfect the reports. Attention is called
                    to my indorsements on brigade reports of this corps.</p>
                <p>First Corps, Lieut.-Gen. Anderson (Maj. John W. Fairfax, assistant adjutant and
                    inspector general).</p>
                <p>No reports has been made by Maj. Fairfax. He and Maj. Latrobe accompanied Gen.
                    Anderson to the Valley with Kershaw's division. Pickett's and Field's divisions
                    report directly to these headquarters. Inclosed will please find reports of
                    inspectors of these divisions.</p>
                <p>Pickett's division (Maj. W. Harrison, inspector), is situated between the James
                    and Appomattox Rivers, and has suffered considerably from ague and fever, a
                    disease peculiar to that locality. Corse's brigade, resting on James River, has
                    suffered most. Attention is called to Maj. Harrison's report and remarks of
                    Surgeon Guild, medical director of the army. I made a general informal
                    inspection of the whole of this division and a more special inspection of
                    Hunton's brigade.</p>
                <p>I found the general condition of trenches, sinks, arms, accouterments, and
                    clothing of Gen. H.'s brigade good. This brigade deserves special mention. It
                    was in all respects most creditable. Gen. H. bivouacs in the trenches with his
                    men, and is active and vigilant in all that is promotive of the comfort and
                    efficiency of his command. Attention is called to report of brigade inspector
                    for the strength of the brigade and the number of officers absent, by what
                    authority, &amp;c. There is a large proportion of absent disabled officers
                    in this brigade. I would respectfully suggest that they be made to appear before
                    an examining board for discharge or retirement. The same thing should be
                    required of absent officers in all the brigades. Hundreds, if not thousands, of
                    meritorious young officers are denied all hopes of promotion, because wounded
                    officers long disabled, some for more than two years (see the accompanying
                    lists), still keep their names upon the rolls. It is an injury to the service
                    and a special wrong inflicted upon those brave men who have so long borne the
                    perils and responsibilities of command without the corresponding rank. The
                    prompt remedy of this evil will remove a feeling of discontent that now prevails
                    to a greater or less extent in every brigade of the army. Attention is called to
                    Maj. Harrison's remarks on the subject of increased desertion in this division.
                    It will be seen that the reports of this division, according to instructions,
                    page 3, are also incomplete. Hereafter the form shall be strictly complied with.</p>
                <p>Field's division (Maj. Masters, inspector): Not having been able to make a
                    personal inspection of this division, attention is called to report of Maj.
                    Masters. He reports health good; the sick and wounded to have had most excellent
                    attention. Clothing and shoes are reported needed, but are being rapidly
                    supplied; discipline is relaxed and the command in need of drilling and other
                    military instruction. Damages committed are said to have been duly assessed (I
                    fear that the facts now being investigated will prove Maj. Masters to have been
                    mistaken in this last assertion). Complaints have been made by different parties
                    against this division, the truthfulness of which will be determined and reported
                    in my next monthly report. The long absence of this division from the Army of
                    Northern Virginia prevents my speaking from personal knowledge of its general
                    condition.</p>
                <p>Third Corps, Lieut. Gen. A. P. Hill (Maj. R. J. Wingate, inspector).</p>
                <p>This corps is stationed in the trenches in front of Petersburg, composing the
                    right of our infantry line. During the month of August Maj. Wingate, assistant
                    inspector-general of the corps, was absent on sick leave; Capt. Adams, signal
                    officer on Gen. Hill's staff, acted in his place. Capt. A. has made no report,
                    but has sent the accompanying note, stating his inability to make any personal
                    inspections. I do not consider his reasons for not inspecting are sufficient;
                    with proper energy and diligence two if not three of the divisions could have
                    been inspected. Capt. A. is inexperienced in the duties of the office, and has
                    rendered me but little assistance. There has been great delay in transmitting
                    reports, all of which had to be returned on account of the errors they
                    contained. (They were returned to-day, 23d of September.) Maj. Wingate having
                    returned to duty, I hope there will be no occasion for complaint in future.</p>
                <p>Between the 9th and 13th of August I inspected in the trenches under arms Heth's
                    division. Gen. Heth had but recently occupied the line, which he found in bad
                    condition, having been badly policed, and full of individual bomb-proofs and
                    covered ways that rendered it difficult to keep in good order. I first inspected
                    Brig.-Gen. Davis' brigade, consisting of Twenty-sixth, Eleventh, Second, and
                    Forty-second Mississippi, Fifty-fifth North Carolina, and Confederate Battalion.
                    The brigade was commanded by Col. A. E. Reynolds, Gen. Davis having left a day
                    or two before on sick leave. I found the arms and accouterments in very bad
                    condition in all the regiments except the Second, Col. J. M. Stone, and
                    Eleventh, Maj. R. O. Reynolds. In the Second they were good; in the Eleventh
                    very good, clean inside and bright outside; the accouterments attached to the
                    guns, which were secured between pegs driven in the breast-works. The trenches
                    were clean, and the general appearance was neat and military. At other parts of
                    the line of the brigade, guns and bayonets were lying loosely about the trenches
                    and under the shelter-tents of the men, peelings of fruit and rinds of melons
                    were dropped promiscuously about the trenches, which, together with the
                    accumulated dirt, indicated a neglect in the most necessary feature of
                    cleanliness. The Twenty-sixth Mississippi, commanded by Capt. A. E. Earley, was
                    in the most discreditable condition. Company I, Lieut. Jackson, was the worst
                    company of the regiment. I called the attention of the officers to the number of
                    guns of sick men that had not been turned in to ordnance officers, as required
                    by the orders. There was much in the appearance of the command to reflect upon
                    the brigade inspector, Capt. Cameron, whom I regretted to find absent, as I
                    wished to call his attention to the irregularities which he allowed to go
                    unreported. If the could not correct them it was his duty to have reported them,
                    which he did not do.</p>
                <p>Cooke's brigade I found in excellent order, as it always is. I inspected this
                    brigade the day Gen. Cooke took command of it at Fredericksburg. I then was
                    compelled to make an adverse report. I have inspected it three times since, and
                    each time have found it equal to any in the army in all respects. Whether in
                    camp, in the trenches, or on the march, it is distinguished for its high
                    discipline and good conduct. I consider the high state of perfection which it
                    has reached attributable more to the energy and devotion of its commander than
                    any other cause. Other brigades have as good material, but few brigades have so
                    watchful and skillful a commander. The arms and accouterments were so generally
                    good that there is no occasion for fault finding with any. The inspection was
                    creditable in all respects as if it had been made in winter quarters. Notes
                    containing the strength of this brigade, the number of absent officers, and by
                    what authority absent, and other points of information, were made by me in
                    conjunction with Capt. Grinnell, the acting division inspector. Capt. G. was
                    wounded a few days after the inspection was made and the notes misplaced. Gen.
                    Cooke declines to send in a report of his brigade on the ground that he is not
                    allowed an inspector. For these reasons I cannot furnish the facts. I took a
                    memorandum of the inspection.</p>
                <p>Fry's brigade, commanded by Col. Mayo, is composed of Archer's and Field's old
                    brigades, with following regiments: First, Seventh, and Fourteenth Tennessee;
                    Thirteenth Alabama; Second Maryland Battalion; Twenty-second, Fortieth,
                    Forty-seventh, and Fifty-fifth Virginia Regiments. After the Pennsylvania
                    campaign, Field's old brigade, commanded for some time by Col. Brockenbrough,
                    and what was left of Archer's after his capture at Gettysburg, were consolidated
                    and placed under command of Gen. H. H. Walker, who was wounded at Spotsylvania
                    Court-House. Subsequently Gen. Fry took command by Col. Mayo. It presented, as
                    it had done at preceding inspections, but few evidences of discipline. In the
                    Fourteenth and Seventh Tennessee guns and accouterments in fair condition.
                    Thirteenth Alabama, Col. Aiken, was in discreditable order; guns very rusty.
                    Lieut. G. W. Callaway, Companies A and G, showed great neglect in the general
                    appearance of this command. Lieut. Lipscomb was specially neglectful of police.
                    In the Virginia regiments the guns for the most part were in serviceable order.
                    Fortieth Virginia, Capt. H. E. Coles, specially bad police. This brigade is now
                    commanded by Brig.-Gen. Archer, who will doubtless improve the discipline and
                    general condition of this command. The Tennesseeans have never been entirely
                    satisfied since the consolidation. Gen. Archer is almost idolized by them, and
                    will, no doubt, harmonize the antagonisms that may have heretofore existed.
                    Improvement is already apparent in this command since the date of my inspection,
                    13th of August (now 23d of September).</p>
                <p>MacRae's brigade, formerly commanded by Gen. Kirkland, consisting of
                    Forty-seventh North Carolina, Maj. W. C. Lankford; Forty-fourth, Maj. C. M.
                    Stedman; Twenty-sixth, Col. John R. Lane; Eleventh, in discipline, arms,
                    accouterments, and clothing; police was fair. Gen. MacRae had recently been
                    assigned to its command from Gen. Cook's brigade, and was devoting himself with
                    great energy to the comfort and efficiency of his command and the improvement
                    and strengthening of his line. Gen. MacRae is a strict disciplinarian, but has
                    secured in an eminent degree the confidence of his men, as was shown in his
                    successful charge at Reams's Station on 25th of August. Attention is called to
                    the report of brigade inspector for strength of this brigade, the number of
                    officers absent, and by what authority, &amp;c. I have considered it
                    unnecessary to attach a duplicate copy of these statistical facts to this
                    report, as the brigade inspector accompanied me and noted these facts at my
                    instance in his report which accompanies this.</p>
                <p>Heth's division hospital, Doctor Hubbard in charge, was inspected by me about the
                    5th of September, in company with Doctor Breckinridge, medical inspector of the
                    army, Doctor Powell, medical director of the corps, and Maj. Wingate, assistant
                    inspector-general. We found the hospital well located in a very beautiful grove
                    near Petersburg, with the ground sloping favorably for policing. With the
                    exception of being too much crowded, the situation was a good one. The police
                    was very bad. In fact, no attention seemed to be paid to cleaning up the grounds
                    immediately in and about the hospital, nor was proper attention bestowed upon
                    the sinks. The ground between the hospital and the sinks had been used for
                    uncleanly purposes by the patients, making it offensive to the sight as well as
                    the smell. In this important feature of cleanliness there was evident and
                    inexcusable neglect in the management of this hospital. I found the sickness of
                    this division was on the decrease and the diseases reported of a mild form.
                    There was and had been a sufficient supply of medicines, except in Davis'
                    brigade. Strength of division, 5,535; total number sick in hospital, 376;
                    disabled, 32. The attention of Surgeon Guild, medical director, and Gen. Heth,
                    and Gen. Lee, was called to the want of proper police in this hospital.</p>
                <p>Transportation of this division I did not inspect, being disappointed two or
                    three times by the weather and since by the presence of office and other duties.
                    The general appearance of the animals, as seen on the roads, at the depot,
                    &amp;c., is good. Their general condition on inspections heretofore has
                    compared well with the best in the army. My daily observation in riding through
                    the army confirms the report of Maj. R. H. Carter, chief inspector of
                    transportation, that the general condition of transportation of the army is
                    good; considering all the circumstances of the campaign, very good.</p>
                <p>RECAPITULATION.</p>
                <p>Two brigades of Heth's division, Cooke's and MacRae's, it will be seen are in
                    specially good order and commanded by two most excellent officers, who are
                    strict disciplinarians, but who have great influence over their men in camp and
                    on the field. Their spirits are specially good since the brilliant victory which
                    they, under Gen. Heth, achieved at Reams' on 25th of August. Archer's brigade,
                    which heretofore has suffered form relaxation of discipline form causes referred
                    to, will soon present a marked improvement under the commander of their choice.
                    Davis' brigade, which has been less distinguished for discipline than any
                    portion of the division, is giving evidence of improvement, as will be seen by
                    second inspection report, made on the 5th of September, and to which attention
                    is called in appendix to this report. This division has done hard and
                    distinguished service during the campaign, and has sustained very heavy losses.
                    Gen. Heth is active and energetic in the discharge of his duties, and is
                    devoting himself with zeal to the improved efficiency of his command.</p>
                <p>Mahone' s and Wilcox's divisions have not been inspected by me, except with the
                    view of observing their general police, which I have found to be fair. Attention
                    is respectfully called to the inspectors' reports of brigades in these divisions
                    and my indorsements thereon.</p>
                <p>Beauregard's command was inspected by me in company with one of his inspectors,
                    Maj. Bryan. Col. Roman, chief inspector, received a circular form the Adjutant
                    and Inspector-Gen.'s Office, containing instructions, which he thought required
                    him to send his reports direct to Richmond. He has not, therefore, transmitted
                    them through me, although he has, since the army reached Petersburg, been
                    reporting to and receiving orders from this office. Under this construction I do
                    not consider it incumbent upon me to make an official report of my inspection of
                    Hoke's and Johnson's division.</p>
                <p>Artillery: Attention respectfully called to reports of Capt. Dandridge, adjutant
                    and inspector general, as to the wants, condition, &amp;c., of artillery
                    Third and First Corps. Capt. D. reports large deficiencies in horses. Please see
                    indorsement of Col. Corley, quartermaster army, on the subject. It will be seen
                    that Huger's and Haskell's battalions, situated between James and Appomattox,
                    have suffered very much from sickness, principally ague and fever; clothing and
                    equipments represented good. The artillery horses have been grazed and fed some
                    miles in rear of the army. The horses of only one battery to each battalion are
                    kept with the guns. There has been scarcity of grass, and rations have been
                    reduced. In addition, the flies have been unprecedentedly annoying, rendering it
                    impossible for horses to fatten. Owing to these reasons, as well as in some
                    cases positive neglect, the artillery horses of the army are generally thin. No
                    reports have been forwarded from artillery of Early's command.</p>
                <p>Cavalry: No reports have come in from the cavalry, notwithstanding the circular
                    of 3d of August, issued from this office, requiring them to be made. Having
                    waited until this date, 23d of September, without hearing from them, I have
                    called upon the inspectors for an explanation of their silence. Since the
                    reorganization of the cavalry into a corps, which has recently occurred, Maj.
                    Venable, assistant adjutant and inspector general, has been assigned as chief
                    inspector of the corps. Maj. V. was formerly in that position under Gen. Stuart,
                    and rendered efficient service. He is zealous and energetic in the discharge of
                    this duties, and will no doubt give increased efficiency to the inspecting
                    department of the cavalry. Having been unable to make any personal inspections
                    of the cavalry, and receiving no reports for the month of August, I will defer
                    for my next report the views suggested by the present condition and necessities
                    of that arm of the service.</p>
                <p>GENERAL REMARKS.</p>
                <p>General orders and instructions from the department require me, as army
                    inspector, to call attention to the irregularities and deficiencies existing in
                    the army and the causes of the same. In compliance with these instructions, I
                    cannot close this report without expressing the conviction, that has
                    strengthened with my experience as inspector, that the source of almost every
                    evil existing in the army is due to the difficulty of having orders properly and
                    promptly executed. There is not that spirit of respect for and obedience to
                    general orders which should pervade a military organization of such size and
                    upon whose perfection of discipline such great issues of life and liberty
                    depend. In my opinion, officers of all grades and departments are more or less
                    to blame, but the brigade commander, more than any one else, is at fault and
                    possesses in a greater degree the power to control and correct the evils
                    resulting from this tendency to neglect of duty. Upon him rests the greatest
                    responsibility, for the brigade is really the unit organization of the army, and
                    reflects the character and qualifications of its commander. Indeed, the
                    brigadier makes the brigade. If he does his duty, the evidences are at once
                    apparent in the superior discipline and efficiency of his command. If he holds
                    his colonels to a strict accountability, the colonels will look to their
                    captains, the captains to their lieutenants, the commissioned to the
                    non-commissioned officers and thus then is that distinct division of
                    responsibility defined and contemplated by the regulations. The proof of this
                    view is in the fact that in the same division will be found one brigade with its
                    complement of bayonets and its guns always bright, whilst another just by, with
                    originally the same number, has no bayonets and its guns invariably in bad
                    order; one will not allow the burning of rails or other depredations of
                    property, whilst the adjoining brigadier of the same command says the evil
                    cannot be stopped; one holds his colonels responsible for Government property,
                    whilst the other says it is impossible to bring volunteers to such a high state
                    of discipline. The illustration might be extended to show that an army with good
                    brigadiers will have good discipline, and that without them the best troops
                    deteriorate. The greatest evil that flows from this laxity in the execution of
                    orders is straggling. It is the parent of almost every other irregularity that
                    affects the army, and contributes more than all others to injure its good name.
                    If the orders governing this subject were rigorously enforced by general
                    officers, thousands of muskets would be heard in every fight that are now never
                    fired, and the disgraceful depredations committed upon private property would be
                    unknown. General Orders, No. 110, Army Headquarters, 1862, requires the
                    inspection of arms and roll-call at the beginning and close of every march, and
                    that all absentees be reported. A more important order was never issued, yet it
                    is very generally neglected throughout the army. The order requiring general
                    officers to ride frequently along their columns, personally inspecting the order
                    of march, is also too generally neglected. They remain for the most part at the
                    head of their troops, rarely seeing to the straggling of their men. Attention is
                    called to circular issued from this office, of the 5th of September, requiring
                    inspectors to report hereafter to this office the manner in which different
                    marches have been conducted and the measures adopted by their respective
                    generals to correct the irregularities reported. If the inspectors fail to make
                    the report, they will be brought before a court-martial for trial for
                    disobedience of orders. The necessity for reform in the marching of troops
                    requires that stringent measures be adopted.</p>
                <p>I have had the honor to report a number of officers to the general commanding for
                    violating the orders requiring all property captured on battle-fields to be
                    turned over to the chiefs of the respective departments. Horses captured from
                    the enemy are in most cases appropriated by the officers of the command
                    capturing them. The chief quartermaster of the army is responsible for the
                    transportation of the army, and should, under instructions of the general
                    commanding, have the sole distribution of Government animals. Attention is
                    respectfully called to instructions to inspectors on this subject of the 28th of
                    July. Orders regulating the settlement of damages done private property are
                    frequently neglected. To insure a compliance hereafter and to ascertain the
                    guilty party when there is neglect, inspectors are required (see circular
                    September 5) to forward tri-monthly certificates with their reports, stating on
                    whose property their commands have encamped the ten days preceding, the
                    condition of the property when first occupied and at the time of breaking up
                    camp, and whether damages inflicted have been settled according to the
                    provisions of General Orders, No. 26. The inspectors of the army have not
                    contributed as much to the repression of the evils and irregularities referred
                    to above as the orders defining their duties contemplated. The chief reason for
                    this delinquency is that inspectors have been too generally considered and used
                    by their generals as members of their personal staff. They have not been
                    encouraged in the discharge of their legitimate and prescribed duties, but have
                    been in many cases ordered to do work of adjutants and aides-de-camp. The
                    functions of the two offices are directly conflicting; indeed, their duties are
                    in many important particulars incompatible. The duties of adjutant are at the
                    desk and by the side, or bearing the orders of this general; those of inspector
                    are supervisory in their nature, and keep him moving constantly along and
                    through his command, seeing to the general execution, and reporting all
                    violations of orders and regulations. He is thus taken from the presence of his
                    commander, when as adjutant he is required at his side. To correct this evil I
                    called the attention of inspectors, in circular from this office of the 6th of
                    July, to the fact that they did not belong to the personal staff, but would be
                    required to discharge the duties prescribed in orders from army headquarters of
                    January, 1863. Notwithstanding these orders generals still use inspectors as
                    adjutants-general. I would respectfully call the attention of the Department to
                    the embarrassments resulting from this course. By this system inspectors are
                    taken from the control of the chief inspector of the army and become subject to
                    the orders alone of their generals. It practically relieves them from the
                    functions as well as the responsibilities of their position. It furnishes an
                    excuse for the neglect of the duties for the faithful discharge of which they
                    were commissioned, and offers every assurance of protection against its
                    penalties. The tendency of such a policy is to impair the efficiency of the
                    department and the usefulness of its officers. I would suggest that
                    aides-de-camp be required to act in place of adjutants-general when the latter
                    are absent from wounds or other causes. This could be done without injury to the
                    service or interference with the officers of another department.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>All of which is respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>H. E. PEYTON,<lb/> Lieut.-Col., Assistant Adjutant and Inspector Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
