<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1421164"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1421164">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Pemberton, John C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1421164</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499562</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Pemberton, John C.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 42, Serial No. 88</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1164-1165</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-07">1864-08-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1421164T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Artillery Colonel John C. Pemberton writes Secretary of War James
                    Seddon regarding August, 1864, preparations for the defense of Richmond.
                    Pemberton mentions that only a limited number of mortars can be made available,
                    since the iron needed to make them can only be obtained from Staunton, VA.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARTILLERY DEFENSES
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. J. A. SEDDON,<lb/> Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-07">August 7, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>His Excellency the President is, as you are aware, very desirous that the most
                    effectual measures which our means will admit shall, with the least delay, be
                    employed in an effort to dislodge the enemy from his intrenched position on the
                    north side of James River, at Deep Bottom. The President is also naturally very
                    anxious that the navigation of James River by the enemy should be made as
                    difficult and as dangerous as possible. To effect these objects, I have
                    proposed, with the sanction of the President, Gen. R. E. Lee, and Lieut.-Gen.
                    Ewell, to locate mortar batteries, and if found practicable, to employ several
                    8-inch siege howitzers as auxiliaries, the trails to be sunk to give the
                    necessary elevation. Unfortunately there are within this department but two
                    10-inch mortars, and Col. Gorgas informs me that, for want of the proper iron,
                    which can only be obtained from Staunton, several weeks must elapse before even
                    a single additional mortar can be furnished. The President has been made
                    acquainted with these facts, and although the means at my disposal may prove
                    inadequate to the end proposed (i. e., dislodging the enemy by rendering his
                    pontoon bridge useless to him), he nevertheless desires the experiment to be
                    tried. From the character of the enemy's position, which is such as to enable
                    him to use his gun-boats with great effect in connection with his land
                    batteries, and in view of the strength of his fortifications, which can only be
                    approached over an open plain, I am satisfied that an attempt to take his works
                    by assault would result in failure, unless he can be so demoralized by alarming
                    his communications and depriving him of the hope of assistance by the bridge as
                    to render his resistance to an assault less determined than it is likely
                    otherwise to be.</p>
                <p>It is proposed to use the two mortars and auxiliary howitzers to enfilade the
                    bridge, while a cross-fire from Tilghman's Gate with rifled field-pieces shall
                    also be maintained. This appears to me to be the only practicable plan of
                    dislodging the enemy from the threatening position he has so long held. It may
                    prove a failure because of the insufficient number of our mortars to keep up a
                    continuous fire; with a battery of six instead of two of these pieces, I am
                    confident he could be compelled to withdraw by their fire alone. The difficulty
                    with the howitzers will be to occupy a position near enough to the bridge to
                    render their comparative short range effective, and this may prove to be
                    impracticable. It is important to open fire as soon as possible, and I had made
                    my arrangements to get everything under way to-day, but on applying for sling
                    carts to transport the mortars, I am officially informed that one of the only
                    two in this department has been ordered to Gen. Lee's army near Petersburg,
                    where it will probably be detained at least a week, and that the axle of the
                    other is broken and unserviceable. This will cause great delay, unless
                    arrangements can be made to give me the use of the cart before it is sent to
                    Gen. Lee's army.</p>
                <p>I have always regarded it as all important to a successful use of field artillery
                    against the enemy's gun-boats and transports that he should be compelled to
                    abandon his position at Deep Bottom. The reasons for this are too obvious to
                    need explanation, but whether he maintains this position or not, our operations
                    with field artillery can, I am confident, be made greatly more effective than
                    they have hitherto been, by assigning this service to a special organization,
                    whose exclusive charge it shall be to harass and damage the enemy on his river
                    communications. This will require that the utmost possible mobility be given to
                    the artillery that a sufficient number of guns adapted to the purpose be always
                    ready for this service without endangering other equally or more important
                    interests by withdrawing them too far from our defensive lines, and, if
                    possible, an adequate support of the most reliable cavalry we can get, whose
                    exclusive duty it shall be to aid and protect the operations of the artillery. I
                    propose, then, that three batteries of four pieces, each under the command of an
                    energetic and competent field officer, be at once thoroughly equipped as horse
                    artillery. This will require that, in addition to the usual six draft horses to
                    each piece and caisson, a sufficient number of horses be furnished to mount all
                    the cannoneers; this is indispensable to the efficient service of the batteries.
                    Two extra horses without harness will be necessary to each piece to meet
                    casual-ties, and two for horse holders to each detachment. A battery of four
                    pieces thus equipped will require fifty-six additional horses, and three
                    batteries will require 168. I propose to place these three batteries under the
                    immediate command of Maj. A. W. Stank, in every respect a most competent
                    officer. He now commands two batteries of four napoleons each, thoroughly
                    equipped in all respects except the additional horses and their accouterments.
                    But I also require a battery of four 10-pounder Parrotts; this I have not got.
                    Unless such a battery can be supplied already prepared for this service from
                    some other command, it will be necessary to equip one throughout. If the
                    requisite number of horses can be obtained, all the rest can be accomplished
                    without difficulty and with very little delay. I have already taken the
                    necessary measures for that end, if it should become necessary, and I have also
                    an organized and well-instructed company, the Louisiana Guard Artillery, under
                    Capt. C. A. Green, now dismounted, ready to take the battery at once. This
                    arrangement, however, will require sixty-two more horses to be supplied than
                    would be necessary if a battery already equipped should be assigned, making the
                    whole number of horses to be furnished 230 instead of 168.</p>
                <p>I will add that in my judgment the supporting cavalry force should not be less
                    than 1,500 men, commanded by an officer of experience and of approved ability in
                    that arm of service.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. C. PEMBERTON,<lb/> Lieut.-Col., Artillery.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
