<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1421162"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R1421162">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1421162</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 2001 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499561</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 42, Serial No. 88</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1161-1162</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-04">1864-08-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1421162T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee reports to Jefferson Davis on the military situation in August,
                    1864. He mentions that cavalry troops crossed the Potomac with orders to move
                    through Chambersburg and raid the Pennsylvania countryside.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JEFFERSON DAVIS:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-04">August 4, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Petersburg, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. PRESIDENT:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In my dispatch of this evening I informed you of the report that forty-six
                    transports (seventeen of which contained cavalry) loaded with troops had
                    descended James River up to last night. This information comes from Lieut.
                    Woodley, of the Signal Corps, stationed at Fort Boykin. Lieut. Welch, of Gary's
                    scouts, stationed on the north side of James River, reported up to last night
                    nine steamers descending the river with troops, four of them conveying horses.
                    Some of these, he stated, were wounded men and some prisoners. He does not,
                    therefore, entirely corroborate Lieut. Woodley's statement. I think it probable
                    that they have sent to Washington that portion of the Nineteenth Corps which was
                    lately operating on the north side of the James River, with some cavalry. A
                    scout reported that on Sunday, the 31st ultimo, a body of cavalry, estimated at
                    two brigades, moved toward James River in the direction of City Point, and this
                    may be the force of cavalry which has been shipped north. I fear that this force
                    is intended to operate against Gen. Early, and when added to that already
                    opposed to him, may be more than he can manage. Their object may be to drive him
                    out of the Valley and complete the devastation they commenced when they were
                    ejected from it. Gen. Grant's plan of operations here appears to be to mine and
                    bombard our lines, with a view of driving us from them, and as he is very
                    strongly fortified he can operate with fewer troops and enable him to detach a
                    sufficient force for the purpose indicated. The largest force which I can detach
                    would be Kershaw's and Field's divisions, and that would leave not a man out of
                    the trenches for any emergency which might arise. If it is their intention to
                    endeavor to overwhelm Early I think it better to detach these troops than to
                    hazard his destruction and that of our railroads, &amp;c., north of
                    Richmond, and therefore submit the question to the better judgment of Your
                    Excellency.</p>
                <p>On the 29th ultimo McCausland's and Johnson's brigades of cavalry crossed the
                    Potomac at Clear Spring, with orders to proceed to Chambersburg, thence west to
                    Cumberland and destroy the bridges over the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and the
                    machinery, &amp;c., at the coal-pots in the neighborhood, and after
                    gathering all the cattle in Allegheny and adjacent counties in Pennsylvania to
                    return through Hardy. To cover this movement two divisions of infantry moved to
                    Williamsport, and a third brigade of cavalry proceeded to Hagerstown, where they
                    burned a train of twenty or thirty cars, loaded with stores. On the 30th ultimo
                    Gen. Early returned to Martinsburg by the west road to avoid observation.
                    Learning that the Sixth and Nineteenth Corps were moving up from Washington, the
                    Sixth Corps having reached Halltown, he determined to fall back to Winchester,
                    where he could deliver battle to greater advantage. I do not think that the
                    whole of the Nineteenth Corps could have reached the Valley, but it seems that
                    Gen. Early's presence in the Valley tends to excite the apprehensions of the
                    Federal authorities and to cause a detachment of troops from Grant. If Morgan
                    could have struck the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad in the neighborhood of Cheat
                    River, and have proceeded into Washington County, Pa., as I had projected, he
                    would have created a valuable diversion in Early's favor.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, with great respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
