<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1421272"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1421272">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1421272</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499565</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap liv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Lee, Robert E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 42, Serial No. 89</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1272</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-14">1864-12-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1421272T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert E. Lee writes Jefferson Davis regarding the strategic situation in
                    December, 1864. Lee reports that he sent a division of men to Staunton to get on
                    trains for Richmond.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JEFFERSON DAVIS,<lb/> President of the
                        Confederate States:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-14">December 14, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">NEAR PETERSBURG,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. PRESIDENT:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>After sending my dispatch to you yesterday, knowing that the snow in the Valley
                    was six inches deep and the weather very cold, and presuming that active
                    operations would necessarily be suspended, I directed Rodes' division to march
                    for Staunton and requested the Quartermaster-Gen. to send cars to convey it to
                    Richmond. It is now on the road, and should reach Staunton to-morrow evening. If
                    the Quartermaster's Department is active, it should arrive in Richmond Friday
                    morning. A dispatch received from Gen. Early last night states that the scouts
                    just in report that the Nineteenth Corps of the enemy had left the Valley, and
                    that the Eighth was under marching orders. The latter might be preparing to move
                    nearer the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, for I do not think they will strip it of
                    all defense, or both corps may be coming to Gen. Grant. Col. Wither' scouts
                    report that a New York regiment of infantry and part of the Seventh Regiment of
                    cavalry had left the Kanawha for the Valley, but I supposed they might have been
                    intended to replace the Farrison at New Creek. I do not know what may be Gen.
                    Grant's next move; his last against the Weldon railroad and our right flank
                    failed. The expeditions from Plymouth and New Berne against Fort Branch, on the
                    Roanoke, and Kinston, N. C., have both retreated before the forces moved against
                    them back to their former positions, and every thing at this time is quiet in
                    the Departments of Virginia and North Carolina. If the reports of the prisoners
                    and the statements of Federal officers to the citizens of country are true, the
                    object of the last expedition was to make a permanent lodgment at Weldon, draw
                    supplies by the Roanoke and Seaboard Railroad, and thence operate against the
                    railroads in North Carolina. Gen. Grant may now be preparing to break through
                    our center, as the canal at Dutch Gap is reported nearly completed. As long as
                    he holds so large an army around Richmond I think it very hazardous to diminish
                    our force. We now can oppose about a division to one of his corps. I fear
                    Savannah is in great danger, and unless our operations there are bold and
                    energetic I am apprehensive of its fall. I hope, though, if all our troops are
                    united, Sherman may be refused. But there is no time to lose. If the Nineteenth
                    Corps does not come to Grant we might spare a division, but if the Nineteenth
                    and Eighth are both drawn to him we shall require more men than we have. I
                    ordered Gen. J. A. Walker, with the Virginia reserves, from Weldon to Kinston,
                    to oppose the movement against that place. He is now on his return to his
                    position on the Danville and South Side roads.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With a firm reliance in our merciful God that he will cause all things
                        to work together for our good, I remain, with great respect, your obedient
                        servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. E. LEE,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
