<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14391210"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14391210">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14391210</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499633</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 91</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 209-210</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-09-29">1864-09-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14391210T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>General Phil Sheridan writes General Grant in September, 1864, to report the
                    Union cavalry's destruction of supplies, arms, and buildings in Staunton. He
                    also remarks on the importance Staunton had as a Confederate base of supply.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut.-Gen. GRANT,<lb/> City Point:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-09-29">September 29, 1864--7.30 p. m.<lb/> (Received October 2.)</date>
                        <name type="place">HARRISONBURG,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>In my last dispatch I informed you that I pressed Early so closely through New
                    Market, at the same time sending cavalry around his flank, that he gave up the
                    Valley and took to the mountains, passing through Brown's Gap. I kept up the
                    pursuit to Port Republic, destroying 75 wagons and 4 caissons. I sent Gen.
                    Torbert, who overtook me at Harrisonburg, to Staunton with Wilson's division of
                    cavalry and one brigade of Merritt's. Torbert entered Staunton on the 26th, and
                    destroyed a large quantity of rebel Government property-harness, saddles,
                    small-arms, hard bread, flour, repair shops, &amp;c. He then proceeded to
                    Waynesborough, destroying the iron bridge over the South Branch of the
                    Shenandoah, seven miles of track, the depot buildings, Government tannery, and a
                    large amount of leather, flour, and stores, &amp;c., at that place. He found
                    the tunnel defended by infantry, and retired via Staunton, destroying,
                    accordingly to your original instructions to me. This morning I sent around
                    Merritt's and Custer's divisions, via Piedmont, to burn grain, &amp;c.,
                    pursuant to your instructions. My impression is that most of the troops which
                    Early had left passed through the mountains to Charlottesville. Kershaw's
                    division came to his assistance, and, I think, passed along the west base of the
                    mountain to Waynesborough. The advance of my infantry is at Mount Crawford,
                    eight miles south of Harrisonburg. I will go on and clean out the Valley. I am
                    getting twenty-five to forty prisoners daily, who come in from the mountains on
                    each side and deliver themselves up. From the most reliable accounts, Early's
                    army was completely broken up and is dispirited. It will be exceedingly
                    difficult for me to carry the infantry column over the mountains and strike at
                    the Central road. I cannot accumulate sufficient stores to do so, and think it
                    best to take some position near Front Royal, and operate with the cavalry and
                    infantry. I will, however, stay here for a few days. Kershaw had not reached
                    Richmond, but was somewhere in the vicinity of Gordonsville, when he received
                    orders to rejoin Early. The destruction of the grain and forage from here to
                    Staunton will be a terrible blow to them. All the grain, gorge, &amp;c., in
                    the vicinity of Staunton was retained for the use of Early's army; all in the
                    lower part of the Valley was shipped to Richmond for the use of Lee's army. The
                    country from here to Staunton was abundantly supplied with forage and grain,
                    &amp;c.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>P. H. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
