<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R143909732"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R143909732">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence. </title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Thayer, Amos M.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R143909732</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499609</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Thayer, Amos M.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 973</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-31">1864-08-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R143909732T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union signal Lieutenant Amos Thayer reports on the actions of his command during
                    August, 1864. He mentions reporting to General Darius Couch in Chambersburg, and
                    describes camping and equipping his men in the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    SIGNAL CAMP,
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. H. S. TAFFT, Chief Assistant, Signal Bureau:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-31">August 31, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Greencastle, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make you the following report of the operations of this
                    detachment during the month ending August 31, 1864:</p>
                <p>At the date of my last report the greater portion of my detachment were on duty
                    at Harper's Ferry, whilst myself and a small party were temporarily stationed at
                    Emmitsburg, Md. From this point we moved into the Cumberland Valley, by order of
                    Capt. F. E. Town, and opened stations at Greencastle, North Mountain, and
                    Williamsport. These stations remained in operation until August 5, when the
                    parties occupying the two last posts were compelled to abandon them on account
                    of the advance of the enemy to Hagerstown and Williamsport. After the retreat of
                    the enemy across the river I requested and obtained permission to return to my
                    command at Harper's Ferry. Immediately upon my return the whole detachment
                    belonging to this department were relieved from duty and ordered to report to
                    Maj.-Gen. Couch. I reported at headquarters Department of Susqehanna August 11,
                    and for some days thereafter remained in camp near Chambersburg, for the purpose
                    of equipping my men with horses and the necessary clothing. These arrangements
                    being completed, I moved the detachment to this place, and reopened our previous
                    stations. I have signal posts at present at this point, on North Mountain, and
                    near Williamsport, and it is my intention to open another at Fairview as soon as
                    possible. From these points it will be very easy to watch the fords of the upper
                    Potomac, from Falling Waters to Hancock, and to give timely notice of any
                    attempt to cross. I regret very much that the haziness of the atmosphere has
                    embarrassed our operations very much for the fall. During the past month Lieut.
                    Reymer has reported to me for instructions and duty. Good horses have been
                    furnished to the enlisted men, and I have the honor of reporting my detachment
                    as well equipped and instructed as any party with which I ever served.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, captain, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>AMOS M. THAYER,<lb/> First Lieut. and Chief Signal Officer.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
