<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14391589"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R14391589">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Mather, Thomas S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14391589</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499678</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Mather, Thomas S.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 91</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 589</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-11-09">1864-11-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14391589T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this November, 1864, dispatch, Union Colonel Thomas Mather reports from
                    Pottsville to John Schultze at Chambersburg on his efforts to preserve order in
                    the mining regions on election day. He mentions that the people fear disorder,
                    and discusses the successful efforts of his men in keeping the peace on election
                    day.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. LEHIGH DISTRICT,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. JOHN S. SCHULTZE,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen.,
                        Chambersburg, Pa.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-11-09">November 9, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Pottsville, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that, in obedience to orders from department
                    headquarters, under date of the 6th instant, I left Harrisonburg by the first
                    train after the receipt of the order and proceeded to this place, arriving here
                    on the afternoon of the 7th, and immediately assumed command of this district. I
                    found upon my arrival here considerable alarm existing among the people lest
                    there should be trouble on the following day; and ascertaining that there was
                    some danger of disturbance at Shenandoah and Mahanoy Cities and in Ashland
                    Township, I forwarded troops to those points, instructing the officers in
                    command of the detachments to be very careful not to allow the men to commit any
                    outrages, or by word or deed to provoke a collision with the inhabitants. I
                    further instructed them not to interfere in any way with the elections and to
                    keep their commands away from the polls, but to see that order was preserved and
                    the citizens protected in the enjoyment of their just rights. I also directed
                    them to promptly quell any outbreak that might arise; and if attacked to use
                    saber and bayonet until the rioters were dispersed and order restored. On the
                    morning of the 8th I ordered out a detachment of cavalry, with instructions to
                    march through Minersville, Upper and Lower Cass Townships, and return by the way
                    of Port Carbon. This detachment returned last night, having marched thirty-eight
                    miles. Learning, on the night of the 7th instant, by messengers from Fremont,
                    that a party of men, numbering 150, deserters and others, were assembled in the
                    woods near that town, with the intention, of driving out some of the inhabitants
                    the day following, I ordered out a small detachment of cavalry to look after
                    them, but upon the approach of the troops they fled, and no trouble ensued.
                    Everything was quiet throughout the day in all parts of the county, and men of
                    all parties unite in saying that it was the most quiet election day held for a
                    long time, though they are of the opinion that there would have been serious
                    trouble in some of the districts had not the troops been present. Many of the
                    citizens have taken occasion to express their appreciation of the services of
                    the major-general commanding in taking precautions to preserve order in the
                    county.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>THOMAS S. MATHER,<lb/> Col., Cmdg. Lehigh District.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
