<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14390507"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14390507">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Powell, William H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14390507</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499580</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Powell, William H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 506-507</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-10-27">1864-10-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14390507T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General William Powell reports on September and October, 1864, operations
                    in the Shenandoah Valley. He mentions Confederate evacuation of Staunton, and
                    the subsequent arrival on the field of Union commanders from that place.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 152.<lb/> Reports of Brig. Gen. William H. Powell, U. S. Army, commanding
                    Second Division (Army of West Virginia), of operations September 24-October 27
                    and November 12.<lb/> HDQRS. SECOND CAVALRY DIVISION,<lb/> DEPARTMENT OF WEST
                    VIRGINIA,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-10-27">October 27, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Front Royal, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In obedience to Special Orders, No. 37, headquarters Cavalry Corps, Middle
                    Military Division, I have the honor to submit the following report of the
                    operations of the Second Cavalry Division, Department of West Virginia, since
                    the 24th day of September, 1864, at which time, in obedience to Special Orders,
                    No. 41, current series, from headquarters Middle Military Division, I assumed
                    command of the division composed of two brigades and one four-gun battery
                    (Battery L, Fifth U. S. Artillery, commanded by Lieut. G. V. Weir), the First
                    Brigade consisting of Eighth Regt. Ohio Volunteer Cavalry, Fourteenth
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry, and Twenty-second Pennsylvania Cavalry, commanded by Col.
                    J. M. Schoonmaker, Fourteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry; and Second Brigade
                    consisting of the First, Second, and Third West Virginia Cavalry Regiments and
                    First New York (Lincoln) Cavalry Regiment, commanded by Col. H. Capehart, First
                    Regt. West Virginia Cavalry. The entire staff of Brevet Maj.-Gen. Averell (whom
                    I relieved), with the exception of surgeon-in-chief, Doctor Wynne, surgeon
                    Fourteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry, accompanied the general (and are still absent),
                    taking with the the papers, books,&amp;c. (all records of the division), by
                    which I have suffered much inconvenience in furnishing necessary reports. At the
                    time I assumed command of the division the strength present of it was 101
                    commissioned officers, and 2, 186 enlisted men; present and absent, 276
                    commissioned officers, and 6,950 enlisted men.</p>
                <p>In obedience to orders from headquarters Middle Military Division I moved the
                    command on the 24th day of September, 1864, at 11 a.m., from the Valley pike
                    across to the Middle road leading through Forest Hill and Broadway to
                    Harrisonburg. My advance met the enemy's pickets one mile north of Forest Hill,
                    drove them beyond Forest Hill a short distance, when the enemy formed line of
                    battle, which, not being very strong, was soon broken and driven in confusion.
                    From the citizens and prisoners taken at Forest Hill I learned that the force on
                    my front was composed of the commands-cavalry-of Gen.'s Imboden, Johnson, and
                    McCausland. I drove them rapidly before me to within four miles of Harrisonburg.
                    Camped the command three miles south of Broadway. The enemy's loss during the
                    day was 15 killed, 18 prisoners, 14 wagons, and a large amount of ammunition. My
                    loss was one man slightly wounded. September 25, broke camp at 8.30 a.m.
                    Movements detained awaiting return of squadron sent to Maj.-Gen. Sheridan's
                    headquarters the evening previous to open communication. Found no enemy on the
                    road to Harrisonburg, which point I reached at noon. After a half of two hours
                    to feed moved out to and beyond Mount Crawford, camping on the north side of the
                    river. September 26, in obedience to orders from headquarters Cavalry Corps,
                    Middle Military Division, moved at daylight across the Valley to Middle River;
                    encountered the enemy's pickets 100 strong; drove them across toward Brown's
                    Gap; thence moved in accordance with orders in the direction of Staunton. On
                    reaching Piedmont I was overtaken by a staff officer from Brig.-Gen. Merritt's
                    headquarters, Port Republic Va., with a request from Gen. M. for my immediate
                    return to Weyer's Cave near Brown's Gap, to co-operate with him in the capture
                    of Gen. Early's train. Having received information that the enemy had evacuated
                    Staunton I returned with my command at once, in compliance with Gen. M.'s
                    request; and on my arrival at Weyer's Cave, s three miles west of Brown's Gap,
                    ordered my command across the South River, prepared for and immediately attacked
                    the enemy's cavalry, the only force that could be seen at that time. This was
                    driven back with but little delay. The enemy at once pushed forward his infantry
                    and opened his artillery vigorously upon my advance, which, together with the
                    dense forest and underbrush, precluded the possibility of a farther advance of
                    my main line, which was then ordered to fall back to the west side of the river,
                    leaving my skirmish line confronting the enemy's during the night.</p>
                <p>September 27, at the request of Gen. Merritt I again threw my command across the
                    South River, except the Second Virginia Cavalry, which was ordered into position
                    on the front of my camp, and two squadrons left in camp to guard train,
                    &amp;c. At the moment I was about to order the advance of my line Fitzhugh
                    Lee's cavalry, with one brigade of infantry and one battery, made an attack on
                    the front of my camp, where the Second Virginia Cavalry was formed. The first
                    intimation I had of the whereabouts of Fitzhugh Lee's command was the opening of
                    his artillery, he having crossed the South River about two miles above my camp
                    at the same time that my command crossed at Weyer's Cave to attack. I changed
                    front immediately, ordered train to the rear, changed position of my battery,
                    and opened vigorously on the enemy, who, in his superiority of strength, was
                    driving the Second Virginia Cavalry. His line was soon checked and held until my
                    main body had recrossed the South River and formed, when my line advanced and
                    charged the enemy, driving him back rapidly, thereby relieving Brig.-Gen. Custer
                    (with a small escort), who was on his way from Staunton to take command of my
                    division. In the meantime a heavy column of infantry, cavalry, and artillery
                    moved out from Brown's Gap, and was preparing to attack my left flank and cut
                    off my retreat, which, however, I prevented by falling back slowly in the
                    direction of Port Republic, keeping my command well in hand for any emergency
                    being followed up closely by Fitzhugh Lee's command and the main of the enemy,
                    who crossed the river at the ford near Weyer's Cave.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
