<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1439031"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1439031">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1439031</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499575</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 30-31</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-10-07">1864-10-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1439031T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>The Shenandoah Valley served as an important source of Confederate food and
                    supply during the war. In late summer, 1864, General Grant ordered General
                    Sheridan to invade the Valley and destroy all crops and supplies that could be
                    used by Confederate armies. In this September dispatch, Sheridan reports on his
                    progress. He discusses the destruction of wheat and the capture of livestock
                    throughout the Valley, and asserts that between Staunton and Winchester Union
                    forces left little food for "man or beast." Sheridan also discusses the low
                    morale of Valley citizens.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut.-Gen. GRANT.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-10-07">October 7, 1864--9 p. m.<lb/> (Received 9th.)</date>
                        <name type="place">WOODSTOCK,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report my command at this point to-night. I commenced moving
                    back from Port Republic, Mount Crawford, Bridgewater, and Harrisonburg yesterday
                    morning. The grain and forage in advance of these points up to Staunton had
                    previously been destroyed. In moving back to this point the whole country from
                    the Blue Ridge to the North Mountains has been made untenable for a rebel army.
                    I have destroyed over 2,000 barns filled with wheat, hay, and farming
                    implements; over seventy mills filled with flour and wheat; have driven in front
                    of the army over 4,000 head of stock, and have killed and issued to the troops
                    not less than 3,000 sheep. This destruction embraces the Luray Valley and Little
                    Forest Valley, as well as the main valley. A large number of horses have been
                    obtained, a proper estimate of which I cannot now make. Lieut. John R. Meigh, my
                    engineer officer, was murdered beyond Harrisonburg, near Dayton. For this
                    atrocious act all the houses within an area of five miles were burned. Since I
                    came into the Valley, from Harper's Ferry up to Harrisonburg, every train, every
                    small party, and every straggler has been bushwhacked by people, many of whom
                    have protection papers from commanders who have been hitherto in this valley.
                    From the vicinity of Harrisonburg over 400 wagon-loads of refugees have been
                    sent back to Martinsburg; most of these people were Dunkers and had been
                    conscripted. The people here are getting sick of the war; heretofore they have
                    had no reason to complain, because they have been living in great abundance. I
                    have not been followed by the enemy up to this point, with the exception of a
                    small force of rebel cavalry that showed themselves some distance behind my rear
                    guard to-day. A party of 100 of the Eighth Shenandoah, near Mount Jackson, was
                    attacked by McNeill, with seventeen men; report they were asleep, and the whole
                    party dispersed or captured. I think that they will all turn up; I learn that
                    fifty-six of them have reached Winchester. McNeill was mortally wounded and fell
                    into our hands. This was fortunate, as he was the most daring and dangerous of
                    all the bushwhackers in this section of the country. I would have preferred
                    sending troops to you by the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad; it would have been the
                    quickest and most concealed way of sending them. The keeping open of the road to
                    Front Royal will require large guards to protect it against a very small-number
                    of partisan troops. It also obliges me to have a pontoon train, if it is to be
                    kept open, to bridge the Shenandoah and keep up communication with Winchester.
                    However, in a day or two I can tell better. I sent a party of cavalry through
                    Thornton's Gap, and directed the balance of the division of cavalry which I have
                    left in the Valley to take position at Millwood, occupying Chester Gap and Front
                    Royal. Thornton's Gap I have given up, as of no value. With this disposition of
                    forces, I will move infantry round the mountains, via Strasburg, as soon as
                    possible. To-morrow I will continue the destruction of wheat, forage,
                    &amp;c., down to Fisher's Hill. When this is completed the Valley, form
                    Winchester up to Staunton, ninety-two miles, will have but little in it for man
                    or beast. In previous dispatches I have used "lower Valley" when I should have
                    said "upper Valley," or, in other woods, in my last dispatch I intended to say
                    that the grain and forage from Staunton up to Lextington had been sent to
                    Richmond, and that the grain and forage from Staunton to Strasburg had been left
                    for the wintering of Early's army. Yesterday Col. Powell captured a guerrilla
                    camp on the mountains, with ten wagons and teams.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>P. H. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
