<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14390491"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14390491">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Lowell, Charles</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14390491</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499579</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Lowell, Charles</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 490-491</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-10-04">1864-10-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14390491T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union cavalry colonel Charles Lowell Jr. reports on September, 1864, actions in
                    the Valley, including an advance on Staunton that resulted in the capture of
                    prisoners, cattle, and stores.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 149.<lb/> Report of Col. Charles R. Lowell, jr., Second Massachusetts
                    Cavalry, commanding Reserve Brigade, of operations September 8-October 4.<lb/>
                    Report of operations of the Cavalry Reserve Brigade from September 8, 1864, to
                    October 4, 1864:
                    <name type="recipient">Capt. A. E. DANA,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen., First
                        Cavalry Division.</name>
                </head>
                
                <p>September 8, 1864, the Reserve Brigade was reorganized under Special Orders, No.
                    103, September 8, 1864, headquarters First Cavalry Division. The First New York
                    Dragoons were replaced by the Second Massachusetts Cavalry, and the Sixth
                    Pennsylvania Cavalry was ordered to Pleasant Valley for muster-out. Col. Lowell,
                    Second Massachusetts Cavalry, assumed command. September 8-12, the brigade lay
                    in camp near Summit Point, picketing on the left of the cavalry line and in
                    front of the Sixth Corps. September 13, made demonstration at Locke's Ford, on
                    the Opequon, in conjunction with First Brigade; took one lieutenant and ten
                    privates of Breckinridge's corps; returned to former camp at night-fall.
                    September 14-18, picketing as before. September 19, marched at 2 a.m.; reached
                    the Opequon at Seivers' Ford before daybreak. The enemy's picket-line was driven
                    in by Second U. S. Cavalry and Second Massachusetts Cavalry, about forty
                    prisoners being taken, and the opposite bank of the creek occupied in a line of
                    about three miles, the right connecting with the First Brigade. A very gallant
                    charge was made by Second U. S. Cavalry on one of Breckinridge's batteries, but
                    was repulsed, the infantry supports being well placed behind rails breast high,
                    a simultaneous charge by the First Brigade being also repulsed. Soon after noon
                    the whole line was advanced to the Martinsburg pike; the brigade was necessarily
                    much scattered. Two squadrons of the Second Massachusetts Cavalry joined the
                    charge of the Second Brigade on the enemy's infantry; the rest of that regiment
                    got mixed up with the skirmish line of Averell's division. The First, Second,
                    and Fifth U. S. Cavalry advanced toward Winchester, on the left of the pike;
                    charged a battery supported by infantry and cavalry; captured two guns, with
                    their caissons and most of the horses and drivers. What part of these regiments
                    could be rallied assisted in the subsequent charge of the First Brigade upon a
                    brigade of the enemy's infantry. After dark the brigade was moved through
                    Winchester and camped two miles out on the Valley pike. September 20, marched to
                    Strasburg and camped on the road to Capon Springs. September 21, marched to
                    Front Royal and camped on the Shenandoah. September 22, marched to Millford in
                    support of the Third Division; relieved one of its brigades on the right of the
                    line, but no attack on the enemy's position was ordered; fell back to McCoy's
                    Ford and camped. Capt. Emmons, assistant adjutant-general, wounded. September
                    23, marched to near Cedarville, dispersing en route a detachment of Mosby, under
                    Capt. Mountjoy, killing thirteen. From Cedarville returned by forced march to
                    Millford, finding that position just evacuated by the enemy. September 24,
                    marched up valley to Luray, supporting First Brigade in a rapid and brilliant
                    affair with one of Wickham's brigades, two squadrons of the Second Massachusetts
                    Cavalry charging and capturing battle-flag of Sixth Virginia Cavalry and twenty
                    prisoners; camped west of Shenandoah. September 25, crossed ridge to New Market;
                    marched in the afternoon to Harrisonburg camped. September 26, the brigade was
                    temporarily detached, acting with Third Division under order of chief of
                    cavalry; marched in the advance to Staunton, capturing prisoners, cattle, and
                    stores; camped east of the town. September 27, destroying; at 4 p.m. marched to
                    Waynesborough. September 28, the brigade on picket at Rock fish Gap and toward
                    New Hope. At 5 p.m. were attacked at both points by cavalry, artillery, and
                    infantry, and fell back to position above Waynesborough. After dark returned
                    with Third Division through Staunton and by forced march to Spring Hill, the
                    brigade having both the advance and rear guards. September 29, moved to
                    Bridgewater and anon to Mount Crawford, camping on the left of the infantry and
                    picketing to Cross Keys and Rockland Mills. September 30, rejoined the brigade,
                    camping and picketing as before. October 1-3, encamped north of Mount Crawford,
                    picketing upon the pike. October 3, made a reconnaissance in afternoon upon
                    pike. October 4, in camp; picketing as before.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>C. R. LOWELL, JR.,<lb/> Col. Second Massachusetts Cavalry, Cmdg.
                        Brigade.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
