<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14390598"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14390598">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Bouldin, Wood Jr.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14390598</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499586</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Bouldin, Wood Jr.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 597-598</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-09-29">1864-09-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14390598T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Assistant Inspector General Wood Bouldin Jr. presents an 1864
                    inspection report for Patton's cavalry brigade. In the report, Bouldin details
                    actions of the brigade, and mentions that most of its official records fell into
                    the hands of the Union army during the first occupation of Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 180.<lb/> Abstract from Inspection Report of Patton's brigade, for September
                    29.
                </head>
                
                <p>This brigade, under the command of Brig. Gen. John Echols, entered upon the
                    campaign of 1864 with 2,150 men and a full complement of officers on May 6. The
                    brigade was then well armed, equipped, and provided with a full supply of
                    clothing, and in a thorough state of discipline and efficiency. The commanding
                    officers of the battalions and regiments composing the command were able and
                    experienced officers--graduates of military schools. Two of them, viz, Col. G.
                    S. Patton (Twenty-second Virginia Regiment), Lieut. Col. G. M. Edgar, were
                    graduates of the Virginia Military Institute, and the third, Lieut. Col.
                    Clarence Derrick (Twenty-third Virginia Battalion), was from West Point. The
                    company officers generally were intelligent men, well acquainted with drill,
                    guard, and picket duty, and all requirements necessary to an efficient soldier.
                    The military bearing and appearance of the brigade was soldierly and imposing.</p>
                <p>In this thorough state of organization and discipline the brigade opened its
                    campaigning with the battle of New Market, on May 13, under Maj.-Gen.
                    Breckinridge. From that time the Valley District has been the scene of its
                    military operations to the present, with the exception of a short campaign with
                    the Army of Northern Virginia around Richmond, in which it bore a conspicuous
                    part in the bloody battle of Cold Harbor and in several other engagements of
                    less importance.</p>
                <p>During this campaign the brigade sustained heavy loss in killed and captured,
                    both officers and men. Among the wounded was the gallant officer, Capt. John K.
                    Thompson, Company A, Twenty-second Virginia Regiment, who here received his
                    third wound; he is now again with his command.</p>
                <p>The morning report exhibits total for duty of 266 and an aggregate of 275. This
                    great and almost unprecedented reduction in five months is due exclusively to
                    the casualties of war. In the hard-fought battle of Winchester, on the 19th, the
                    brigade organization was almost broken up. Col. George S. Patton, commanding the
                    brigade, an officer of highest gallantry and standing and a gentleman
                    irreproachable in character, was left in the hands of the enemy mortally
                    wounded. Lieut. Col. C. Derrick, the commanding officer of the Twenty-third
                    Virginia Battalion, and Lieut. Col. G. M. Edgar, of the Twenty-sixth Virginia
                    Battalion, were captured while gallantly attempting to rally their commands,
                    thus leaving the brigade without an officers, the most gallant and efficient,
                    either met their deaths on the battle-field or fell captive into the hands of
                    the enemy. The discipline and general efficiency of the brigade is much impaired
                    by the loss of the brigade and battalion commanders. The officers now with the
                    command are, with a few exceptions, very efficient and anxious to contribute all
                    that is in their power for the good of the brigade. They have not, however,
                    commanded heretofore an organization larger than a battalion.</p>
                <p>The adjutant's department has heretofore been conducted with great system and
                    care, and complete records of orders and files of papers were preserved prior to
                    the commencement of the present campaign. All of these papers were captured by
                    the enemy on the first occupation of Staunton, and during this campaign the
                    supply of stationery has been so limited that it has been a matter of
                    impossibility to pay that attention to this department that military usage
                    requires.</p>
                <p>This brigade is charged at almost every camp for burning rails. No axes are
                    furnished. It is respectfully asked that the attention of commanding general be
                    called to the fact and a necessary number of axes supplied.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed>WOOD BOULDIN, Jr.,<lb/> Asst. Inspector-Gen., Patton's Brigade,
                        Wharton's Division.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
