<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14390610"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14390610">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Moore, Edwin L.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14390610</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499588</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Moore, Edwin L.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 43, Serial No. 90</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 609-610</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-21">1864-08-21</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14390610T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This abstract of an 1864 Confederate inspection report for Gordon's Division
                    mentions that when the division left Staunton in June, much of its baggage was
                    discarded for ease of movement.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 185. Abstract from Inspection Report of Gordon's division, Early's corps, for
                    August 21.
                </head>
                
                <p>There has been but one regular inspection of troops in this division since it
                    left Richmond on the 13th of June last. It will sufficiently account for this to
                    say that since this date to the present time it has performed 800 miles of route
                    marching, independent of movements in the presence of the enemy; that it has
                    been engaged in seventeen battles and skirmishes, some of which have lasted
                    through two and three days, an in which it has captured 500 prisoners, and that
                    it has been almost constantly in the presence of the enemy, either in the
                    advance or in retreat. Under such circumstances regular inspections have been
                    impossible, and inspectors have been compelled to make their observations whilst
                    moving along the column on the march. On leaving Staunton in the latter part of
                    June the transportation of Lieut.-Gen. Early's command was reduced so as to
                    allow neither company nor field officers an ounce of baggage, except such as
                    they could carry themselves or on their horses; hence records have been left
                    behind and reports are irregular and incomplete. For the same reasons officers
                    of the quartermaster's and commissary departments have been compelled to leave
                    the most of their papers in rear and carry only such as were indispensable.</p>
                <p>The discipline in this command is lax. It will be remembered that York's brigade
                    is composed of the discordant fragments of Hay's and Stafford's brigades, and
                    that Terry's is made up of the remnants of the Stonewall, Jones', and Steuart's
                    brigades, formerly of Johnson's division, comprising the remains of fourteen
                    regiments. Both officers and men bitterly object to their consolidation into one
                    brigade. Strange officers command strange troops, and the difficulties on fusing
                    this incongruous mass are enhanced by casualty so may and such valuable officers
                    as to interfere seriously with its good management. I am pleasant to be able to
                    add that the discipline of the command is improving, and that in spite of all
                    defects, the division has fought with conspicuous gallantry and constant
                    success. The clothing of the troops, though poor, is better than could be
                    expected in so active a campaign, and under the difficulties of transporting
                    supplies so great a distance. Ordnance stores have been supplied to the full
                    extent of need from battle-fields, and it has been a matter of regret that want
                    of transportation has prevented our saving more ordnance supplies from the same
                    source. Our animals have been worked hard and very poorly supplied with grain;
                    grazing and hay have, however, been abundant, and they are in excellent
                    condition. The troops have been well supplied whit rations of flour and beef, to
                    which the country has added milk, butter, and vegetables; are consequently in
                    good health.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>EDWIN L. MOORE,<lb/> Maj. and Assistant Inspector-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
