<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14695528"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14695528">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Thompson, John L.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14695528</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499755</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Thompson, John L.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 528-529</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-09">1865-03-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14695528T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Cavalry Colonel John Thompson reports on a March, 1865, expedition to bring
                    Confederate prisoners from Waynesborough to Winchester. Thompson passed through
                    Staunton with the troops, ordering the town's citizens to provide food for the
                    prisoners. When they only could scrape together a "poor pittance" Thompson
                    reports taking food from the town asylum for the men's subsistence. Thompson
                    also discusses military actions in the Valley and the Staunton area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 2.<lb/> Report of Col. John L. Thompson, First New Hampshire Cavalry, of
                    operations March 3-8.<lb/> HDQRS. DETACHMENT OF CAVALRY,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. WILLIAM RUSSELL, Jr.,<lb/> Asst. Adjt. Gen., Cavalry
                        Corps, Middle Military Division.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-09">March 9, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the conducting a convoy of
                    prisoners from Waynesborough to our lines at this place:</p>
                <p>Some 1,300 prisoners, including 56 officers, were turned over to me at
                    Waynesborough on the 3d instant, with instructions to conduct them to
                    Winchester. I was furnished with an escort, consisting of the dismounted men and
                    those with poor horses, from all the cavalry, about 600 men, together with seven
                    small organizations, numbering about 600 men in the ranks.</p>
                <p>I destroyed at Waynesborough 4 guns and caissons and 6 ambulances, leaving the
                    sick and wounded in the houses, the horses and mules being too weak to draw
                    them. I took I gun, with a train of 14 horses and 2 mules. I was provided with
                    no forage for the horses nor rations for the escort or prisoners, except three
                    day's rations of coffee, sugar, and salt.</p>
                <p>I encamped at Fisherville on the night of the 3d, and before daylight sent the
                    Fourth New York Cavalry, Maj. Schwartz commanding, to secure the two bridges
                    between Staunton and Harrisonburg, as the streams were so swollen that it was
                    impossible to ford them. They arrived only in time to save them from burning.</p>
                <p>Maj. Schwartz was directed to inform the citizens of Staunton that a large number
                    of prisoners would pass through the town, and that they must supply them with
                    food. On reaching Staunton I found a few females bringing out a poor pittance in
                    small baskets. I refused to allow them to approach the prisoners, and told the
                    citizens that they could have a half hour to provide food or I should take it
                    from the insane asylum. They brought none, and I took flour and bacon from the
                    asylum, upon which the prisoners subsisted until they arrived at Winchester. I
                    learned at Staunton that Gen. Rosser was collecting his command, which had all
                    been furloughed, for the purpose of releasing the prisoners. He had then only
                    fifty men, with whom he skirmished with the rear guard and prevented foraging
                    except with large parties.</p>
                <p>At Harrisonburg McNeill's company joined him, together with about 100 more of his
                    regular troops. He had sent dispatches in front of us to all parts of the
                    country, directing the citizens and soldiers to rendezvous at Mount Jackson to
                    prevent our crossing the North Fork of the Shenandoah, stating that he would
                    follow with his forces, and certainly capture us. I arrived at Mount Jackson at
                    noon on the 6th, and found the river impassable, even for horsemen, except at
                    the ford near the pike. A force of 200 men had collected, and held all the
                    fords. I spent the afternoon in trying to build a bridge by felling trees, but
                    was unsuccessful. The river was falling rapidly, however, and would be fordable
                    the next morning. At daylight I directed Maj. Brown, commanding Twenty-second
                    New York, with his own regiment and the First Rhode Island, to force the ford
                    above the pike, and drive the enemy from the main ford. This was executed very
                    handsomely; in ten minutes the enemy was scattered in the mountains, and we had
                    taken several prisoners. At this time the enemy attacked our rear,which had
                    taken a position on Rude's Hill, but was repulsed. The dismounted men and
                    prisoners forded the stream in groups of fifty or sixty, holding each other by
                    the arm. It was impossible for a single footman to ford, the water being breast
                    high, with a rapid current. When the fording was nearly completed Gen. Rosser,
                    with about 300 men, made a vigorous assault upon the troops guarding our rear,
                    and was again repulsed, with a loss to him of 10 killed, several wounded, and 25
                    prisoners. The enemy made no other attack, though I was informed by the citizens
                    that Mosby's men were to join Gen. Rosser, and they would attack us in our camp
                    that night. We marched, however, across Cedar Creek, and encamped in the
                    earth-works at that place, reaching our lines at Winchester at noon on the 8th.
                    I think Gen. Rosser gave up the pursuit at Woodstock. During the night at Mount
                    Jackson the gun we had brought was spiked and the carriage destroyed, as I was
                    fearful that it could not be drawn over the ford, and it might fall into the
                    hands of the enemy. I had no ammunition for it, the cartridges having been
                    taken, by order of Gen. Merritt, to destroy the bridge at Waynesborough.</p>
                <p>Lieut.-Col. Nichols, Ninth New York Cavalry, who was detailed by Gen. Sheridan to
                    take command of the troops belonging to the First Division, rendered very
                    efficient services. Lieut.-Col. Boice, Fifth New York Cavalry, whom I put in
                    charge of those from the Third Division, deserves high commendation. He covered
                    the rear during the entire march. His repulse of the enemy in the two assaults
                    at Rude's Hill was brilliant. The prisoners could not withhold their
                    commendation, but shouted with our own men.</p>
                <p>Maj. Brown, Twenty-second New york, also merits praise for the manner in which he
                    forced the ford, and cleared the enemy from our front.</p>
                <p>The troops were all severely tried with labor and hunger, and behaved perfectly.</p>
                <p>Our loss was 1 officer (Capt. Wyatt, First New Hampshire) and 5 men wounded, and
                    2 captured. The number of prisoners was increased by 4 officers and 30 men.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. L. THOMPSON,<lb/> Col. First New Hampshire Cavalry, Cmdg. Detachment.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
