<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1461089"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1461089">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Curtis, Newton M.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1461089</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499731</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Curtis, Newton M.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 97</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1088-1089</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-05-04">1865-05-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1461089T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Newton M. Curtis orders Colonel Stratton to march with his command
                    to Staunton in May, 1865, to accept the surrender of Confederate General Thomas
                    Rosser's command. Curtis instructs Stratton on procedure for turning surrendered
                    arms and stores over to the army. He instructs that all commissary stores be
                    distributed to needy Valley citizens, and that all private citizens be well
                    treated.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF VIRGINIA,<lb/> ARMY OF THE JAMES
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut.-Col. STRATTON,<lb/> Cmdg. Eleventh Pennsylvania
                        Cavalry:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-05-04">May 4, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The commanding general directs that you proceed to Staunton, Va., to receive the
                    surrender of Gen. Rosser's command. By agreement with the authorities here he is
                    to have his command collected and necessary steps taken for their parole on the
                    10th instant. The general terms are the same as those agreed upon between Gen.'s
                    Grant and Lee. All public stores appertaining to said command,whether of
                    ordnance, quartermaster's, or commissary will be received by you. The ordnance
                    stores will be brought to such point on the Virginia Central Railroad as is in
                    communication with this place by cars, and thence sent forward to the chief of
                    ordnance of this department by railroad. All quartermaster's and commissary
                    stores will be distributed to the needy persons of the country between Staunton
                    and Gordonsville. When you shall have received the public stores of Gen.
                    Rosser's command you will return to Charlottesville and communicate with these
                    headquarters by telegraph, or, should there be no communication with this place
                    by telegraph or cars, you will go to such point of the Central Railroad that
                    there is. In your march through the country you will hold your command to the
                    strictest rules of discipline and order, giving protection to persons and
                    property, and bands of outlaws and guerrillas infesting the country will be
                    broken up, and the partisans sent to these headquarters for trial. You will move
                    with fourteen days' rations and short forage for your command. You will forward
                    from Charlottesville, or such other place as you return to, a full report of
                    your operations, indicating the number of arms received, quantity of
                    quartermaster's and commissary stores and the disposition made thereof. Such
                    instructions as you may need hereafter will be received from Brevet Brig.-Gen.
                    Voris, commanding the district, or from these headquarters direct.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, very respectfully, &amp;c.,</salute>
                    <signed>N. M. CURTIS,<lb/> Brig.-Gen. and Chief of Staff.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
