<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14696115"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14696115">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sharpe, George H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14696115</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499760</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sharpe, George H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 96</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 114-115</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-01-13">1865-01-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14696115T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>George Sharpe writes Union General George Meade with intelligence on January,
                    1865, conditions in Confederate Richmond. Among other things, Sharpe remarks on
                    the importance to the capital of supplies such as lead arriving on the railroad
                    from Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. GEORGE G. MEADE,<lb/> Cmdg. Army of the
                        Potomac:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-01-13">JANUARY 13, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Our men came in last eight from the Chickahominy, where they had met an agent who
                    left Richmond yesterday. He attempted to come out day before yesterday, but was
                    obliged to return on account of the imperative orders which have been issued to
                    allow no one, white or black, to come in or out of the city. The only road that
                    he could leave on yesterday was the Brook turnpike, running northwardly and
                    nearly parallel with the Central railroad; ingress and egress on no other was
                    permitted. Our agent was thus obliged to walk over thirty-five miles, and then
                    cross the Chickahominy in a boat. It would seem that these extraordinary
                    regulations were made for the purpose of preventing information going out of the
                    real condition of the city, which is daily becoming worse. Gold has risen to
                    seventy for one. Flour, according to the grade, is sold at from $600 to $800 a
                    barrel; beef, salt, and all other articles steadily advancing. One of our
                    correspondents, an engineer on the Danville railroad, sends word that on that
                    road eight trains a day have been run each day lately. He says that within the
                    past two weeks transportation has been provided over the road for 16,000 men
                    from Gen. Lee's army. It is understood that it is intended to convey Hoke's
                    division, Kershaw's division, and the brigades lately sent from Early's corps to
                    Wilmington. He sends some facts as to the number of men that could be
                    transported in a train and the number of trains that carried them, in order to
                    show that his information of the number sent south is correct. He adds that
                    there are now forty-five engines on that road, fifteen of which are not in use,
                    that cars and other transportation have been taken from the Petersburg railroad
                    and engines have been withdrawn from the Central and added to the Danville. By
                    the last freshest the Danville and Greensborough Railroad is very badly damaged
                    between these two points. It was a matter of rumor that fifteen days would be
                    required to put the road in repair. The superintendent of another railroad
                    leading out of Richmond, whose name and position are known to the commanding
                    general, says that perhaps it may be repaired in ten days, but that probably
                    fifteen will be required. The army have been put upon half rations. One of our
                    correspondents says, "Evacuation is upon everyone's lips. Commissary stores are
                    very low;" and our other friends in Richmond send us word that evacuation is not
                    only a matter of talk, but a matter of earnest. Early is in the neighborhood of
                    Staunton with one division of infantry and about 2,000 cavalry. On the account
                    of the failure in the supply of lead, the rebels are thrown back to the
                    resources of that kind which come over the Central road, and out friends say
                    that if the road was destroyed near Staunton the supply would be completely
                    broken up. The information before communicated in regard to railroad supplies is
                    renewed as follows, namely: That the railroad companies in the South have
                    contracted for block tin, zinc, and other necessaries of like nature to be sent
                    to them in some way through Norfolk; it is understood that the supplies are to
                    come from a firm or firms in Philadelphia; that the negotiation is to be
                    perfected by the exchange of cotton, which is to go down the Blackwater in small
                    boats. This information comes from a different source from that by which it was
                    formerly received. Great depression is said to exist everywhere in Richmond. As
                    a specimen of it the following is given: At a meeting of the board of directors
                    of the railroad company, of which one of our friends is superintendent and was
                    present, the president of the road, being the father of Gen. Breckinridge's
                    acting assistant adjutant-general, came in and met his son there. The first
                    question was, "What is the news?" to which the officer replied, "Damned bad. If
                    Sherman cannot be stopped, there is an end to the business." Our friends quite
                    naturally send us word that the Union sentiment is largely on the gain.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>GEO. H. SHARPE.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
