<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14695489"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14695489">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Devin, Thomas</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14695489</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499750</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Devin, Thomas</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 488-489</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-25">1865-03-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14695489T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Cavalry General Thomas Devin reports on a February-March, 1865, expedition
                    in the Shenandoah Valley. Devin reports camping near Staunton and destroying a
                    railroad bridge and supplies in the area. He also reports destroying a
                    blacksmith shop, a tannery, and wagons in the town.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Report of Brig. Gen. Thomas C. Devin, U. S. Army, commanding First Cavalry
                    Division.<lb/> HDQRS. FIRST CAVALRY DIV., ARMY OF THE SHENANDOAH,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-25">March 25, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp at White House,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>CAPT.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to submit the following report of the operations of this
                    division from February 27 to March 18, inclusive:</p>
                <p>On the morning of February 27 the division marched from Winchester on the Valley
                    turnpike, and passing through Newtown, Middletown, and Strasburg, encamped the
                    same night near Woodstock. The Sixth Pennsylvania Cavalry were ordered to push
                    on and seize and hold the bridge across Stony Creek at Edenburg. The order was
                    carried out with slight opposition from a party of rebel cavalry. At 5 a.m. the
                    same regiment was ordered to push on to Mount Jackson and seize and hold the
                    bridge across the North Fork of the Shenandoah, if it had not been destroyed.
                    The regiment reached the river, but found the bridge had been destroyed some
                    time previous.</p>
                <p>On the morning of the 28th the division marched, in rear of the trains, to Mount
                    Jackson, crossed the North Fork on pontoons, marching thence through New Market
                    to Lacey's Spring, where the division encamped at 12 p.m. While on the march
                    between Woodstock and Edenburg the train was attacked in flank by a party of
                    rebel cavalry, who were quickly driven off. The Reserve Brigade, which covered
                    the taking up of the pontoons, did not reach camp until 3 a.m. On the morning of
                    March 1 the division marched, in advance of the train, to Harrisonburg; thence
                    to Mount Crawford, crossing the North River by the turnpike bridge; thence by
                    Mount Sidney to the Middle River, which was crossed on the turnpike bridge, the
                    division encamping within four miles of Staunton, having marched twenty-nine
                    miles. At 8 p.m. the First Brigade, Col. Stagg commanding, was ordered to march
                    through or around Staunton and destroy the railroad bridge at the crossing of
                    Christian's Creek. Col. Stagg succeeded in reaching the bridge with but slight
                    opposition, fired the bridge, and returned to Staunton. From some cause (a heavy
                    rain was falling) the structure was not thoroughly destroyed. In connection
                    therewith, I would respectfully refer to the report of Col. Stagg.</p>
                <p>On the morning of March 2 the division marched, in rear of the trains, to
                    Staunton. At this point 300 men of the Twentieth Pennsylvania Cavalry, of Second
                    Brigade, under Maj. Douglass, were ordered to proceed to Swoope's Station and
                    destroy the Government property at that point. The expedition was entirely
                    successful, resulting in the destruction of the depot and four barns in that
                    vicinity, with all their contents, consisting of an immense amount of valuable
                    commissary and quartermaster's stores and a small quantity of ordnance stores.
                    The Sixth New York Cavalry were detailed to destroy all Government property at
                    Staunton, which duty was fully accomplished, the Government blacksmith shop, a
                    large tannery, and a number of wagons and stage coaches being totally destroyed.
                    The division marched in rear of the trains, and encamped east of the crossing at
                    Christian's Creek, having made but twelve miles. The road from Staunton to the
                    creek was very heavy and the progress of the train very slow. . .</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
