<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14695533"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14695533">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Brown, Charles C.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14695533</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499756</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Brown, Charles C.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 95</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 532-533</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-19">1865-03-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14695533T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union Major Charles Brown reports on a March, 1865, scouting expedition in the
                    Shenandoah Valley. Brown reports hearing rumors that Confederate General Thomas
                    Rosser was preparing a raiding force at Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    No. 6.<lb/> Report of Maj. Charles C. Brown, Twenty-second New York Cavalry, of
                    operations March 17-19.<lb/> HDQRS. TWENTY-SECOND NEW YORK CAVALRY,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. WILLIAM RUSSELL, Jr.,<lb/> Assistant
                        Adjutant-Gen.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-19">March 19, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report that, in compliance with orders from Brevet Maj.-Gen.
                    Torbert, commanding Cavalry Corps, Middle Military Division, I left Winchester
                    on the morning of the 17th at 1.30 o'clock, and moved up the Back road to Cedar
                    Creek, with the intention of crossing at either Fawcett's or Mount Hope Gap. On
                    arriving at Cedar Creek I found the water so high that it was impossible to
                    cross. I then moved by a mountain road and struck the Moorefiled pike, moving up
                    Cedar Valley, crossing Cedar Creek at the entrance of Rudolph's Pass, crossed
                    the mountain by that pass, and struck on the Back road, moving up on that road
                    as a far as the cross-road leading to Woodstock, where I encamped for the night.
                    The guide (Sailor) judging from Cedar Creek and all the runs that we passed that
                    it would be dangerous, if not impossible, to cross Stony Creek, and also the
                    fact that it would be impossible for me to reach Columbia Furnace without the
                    enemy being notified of my approach, I decided to move directly to Woodstock,
                    and then to Edenburg, if I found it necessary. On arriving at Woodstock the
                    scouts dashed through the town, followed by the advance guard, capturing two
                    rebel cavalrymen, dismounted, belonging to Gilmore's battalion; one or two
                    others managed to get away. From information gained from Union families along
                    the route and at Woodstock, I found that there was no force at all this side of
                    New Market, and doubtful if any this side of Staunton. From the time we left
                    Winchester till we reached Woodstock but two rebel soldiers were seen; all that
                    I conversed with gave the same information, that all the soldiers were moving up
                    the Valley. By one Union family in Woodstock I was told that there was an order
                    for all of Rosser's command to meet at or near Staunton, and that small parties
                    of six or eight were passing about every day through Woodstock and on the Back
                    road up the Valley, and none moving down. The scout Stearns, who had been lying
                    at or near Woodstock for a week, confirmed this information from his own
                    knowledge. His impression was, he told me, that Rosser had gathered about 800
                    men between New Market and Staunton, and that his intention was to make a raid
                    in some direction down one of the valleys. Among the Union families in Woodstock
                    the impression prevailed that Rosser was gathering in his cavalry with the
                    purpose of withdrawing toward Richmond, instead of a raid down the Valley.
                    Having been frustrated by the high water my intention of passing to the rear of
                    Edenburg unheralded, and being certain from all the information gained that
                    there was no force at all this side of New Market, and also from the fact that
                    the detachment of the Eighteenth Pennsylvania had joined me without a pound of
                    forage or rations, I decided to return to Winchester without proceeding farther.</p>
                <p>In explanation of my not moving at 6 p.m. of the 16th as ordered, I have the
                    honor to state that when I reported to Gen. Torbert at 5 o'clock of that evening
                    the eighty men that I reported to him as all the men that I could move with,
                    from this regiment, were saddled, bridled, forage packed on the horses, and men
                    ready to move off, as soon as I returned; that on my return to the regiment I
                    found that Col. Ives, commanding this detachment of cavalry, had made a detail
                    from this regiment for thirty mounted men for picket duty. Thirty of the eighty
                    men ready to move with me had gone on picket at Kernstown. Col. Ives requested
                    that I would replace these men by others, and it occasioned a delay in my moving
                    of two hours in getting those men back again. I had ordered Capt. Johnson, of
                    the Eighteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry, on his reporting to me to move out on the
                    pike to the pickets at Mill Creek, and to notify me of his arrival. Not hearing
                    from him within an hour after I was ready to move, I sent an orderly to try and
                    find the command. He found them at Kernstown. Capt. Johnson was not to be found;
                    had not been seen within an hour and a half. Lieut. McKay, the next in command,
                    reported to me. It was then raining in torrents, and it was too dark to move
                    with safety to man or beast. I ordered Lieut. McKay to shelter his men in the
                    house and out houses of Mr. Prichard, near the pike.</p>
                <p>At 1.30 the next morning, the moon being up and it having ceased raining, I
                    moved. Lieut. McKay reports to me that the detachment of the Eighteenth
                    Pennsylvania left their camp, under command of a man named Johnson done officer,
                    Lieut. McKay; that Johnson was a sergeant in some other regiment, was mustered
                    out to receive promotion in the Eighteenth Pennsylvania Cavalry as captain, and
                    has never been mustered in as captain; that he was, or appeared to be, under the
                    influence of liquor; that he laid down under a tree while the command was
                    waiting at Kernstown and could not be found, and was not seen again; that while
                    Lieut. McKay was absent from his command at Kernstown, reporting to me, quite a
                    number of the men left the command and went back to Winchester, leaving only
                    seventy-five men and one commissioned officer. The two prisoners we captured I
                    sent you by Capt. Cadwell, the next in command.</p>
                <p>In my decision as to the direction, after finding it impossible to cross at Mount
                    Hope Ford, I was governed mainly, of course, by the judgment of the scout
                    Sailor, keeping in view the end to be obtained. I have nothing to say of him but
                    praise for his general conduct, forethought, and intelligences. I also have the
                    honor to state that I should have reported promptly in person last evening and
                    with written report, but for a violent attack of bilious colic, which made it
                    impossible for me to move farther than the camp. I am still suffering severely
                    from its effects.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, major, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>C. C. BROWN,<lb/> Maj., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
