<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14696386"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14696386">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Statement of Sergeant S. A. Dunning.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii statement of sergeant s a dunning</title>
        <author>Dunning, S. A.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14696386</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499766</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Statement of Sergeant S. A. Dunning.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii statement of sergeant s a dunning</title>
            <author>Dunning, S. A.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 96</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 385-386</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-02-04">1865-02-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14696386T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Sargeant S. A. Dunning gives a statement to Union officers on the
                    February, 1865, disposition of Confederate forces in the Shenandoah Valley.
                    Dunning mentions a stage that runs daily from Staunton to Mount Jackson. Dunning
                    also mentions the condition of Valley citizens.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">WINCHESTER, VA.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Statement of Sergt. S. A. Dunning, Signal Corps, C. S. Army, attached to Gen.
                    Early's headquarters:</p>
                <p>I entered the Federal lines Thursday, February 2. I had with me another man at
                    Pitman Point, at the extreme end of the Massanutten Mountain, near Strasburg.
                    Have been there about two months. We had a very fine glass (captured from the
                    Federal Army), with which we could look into the streets of Winchester. No force
                    can leave Winchester or go to Strasburg, Front Royal, Ashby's Gap, or Snicker's
                    Gap, or in any direction, without being seen, except at night or rainy weather.
                    We were on post from 8 a. m. until 3 p. m. Usually we boarded with Mr. Bruash
                    Mackintosh, near the signal station. My companion will think that I am captured,
                    as I told him I was going on a scout. There is a chain of signal stations, all
                    connecting with New Market, from which place a telegraph goes to Gen. Early's
                    headquarters. There is a station on the mountain at Ashby's Gap; one at Hominy
                    Hollow, on Bock's Hill, near Front Royal; one at Burnt Springs, on Fort
                    Mountain, opposite Honeyville, at Ed. Brownman's, between Burnt Springs and New
                    Market Gap, and the station at Pitman Point. I am perfectly familiar with the
                    rebel signal code. The road through Fort Valley is very bad. It would be very
                    difficult for a cavalry force ot go through there; the road crosses a creek
                    several times, and when the crossings are frozen up it is almost impossible to
                    cross. After a thaw there would not be much trouble. A large number of the
                    citizens in Fort Valley are Dunkards and Union men. A number of stragglers and
                    men on furlough are constantly in the Fort Valley visiting their friends. Mosby
                    has not yet recovered from his wound. Four of his companies have been sent to
                    Northern Neck, Washington County; the rest of his men are scattered through
                    Loundoun and Fauquirer Counties. They are not doing much scouting because of the
                    difficulty in crossing the river. Gilmor is in command of McNeill's company,
                    near Moorefield. There is a picket-post of three companies at Edenburg. The
                    furnace in Fort Valley, about eight miles from Edenburg, is working for the
                    government; no guard there. No forces between Edenburg and Staunton. The stages
                    run daily between Mount Jackson and Staunton. Gen. Early is at Fishersville. His
                    chief signal officer is Capt. R. E. Wilbourn; chief of artillery, Gen. Long;
                    chief of cavalry, Gen. Fitzhugh Lee. Brig.-Gen. Wharton commands Breckinridge's
                    old division, about 3,000 strong, about three miles from Fishersville. Gen. Long
                    has a park of probably forty-five guns; there are, besides, two horse batteries
                    (Fitzhugh's and Chew's). Fitzhugh Lee has his headquarters at Waynesborough, or
                    near there. Rosser and Lomax are the cavalry division commanders. Rosser's old
                    brigade is at Swoope's Station, near Buffalo Gap. Two regiments of Payne's
                    brigade are at Lexington; the rest of the brigade is at Fishersville. Wickham's
                    brigade is east of the Blue Ridge, between the mountain and Charlottesville.
                    Imboden is near Buffalo Gap. McCausland and Jackson are in Highland County. I
                    estimate the effective cavalry force of Gen. Early's command at 5,000; not more.
                    I am positive forage is very scarce, and it is now very difficult to get a new
                    horse when a man is dismounted. There is no force at Staunton. Early is very
                    unpopular. Gordon is the favorite of the troops. He was with me on the mountain
                    overlooking Gen. Sheridan's army at Cedar Creek the day previous to the attack
                    on the 19th last October; he planned the attack. The citizens in the Valley are
                    very destitute, and depend principally on their friends below Mount Jackson
                    twenty-four hors. Numbers of the rebel cavalry are in the habit of visiting
                    Newtown. They frequently spend twenty-four hours there. A few days since a
                    captain in the First Virginia Cavalry visited his friends there. They will not
                    disturb the Yankee soldiers, for fear the citizens will suffer. There is nothing
                    to prevent a spy from going to Staunton via Fort Valley, along the foot of
                    Massanutten Mountain by Conrad's Store. There are no pickets. I have never known
                    a mounted man to be stopped. Cavalry soldiers seldom desert; they fear their
                    horses will be taken away from them.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
