<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14696792"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14696792">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14696792</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499775</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 96</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 792</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-08">1865-03-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14696792T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Phil Sheridan writes to Chief of Staff Henry Halleck to report on
                    his March, 1865, expedition in the Shenandoah Valley. Sheridan details the Union
                    entrance into Staunton, and the Confederate property destroyed in the town and
                    its vicinity.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. H. W. HALLECK, Chief of Staff:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-08"> March 8th, 1865. (Via Winchester, Va. Received 4.15 p.m. 8th.)</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report the following operations of the forces under my
                    command since leaving Winchester:</p>
                <p>We pushed rapidly up the valley to Staunton, arriving there on the night of the
                    1st instant, encountering but little opposition. Parties of the enemy made their
                    appearance on our flanks, but no attention was paid to them. At Mount Crawford,
                    Rosser, with a portion of his command, attempted to hold the position and
                    destroy the bridge, but was handsomely charged by a portion of Col. Capehart's
                    brigade, and drove them on a run to Mount Sidney. Gen. Early then hastily
                    evacuated Staunton, which was occupied by Col. Stagg's brigade, and the railroad
                    bridge over Christian's Creek was burned. On the morning of the 2d the whole
                    command marched into Staunton. I then directed Gen. Merritt to order Gen.
                    Custer, with his division, to follow up the enemy, who had moved in the
                    direction of Waynesborough, the First Division following in support of Gen.
                    Custer. Gen. Custer found the enemy in line of battle in a strong position at
                    Waynesborough, and at once attacked him with Pennington's and Wells' brigades,
                    of his division, and Capehart's brigade, of the Second Division (Gen.
                    Chapman's), with the following result: 9 pieces light artillery, 13
                    battle-flags, 1,165 enlisted men, 78 officers, from 125 to 150 wagons and
                    ambulances, with teams complete, captured. The caissons and teams of the
                    artillery were also complete. Nearly the entire force of the enemy was captured.
                    Gen.'s Early, Wharton, Rosser, and Lilley were present on the field. Gen.'s
                    Early and Lilley escaped to the mountain. In addition to the above captures, we
                    destroyed between Harrisonburg and Staunton 25 wagons and ambulances, and at
                    Staunton 100 wagons. At Swoope's Depot 1,200 uniforms and a quantity of
                    subsistence stores, burning the Government buildings. The force that made the
                    stand here was two brigades of Wharton's division and a portion of Rosser's
                    cavalry.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>P. H. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"> P. S.--Among the prisoners taken are Gen. Early's
                        medical director and adjutant-general. The roads off the pike are in a
                        terrible condition. It has been raining hard for the last twenty-four
                        hours.<lb/> P. S.--The following has this moment been received from Gen.
                        Custer: I have just captured Greenwood Depot, with 75 prisoners and 3 guns,
                        together with an immense quantity of Government stores and cotton. Have
                        destroyed all these stores, together with 500 saddles complete.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
