<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14696573"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14696573">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Forsyth, James W.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14696573</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499773</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Forsyth, James W.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 96</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 572-573</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-02-16">1865-02-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14696573T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>James Forsyth reports to Union General Phil Sheridan on February, 1865,
                    conditions in the Shenandoah Valley. He discusses movement of Confederate troops
                    in the Staunton area, and the overall sentiment in favor of peace in the
                Valley.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. MIDDLE MILITARY DIVISION,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Cmdg. Middle Military Division,
                        Eutaw House, Baltimore, Md.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-02-16">February 16, 1865.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Deserters to the number of ten, most of them belonging to the First Virginia
                    Cavalry, came in last night. They report that the Second and Third Virginia
                    Cavalry left some time last week for Richmond, and that the First and Fourth
                    Virginia Cavalry had orders to march for Richmond on last Saturday. The
                    above-named regiments composed Wickham's old brigade. Payne's brigade was
                    stationed at Swoope's Depot, seven miles west of Staunton, and had also received
                    marching orders for Richmond. These troops marched to their destination; did not
                    go by railroad, Wickham's old brigade assembled at or near Orange Court-House
                    before marching. The horses of the rebel cavalry reported in a wretched
                    condition. Imboden's cavalry are in Hardy County. One of these deserters, George
                    P. Burtner, First Virginia Cavalry, is from Keezletown. He is a miller; has been
                    in the service some time, but never served with his regiment. He has during the
                    winter (his regiment being disbanded) been grinding wheat for Wharton's
                    division. The last issue made was about one month ago, and it took nine barrels
                    of flour to make a ration, would make the division 2,205 strong. The men
                    questioned by me, George P. Burtner and Peter Bonds, are smart, intelligent men,
                    and I am convinced told the truth. Peter Bonds has been forage master for Gen.
                    Fitz Lee since the breaking out of the war. He says that the people and soldiers
                    think that Virginia will be evacuated, and the soldiers belonging to the cavalry
                    are very much disgusted at being ordered back to Richmond; and he says he knows
                    that a great number of them will not go, but will either come North or go into
                    the mountains and swamps. The artillery that was at Fishersville and Staunton
                    has been sent off, and the hospital at Harrisonburg was ordered to be broken up.
                    This order, however, was countermanded. Both these men say that they think
                    Wharton's division has also gone to Richmond. As stated above the last issue of
                    flour made to this division was one month ago. The rebels in the Valley were
                    very hopeful when the Peace Commissioners started North from Richmond, and they
                    reported that they would have peace at once, and so on up to thirty days;
                    bon-fires were burning and salutes fired in this fond expectation. These peace
                    rumors and reports were telegraphed by signal to Millwood and other points in
                    the Valley. I have been thus particular in the foregoing because these men are
                    the most intelligent, truthful, and reliable men that I have seen. All quiet
                    here. Snow melting very fast. Fitz Lee's and Early's headquarters were at
                    Staunton; Rosser's was at Swoope's Depot.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>JAS. W. FORSYTH,<lb/> Chief of Staff.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
