<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14696919"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14696919">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14696919</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499784</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Sheridan, Phillip H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 46, Serial No. 96</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 918-919</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-10">1865-03-10</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14696919T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Phil Sheridan reports to General Grant on March, 1865, operations
                    in the Shenandoah Valley and Central Virginia. Sheridan reports the destruction
                    of railroad bridges around Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. MIDDLE MILITARY DIVISION,
                    <name type="recipient">Lieut. Gen. U. S. GRANT,<lb/> Cmdg. Armies of the United
                        States:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-10">Friday, March 10, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place">Columbia, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In my last dispatch, dated Waynesborough, I gave a brief account of the defeat of
                    Gen. Early by Custer's division. The same night this division was pushed across
                    the Blue Ridge, and entered Charlottesville at 2 p.m. the next day. The mayor of
                    the city and the principal inhabitants came out and delivered up the keys of the
                    public buildings. I had to remain at Charlottesville two days; this time was
                    consumed in bringing over from Waynesborough our ammunition and pontoon trains.
                    The mud was horrible beyond description and the rain incessant. The two
                    divisions were during this time occupied in destroying the two large iron
                    bridges--one over the Rivanna River, the other over Moore's Creek, near
                    Charlottesville--and the railroad for a distance of eight miles in the direction
                    of Lynchburg.</p>
                <p>On the 6th of March I sent the First Cavalry Division, Gen. Devin commanding, To
                    Scottsville, on the James River, with directions to send out light parties
                    through the country and destroy all merchant mills, factories, and bridges on
                    the Rivanna River, these parties to join the division at Scottsville. The
                    division then proceeded along the canal to Duguidsville, fifteen miles from
                    Lynchburg, destroying every lock and in many places the bank of the canal. At
                    Duguidsville we hoped to secure the bridge, to let us cross the river, as our
                    pontoons were useless on account of the high water. In this, however, we were
                    foiled, as both this bridge and the bridge at Hardwicksville were burned by the
                    enemy upon our approach. Gen. Merritt accompanied this division. The Third
                    Division started at the same time from Charlottesville and proceeded down the
                    Lynchburg railroad to Amherst Court-House, destroying every bridge on the road
                    and in many places miles of the track. The bridges on this road were numerous,
                    and some of them 500 in length. Finding I could not cross the James, I
                    concentrated at New Market, and determined to return along the canal and still
                    further destroy it, in the direction of Richmond. We arrived here to-night and
                    will destroy the canal as far as Goochland to-morrow. I will then move on to the
                    Central road and continue its destruction, and will then strike the
                    Fredericksburg railroad and destroy it.</p>
                <p>We have found great abundance in this country for our men and animals; in fact,
                    the canal has been the great feeder of Richmond. At the Rockfish River the bank
                    of the canal was cut, and at New Market, where the dam is across the James, the
                    guard lock was destroyed and the James River let into the canal, carrying away
                    the banks and washing out the bottom of the canal. The dam across the James at
                    this point was also partially destroyed. After finishing the Fredericksburg road
                    I will join you, unless otherwise directed. Send forage and rations to the White
                    House, also pontoons, in case I have to go around that far. I have had no
                    opposition; everybody is bewildered by our movements. I have had no news of any
                    kind since I left, the latest Richmond paper was of the 4th, but contained
                    nothing.</p>
                <p>I omitted to mention that the bridges on the railroad from Swoope's Depot, on the
                    other side of Staunton, to Charlottesville were utterly destroyed, also all
                    bridges for a distance of ten miles on the Gordonsville railroad.</p>
                <p>The weather has been very bad indeed; raining hard every day, with the exception
                    of four days, since we started. My wagons have, from the state of the roads,
                    detained me. Up to the present time we have captured 14 pieces of artillery--11
                    at Waynesborough and 3 at Charlottesville. The party that I sent back from
                    Waynesborough started with six pieces, but they were obliged to destroy two of
                    the six for want of animals. The remaining nine pieces were thoroughly
                    destroyed. We have captured, up to the present time, 12 canal-boats laden with
                    supplies, ammunition, rations, medical stores, &amp;c.</p>
                <p>I cannot speak in too high terms of Gen.'s Merritt, Custer, and Devin, and the
                    officers and men of their commands; they have waded through mud and water during
                    this continuous rain, and are all in fine spirits and health.</p>
                <p>Commodore Hollins, of the rebel navy, was shot near Gordonsville while attempting
                    to make his escape from our advance in that direction.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>P. H. SHERIDAN,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
