<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R14799860"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R14799860">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Grant, Ulysses S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R14799860</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499794</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LVIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lviii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Grant, Ulysses S.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 47, Serial No. 99</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 859-860</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-03-16">1865-03-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R14799860T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>General Grant writes General Sherman in March, 1865, to discuss the movements and
                    strategies of the Union armies in the field that Spring. He reports on
                    Sheridan's plans to advance to Staunton and destroy the Virginia Central
                    Railroad.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. ARMIES OF THE UNITED STATES,
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. W. T. SHERMAN,<lb/> Cmdg. Military Division of
                        the Mississippi:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-03-16">March 16, 1865.</date>
                        <name type="place"> City Point, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your interesting letter of the 12th instant is just received. I have never felt
                    any uneasiness for your safety, but I have felt great anxiety to know just how
                    you were progressing. I knew, or thought safely somewhere. To secure certain
                    success I deemed the capture of Wilmington of the greatest importance. Butler
                    came near losing that prize to us, but Terry and Schofield have since retrieved
                    his blunders, and I do not know but that the first failure has been as valuable
                    a success for the country as the capture of Fort Fisher. Butler may not see it
                    in that light. Ever since you started on the last campaign, and before, I have
                    been attempting to get something done in the West, both to co-operate with you
                    and to take advantage of the enemy's weakness there to accomplish results
                    favorable to us. Knowing Thomas to be slow beyond excuse I depleted his army to
                    re-enforce Canby, so that he might act from Mobile Bay on the interior. With all
                    I have said he had not moved at last advices. Canby was sending a cavalry force
                    of about 7,000 from Vicksburg toward Selma. I ordered Thomas to send Wilson from
                    Eastport toward the same point and to get him off as soon after the 20th of
                    February as possible. He telegraphed me that he would be off by that date. He
                    has not yet started, or had not at least advices. I ordered him to send Stoneman
                    from East Tennessee into Northwest South Carolina to be there about the time you
                    would reach Columbia. He would either have drawn off the enemy's cavalry from
                    you or would have succeeded in destroying railroads, supplies, and other
                    materials which you could not reach. At that time the Richmond papers were full
                    of accounts of your movements and gave daily accounts of movements in West North
                    Carolina. I supposed all the time it was Stoneman. You may judge my surprise
                    when I afterward learned that Stoneman was still in Louisville, Ky., and that
                    the troops in North Carolina were Kirk's forces. In order that Stoneman might
                    get off without delay, I told Thomas that 3,000 men would be sufficient for him
                    to take. In the meantime I had directed Sheridan to get his cavalry ready and as
                    soon as the snow in the mountains melted sufficiently to start for Staunton and
                    go on and destroy the Virginia Central road and the canal. Time advanced until
                    he set the 28th of February for starting. I informed Thomas and directed him to
                    change the course of Stoneman toward Lynchburg to destroy the road in Virginia
                    up as near to that place as possible. Not hearing from Thomas I telegraphed to
                    him about the 12th to know if Stoneman was yet off. He replied that he had not
                    but that he (Thomas) would start that day for Knoxville to get him off as soon
                    as possible. Sheridan has made his raid and with splendid success so far as
                    heard. I am looking for him at White House to-day. Since about the 20th of last
                    month of Richmond papers have been prohibited from publishing accounts of army
                    movements. We are left to our own resources, therefore, for information. You
                    will see from the papers what Sheridan has done. If you do not the officer who
                    bears this will tell you all. Lee has depleted his army but very little recently
                    and I learn of none going south. Some regiments may have been detached, but I
                    think no division or brigade. The determination seems to be to hold Richmond as
                    long as possible. I have a force sufficient to leave enough to hold our lines,
                    all that is necessary of them, and move out with plenty to whip his whole army.
                    But the roads are entirely impassable. Until they improve I shall content myself
                    with watching Lee and be prepared to pitch into him if he attempts to evacuate
                    the place. I may bring Sheridan over; I think I will, and break up the Danville
                    and South Side railroads. These are the last avenues left to the enemy. Recruits
                    have come in so rapidly at the West that Thomas has now about as much previous
                    orders would go to him, except those from Illinois. Fearing the possibility of
                    the enemy falling back to Lynchburg, and afterward attempting to go into East
                    Tennessee or Kentucky, I have ordered Thomas to move the Fourth Corps to Bull's
                    Gap and to fortify there, and to hold out to the Virginia line if he can. He has
                    accumulated a large amount of supplies in Knoxville and has been ordered not to
                    destroy any of the railroad west of the Virginia line. I told him to get ready
                    for a campaign toward Lynchburg, if it became necessary. He never can make one
                    there or elsewhere, but the steps taken will prepare for any one else to take
                    his troops and come east or go toward Rome, whichever may be necessary. I do not
                    believe either will. When I hear that you and Schofield are together with your
                    back upon the coast I shall feel that you entirely safe against anything the
                    enemy can do. Lee may evacuate Richmond, but he cannot get there with force
                    enough to touch you. His army is now demoralized and deserting very fast, both
                    to us and to their homes. A retrograde movement would cost him thousands of men,
                    even if we did not follow. Five thousand men belonging to the corps with you are
                    now on their way to join you. If more re-enforcements are necessary I will send
                    them. My notion is that you should get Raleigh as soon as possible and hold the
                    railroad from there back. This may take more force than you now have. From that
                    point all North Carolina roads can be made useless to the enemy without keeping
                    up communications with the rear. Hoping to hear soon of your junction with the
                    forces from Wilmington and New Berne.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain, very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>U. S. GRANT,<lb/> Lieut.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
