<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151868"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R151868">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">15</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151868</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499918</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Haupt, Herman</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 107</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 867-870</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-09-27">1862-09-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151868T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Herman Haupt, Chief of Union Military Railroads, reports in September, 1862, to
                    General in Chief Henry Halleck on efforts to keep supplies flowing during the
                    Antietam campaign. Haupt mentions actions in the Chambersburg area on several
                    occasions.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. HALLECK:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-09-27">September 27, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">WASHINGTON,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>On Thursday, September 18, I was authorized and directed by Special Orders, No.
                    248, to do whatever I might deem expedient to facilitate the transportation of
                    troops and supplies to aid the armies in the field in Virginia and Maryland. I
                    immediately proceeded to Baltimore, where a conference was held with Gen. Wood,
                    Quartermaster Belger, President Garrett and Superintendent Smith, of the
                    Baltimore and Ohio Railroad. This conference resulted in changing the route for
                    several regiments then ordered to the front and in the establishment of the
                    following rule for future operations:</p>
                <p>Rule.--All troops and supplies sent from Baltimore and points south thereof to
                    the army in Maryland shall be forwarded by the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and
                    all sent from points north of Baltimore by the York and Cumberland Railroad.</p>
                <p>I was clearly of the opinion that it was expedient in general to operate the
                    railroads used for military purposes by and through the regular officers and
                    employees of said roads, using military authority only where necessary to render
                    assistance to them in procuring rolling-stock or securing regularity in train
                    movements. The efficiency of the management of the officers of the Baltimore and
                    Ohio Railroad, their readiness to give Government supplies the preference over
                    all other transportation, and the capacity of the road, which is greater than
                    any ordinary or even extraordinary demands that may be made upon it, left
                    nothing more to be desired except the prompt return of cars from the advanced
                    terminus; and having concluded all necessary arrangements, I proceeded the same
                    night to Harrisburg, arriving in that city on Friday morning, September 19, at
                    3.30 a. m. The arrangement of sending supplies from Baltimore and points south
                    thereof over the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, relieving the Northern Central of
                    its transportation of Government supplies northward, left no question as to the
                    ability of this road to meet any anticipated demands upon it, and I therefore
                    continued my journey at 7.30 a. m. over the York and Cumberland Railroad to
                    Chambersburg, where, after many delays caused by passing trains, I arrive at
                    2.30 p. m. The amount of business on the York and Cumberland Railroad exceeded
                    its capacity for prompt accommodation. About eighteen regiments of Pennsylvania
                    militia had been sent forward and more were on the way, the Pennsylvania
                    Railroad Company furnishing cars and engines and assisting, as I understood, in
                    the management of the road. Under these circumstances the only action at that
                    point which I considered expedient was to order that all private sidings should
                    be vacated, and that all cars belonging to individuals and all others not
                    required for military purposes should be either run off the tracks or sent to
                    other stations where the sidings were not required for the use of the
                    Government. I found a very efficient officer in charge of the depot and station
                    at Chambersburg, Mr. J. D. Potts, formerly assistant superintendent on the
                    Western Division of the Pennsylvania Railroad, to whom I gave such instructions
                    as appeared to be necessary.</p>
                <p>At Hagerstown the main track was blocked with cars. There was no adequate siding
                    or warehouse accommodation, no competent person in charge, and much confusion
                    existed. I found it necessary to assume military possession of the Trunk Line
                    Railroad between Chambersburg and Hagerstown; attended personally to the duty of
                    raising the blockade; cleared the track of some five or six trains that had
                    accumulated at Hagerstown; placed Mr. Potts in charge as superintendent;
                    directed him to procure a substitute in the Chambersburg office; left written
                    instructions as to the future management, and also wrote to Gen. Kenly, the
                    officer understood to be in command at Hagerstown, informing him of the existing
                    arrangement for transportation, and giving the names of the officers in charge.
                    On Saturday, September 20, I rode from Hagerstown to Sharpsburg, where, after a
                    half hour's interview with Gen. McClellan, I repaired to Boonsborough and
                    returned via Frederick City to Baltimore. At Monocacy I found about 200 loaded
                    cars on the sidings, some of which had been standing nearly a week. Gen. Wool,
                    at my request, sent an efficient officer of his staff to insist upon the
                    unloading and return of cars. On Monday, September 22, I returned to Washington
                    and made a verbal report to you of my doings. On Tuesday, September 23, having
                    received information that the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company were
                    embarrassed in their operation in consequence of the non-return of cars, I sent
                    two of our most experienced train dispatchers from the Camden and Amboy Railroad
                    over the Northern Central, Pennsylvania, and connecting roads to search for and
                    return cars of Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, and of the U. S. military
                    railroads. The same evening I started for Baltimore and Harper's Ferry to render
                    such assistance as might be in my power in opening communications with that
                    post. I arrived at Harper's Ferry about noon on Wednesday, September 24, and
                    remained until Thursday afternoon, September 25. The supply of material being
                    insufficient, and the force of mechanics for the railroad bridge very small, I
                    telegraphed for the construction corps of the Camden and Amboy Railroad, which
                    was promptly forwarded, together with about 150,000 feet of long, square timber,
                    which we fortunately had on hand at Alexandria, and which could not elsewhere
                    have been procured in time.</p>
                <p>About six days will complete the railroad trestle bridge and secure connection by
                    rail with Harper's Ferry, but a much longer time will be required to replace the
                    permanent structure. The trestle bridge will be in danger of destruction from
                    freshets. The most certain reliance for the supplies in the event of such a
                    contingency will be the pontoon bridge which has been reconstructed. With proper
                    management at Harper's Ferry and Sandy Hook, the supply question presents no
                    difficulty, even in the case the trestle bridge should be swept away. These are:
                    First. Sending supplies to the advanced terminus before they are required. Such
                    supplies are not unloaded. They block the track, impede retreat, and are in
                    danger of capture or destruction. Nothing should be sent to the extreme front
                    until it is actually needed. A reasonable amount can be kept on some siding a
                    few miles in the rear. Second. A second difficulty arises from the fact that
                    cars are not promptly unloaded and returned. Sometimes only a single car will be
                    unloaded at a time, when there should be force sufficient to discharge the
                    contents of a whole train. Cars are often kept for weeks as store-houses. Third.
                    A third difficulty arises from the practice of detaining trains beyond schedule
                    time. Nothing more certainly throws the business of a line into confusion,
                    especially if there be but a single track. Medical directors and officers should
                    conform to the schedule time of trains, or if extras are required for sick,
                    wounded, or for supplies, they should always be furnished when practicable, but
                    when the hour fixed for starting has arrived the trains should be promptly
                    dispatched. It has been the practice on most roads used for military purposes,
                    under the influence of a pressure of business and the impatience of military
                    officers, to abandon the schedule and resort to the use of the telegraph
                    exclusively for running trains. This practice invariably leads to difficulty and
                    in case of any derangement to the delicate mechanism of the telegraph, puts an
                    end to all business and blocks every wheel upon the road. I believe that it is
                    always possible, with good management, to run the trains by schedule, and the
                    telegraph, although valuable as an auxiliary, should not be used as a principal.
                    It is desirable that uniformity should be introduced in the management of all
                    railroads used for military purposes.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully submitted.</salute>
                    <signed>H. HAUPT,<lb/> Brig.-Gen., Chief of Construction and Transportation, U.
                        S. Military Railroads.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
