<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1511225"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1511225">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jones, James F.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">14</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1511225</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499817</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jones, James F.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 107</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1225-1227</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-30">1864-06-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1511225T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In June, 1864, Union forces under David Hunter advanced on Staunton, Virginia.
                    Confederate officers attempted to scrape together a force to meet the advance,
                    and resorted to calling to the front all men detailed for niter and mining duty.
                    James Jones, captain of the Niter and Mining Corps, reports from offices in
                    Staunton on how his men gathered in the town, and the role they played in the
                    ensuing Battle of Piedmont.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    OFFICE OF THE NITER AND MINING DISTRICT, No. 4 1/2
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. RICHARD MORTON,<lb/> Niter and Mining Corps,
                        Richmond.</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-30">June 30, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton, Va.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MAJ.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to report to you that on the 1st instant I received an order
                    from Gen. J. D. Imboden, commanding the Valley Department, to report to him for
                    active duty in the field, with all my men detailed for niter service, at as
                    early a moment as possible; and I immediately dispatched couriers through the
                    different counties to notify my men to report to me at Staunton, with all
                    possible speed. Army works extend through all the neighboring counties, it
                    required much activity to notify them and then collect them at Staunton in time
                    to bear their part in the battle which was evidently close at hand. On Friday,
                    the 3d instant, I had collected 130 of my men at this point, and I organized
                    them immediately into two companies, placing one under the command of W. L.
                    Clark as captain, and the other under Capt. F. P. Clark, assistant
                    quartermaster, C. S. Army, who had volunteered to serve until N. R. Heaton,
                    superintendent of the Bates County Government niter works, would be able to
                    report as the permanent captain. I also appointed the other officers and
                    procured such arms as the ordnance depot at this place could afford. Knowing the
                    urgency of the case, I marched my command at once toward the scene of action,
                    and arrived at the camp near Mount Crawford early Saturday morning and
                    immediately reported them for duty, and was assigned to Maj. Brewer's command,
                    which was composed chiefly of dismounted cavalry. Early on Sunday morning we
                    were marched from near Mount Crawford to New Hope, in Augusta County, a distance
                    of twelve miles; and I had no sooner arrived on the field, without a moment of
                    rest for my men, when I was ordered to take an advanced position about one mile
                    in front of our principal line of battle, to support a battery and a line of
                    skirmishers which had been established at that point for the purpose of holding
                    the enemy in check until our principal line of battle could be formed in the
                    rear. The positions thus assigned were held by us for one hour and a half,
                    during one hour of which we were subjected to a heavy artillery and musketry
                    fire, and we did not leave it until all our forces stationed there were driven
                    back by the overwhelming advance of the enemy's main column of attack. My
                    battalion was on the extreme left of this advanced line, and as the main attack
                    was on the right, we were compelled to fall back as the troops on the right and
                    center successively gave away. There was at the same time a heavy advance of the
                    enemy on our front, and our left flank was threatened by cavalry, by which some
                    of my men were captured in the movement to the rear. Having been driven from
                    this position, we fell back upon our principal line of battle, and took our
                    position within the line of fortifications which had been hastily thrown up by
                    the main body of our army. The interval which occurred before our principal line
                    was attacked was employed by my men in throwing up a rough line of breast-works
                    in an unoccupied point on the extreme left which I had been requested to occupy
                    by Capt. Thornton, who was in command of a battalion of the Thirty-sixth
                    Virginia Infantry along that part of the line. Notwithstanding their fatigue, my
                    men went at once to work in filling up this gap, and then awaited the advance of
                    the enemy. The first demonstrations were made by the enemy's cavalry, which
                    drove in our skirmishers, and then advanced within range of our muskets, but
                    were soon repulsed. This was soon followed by an advanced within range of our
                    muskets, but were soon repulsed. This was soon followed by an advance of the
                    enemy's infantry in line of battle, which being driven back, was followed by a
                    second attack of similar character after an interval of three-quarters of an
                    hour, the intervening time being occupied by either side in a desultory but
                    constant skirmishing fire. This second attack of the enemy's main line was
                    repulsed like the first, and no renewal of the attack was made upon the left in
                    line of battle. Such an attack had been proven hopeless, as the position we
                    occupied on the left and the firm bearing of the whole line clearly indicated it
                    would be. We were, however, from this moment subject to a severe artillery fire
                    from a battery of two guns, at a distance of not more than 500 yards, and which
                    became a more severe ordeal than the fire of the enemy's infantry. The incidents
                    thus described occupied a space of two hours, from 12 m. to 2 p. m., and we were
                    at the height of certain victory when we began to find the whole center of our
                    line crowded down upon our left, and discovered that the enemy had availed
                    themselves of an open space in our right center to enter within our lines, and
                    had crowded down our center upon our left, throwing the whole into confusion,
                    and subjecting us to a fire from our front and both our flanks. It was evident
                    the position was no longer tenable, and we followed the example of the veteran
                    troops around us in abandoning the position which we had successfully defended
                    against the three separate attacks which had been made directly upon our front.
                    My loss during the day was 5 killed and 14 wounded and 8 prisoners. I cannot but
                    commend the conduct of my men, both for the alacrity with which they obeyed my
                    summons for duty, and the mode in which they discharged that duty in the field,
                    They were armed with only the altered smooth-bore musket, and had no bayonets or
                    cartridge-boxes; and although thus unequally armed, they were placed in the most
                    advanced line and were among the last to leave the final scene of battle. The
                    conduct of my command was highly complimented by Capt. Thornton, of the
                    Thirty-sixth Infantry, to whom I have before referred. The whole army having
                    fallen back to Waynesborough, and my command having been thrown into the
                    regiment of reserves under the command of Col. William H. Harman, I placed the
                    remained of my men under the command of Capt. N. R. Heaton, having consolidated
                    them into one company, and they have since served in resisting the advance of
                    Gen. Hunter's army upon Lynchburg, and in the pursuit of that army upon its
                    retreat into Western Virginia. The reserves have since then been discharged from
                    duty, with the thanks of the commanding general, and my men have returned to
                    their appropriate duties.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>JAMES F. JONES,<lb/> Capt. Niter and Mining Corps, and in Command of
                        Battalion.</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P. S.--The names of the killed and wounded will be
                        forwarded as soon as possible.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
