<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151133"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151133">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Allen, John L.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151133</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499819</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Allen, John L.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 133-134</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-02">1861-06-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151133T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This June, 1861, report of a Virginia state governmental committee advises
                    Governor Letcher on procedure for transferring Virginia's officers, soldiers,
                    and military property to Confederate control. It also advises establishing a
                    telegraph line from Staunton to Charleston in the Kanawha Valley.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    The note of President Davis, made a part of the committees report, is as
                    follows:
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JOHN LETCHER,<lb/> Governor of the State:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-02">June 2, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">RICHMOND,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to acknowledge yours of yesterday, inclosing two advisory
                    communications from your council to yourself as the basis of your tender to the
                    Confederate States, by regiments, of all the volunteer forces which have been or
                    may be mustered into the service of Virginia and all seamen and marines in said
                    service, and all quartermaster's and commissary stores now in possession of said
                    State, and also to tender the use of all the public property, naval stores,
                    munitions of war, &amp;c., acquired from the United States and now in
                    possession, except the machinery for the manufacture of arms captured at
                    Harper's Ferry. Thanking Your Excellency and council for the readiness with
                    which you have met the wants of the common defense, most pressing upon us
                    because of the invasion of Virginia, I hope to be pardoned for suggesting that
                    the machinery at Harper's Ferry is essential for the speedy preparation for both
                    repair and construction of small-arms, and if it can be used for that purpose
                    more beneficially to the public interest by retaining it in the possession of
                    the State to urge upon you a more effectual protection for it than it now
                    enjoys. Public buildings and all other public property captured from the United
                    States must be the subject of future settlement with the United States
                    Government, should negotiations ever take place between the two Governments. The
                    machinery at Harper's Ferry in that respect will not constitute an exception,
                    and unless the officers and employees of Virginia can, better than those of the
                    Confederate States, secure it and make it tributary to the public interest, I
                    respectfully submit whether it had not better be put in the general condition
                    which you have given to other public property similarly situated. In relation to
                    the proposition concerning officers who have left the service of the United
                    States and entered the Army or Navy of Virginia, I can only say that the
                    Congress of the Confederate States secured by law to officers of the Army thus
                    entering the service, so far as they were of the same grade, they should have
                    the same relative rank in this service as the one they left. The reason of the
                    rule would equally apply to officers of the Navy, and I do not anticipate its
                    being either disregarded or violated. But the Confederate authority has been
                    invested with discretionary power both as to the acceptance of the services of
                    officers who may resign from the United States and in filling original
                    vacancies. To determine the grade which should be given to such officers, I can
                    only say that it is not probable that any officer thus accepted will be
                    appointed to a lower grade than that he held in the service of the United
                    States. The only right, however, which I can recognize is that of transfer,
                    according to the existing law of Congress, of officers with the troops to which
                    they have been appointed.<lb/> Yours, most respectfully,<lb/> JEFF'N DAVIS.</p>
                <p>After considering these papers, the council adopted the following advice: Advised
                    unanimously that the Governor of Virginia forthwith direct by general orders a
                    transfer to the authorities of the Confederate States, be regiments, of all the
                    volunteer forces which have been mustered into the service of the State, and
                    direct a like transfer by regiments of all other volunteers or militia as the
                    same shall be formed and their services may be required.</p>
                <p>It is further advised that the Governor direct by general order as transfer to
                    the authority of the Confederate States of all the officers, seamen, and marines
                    of the Provisional Navy of Virginia for service in the Confederate States.</p>
                <p>Waiving for the present any objection to the constitutionality of so much of the
                    ninth section of the act of the Provisional Congress, approved March 6, 1861, as
                    provides for the appointment by the President, by and with the advice and
                    consent of the Congress, of regimental staff officers of the volunteers and
                    militia when called into the service of the Confederate States, it is further
                    advised that, inasmuch as the State of Virginia has put into efficient
                    organization the various departments of the military staff essential for the
                    comfort and efficiency of an army in the field, the Governor tender to the
                    President of the Confederate States the services of the officers of their
                    various departments for duty in the Confederate service, temporarily or
                    permanently, as the exigencies of the public service may require. It is further
                    advised that the Governor submit to the President a respectful request that he
                    will facilitate the prompt removal to Fayetteville, N. C., of the rifle
                    machinery captured at Harper's Ferry, loaned by the State of Virginia to the
                    State of North Carolina. It is further advised that the Governor tender to the
                    President the services of the Provisional Army of Virginia, to be incorporated,
                    in whole or in part, into the Army of the Confederate States upon such terms as
                    may be deemed proper by the President and not inconsistent with the terms of the
                    convention between the State of Virginia and the Confederate States and may best
                    subserve the pubic interest, or to be used as the other forces of the State are
                    used, in the common defense.</p>
                <p>The following was proposed to be adopted; The council advise that the Governor be
                    authorized to contract for erecting a telegraph line from Staunton to Charleston
                    in the Kanawha Valley, provided that the average costs shall not exceed $62.50
                    per mile. Whereupon, on motion of Mr. Montague, the proposed advice as laid on
                    the table, Messrs. Smith and Maury voting against laying it on the table.</p>
                <p>The following was then proposed and adopted, Messrs. Allen and Haymond
                    dissenting; Advised that the Governor contract for the erection the same may be
                    done at a cost not exceeding $62.50 per mile.</p>
                <p>Advised unanimously that the companies of Texas Rangers now in this city be
                    ordered, under the command of some suitable officer, to the defense of the
                    Kanawha Valley, and that the officer commanding, in that section be further
                    directed to call out volunteers from the counties of Greenbrier, Fayette,
                    Nicholas, Logan, Wyoming, Boone, Cabell, Wayne, and Raleigh for the defense of
                    that region, said volunteers to be armed with their own rifles or such weapons
                    as may be collected for this service.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>JOHN L. ALLEN.<lb/> FRANCIS H. SMITH.<lb/> M. F. MAURY.<lb/> RO. L.
                        MONTAGUE.<lb/> T. S. HAYMOND.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
