<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151124"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151124">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Allen, John J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1511224</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499818</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Allen, John J.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 124</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-06-01">1861-06-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151124T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>June, 1861, Virginia resolutions transferring all officers, men, and military
                    equipment to control of the Confederate government. The document also suggests
                    that Michael Harman, quartermaster at Staunton, be ordered to call out militia
                    for use at Philippi.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Present, John J. Allen, president; F. H. Smith, M. F. Maury, R. L. Montague, and
                    T. S. Haymond.
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-06-01">SATURDAY, June 1, 1861.</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>Advised unanimously that the Governor tender to the President the services of the
                    officers of the Army and Navy who have retired or may retire from the service of
                    the late United States and entered or may enter that of Virginia, to the end
                    that they may be regularly incorporated into the Army and Navy of the
                    Confederate States, with the view of increasing the efficiency thereof; and
                    further, that the attention of the Confederate authorities be invited to the
                    terms of the invitation of Virginia to those officers, by which it was made the
                    duty of the Governor to assign to them such rank as will not reverse the
                    relative rank held by them in the U. S. service, and will at least be equivalent
                    thereto, it being the desire of the State of Virginia that in assigning to these
                    officers rank in the Confederate service this rule should be observed, except
                    with regard to brigadier-generals and major-generals.</p>
                <p>Advised unanimously that the Governor of Virginia tender, by regiments to the
                    President of the Confederate States all the volunteer forces of Virginia which
                    have been or may be mustered into the service of Virginia to the end that they
                    may be received into the service of the Confederate States; and that he also
                    tender to the President the use of all the public property, naval stores, and
                    munitions of war, &amp;c., acquired from the United States now in the
                    possession of the State of Virginia, except the machinery for the manufacture of
                    arms captured at Harper's Ferry.</p>
                <p>It is further advised that all quartermaster's commissary, and hospital
                    Confederate States for the use of the same.</p>
                <p>Absent, M. F. Maury, and R. L. Montague.</p>
                <p>Advised by the councilors present that the Governor send a special messenger by
                    an express car to Staunton with orders to Maj. Harman to order out the militia
                    in the counties of Bath, Pocahontas, Pendleton Highland, Randolph, Barbour, and
                    Tucker; to cause them to assemble with such arms as they may be able to bring
                    with them, and to supply the remainder with arms hitherto sent out. These troops
                    are to assemble and re-enforce Col. Porterfield at Philippi. It is further
                    advised that Col. Porterfield be directed to destroy the bridge, culvert and
                    trestle-work at Cheat River and in every possible way destroy the railroad on
                    both branches so as to interrupt the free passage of trains, and that this last
                    order be kept with secrecy, that it may not be anticipated or interfered with;
                    and for the purpose of executing this order effectively at Cheat River it is
                    suggested that Col. Porterfield consider the propriety of sending a strong
                    detachment across the Laurel Ridge and down Clover Run to Cheat.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>JOHN J. ALLEN.<lb/> T. S. HAYMOND.<lb/> FRANCIS H. SMITH.<lb/> M. F.
                        MAURY.<lb/> RO. L. MONTAGUE.<lb/>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
