<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151994"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151994">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Tyler, John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151994</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499929</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Tyler, John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 993-995</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-06-07">1864-06-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151994T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>John Tyler, riding with Lee's staff in June, 1864, reports to Confederate General
                    Sterling Price on the fighting he has witnessed during the spring and the
                    summer. Tyler gives accounts of the Wilderness Campaign, his impressions of
                    Grant and Lee, and changes in strategy due to the loss of Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. STERLING PRICE,<lb/> Cmdg. District of
                        Arkansas:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-06-07">June 7, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Mechanicsville, Hanover County, Va.,</name><name type="location">HDQRS. OF GEN. ROBERT E. LEE,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>MY DEAR GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Since active operations commenced on the Rapidan and the enemy crossed over, I
                    have been riding with the staff of Gen. Lee, and so passed through the battles
                    of the Wilderness, of Spotsylvania Court-House, and of those since fought here
                    on the line of the Chickahominy. Up to this time our loss in killed, wounded,
                    and prisoners does not exceed 18,000, while that of the enemy in similar
                    respects is not less than 70,000. But both armies have been built up through
                    re-enforcements to their original standard, and other battles have still to be
                    fought equally bloody with the bloodiest. Here on the Chickahominy we occupy
                    McClellan's old line, with this difference, we face to the east, whereas he
                    faced to the west; hence Jackson's attack upon him was in his rear, whereas
                    Grant's attack on us is to our front. From first to last Grant has shown great
                    skill and prudence combined with remorseless persistency and brutality. He is a
                    scientific Goth resembling Alaric, destroying the country as he goes, and
                    delivering the people over to starvation. Nor does he bury his dead, but leaves
                    them to rot on the battle-field. He has commenced again sliding his right down
                    past his left, doubtless in order to reach Bottom's Bridge and the Long Bridge,
                    with the intention of crossing to the Richmond side. Lee, accordingly, is
                    throwing down his left. On both sides I apprehend the lines will be contracted
                    and massed, and a desperate encounter take place in the course of the movement.
                    In view of the fact, just arrived by telegraph, that the enemy in the Valley
                    have defeated and killed Gen. Jones and taken Staunton, and now have the Valley
                    at their mercy--the remainder of our troops having been drawn here under
                    Breckinridge from that quarter--it may be, and probably is, Grant's design to
                    make across the James River to seize our communications, and thus to assure the
                    destruction of our supplies and compel a surrender ultimately through
                    starvation. Should he succeed in getting over the James and in forming his lines
                    across our railroads on the south side, our situation will be at least
                    uncomfortable, if not alarming, and I am unable to see, without the intervention
                    of some special Providence, any assurance of a successful termination of the war
                    on our part this year or the next. But Providence and a good cause may save us
                    here as they seem to have saved you all in the Trans-Mississippi in despite of
                    bad management and against every human calculation.</p>
                <p>The game going on upon the military chessboard between Lee and Grant has been
                    striking and grand, surpassing anything I have heretofore witnessed, and
                    conducted on both sides with consummate mastery of the art of war. It is
                    admitted that Lee has at last met with a foeman who watches his steel, although
                    he may not be worthy of it. Each guards himself perfectly and gives his blow
                    with a precise eye and cool and sanguinary nerve. In Lee's army everything is
                    reduced down to the smallest compass, and the discipline and obedience of the
                    officers and men is perfect. Your own headquarters establishment is more
                    numerous and bulky. He rides with only three members of his staff and never
                    takes with him an extra horse or servant, although he is upon the lines usually
                    from daybreak until dark. He is almost unapproachable, and yet no man is more
                    simple, or less ostentatious, hating all pretension. It would be impossible for
                    an officer to be more reverenced, admired, and respected. He eats the ration of
                    the soldier and quarters alone in his tent. Without parade, haughtiness, or
                    assumption he is elevated in his thought and feeling, and is worthy of the cause
                    he represents and the army he commands. And now, I wish to say I have found
                    myself laboring under the odium of the little West Pointers in Richmond and
                    their partisans. They oppose me in the War Office at all points in regard to any
                    and every wish, and seek to drive me to a resignation. There is one favor I wish
                    you to do me.</p>
                <p>The horse that Maj. Monroe let me have on my receipt was taken possession of at
                    the river by Kelso, who was with Norton when we crossed the Mississippi. He also
                    took charge of my saddle and bridle. He returned to your command with this
                    horse, saddle, and bridle. If I do not resign I shall rejoin you, and I wish
                    this horse and accounterments secured by your quartermaster against my arrival,
                    and in any event my receipt for the horse to Maj. Monroe be canceled, so that
                    the claim will not come against me hereafter. I also got an ambulance from Maj.
                    Hill when I went to Texas. True, it was broken down and I did not receipt for
                    it, but doubtless it stands charged against me. Norton had it repaired and
                    returned to your command in this ambulance, and I returned with your son.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Please have this ambulance turned over to your quartermaster and
                        receipted for to me also, and believe me, as ever, very truly, your friend,</salute>
                    <signed>JOHN TYLER,<lb/> C. S. Army.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
