<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151759"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151759">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Walke, Isaac T.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151759</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499898</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Walke, Isaac T.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 758-759</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-08-22">1863-08-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151759T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Ordnance Officer Isaac T. Walke reports on damaged guns sent to
                    Staunton following the June-July, 1863, Gettysburg campaign.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Col. J. B. WALTON,<lb/> Chief of Artillery, First Army
                        Corps:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-08-22">August 22, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">ORDNANCE OFFICE, ARTILLERY FIRST CORPS,<lb/> ARMY OF NORTHERN VIRGINIA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>COL.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to make the following report of the disposition of the guns that
                    were "turned over, sent to the rear, and ordered to be abandoned" after the
                    battle of Gettysburg. In the communication of Lieut. Col. G. M. Sorrel to
                    yourself, dated July 19, which was referred to me for a report of the
                    disposition of the guns, the guns "turned over, sent to the rear, and ordered to
                    be abandoned" embrace the following: First, a Napoleon gun of the Washington
                    Artillery, sent to the rear; second, a 12-pounder howitzer of Dearing's
                    battalion, sent to the rear; third, a 12-pounder howitzer of Alexander's
                    battalion, sent to the rear; fourth, a 12-pounder howitzer of Washington
                    Artillery, sent to the rear; fifth, a 12-pounder howitzer of Henry's battalion,
                    injured, and turned over; sixth, a 3-inch rifle (manufactured at Rome, Ga.) of
                    Cabell's battalion, turned over; seventh, a 12-pounder howitzer of Alexander's
                    battalion, injured, and ordered to be abandoned; eight, a 3-inch rifle (Richmond
                    make) Henry's battalion, burst at Gettysburg. In obedience to orders from you to
                    ascertain, if practicable, the present position of these guns, I telegraphed on
                    August 4 to Maj. B. Randolph, ordnance officer at Staunton, Va., inquiring if
                    these guns were at that depot. I at the same time wrote to Maj. Randolph,
                    inquiring at some length about the guns and asking for the distinguishing marks
                    of the guns received at Staunton since the battle of Gettysburg to enable me to
                    identify those belonging to this corps. I received shortly afterward a telegram
                    from Lieut. Cosby, assistant ordnance officer at that post, which was altogether
                    unsatisfactory in the information it gave, and a few days later a letter, dated
                    August 7, accompanying a list of all the guns at Staunton. From this I could
                    only gain the number and character of the guns at that place. I sent you a
                    communication, dated the 9th instant, giving the result of my inquiries, and
                    received yours in reply, dated the 10th, with instructions to make further
                    inquiries about the guns and ascertain if possible what had become of them after
                    they passed out of the hands of this corps. I wrote to Lieut. Cosby August 10,
                    asking him to send me a list of the marks on all the Napoleons, Rome rifles, and
                    12-pounder brass howitzers at Staunton. His reply, dated the 17th, put me in
                    possession of the following facts: First, that the "injured Napoleon of the
                    Washington Artillery" was in Staunton, Va.; second, that the 12-pounder howitzer
                    of Alexander's battalion, "sent to the rear," was in Staunton; third, that the
                    12-pounder howitzer of the Washington Artillery, "sent to the rear," was in
                    Staunton; fourth, that the 12-pounder howitzer of Henry's battalion, "injured
                    and turned over," was in Staunton; fifth, that the 12-pounder howitzer of
                    Alexander's battalion, "injured and ordered to be abandoned," was in Staunton.
                    In reference to the other guns enumerated in the communication of Lieut.-Col.
                    Sorrel, I have to report that I have in my possession no history of the guns of
                    Dearing's battalion dated prior to the battle of Gettysburg. There were in
                    Staunton on the 7th instant fifteen bronze 12-pounder howitzers. I identified
                    four belonging to this corps. I have been unable to get from the battalion
                    ordnance officers of Dearing's battalion any description of this fifth howitzer
                    of that battalion which might enable me to identify it. It was very probably
                    included in the fifteen reported at Staunton. The 3-inch (Rome, Ga.) rifle of
                    Cabell's battalion has no distinguishing marks in the history of guns of that
                    battalion. There had been at the time of Lieut. Cosby's writing two 3-inch
                    (Rome, Ga.) rifles at Staunton. One had been sent to Richmond and the other had
                    been given to Jackson's battery. This gun was started by me from Bunker Hill
                    being a wagon its way to Staunton, and I am sure it reached its destination. The
                    3-inch rifle (Richmond make) of Henry's battalion that burst at Gettysburg,
                    burst on 2d of July and was left behind by order of Maj. Henry. I am informed
                    that all the guns which were in Staunton have lately been sent to Richmond.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I have the honor to be, with high respect, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>ISAAC T. WALKE,<lb/> Lieut. and Ordnance Officer, Artillery, First
                        Corps.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
