<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151182"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151182">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jackson, Henry R.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151182</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499825</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jackson, Henry R.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 181-182</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-07-20">1861-07-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151182T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In the first months of the war, Staunton, VA, served as an important rendezvous
                    point for Confederate troops on their way to defend what is now West Virginia.
                    In this July, 1861, dispatch, Confederate General Henry Jackson writes Assistant
                    Adjutant George Deas describing the state of the forces defending western
                    Virginia. He mentions regiments moving through Staunton, and discusses Staunton
                    quartermaster Michael Harman's role in organizing the defense.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Col. GEORGE DEAS,<lb/> Assistant Adjutant-Gen., C. S.
                        Army, Richmond, Va.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-07-20">July 20, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp at Monterey,</name><name type="location">BRIGADE HEADQUARTERS,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yesterday I received the letter of Gen. Lee of the 16th of July, unaccountably
                    delayed upon the road, in which he refers to the importance of defending the
                    mountain passes to prevent the advance of the enemy to the Central Railroad at
                    Millborough. I have been exceedingly anxious that the general should be apprised
                    by personal inspection of the indescribable condition into which this branch of
                    the army has fallen, and therefore have learned with great pain, through Maj.
                    Harman, that his contemplated movement toward this quarter has been delayed. I
                    can confidently say that of all the troops under my command the regiments from
                    Georgia and North Carolina are alone reliable and fit for service, all the rest
                    having been demoralized to a greater or less extent by our late disasters. The
                    condition of Col. Ramsey's command, the larger portion of which has arrived in
                    camp, is in truth pitiable. Officers and men are absolutely stripped of
                    everything-tents, clothing, cooking utensils, shoes-and I am sorry to believe
                    that many have thrown away their arms. Men and horses jaded, dispirited, half,
                    and limping, are wholly unfit for duty, and what disposition to make of them is
                    a most serious question. No re-enforcements have come up from below. The
                    Arkansas regiment, so long and anxiously looked for, did not leave Staunton
                    until yesterday. It certainly must be obvious at a glance that with the
                    available troops at hand little or nothing can be done, and yet, unless the
                    points referred to by the general be taken at once, they must pass into the
                    enemy's hands. Is the whole country thus to be surrendered? A glance at the map
                    will show that to prevent the advance of the enemy at least two routes toward
                    the east must be at once held-the one upon which we now are and the turnpike
                    from Huttonsville through Huntersville to Millborough. My letter of yesterday
                    will have informed you that I have sent forward a small but comparatively
                    well-organized force to occupy the Alleghany pass on the former, with the faint
                    hope that they might ascertain by reconnoitering that the Cheat pass had as yet
                    been neglected by the enemy, and by a forced march at night might throw
                    themselves into it. This movement, contemplated by me from the first, had been
                    delayed by the sickness of Col. Johnson, who, it is needless to say, had been my
                    main reliance. I am sorry to say that he is still unwell and unable to sustain
                    the advance by his presence. The inhabitants of Pocahontas, through which the
                    other route passes, are said to be loyal. Those of them who are not already in
                    Gen. Wise's brigade are flying, or are disposed to fly, to arms. But they appeal
                    for assistance and ask not to be abandoned. Under these circumstances, weak as I
                    am, the receipt of the general's letter decided me at once to send the Sixth
                    North Carolina Regt. into Pocahontas and to the Elk Mountain pass, said to be
                    defensible, accompanied by the Bath County Cavalry. I have taken the liberty of
                    countermanding the proclamation of Maj. Harman calling upon the militia of
                    Pocahontas and adjacent counties to rendezvous at Staunton. Have directed that
                    they rendezvous at Huntersville; have sent them powder for their rifles; have
                    ordered them to go at once against the enemy, to blockade the road from
                    Huttonsville to Elk Mountain by felling trees before him, and to beset his
                    flanks from the adjacent woods and fastnesses. I have also written to Maj.
                    Harman to send one of the regiments at Staunton by the railroad and Millborough
                    in the same direction, and shall make arrangements at Huntersville for their
                    supplies. I think the general will perceive that in comparison with my resources
                    I have undertaken a vast deal, and yet what else was to be done? I must either
                    advance or retreat from this point. To advance may be dangerous; to retreat
                    would be ruinous, since the whole country, thus apparently abandoned, would
                    probably turn from us to receive the enemy with open arms. I must be excused,
                    therefore, for praying most earnestly that attention be turned in this
                    direction; that re-enforcements of all kinds be forwarded at once; that some one
                    more competent than I be placed in charge of these complicated operations; or
                    that, if this cannot be, the necessary staff officers be sent to my assistance,
                    since, without any exaggeration, apart from the anxieties of my position, flesh
                    and blood cannot long stand the mere detail imposed upon me.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>HENRY R. JACKSON,<lb/> Brig.-Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
