<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151108582"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R151108582">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence. </title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Parker, Richard</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151108582</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499807</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Parker, Richard</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 58-59</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-04-30">1861-04-30</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151108582T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Citizens of Winchester write Robert E. Lee in April, 1861, to complain of the
                    lack of defenses along Virginia's northwestern border. They express fear of a
                    Union build-up of forces at Chambersburg, and describe the state of Confederate
                    forces in the area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj.-Gen. LEE:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-04-30">April 30, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">WINCHESTER,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>DEAR SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>As citizens of the town of Winchester we deem it our duty to call your attention
                    to the defenseless condition of the place and of all the region of country which
                    lies between this and the Pennsylvania border, the quarter from which an attack
                    on this part of Virginia is to be apprehended. Our distance from the
                    Pennsylvania line is not over forty miles, and at Chambersburg, within a day's
                    travel, we are informed a large force of Northern troops is concentrating,
                    already numbering, as reported, 5,000, and with daily accessions. If the enemy
                    is designed for offensive operations, their destination is doubtless the Valley
                    of Virginia, which may be reached at Harper's Ferry, Shepherdstown, or
                    Martinsburg, where there are bridges, ferries, and turnpike roads, to say
                    nothing of intermediate points and points higher up the Potomac, where the
                    transit across Maryland is only a few miles; at one place (Hancock) only one
                    mile and a half. To repel this invasion, should it come, we have at Harper's
                    Ferry, all told, no over 2,500 troops, made up promiscuously of raw and
                    uninstructed volunteers, who have entered the service at a moment's warning,
                    without arms or uniforms, and some pretty well armed and drilled companies. To
                    form this force at the Ferry, all the organized companies of this part of the
                    Valley have been required, so that this town and other towns above mentioned,
                    and the whole line of frontier from Harper's Ferry to the head of the Potomac,
                    is utterly defenseless. To repel an enemy at this point we have in and about the
                    town no artillery, not fifty muskets, and literally no arms of any kind. We have
                    remaining in the town a company of aged and middle-aged men, organized into what
                    is called the home guard, ready to fight to the death in defense of their homes,
                    but with nothing to fight with. In the neighboring country, which is populous,
                    there is a large force of the ordinary militia, but wholly undisciplined,
                    unorganized, and unarmed, and they have no officers who have any training or
                    efficiency for active service. We submit these facts to your consideration and
                    commend them to your earnest and anxious attention. If devastation and plunder
                    are to form a part of the system of this war, this is certainly an inviting
                    field for it. This was selected as the theater of John Brown's raid, and if the
                    destruction of slavery and the liberation of slaves is an object with our enemy,
                    as it is proclaimed to be a chief object, these northern troops will be apt to
                    follow the footsteps of their great file leader. We make free to suggest that
                    good drill officers be sent in sufficient numbers to this section of country,
                    around whom volunteer companies can be rallied, and above all, that arms and
                    ammunition be promptly furnished to men who are willing to fight but in their
                    condition are perfectly impotent. In the article of ammunition we are even more
                    deficient than in arms.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>RICHARD PARKER.<lb/><lb/> J. H. SHERRARD.<lb/><lb/> P.
                        WILLIAMS.<lb/><lb/> D. W. BARTON.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
