<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R1511087"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R1511087">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii union correspondence</title>
        <author>Milroy, Robert H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R1511087</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499809</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii union correspondence</title>
            <author>Milroy, Robert H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 107</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 1087-1088</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-13">1863-09-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R1511087T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General Robert Milroy writes Abraham Lincoln in September, 1863, concerning
                    his thoughts on the army, strategy, and his desire for a command in Texas.
                    Milroy stresses to Lincoln the importance of the Shenandoah Valley as a source
                    of supply for the Confederacy, and declares that it should be held all the way
                    to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">President LINCOLN:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-13">September 13, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">WASHINGTON CITY, D. C.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>DEAR SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I hope you will pardon this intrusion upon your valuable time. I know you would
                    if you could see my motives. There are many things I wished to say to you this
                    morning which my want of self-esteem and your apparent desire to end the
                    interview prevented. God knows that my strongest desire is to assist you to the
                    best of my ability in your mighty task, the most important that ever devolved of
                    man, that of saving and restoring the great model Government of earth. I will
                    but briefly to a few of the most important points which I desired to speak of.
                    You in your exalted station can only be informed of army matters through
                    official sources, which through selfishness are often unreliable, and therefore
                    are not made aware of many things that need reform. The use intoxicating liquor
                    as a beverage is prohibited to soldiers; why not also prohibit its use to
                    officers. The use of intoxicating liquor in our army is enormous among the
                    officers, and drunkenness among them from the generals to second lieutenants
                    very common, and a very great evil to the service, and should be reformed. I
                    would suggest that a general order be issued prohibiting its use by any person
                    in the service of the United States as a beverage under penalty, if an officer
                    of prompt dismissal from service, and get rid of some of these "bulls" extra.
                    Another point I wished to mention is the vast importance of holding the
                    Shenandoah Valley. Having been campaigning two years in the vicinity of that
                    valley and west of it, I know it to be the Egypt of Virginia, from whence the
                    greater part of the subsistence of Lee's army is drawn. It should be seized and
                    held from Martinsburg to Staunton, a matter I would be pleased to do if provided
                    with a proper command. Again, in your letter to me of June 29, you speak of my
                    "chafing acting the part assigned" me by me superior officers, I wish to say on
                    this point that you have been misinformed and don't know me. I have believed
                    that the best interests of the country required that the rebellion should be
                    speedily crushed and peace restored, and that this could only be attained by
                    following up our blows upon the enemy one after the other with rapidity, never
                    giving them time to recover. You are aware that this is Hoosier and Sucker
                    tactics, but I have discovered that it is not West Point science. I confess I
                    have often expressed and felt great importance at being restrained from
                    striking, and at the slow progress made in the great work of striking a blow and
                    waiting six months to study its effect. Another point is, I would be greatly
                    pleased to be restored to the command of my old division. All its commissioned
                    officers with two or three exceptions have petitioned you asking it, as also the
                    Union citizens of the valley. If this cannot be granted, I would for many
                    reasons desire a command in Texas. I have traveled through and resided there for
                    a time and became a naturalized citizen there before the annexation. I would be
                    greatly pleased to help avenge the terrible wrongs of Union citizens on the
                    monsters, and desire to be down there when the rebellion ends, to be ready to
                    pitch into the French in Mexico. Another point is, if you leave my assignment to
                    a command to Gen. Halleck I will get none. I pray you order this yourself or
                    direct the Secretary of War to do it. I will take any command rather than be
                    idle.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With great respect, your most obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>R. H. MILROY,<lb/> Maj.-Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
