<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151424"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151424">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Smith, Francis H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151424</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499880</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Smith, Francis H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 424</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-12-19">1861-12-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151424T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Superintendent of the Virginia Military Institute Francis H. Smith writes
                    Virginia Governor John Letcher in December, 1861, concerning the reopening of
                    the academy. Smith requests that the commissary at Staunton be instructed to
                    sell him food and supplies for the incoming cadets.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">His Excellency JOHN LETCHER,<lb/> Governor of Virginia:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-12-19">December 19, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">HDQRS. VIRGINIA MILITARY INSTITUTE,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GOVERNOR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>You are aware that the Board of Visitors of this institution, in response to the
                    public demand, and acting under the expressed wishes of the President of the
                    Confederate States, have directed the reopening of the school on the 1st of
                    January next. On that day it will be reopened with 250 cadets. In making the
                    necessary preliminary arrangements for supplies, I find great difficulty in
                    securing the transportation of groceries, from the fact that the Confederate
                    Government, very properly, has the preference for its own supplies. In view of
                    these difficulties, and of the importance of the continued operation of the
                    Military Institute to the military defenses of our common country, I
                    respectfully request that you will solicit from the War Department an order upon
                    the commissary at Staunton to supply me, upon requisition, such an amount of
                    groceries, at cost for cash, as may be required for the conduct of the school,
                    and upon like terms as such supplies are now issued to officers. I would add
                    that besides the general benefit which the Confederate Government is receiving
                    from the Military Institute, there is at this time the special one of a
                    cartridge laboratory, with forty operatives, making some 10,000 cartridges per
                    day, and the order which I have requested will facilitate this important branch
                    of the Ordnance Department of the Confederate States. I will also take this
                    occasion to say that in reopening the Military Institute, during the pendency of
                    the war, the great purposes of the school may be much promoted by some
                    arrangement with the Confederate Government by which a board of examiners may be
                    detailed by the War Department to attend each annual examination, and select
                    from the graduating class such cadets as in the judgment of the board may be
                    found worthy to be recommended to the President for the commission of brevet
                    second lieutenants in the various corps of the Army. Such an arrangement will
                    not only provide the Army with a select number of educated young officers to the
                    extent that may be demanded, but will operate as a most salutary stimulus to the
                    industry and order of the cadets. I ask no exclusive privilege for the Military
                    Institute, and suggest this as one of the ways in which the largest and most
                    efficient military school of the South may be made most effective for the public
                    service. I do not know what legislation, if any, may be necessary should this
                    suggestion meet with favor with the President, but his intimate acquaintance
                    with the subject, in all its bearings, will enable him to point out the best
                    mode of carrying out the plan.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain, Governor, very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>FRANCIS H. SMITH,<lb/> Maj.-Gen. and Superintendent Virginia Military
                        Institute.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
