<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R151550"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R151550">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Stuart, Alex H. H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R151550</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499881</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. LXIII. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap lxiii confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Stuart, Alex H. H.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 51, Serial No. 108</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 550-551</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-29">1862-04-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R151550T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Alexander H. H. Stuart writes Confederate Secretary of War George Randolph in
                    April, 1862, to stress the importance of protecting the Shenandoah Valley as a
                    base of supply for Confederate armies. Stuart discusses Augusta county's crop
                    production, and estimates stores and yields. He also mentions important
                    industries in Staunton. Stuart also informs Randolph that many Augusta County
                    farmers wonder just how much to plant, if their crop will only be captured by
                    the enemy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. GEORGE W. RANDOLPH:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-04-29">April 29, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">STAUNTON,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>DEAR SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In a postscript to a letter which I addressed to you some days ago I adverted to
                    the propriety of retaining possession of the upper part of the Valley. I hope
                    you will pardon me for presenting somewhat more fully my views on that subject.
                    In looking to our future military operations and the probability that the
                    Federal forces will, as the sickly season advances, be withdrawn from the Gulf
                    States and concentrated in Virginia (which will involve the necessity of our
                    doing the same), the question presents itself, how are our armies to be fed? The
                    supply of beef and pork from Texas and West will be cut off, and we will be
                    compelled to rely on our home supplies. The counties of Augusta, Rockingham, and
                    Rockbridge now abound with supplies of wheat, flour, corn, pork, bacon, cattle
                    and sheep. Last year's crop of corn and wheat were the largest ever raised in
                    those counties, and the growing crops are remarkably promising. The invasion of
                    the western counties compelled the inhabitants to drive their stock to the
                    Valley, and thus we have on hand a double supply of cattle, hogs and sheep. An
                    intelligent man, well acquainted with the subject, told me this morning that not
                    less than 100,000 sheep had been brought into Augusta produces near 500,000
                    bushels of what, and as much corn. Last year's crop was estimated to be 33 1/3
                    per cent. over an average crop. The stoppage of all the distilleries has left
                    large supplies of corn in our cribs, and the difficulty of procuring
                    transportation has compelled the farmers to retain most of their wheat and
                    flour. These facts will show that we have in our country a vast surplus of
                    provisions, which will be greatly augmented when the growing crop matures, sixty
                    days hence. Should the enemy get possession of the upper Valley they will gain
                    supplies sufficient to maintain a large army for twelve months to come. If, on
                    the other hand, we can drive them out, these supplies can be applied to the
                    sustenance of our own troops. A very intelligent gentlemen who was employed to
                    purchase flour for the Government, and who in his official capacity traversed
                    Jefferson, Berkeley, Clarke and Loudoun, told me he thought there were 1,000,000
                    bushels of wheat in those four counties. The people have almost two entire crops
                    on hand. All this had fallen into the hands of the enemy, who are now rapidly
                    removing it to Maryland. The surrender of Frederick, Warren, Shenandoah, Hardy,
                    Page, and Rockingham involves the loss of as much more. If, now, we lose the
                    remaining grain counties of the Valley I do not see where our supplies are to
                    come from. The commissariat department has, I think, been injudiciously managed,
                    as large supplies of flour, corn, &amp;c., have been brought here from
                    Eastern Virginia, while our own granaries have been teeming with abundance. It
                    seems to me that an effort ought to be made, if possible, to regain possession
                    of Rockingham and Shenandoah before the enemy can remove the provisions from
                    those counties. High waters and bad roads have prevented them from accomplishing
                    much in the way of removal thus far. If you could not throw 10,000 or 15,000
                    troops, in addition to the commands of Jackson and Ewell into the Valley about
                    Luray, it would be practicable to cut off and possibly capture the army of
                    Banks. The stores of provisions would thus be secured, and if we are obliged to
                    abandon the valley, it should be postponed, if possible, until the next harvest
                    is secured. The abandonment of the upper Valley also involves the loss of our
                    most valuable iron-works, many woolen factories, and the shoe factory here that
                    supplies 100 pairs of boots and shoes per day. The corn-planting season has
                    arrived, and in the present state of uncertainty our farmers do not know what to
                    do. Some of them talk of planting but ten or twenty acres, as they are
                    determined no to contribute to the support of the enemy. If they had any
                    intimation that they could do so with security, they would make. It seems to me
                    also that a strong demonstration in the lower Valley would create a beneficial
                    diversion in favor of Richmond. I hope you will pardon the freedom of this
                    communication. It is dictated by an earnest desire to promote the public
                    intersects, and I offer that as my apology.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>ALEX. H. H. STUART.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
