<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R155900"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R155900">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Baldwin, John</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R155900</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499951</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Baldwin, John</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 5, Serial No. 5</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 899-900</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-10-16">1861-10-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R155900T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Colonel John Baldwin writes Secretary of War Judah P. Benjamin
                    concerning the state of supply facing his men in the Alleghany Mountains in
                    October, 1861. Baldwin states that Staunton is one of the only reliable sources
                    of supply, and discusses the route to the town.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. J. P. BENJAMIN, Acting Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-10-16">October 16, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Top of Alleghany Mountains,</name><name type="location">CAMP OF FIFTY-SECOND VIRGINIA REGT.S,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Having been stationed at this place with my regiment for two weeks past, I hope
                    it will not be considered a violation of any of the rules of the service if I
                    address to you directly a suggestion or two, involving, as I believe, the safety
                    of my command and of all the Confederate forces on this time.</p>
                <p>You are no doubt aware that the army on this line cannot depend upon the
                    surrounding country for supplies of any kind. The country at the best is
                    sparsely populated, and produces no surplus of any kind of provision except live
                    stock, and the troubles of the times have brought upon the people an unusual
                    scarcity of all kinds of supplies. The only points from which any supply of food
                    or forage has been drawn in the past are the Hardy Valley and the region about
                    Staunton, and there is no other promise for the future so far as I know. As to
                    the Hardy Valley, the supply has been much interrupted by incursions of the
                    enemy, who have succeeded in capturing some of our trains and have produced men
                    to engage in the transportation of supplies to our army. At the best the
                    distance from this point to Petersburg is at least 70 miles, and the road one
                    which in winter would hardly be practicable for loaded wagons. As to the other
                    route, from Staunton, the distance to this point is 60 miles, and to the
                    principal camp at Greenbrier River is 68. The road in summer is good, but in
                    winter may fairly be said to be impassable for wagons, and even now is in such a
                    condition as to require the constant services of a large force to keep it in a
                    tolerable condition. Since I have been stationed at this rations of corn, and
                    for nearly all the time they have been wholly without forage of any kind. They
                    are now subsisting upon the only hay to be procured within 10 miles of the camp,
                    and that supply is only for a very few days.</p>
                <p>I by no means seek to obtain information which in the discretion of my superior
                    officers is withheld from me, but if it is the purpose of the Government to
                    retain troops upon this line, it seems to me to be of high, concern to know that
                    a single snow-storm, such as is by no means uncommon in these mountains at this
                    season, would starve every horse in this army, and, unless the other troops are
                    supplied differently from my regiment, would seriously endanger the entire
                    command. Independent of any of these considerations I deem it proper to state
                    that the advance of the season admonishes us of the rapid and near approach of
                    winter. Two weeks from to-day the winter in these mountains may be said to have
                    set in. As yet there is no preparation for the wintering of troops here; no huts
                    or houses have been prepared, nor can any be found in this region already built.
                    I have upon my own responsibility instituted inquiries for the tools necessary
                    to enable my men to build for themselves if required, and to my surprise and
                    alarm I find that we have not in this army enough tools of the most common kind
                    to enable us to use the timber which is so abundant all around us. Already the
                    weather has been such as to freeze the tents of my regiment solid after a
                    soaking rain and to coat the water in vessels with thick ice, and I am satisfied
                    that this is not more than what may be expected at this season in these
                    mountains. If, as I have stated, it is the purpose to retain troops here for the
                    winter, measures cannot be too promptly or energetically taken and pressed for
                    putting them into habitable winter quarters. These facts and my impressions upon
                    them I have felt bound to communicate as a part of my duty to the Government and
                    to the regiment, composed of my neighbors and friends, which has been instructed
                    to my care.</p>
                <p>I hope I shall not be understood as disposed to avoid any fair share of the
                    labors and sacrifices which must fall upon all engaged in our national defense.
                    My men have made no complaint, but are looking forward with calm confidence in
                    the provident care of the Government.</p>
                <p>I trust their confidence will be fully justified in their future history.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JOHN B. BALDWIN,<lb/> Col. Fifty-second Virginia Regt.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
