<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R155956"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R155956">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Johnston, Joseph E.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R155956</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499961</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Johnston, Joseph E.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 5, Serial No. 5</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 955-956</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-11-16">1861-11-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R155956T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Joseph E. Johnston writes Secretary of War Judah P. Benjamin
                    on the November, 1861, strategic situation in northern Virginia. Johnston
                    expresses the hope that troops from Staunton can be moved to aid him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. J. P. Benjamin, Acting Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-11-16">November 16, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Centreville, HDQRS.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I respectfully inclose herewith copies of two letters just received from
                    Brig.-Gen. Whiting. His officer, with his town brigade and three Texan regiments
                    of Wogfall's brigade, is in the neighbourhood of Dumfries. I have directed that
                    the three new regiments shall be added to this force-those coming via
                    Fredericksburg.</p>
                <p>My object in laying these letters before you is to show the importance of
                    additional re-enforcement to enable Brig.-Gen. Whiting to defeat such attempts
                    of the enemy as he expects. If you have any disposable troops, I venture to
                    assert that no more important object can be found for their employed. Superior
                    numbers and the control of the river and possession of a great number of
                    vessels, give the United States troops in Maryland opposite to Evansport great
                    advantages over us. Should he (the enemy) establish himself on our shore in
                    force, he will so intrench himself in a few hours as to make it impossible to
                    dislodge him, and we shall soon have a fortified army on our right flank. The
                    condition of the roads is now such from the rains, unusual at this season, that
                    the troops here cannot move with such facility as to be able to guard this
                    position and watch the Lower Occoquan and shore of the Potomac near its mount.
                    We have great difficulty in transporting our supplies from Manassas even. It is
                    necessary, therefore, in order to prevent the apprehended landing of the enemy,
                    that we should have as nearly as possible a sufficient number of troops to repel
                    the enemy on the Occoquan or the bank of the Potomac. It would be impossible to
                    march from this position in time to aid Brig.-Gen. Whiting after learning the
                    enemy's designs, which could only be known after his movements should be
                    commenced.</p>
                <p>Should the enemy establish a new base on the river below the Occoquan in the
                    manner indicated above, it would be impossible to hold this position. The
                    superiority of numbers against us makes it impracticable to divide this army.
                    This position cannot be given up upon any conjuncture of the enemy's designs. I
                    therefore respectfully urge that any disposable troops you may have be ordered
                    to this army for service under Gen. Writing. Should they be at Richmond, the
                    Fredericksburg road would be most expeditious for a part of the force at least.</p>
                <p>The Adjutant-Gen. informed me that 6,000 or 7,000 of Gen. Lorning's troops would
                    be near Staunton about his time. They might serve here during the crisis, and
                    afterward perform the service for which they have been intended.</p>
                <p>This will be delivered to you by Lieut. Lane, son of the late United States
                    Senator from Oregon.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>J. E. JOHNSTON,<lb/> Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
