<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R155984"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R155984">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Loring, William W.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R155984</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499977</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Loring, William W.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 5, Serial No. 5</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 983-984</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-11-29">1861-11-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R155984T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General William Loring reports on the situation facing his armies
                    defending western Virginia in November, 1861. Loring mentions the need to move
                    supplies, ammunition and sick men away from the front to Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-11-29">November 29, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Huntersville, va.,</name><name type="location">HDQRS. NORTHWESTERN ARMY,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your letter of the 24th instant,
                    inclosing one from Maj.-Gen. Jackson, when on a tour of inspection to my
                    hospital in rear.</p>
                <p>The policy of marching a force from Winchester or that vicinity in the direction
                    of Romney was the subject of conversation between Gen. Lee and myself during the
                    recent campaign of this purpose.</p>
                <p>I consider a winter campaign practicable if the means of transportation
                    sufficient to move this army can be obtained, and especially in a country where
                    supplies are abundant, which I am informed in the communication inclosed in your
                    letter is the case in that section of Western Virginia where it is proposed to
                    operate. With warm clothing good tents, and proper attention by the regimental
                    and company officers there need be no suffering from the climate in that region.</p>
                <p>I consider that it is proper that I should place you the present disposition of
                    this army, made with to the defense of our extended line. The passes now guarded
                    are at Alleghany on the Staunton and at Huntersville on the Millborough
                    turnpike, besides the approaches on the right in front of Franklin and on the
                    left from Summersville and that section on the Lewisburg and Marlin Bottom
                    turnpike-the whole distance between one and two hundred miles. The enemy is
                    strongly fortified on Cheat Mountain, and at Crouche's, on this turnpike, and
                    had a short time since about 8,000 men at and near these places. To-day reliable
                    returned from the vicinity of these point, and report the enemy are moving
                    several regiments, they (the enemy) say in the direction of Kentucky and Gen.
                    Floyd, but it is believed by the people their destination is Romney, in
                    consequence of an apprehended attack from Gen. Jackson, now at Winchester. It
                    may be observed that a campaign from Winchester against the enemy at Romney is
                    the subject of conversation among the people from Petersburg to this place, and
                    yesterday I received an express from Gen. Boggs, asking a regiment to aid him in
                    forcing the militia of Pendleton Country to turn out for that purpose. The
                    troops here and at Alleghany have nearly completed their huts, and, as now
                    located, it is believed could be subsisted through the winter. Owing to the
                    difficulty of procuring means of transportation and to the present state of the
                    roads, it will require, with every exertion, two, possible three, weeks to
                    remove to the rear the troops, a large sick report, and a considerable amount of
                    munitions not needed on the campaign.</p>
                <p>In order to conceal, as far as possible, the movements of the army, I think it
                    best to send the troops on this line to Millborough, and thence by rail to
                    Strasburg; these at Monterey either direct to Moorefield or to Strasburg via
                    Staunton. The forces at Monterey will check any advance on that line, if
                    attempted, and be in readiness to move as indicated. If the road from Strasburg
                    is practicable, the command ordered there could act with that from Moorefield;
                    it impracticable, with that from Winchester.</p>
                <p>I do not think that a movement of the army could be kept fully concealed from the
                    enemy, because the Union men have numerous rations throughout this region, and
                    will, notwithstanding the utmost vigilance, obtain information. If the purpose
                    of the withdrawal of this column can be disguised until that at Monterey shall
                    have been fully prepared, the desired object may be effected by a rapid
                    movement. I shall not, therefore, commence the march till sufficient
                    transportation can be procured for the whole command. In the mean time (orders
                    have been give therefor) the sick and public property not needed for the
                    cavalry, which you suggest be left to protect the country against marauding
                    parties, will be removed to the rear as rapidly as possible. It appears that
                    Gen. Jackson anticipates a sudden movement of this command. With the utmost
                    exertion on our part it is impossible to effect it in less time than that
                    heretofore stated. There is a large quantity of ammunition, and from two hundred
                    and fifty to two hundred and sixty thousand pounds of subsistence stores at this
                    depot, reserve of ammunition at Warm Springs, and a large number of sick in
                    hospital at the springs between this and the railroad. All of these must be
                    transferred to Staunton, and transportation collected here, before the movement
                    can be made.</p>
                <p>As I consider prompt after starting of much importance, and as my suggestions
                    differ somewhat from those contained in the letter of Gen. Jackson, I deem it
                    proper to submit these suggestions to you, and ask for them your attention and
                    opinion before perfecting my arrangements.</p>
                <p>If, upon consideration of affairs on this line you should desire the proposed
                    campaign to be prosecuted, be assured that I shall enter into it with a spirit
                    to secured, and will be seconded by a command as ardent in the cause as any in
                    the country, and who will cheerfully endure all the hardships incident to a
                    winter campaign.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With respect, I have the honor to be, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>W. W. LORING,<lb/> Brig. Gen., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
