<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R155745"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R155745">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xiv union correspondence</title>
        <author>Rosecrans, William S.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R155745</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499941</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XIV. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xiv union correspondence</title>
            <author>Rosecrans, William S.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 5, Serial No. 5</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 744-746</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-03-12">1862-03-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R155745T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General William S. Rosecrans outlines plans for operations in the
                    Shenandoah Valley, including Staunton and Augusta County, in March, 1862.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Brig. Gen. L. THOMAS,<lb/> Adjutant-Gen. U. S. Army,
                        Washington, D. C.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-03-12">March 12, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Wheeling</name><name type="location">HDQRS. DEPARTMENT OF WESTERN VIRGINIA,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Since the valley of Virginia, except the valleys of Great and Little Cacapon and
                    of the Shenandoah, had been added to the limits of this department, I beg leave
                    to submit for the consideration of the Secretary of War a project of operations
                    deemed feasible within the limits of this department:</p>
                <p>1. The exclusion of Rockbridge and Augusta Counties, containing Lexington and
                    Staunton, leaves nothing to be done on our eastern limits but to expel the eight
                    rebel forces of, say, 3,500 men, from the valley, to occupy the passes on main
                    roads, hold the important points with forces sufficient to guard them, and
                    tranquilize the country. This should be done by a force moving from Cumberland,
                    New Creek, &amp;c., up the valley of the South Branch of the Potomac, via
                    Franklin and Dunwiddie's Gap, to capture if possible the rebel forces at Fort
                    Alleghany, on the Beverly and Staunton turnpike. The main force at Huttonsville
                    should co-operate with this, leaving a sufficient guard against a flank movement
                    by Gen. Heth, who commands at Lewisburg and Huntersville.</p>
                <p>The force required for this operation from Cumberland should be four regiments of
                    infantry, one of cavalry, and a good battery of artillery, of which three
                    regiments of infantry and the one of cavalry are still required. The conduct of
                    this column should be such, if possible, as to cut off the retreat of the rebel
                    troops on Staunton, and when the Beverly road is in our hands the troops on
                    Cheat Pass should unite with this column, seize the railroad at Millborough, and
                    act as occasion may require towards the rebel forces in the direction of
                    Staunton and Lexington, while we in sufficient force seize Warm Springs and
                    Jackson River Depot, cutting off the retreat eastward of any rebel troops that
                    may be in Greenbier.</p>
                <p>The general commanding should be charged with the restoration of law, order, and
                    confidence in the Government of the United States, and should the rebels hold
                    their ground east of the Blue Ridge, to guard the great passes from East to West
                    Virginia against unexpected projects or reverses of our arms.</p>
                <p>Second objective, by a simultaneous movements, begun with the least practicable
                    delay, should be from Gauley Brigade to seize Lewisburg, White Sulphur, and to
                    strike the Southwestern Virginia and Tennessee Railroad at some point between
                    Bonsack's and Salem, the nearer Bonsack's the better. This column should consist
                    of a force sufficient to expel Heth, hold Greenbier, protect the depots there,
                    and hold the railroad with 2,000 men, a field battery, and a couple of squadrons
                    of cavalry. They should establish and garrison depots at Lewisburg and Union.</p>
                <p>A third objective would be holding Fayette, to establish a depot at Raleigh, and
                    from thence seize the railroad at Wytheville or Newbern, hold it in force
                    against the rebels, and pacify the country there immediately.</p>
                <p>Fourth object. The force now on Big Sandy can be supplied with provisions by
                    small steamboat navigation in time of high water to Pikeville, whence it is 88
                    miles over bad roads to Baker's Station, on the Southwestern Virginia and
                    Tennessee Railroad. This column should move by the Louisa Ford to Buchanan and
                    Jeffersonville, seize the Northwest Virginia Branch Bank there, and thence take
                    possession of the railroad at the Salt Works. Should the rebels be at Pound Gap
                    a demonstration of a movement should be made and watched to keep the attention
                    of them, while the main column, pursuing the route indicated, would seize the
                    railroad and cut off the retreat of these rebel forces.</p>
                <p>These forces once in the valley, Wytheville, Abingdon, Newbern, &amp;c., all
                    succumb. Troops purchase what they need for subsistence.</p>
                <p>The estimated force requisite for all these purposes, based on the assumption
                    that rebel capacity for local mischief in these regions should what we now have,
                    would be:</p>
                <p>For the Cumberland column-Three regiments of infantry, one regiment of cavalry,
                    and one battery of artillery.</p>
                <p>For Cheat Pass--One regiment of infantry.</p>
                <p>For Kanawha--One regiment of infantry and one battery of artillery.</p>
                <p>For Big Sandy--One regiment of infantry.</p>
                <p>Total--Six regiments of infantry, one regiment of cavalry, and two field
                    batteries, the most important of which are the three regiments of infantry and
                    one of cavalry at Cumberland. They should be sent there without delay. Should
                    they be ordered from an adjoining State, time could be gained by sending forward
                    all troops on the railroad except those strictly requisite to guard the railroad
                    line and the depots. Should the rebel forces east of the Blue Ridge fall back
                    towards Lynchburg, retaining their organization and force, as now seems
                    possible, I would advise strengthening the Lewisburg column so as to make and
                    effective force of from 12,000 to 15,000 men, with orders to seize the
                    Southwestern Virginia and Tennessee Railroad, and make a strong demonstration on
                    Lynchburg, seizing it if opportunity offers. On this supposition an additional
                    force of 6,000 or 8,00 men should be thrown into the great valley, to occupy
                    August and Rockbridge and watch the passes through the Blue Ridge there and
                    southward.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>W. S. ROSECRANS,<lb/> Brig.-Gen., U. S. Army.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
