<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R155937"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R155937">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R155937</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:499955</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAP. XIV. Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">chap xiv confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Jackson, Thomas J.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 1, Volume 5, Serial No. 5</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 937</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-11-05">1861-11-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R155937T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate General Thomas J. Jackson writes to Secretary of War Judah P.
                    Benjamin in November, 1861, regarding the strategic situation in the Shenandoah
                    Valley, including the Staunton area.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. J. P. BENJAMIN, Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-11-05">November 5, 1861.</date>
                        <name type="place">Winchester,</name><name type="location">HDQRS. VALLEY DISTRICT,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>SIR:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yesterday morning I received the order from Gen. J. E. Johnston directing me to
                    assume command of this district, and, leaving Manassas by the first train of
                    cars, arrived here last night.</p>
                <p>A prisoner who has escaped from the Federal authorities at Williamsport, Md.,
                    states that there are about 1,200 of the enemy ready to cross the Potomac so
                    soon as the river shall be fordable. Lieut. Col. Turner Ashby, of the cavalry,
                    reports that additional troops have been moving up the river recently. The most
                    reliable information received from Romney makes the enemy's strength there near
                    4,000, and from the last official intelligence they are threatening an advance
                    on this place.</p>
                <p>Deeply impressed with the importance of not only holding Winchester, but also of
                    repelling the invaders from this district before they shall secure a firm
                    lodgment, I feel it my duty respectfully to urge upon the Department the
                    necessity of ordering here at once all the troops at Cheat Mountain, and if
                    practicable those also from Valley Mountain, or those near Huntersville. I have
                    frequently traveled over the road from Staunton to Cheat Mountain, and I hope
                    that you will pardon me for saying that if the withdrawal of the Confederate
                    forces from the Cheat Mountain region shall induce the enemy to advance on
                    Staunton it will be his ruin, provided a sufficient available force is kept in
                    this district in marching order. It is very important that disciplined troops of
                    not only infantry, but also of artillery and cavalry be ordered here. It appears
                    to me that there should be at least twenty pieces of field artillery, with their
                    complement of horses, harness, implements, &amp;c., assigned to this
                    command. It will be seen from the accompanying list of ordnance and ammunition
                    that Gen. Carson's command only had three field pieces. Gen. Carson also reports
                    to me that he has in service only 1,461 militia, in addition to 130 mounted
                    militia.</p>
                <p>The detailed instructions referred to in your letter announcing my assignment to
                    this command have not yet been received.</p>
                <p>The heavy guns here are but imperfectly available for defense, in consequence of
                    not having officers and men acquainted with the method of serving them. If you
                    can order here Lieut. Daniel Truehart, jr., or some other good artillery
                    officer, to take charge of the heavy ordnance, the efficiency of this arm of the
                    service will be greatly increased. A good engineer officer is very desirable. I
                    have ordered Gen.'s Carson, Meen, and Boggs to march their commands here
                    forthwith.</p>
                <p>Lieut. Col. J. T. L. Preston, Virginia volunteers, the bearer of this letter,
                    will give you a full statement respecting the defenseless condition of this
                    place.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>T. J. JACKSON,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., P. A. C. S.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
