<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R271208502"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R271208502">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">POW. Union Correspondence. </title>
        <title type="sort">pow union correspondence</title>
        <author>Hamilton, James</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R271208502</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500003</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>POW. Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">pow union correspondence</title>
            <author>Hamilton, James</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 2, Volume 7, Serial No. 120</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 849-850</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-09-02">1864-09-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R271208502T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>James Hamilton writes Secretary of War Edwin M. Stanton in September, 1864,
                    concerning his time at Salisbury, North Carolina, where he was held by the
                    Confederacy as a citizen prisoner. Hamilton, who requests a response at
                    Chambersburg, claims that he was released after promising to help secure the
                    release of Confederate citizens held by the Union. In this letter, Hamilton
                    attempts to act on his promise, and asks the government to secure freedom for
                    the remaining Pennsylvania citizens held in the South. Hamilton also mentions
                    the controversial issue of exchanges for African American POW's held by the
                    Confederacy.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon. E. M. STANTON, Secretary of War:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-09-02">September 2, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">WASHINGTON,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>DEAR SIR: Mr. Culbertson and I were prisoners for thirteen months, held as
                    hostages. Ould alleges that you hold citizens on insufficient or no charges who
                    are not connected with military organizations. He released us because we
                    promised to try to effect the release of Smithson and Reverend Doctor Handy. We
                    were told that you consent to the release of Handy. Ould proposed to release all
                    civilians and capture no more. He proposes to exchange the soldiers, man for
                    man, and hold the excess, and says you might hold hostages for the negro
                    soldiers if they refuse to exchange them. This much I promised to say. Could you
                    not capture and hold as hostages, say, two or three for one, some prominent
                    citizens of Virginia to procure to release of the seven citizens who are
                    remaining in prison at Salisbury, N. C.? West Virginia did so for some of her
                    citizens, and they were sent North. I received some intimations that such a
                    course would prove successful.</p>
                <p>The treatment of prisoners is severe; food deficient in quantity and quality.
                    Returned prisoners' accounts of treatment are true, Fulton and Ould to the
                    contrary notwithstanding. Boxes and letters even are not given. I received no
                    letters, nor any one else, for two months previous to my release. The boat that
                    brought me up had boxes on it for rebels in our prisons. Many think that Maj.
                    Mulford is too kind to them and cares less than he should for our men. The
                    Reverend Doctor Moore, who did much to get us away and contributed largely to
                    our comfort during our imprisonment, has two sons in Northern prisons-one,
                    Lieut. J. B. Moore, at Johnson's Island, and the other, Private J. N. Moore, at
                    Elmira. Could you not make a special exchange for these men, or release them? I
                    think that the son (a lieutenant) of Reverend Doctor Breckinridge would be sent
                    on for Lieut. Moore. Would you not grant us permits to visit these men and do
                    something for their comfort as an expression of our gratitude for the kindness
                    of their father? Permit me to thank you cordially for your great kindness in
                    making efforts to secure our release. I fear to occupy too much of your lines;
                    at any rate, I cannot yet write connectedly, having lost much of healthy mental
                    tone through sufferings experienced in prison. We understood that you had issued
                    an order for the release of Reverend Doctor Handy for the release of Mr.
                    Culbertson. I presume that you know all about the fearful mortality at
                    Andersonville, Ga., and the fiendish treatment that causes it. You would confer
                    a great obligation by a reply addressed to me to Chambersburg, Pa.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your obedient and humble servant,</salute>
                    <signed>JAS. HAMILTON.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
