<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R33124573"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="fr" id="R33124573">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Union Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">union correspondence</title>
        <author>Cadwalader, George</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R33124573</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500026</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Union Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">union correspondence</title>
            <author>Cadwalader, George</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 3, Volume 3, Serial No. 124</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 573</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-07-25">1863-07-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R33124573T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Union General George Cadwalader writes from Philadelphia in July, 1863, to
                    General Darius Couch, commanding the Department of the Susquehanna at
                    Chambersburg. Cadwalader requests that he be allowed to retain the services of
                    General Dana, and reports on the progress of the draft in Pennsylvania. He
                    reports that enrollment is going forward quietly in Philadelphia, but in
                    Schuylkill County an armed force of resisters is rumored to be gathering and
                    drilling. Cadwalader proposes making plans to deal with any emergency.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Maj. Gen. D. N. COUCH,<lb/> Comdg. Dept. of the
                        Susquehanna, Chambersburg, Pa.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-07-25">July 25, 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">HDQRS.,<lb/> Philadelphia, Pa.,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your two telegrams of the 23d instant in relation to Maj.-Gen. Dana were dully
                    received, and I have this morning received your letter of the same date by mail.</p>
                <p>The services of Maj.-Gen. Dana will, as I have already informed you, be required
                    here in the event of the troops now on duty here being called upon for active
                    service, and in the meantime he is also rendering assistance to Professor Bache
                    in the construction of the works for the defense of the city, with which he has
                    been familiar, and which duties Professor Bache requested that he should
                    continue to perform. I will therefore avail myself of your permission to retain
                    Gen. Dana here for the present.</p>
                <p>It seems from your letter just received that you had not received my letter of
                    the 18th instant addressed to Harrisburg informing you of my having been
                    assigned to the command here by the Gen.-in-Chief. The receipt by you of the
                    copy of my instructions, which I subsequently transmitted to you to
                    Chambersburg, supplied you with the information contained in my former letter.</p>
                <p>The draft is progressing quietly here, and we do not anticipate any different
                    until it is attempted to take the drafted men who do not report.</p>
                <p>I think it proper to state that I hear from different sources of a strong
                    combination in Schuylkill County, in this State, to resist the arrest of drafted
                    men. It is also stated by some of the citizens of Pottsville to consist of about
                    3,000 men, armed, and having officers who are said to be drilling them, who have
                    been in the U. S. service. It is also stated that they have several pieces of
                    artillery, and that they are supplied with ammunition. It may be important to
                    consider from what direction forces are to be drawn to be sent there when the
                    emergency may arise, and it may perhaps be well that some discreet person should
                    be sent there to inquire about it.</p>
                <p>Governor Curtin may perhaps have the information, or could take measures to
                    obtains it.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very respectfully, your obedient servant,</salute>
                    <signed>GEO. CADWALADER,<lb/> Maj.-Gen., Comdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
