<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R42128171"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R42128171">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Shields, J. D.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R42128171</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500045</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Shields, J. D.</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 4, Volume 2, Serial No. 128</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 171</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-06">1862-11-06</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R42128171T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Confederate Colonel J. D. Shields reports to Adjutant General Samuel Cooper on
                    enrolling conscripts in November, 1862. Shields discusses the availability of
                    conscripts and mentions Colonel Michael G. Harman's command at Staunton.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    HDQRS. CAMP OF INSTRUCTION,
                    <name type="recipient">Gen. S. COOPER,<lb/> Adjutant and Inspector Gen.:</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-06">November 6, 1862.</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Richmond,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>GEN.:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Accompanying my report, herewith inclosed, I have the honor to submit the
                    following statement: The report only gives the operations of this and the camp
                    of instruction at Dublin Depot. The counties of the Valley have been nearly
                    drained of conscripts by officers sent for the purpose by Maj.-Gen. Jackson, and
                    the men never accounted for to me, with the exception of those reported by Col.
                    M. G. Harman, Fifty-second Virginia Regt., enrolling officer at Staunton. The
                    same is the case with all the counties within the influence of Maj.-Gen.
                    Loring's command. Undoubtedly a very large number of conscripts have been
                    collected and sent to the armies of the Valley and Southwestern Virginia who do
                    not appear upon my report, which is chiefly confined to the eastern portion of
                    the State. The discrepancy between the "total number enrolled as liable to duty"
                    and the total number actually received into the camps of instruction is due to
                    the fact that a great many of the men fail to report at the time and place
                    appointed, and others desert en route. The enrolling officers, as a general
                    thing not being provided with competent guards, have not the means of preventing
                    this, but many of these men subsequently join volunteer companies already in the
                    service, and should be properly accounted for to me by the officers receiving
                    them. The number of desertions from this camp have been about 140 up to this
                    time; four-fifths of these have been substitutes deserting within twenty-four
                    hours of their being received as such. I have endeavored in every way to protect
                    the Government in this matter of substitutes, even to retaining the money until
                    they are assigned, but with no success. Either some example should be made of
                    them or the principal be in some manner held responsible. I should be pleased to
                    receive any suggestions or instructions concerning this subject from the
                    Department. A majority of the enrolling officers have failed or not deemed it
                    necessary to report to me the number or deserters, stragglers, &amp;c.,
                    arrested by them and returned to their respective regiments. I am confident the
                    number so arrested is very large, nearly equaling the conscripts, from the
                    verbal statements of these officers, and it should be credited to the recruiting
                    conscripts service. I shall instruct the officers hereafter to make their
                    reports embrace this class as well as the conscripts. At the beginning of the
                    conscripts service I was mainly dependent upon the State officers for purpose of
                    enrollment, but subsequently received the services of many regular C. S.
                    officers. Nine out of ten State officers and a large number of C. S. officers
                    proving inefficient, have been from time to time relieved. Now that the act has
                    been extended to embrace all persons between eighteen and forty, I respectfully
                    request that I may be permitted to select from the regular service such officers
                    as I know will render efficient service in enrolling and reporting the
                    conscripts promptly into camp. In this connection I have already brought to your
                    attention the names of Maj. Cabell, Capt. McPhail, and one or two others. I
                    propose to assign a superior officer to each Congressional district, who will
                    have entire charge of the business in his district, receiving the reports of
                    subordinate officers in the different counties, and forwarding the conscripts as
                    enrolled to the nearest camp of instruction. He will also have control of the
                    expenditures of the subordinate officers, and thus effect a great saving to the
                    public Treasury, as he will be required to certify to the justness of all
                    accounts before they are submitted to this office. I hope it will be the
                    pleasure of the Department to accept my suggestion in this matter, as it is my
                    earnest desire to see the act carried out in the most expeditious and effective
                    manner, and at the same time with the very smallest cost to the Government.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I am, general, very respectfully,</salute>
                    <signed>J. D. SHIELDS,<lb/> Lieut.-Col., Cmdg.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
