<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="R43129248"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
<TEI.2 n="au" id="R43129248">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Confederate Correspondence.</title>
        <title type="sort">confederate correspondence</title>
        <author>Cooper, Samuel</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version:</resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent> 
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">R43129248</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1999 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved.</p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500048</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Confederate Correspondence.</title>
            <title type="uniform">The War of The Rebellion: Official Records of the
                            Union and Confederate Armies</title>
            <title type="sort">confederate correspondence</title>
            <author>Cooper, Samuel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Translator:</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p>Series 4, Volume 3, Serial No. 129</p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>Pages 248</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Broadfoot Publishing Company</publisher>
                        <pubPlace>Wilmington, NC</pubPlace>
                        <date value="1997">1997</date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Publisher</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-23">1864-03-23</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term/>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="R43129248T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>May, 1864, Confederate General Orders providing for the formation of Maryland
                    regiments. The orders establish Camp Maryland at Staunton, VA, for the
                purpose.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    GENERAL ORDERS, No. 38., ADJT. AND INSP. GEN.'S OFFICE,
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-23">March 23, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>
                <p>I. The second and third paragraphs of General Orders, No. 8, Adjutant and
                    Inspector Gen.'s Office, series of 1862, are hereby revoked.</p>
                <p>II. With a view to facilitate the organization of citizens of Maryland into
                    companies, squadrons, battalions, and regiments, in accordance with the act to
                    authorize and provide for the organization of the Maryland Line, published in
                    paragraph I, General Orders, No. 8, above referred to, a camp will be
                    established at Staunton, Va., to be called Camp Maryland, and a camp near
                    Hanover Junction, to be called Camp Howard.</p>
                <p>III. The troops now under the command of Col. Bradley T. Johnson will for the
                    present occupy Camp Howard, and all other Maryland companies, squadrons, and
                    battalions will, upon their written application, be detached by commanding
                    generals from their present commands and ordered to proceed, for the purpose of
                    being organized into regiments, either to Camp Maryland or to Camp Howard, as
                    they may elect.</p>
                <p>IV. All persons now in service in other than Maryland companies who are, or were
                    at the commencement of the war, native or adopted citizens of Maryland, and who
                    desire to join companies from their own State, will, upon their application in
                    writing with reliable evidence of their citizenship, addressed and sent directly
                    to the commandant of Camp Maryland or to the commandant of Camp Howard, be
                    transferred to the Maryland Line, and at their option will either be assigned to
                    Maryland companies now existing, or, provided the number be sufficient,
                    organized into new companies with the privilege of electing company officers.
                    And persons now in service in Maryland companies who are citizens of other
                    States will, upon their request in writing, accompanied by proper evidence of
                    their citizenship, be transferred by commanding generals to any company from
                    their own States in the army to which they belong.</p>
                <p>V. Upon receipt of orders from this office making transfers in accordance with
                    the preceding paragraph commanding generals are direct to forward the men so
                    transferred to the camp designated in charge of commissioned officers, and they
                    will furnish every possible facility for the prompt movement of companies,
                    squadrons, and battalion as directed in the third paragraph of this order.</p>
                <p>VI. All native or adopted citizens of Maryland who are not now in the Confederate
                    service will, upon application to either of the commandants herein mentioned
                    within the next sixty days, be enlisted into the Maryland Line, and at their
                    option assigned to existing Maryland companies or organized into the new
                    companies hereinbefore provided for.</p>
                <p>VII. Maj.-Gen. Elzey is relieved from the command of the Department of Richmond
                    and assigned to the command of the Maryland Line. He will for the present take
                    immediate command of Camp Maryland. Col. Bradley T. Johnson will assume command
                    of Camp Howard. They will at once proceed to carry out the purpose of these
                    orders.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>By order:</salute>
                    <signed>S. COOPER,<lb/> Adjutant and Inspector Gen.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
