<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.05.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/24/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-12">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">12</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.12.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.12.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Our Neighbors Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Tuesday of last week, the Radical County Committee met in this Borough to
                        elect a delegate to the State Convention.--There was considerable excitement
                        among the loyal. The difference of opinion was not in the Committee, for
                        when its members came to ballot, there was a unanimous vote on instructions.
                        But, outside of the Committee there was a Geary and an anti-Geary party, the
                        latter headed and apparently, tailed, by our editorial neighbors of the
                            <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>.</p>
                    <p>It seems to have heretofore afforded our brethren of the quill, infinite
                        satisfaction, (inasmuch as they have taken occasion, several times to allude
                        to it in their columns) that one of the Editors of this paper signed a
                        letter to a distinguished Democrat asking him to be a candidate for the
                        Democratic nomination, and that the delegates selected from this County to
                        the Democratic Convention are supposed to be in favor of another gentleman.
                        We have the satisfaction of knowing that a very respectable portion of the
                        Democracy are with us in sentiment.</p>
                    <p>But what has been the fate of our neighbors? They opened out their heaviest
                        batteries on Geary. They denounced him in their paper. They held him up to
                        public ridicule and contempt. They frequently indulged in covert sneers at
                        him and, at last, grew so reckless as to call him a goose. How did the
                        Committee respond to these sentiments? Mr. A. H. Schafhirt was elected
                        delegate and <emph rend="italic">instructed unanimously for Geary</emph>. It
                        is even stated that the Committee refused to hold its session in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph> Building, and adjourned to the Court
                        House. Whether this is true or not we have not been accurately informed,
                        but, it is certain that the instructions to the delegate are not in
                        accordance with the teachings of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>
                        and at total variance with the feelings of its editors.</p>
                    <p>These gentlemen did not know as much about the working of their party
                        machinery as we did ourselves. We are never entrusted with Radical secrets,
                        but we saw plainly, and so announced in our last issue, that the thing was
                        set up and Geary's nomination a foregone conclusion. Of course, we judged of
                        this from indications here as well as elsewhere, and had the sagacious
                        editors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> but kept their eyes
                        open, they might have seen that it would be an utter impossibility to defeat
                        instructions for Geary. How bitter must be their mortification at not being
                        able to muster <emph rend="italic">one</emph> vote against these
                        instructions!</p>
                    <p>This is not our fight. We have nothing to do with it at the present stage.
                        Our business will be to help to whip the nominee of the Radical Convention
                        whoever he may be. It is a source of joy to us that there is an almost
                        absolute certainty of Geary being the nominee. If we had the privilege of
                        naming the standard-bearer of the Radical party for the coming campaign, our
                        choice would certainly fall upon "the hero of Lookout Mountain." He is the
                        weakest man in the State who makes any pretensions to prominence.</p>
                    <p>A story is told that when Stonewall Jackson was wounded at the battle of
                        Chancellorsville and carried back, bleeding, on a litter, he said to his
                        attendants "where the fight raged fiercest and bullets flew thickest and the
                        charge was most terrific, did you see that tall handsome man with heavy
                        black whiskers, seated on a noble black steed?" The answer was "yes,
                        General." "who was he"? said the dying warrior. "<emph rend="italic">General
                            John W. Geary</emph>," was the reply. And then, raising himself from his
                        rude couch, with a supernatural gleam in his eye and lifting his long, bony
                        finger to give emphasis to his utterance, he exclaimed, "mark my words,
                            <emph rend="italic">John W. Geary is the bane of the Southern
                            Confederacy</emph>."</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">This story was first told by John W. Geary</emph>. It had
                        its origin in his brain and was related to gratify his egotistic vanity.</p>
                    <p>Could not Geary manage to manufacture a similar story and make some prominent
                        dying Democrat utter the prophetic words, <emph rend="italic">John W. Geary
                            will be the bane of the Democratic party</emph>. Having with his own
                        strong right arm vanquished the Rebel forces, he, assuredly, ought to be
                        equal to the task of overwhelming the Copperheads, and it should not be
                        difficult for him to imagine that somebody had given him credit for doing it
                        before it is actually done.</p>
                    <p>The Democratic party stands in no dread of the redoubtable General. It don't
                        exactly credit his story about the truth of Stonewall Jackson's prophecy,
                        nor does it believe that the facts verify the prophecy. On the contrary, it
                        is of the opinion that about as poor a specimen of a soldier as ever drew
                        sword from its scabbard is this same egotist Geary. And it has an idea that
                        the people have taken his true measure by this time, and will announce it in
                        October. That announcement will be one of condemnation, and when it is made,
                        our grand old commonwealth will have taken one step towards its redemption
                        from the Radical misrule. Put a Democrat in the Gubernatorial chair at
                        Harrisburg of the same stuff that Governor Hoffman of New York is made of,
                        and the people will have some protection from the Radical pack that annually
                        infests our Legislative halls.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules the local Republican paper for failing to predict the selection
                    of a pro-Geary delegate for the Republican State Convention. Also ridicules
                    Geary, calling him vain and egotistic, and confidently predicts his defeat in
                    the fall election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>In Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper gloats that John Cessna is having trouble delivering the posts he
                    promised to his supporters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Grant's Administration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last week we published an article from the Chicago <emph rend="italic"
                            >Tribune</emph>, Radical, commenting upon the errors of the present
                        administration. We call attention this week to an article, published
                        elsewhere in our columns, from the Chicago <emph rend="italic"
                        >Republican</emph>, another leading Radical paper of the West, in which the
                        sorrowful acknowledgment is made that mistakes of the gravest character, and
                        possibly, of the most pernicious influence, have been made by President
                        Grant. These articles are of importance as showing how much the President
                        has fallen in the esteem of his political friends since his inauguration.
                        The confidence which they unthinkingly hastened to repose in him has been so
                        much weakened that fears are entertained for the future successes, and
                        perhaps, for the very existence of the Radical organization. The numerous
                        blunders which signalized the opening of his administration, the disgraceful
                        ignorance of the laws disclosed by his ill-advised appointments, and his
                        subsequent determination to leave not a single relation, no matter how
                        distant, unprovided with an honorable or a lucrative office, have combined
                        to create a distrust of his ability and even of his good intentions. It
                        would be hard to get a majority of the politicians to vouch for Grant's
                        strict integrity. None of them would testify to his firmness and
                        resoluteness of purpose. Firm and resolute he may have been in the midst of
                        leaden hail and in the face of an attacking force, but in the onset made
                        upon him by hordes of hungry office-seekers, he has vacillated and swung
                        from one applicant to another and then back again, and finally settled down
                        upon some new man altogether. He gets so completely entangled in the
                        difficulties with which politicians have environed him, that he cannot see
                        his way out and consequently sits dumfoundered and despairing. No doubt, he
                        has often wished the whole crew of office-seekers in the bottom of the
                        Atlantic Ocean. But wishing will not put them there. And so, each morning as
                        he rises from the breakfast table, he has the pleasing prospect of being
                        button-holed all day by the friends of this and that man, who desire him to
                        turn some one out of office who is a better man than the whole party of
                        applicants put together.</p>
                    <p>Under such circumstances, a man of large experience in public affairs, of
                        keen insight into human nature, of independent will, and honesty of purpose,
                        commends himself to public admiration in the Presidential chair. He takes a
                        bold, decided stand and keeps it. He detects the scoundrel and rejects him.
                        He recognizes worth and talent and employs them.</p>
                    <p>Tried by this rule, how dwarfed and insignificant does Grant appear. Who is
                        satisfied with him? Not even his own party friends. They feel that his
                        election was a terrible mistake. He is neither a statesman himself nor has
                        he called practical statesmen about him. Former Presidents have been weak
                        but they have been possessed of sufficient wisdom to select wise
                        constitutional advisers. But Grant has failed even in this. He is groping in
                        the dark. His advisers are groping in the dark and the consequence is that
                        public affairs are sadly mismanaged. It is no wonder that an earnest
                        protestation has gone up from the leading papers of the West and been
                        re-echoed by the New York <emph rend="italic">Times</emph> and New York<emph
                            rend="italic">Post</emph> and New York <emph rend="italic">Sun</emph>,
                        all Radical papers, in the East.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Elated that many Republicans are expressing dissatisfaction with Grant.
                    Accuses him once again of making poor nominations for high office, which
                    indicates his weak qualifications for the Presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.12.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>New Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuss</ln>
                        <fn>Eli</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nevin</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. H. Miller is replacing Eli Fuss as postmaster at Greencastle and A. G.
                    Nevin is replacing J. R. Welsh at Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Circus and Menagerie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bryan's circus drew large attendance and gave the streets of Chambersburg a
                    "gay appearance."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>National Bank of Chambersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares the bank in a healthy condition and reports the amount
                    of its loans and discounts at $964,576.73; capital, $250,000; Surplus Fund,
                    $83,000; Individual Deposits, $226,700.54.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Minstrels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Skiff and Gaylord's Minstrels will perform in Repository Hall. "They are
                    represented to be first-class performers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A New Life Insurance Agent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nead</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Nead replaces George Eyster as Franklin agent of the National Life
                    Insurance Company. The editors praise the company and the choice. He will make
                    his office in the building of H. C. Keyser.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The "surviving soldiers of the late war" will meet in the room of the
                    Building Association over Mr. Snider's book store to make plans to decorate the
                    graves of the dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A Generous Gift</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorehead</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William G. Moorehead, a member of the Episcopal Church, has donated $5000
                    toward the Wilson Female Seminary. The Episcopalians are also raising funds to
                    establish a similar school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Discharged</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Norris, an African American charged with attempted rape, was
                    discharged from jail on a writ of habeas corpus. Nobody appeared in court to
                    prosecute the accused, and the case will have to be taken up in the August term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whetstone</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. Miller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atherton</ln>
                        <fn>I. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The County School Directors met and elected Samuel Gelwix to replace P. M.
                    Shoemaker as County Superintendent. Gelwix defeated rivals W. H. Hockenberry,
                    George H. Cook, I. Y. Atherton, and George E. Jones. "He is a young gentleman of
                    excellent moral character, fine literary attainments and very considerable
                    experience as a teacher."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gees</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>Amelia Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Gees and Miss Amelia Jane Elder, both of Chambersburg, were married
                    on May 6th by the Rev. J. Hassler.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>William</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah William died near Greenwood on May 4th. She was 40 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Alexander died near Spring Run on April 25th. He was 41 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Stewart died near Spring Run on April 30th. He was 69 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.12.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
