<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.05.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/24/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-05">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.05.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Naturalization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Republicans for taking steps to prevent the
                    foreign-born from receiving naturalization papers and voting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Registry Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper criticizes Republicans for writing registration laws that promote
                    voting rights for blacks, but make it difficult for the foreign-born to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Plundered People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If the speech of Hon. William A. Wallace, which we print today, does not open
                        the eyes of the people of Pennsylvania to the enormities of Radical misrule,
                        then indeed must their eyes be hopelessly shut. The stubborn facts set forth
                        in this speech are enough to alarm any man who feels an interest in the
                        welfare of the State. It must be clear to any mind capable of understanding
                        the most common affairs, that the Radicals who have ruled Pennsylvania for
                        the last eight years <emph rend="italic">have plundered her people of more
                            than sixteen million dollars</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Wallace shows from the reports of the Auditor General and State Treasurer
                        that the amount received into the State Treasury from 1861 to 1868 was over
                        forty-five million dollars--$45,346,506. He also shows from the same sources
                        that the whole amount of State debt and interest paid from 1860 to 1868 was
                        a little over twenty-four million dollars--$24,291,196. Deducting the amount
                        paid on State debt and interest from the whole amount received, we have a
                        balance of more than twenty-one million dollars--$21,055,399. <emph
                            rend="italic">What has become of this balance?</emph></p>
                    <p>The expenses of the State government, as shown in the official reports
                        referred to, from 1861 to 1868, were less than five million
                        dollars--$4,842,658. Deduct these expenses from the balance left over after
                        paying the amount above given on State debt and interest, and there is left
                        the enormous sum of more than sixteen million dollars--$16,212,741. What has
                        become of this enormous sum? It was left over after paying twenty-four
                        millions on State debt and interest and all the expenses of the State
                        government. Where has it gone? It is not in the Treasury. Who has got it?</p>
                    <p>The plundering disposition of the Radicals who have had control of our State
                        government is shown by the growth of salaries and the general increase of
                        expenditures. Before the war, the Governor got $4,000 a year, the Secretary
                        of the Commonwealth $1,700, the Auditor General $2,000, the Surveyor General
                        $1,600, the Attorney General $3,000, and the Adjutant General $300. Now the
                        Governor gets $5,000, an increase of $1,000; the Secretary $3,500, an
                        increase of $1,800; the Auditor General $3,300, an increase of $1,300; the
                        Surveyor General $2,500, an increase of $900; the Attorney General $3,500,
                        an increase of $500; and the Adjutant General $2,500, an increase of $2,200.</p>
                    <p>The expenditures of all the Departments of the State government have
                        increased enormously. The worst of it is that they keep on increasing. They
                        are higher now than they were during the <sic>heighth</sic> of the war. They
                        were higher in 1868 than in any previous year in the history of the
                        commonwealth. In 1863, under the Governorship of Curtin, who was not at all
                        distinguished for economy, when the State was exerting all her energies to
                        aid the General government in putting down the rebellion, the expenses of
                        the State government were less than half a million--$446,456. In 1868, under
                        the Governorship of Geary, in a time of profound peace, when no
                        extraordinary expenditures were required, the expenses of the State
                        government reached well up towards a million dollars--$845,539.</p>
                    <p>John W. Geary, under whom this extraordinary increase has taken place, will
                        be a candidate for re-election next fall. The plundered people of
                        Pennsylvania will then have an opportunity to condemn his extravagant
                        administration of their public affairs. They will then have an opportunity
                        to say, in tones that cannot be misunderstood, that this corrupt and
                        reckless waste of money must be stopped. If the people withhold from him and
                        his partisans in the Legislature the condemnation they have richly earned,
                        then let them not complain that "times are hard" and "money scarce." When
                        people allow themselves to be plundered year after year, money must and will
                        be scarce with them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Launches an attack on Republicans in the Legislature for wasteful spending.
                    Shows how salaries of government officials and government expenditures have
                    risen dramatically since the war. Says if people don't turn these men out of
                    office, they will only have themselves to blame for the scarcity of money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crider</ln>
                        <fn>Philip D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Folker</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Philip D. Crider of Hamilton and Margaret A. Coble of St. Thomas were
                    married on April 27th by the Rev. A. G. Folker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Claudy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>Willie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Claudy of Pottsville and Miss Willie M. Youst, daughter of William
                    Youst, were married on April 26th at the residence of the bride's parents by the
                    Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clement</ln>
                        <fn>Peter E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter E. Clement and Miss Mary Armstrong, both of Franklin, were married by
                    the Rev. S. Barnes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.05.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
