<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.08.25">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/29/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-08-25">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">25</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.08.25.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.08.25.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Democracy and Conservatives will assemble in primary meetings in the
                        several election districts of the County, on Saturday next, to elect
                        delegates to the County Convention to be held in this Borough on Tuesday
                        next, the 31st instant. The Radical ticket has been nominated and has failed
                        to give anything like general satisfaction. All that is required on the part
                        of the Democracy is to form a good ticket, and success is secured beyond any
                        contingency. This can be easily done by the exercise of proper care. Good
                        men are announced for the different offices and the Convention can not go
                        far wrong in making its selections. We hazard nothing in saying that no
                        matter who are chosen from the gentlemen named, our ticket will surpass the
                        Radical ticket in ability and availability. The opinion seems to be
                        universal that, for many years, the opposition have not presented a weaker
                        ticket than that now in the field. We call upon the people to attend the
                        delegate elections, and select their best men to represent them in the
                        Convention. We desire to see a ticket nominated that will be elected from
                        top to bottom. We hope to be spared the mortification of announcing the
                        defeat of any one of the Democratic candidates. Our County is a close one.
                        One hundred votes won from either side may elect the candidate in whose
                        favor they are cast. Under such circumstances how important it becomes to
                        nominate men who can assuredly poll more than their party vote. It may be
                        that our party majority will be large enough to carry our whole ticket
                        without regard to the ability and standing of the nominees. But it is not
                        best to rely on that. For seven years, the majority on either side has been
                        small. On either side, a candidate possessing a small amount of personal
                        popularity has succeeded in winning enough votes from the opposition to
                        insure his success. Almost every year during the time named, both parties
                        have succeeded in electing portions of their tickets. Surely no stronger
                        argument could be presented in favor of the selection of the men who are
                        strongest before the people. Let the delegates, therefore, assemble in a
                        spirit of harmony and with a determination to sacrifice personal and local
                        interests for the general good of the party. Let the questions asked for the
                        determination of their course of action, be, who is the best and strongest
                        man? Who can poll the largest number of votes, and who will best fill the
                        offices after they are elected?</p>
                    <p>Democrats, see to it that you exercise your best judgments in this matter.
                        The candidates at the head of your ticket are men of whom you may well be
                        proud. Let your candidates for County offices be equally worthy of the
                        places, the duties of which they will be called upon to discharge.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces meetings to be held to select Democratic nominees for county
                    offices. Tells supporters that elections have usually been close in the county
                    so extra effort is needed to get out the votes and find the right candidates to
                    run. Also calls for party harmony to ensure success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>A New Party Proposed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is stated in correspondence from Washington, that just after the result of
                        the Virginia election became known, Chief Justice Chase wrote a confidential
                        letter to a prominent politician in Tennessee, an old friend of his, wherein
                        he expressed much gratification at the defeat of the bitter enders in
                        Virginia and rejoiced over the success of the conservatives. The Chief
                        Justice expressed the hope that results similar to that in Virginia would be
                        produced in Tennessee, Mississippi and Texas, and strongly hinted that in
                        his opinion the republican party had served its day, and that the time was
                        at hand when a new conservative party should be formed which would embrace
                        the moderate men of all existing parties.</p>
                    <p>Judge Chase was one of the founders of the Republican party and he certainly
                        would be one of the last to propose to break it up if it gave any promise of
                        future usefulness. But it has gone beyond the control of the men of real
                        ability who brought it into existence as a breakwater to the advancing tide
                        of slavery, and has become an agent of evil in the hands of politicians of a
                        low order of intellect and morals. It is therefore no wonder that Judge
                        Chase, whose intellectual and moral rank is of the highest order, should
                        come to the conclusion that the Republican party of the present day is only
                        worth breaking up.</p>
                    <p>But the Judge, it seems, thinks "the time is at hand when a new conservative
                        party should be formed which would embrace the moderate men of all existing
                        parties." Here he is a little wrong. The Democratic party is made up in the
                        main of moderate men, and it is wholly under the control of such. Here and
                        there a "Brick Pomeroy" is found adhering to it, but its policy is shaped by
                        men of a totally different stamp. What the country needs is not a new party,
                        but such an accession of moderate men from the Republican to the Democratic
                        party as will enable the latter to crush out the Radicals. Let Judge Chase
                        and other distinguished Republicans who are disgusted with the small men who
                        now control public affairs, and alarmed at the violent measures by which
                        they propose to secure a long lease of power, come over to the Democratic
                        party and bring with them all the moderate men of their political household,
                        and there will soon be an end of the Grants, and Boutwells, and Butlers, and
                        Chandlers, and men of that stamp, who occupy without filling the high places
                        adorned by intellectual giants in the better days of the Republic.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes with appreciation Salmon Chase's recent comment that a new party
                    should be formed by conservatives. Doesn't agree completely because editor says
                    it would be better for all moderate and conservative men to join the Democrats
                    in order to drive out the Radicals. Seems to use Chase's idea as a backdoor for
                    getting more support for Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.08.25.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. E. E. Higbee preached in the German Reformed Church on Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Camp Meeting of the United Brethren begins tomorrow in Yawkey's Woods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>North Ward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of the Chambersburg's North Ward will meet at the Montgomery
                    Hotel to elect delegates to the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>South Ward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of the South Ward will meet at Samuel R. Boyd's Hotel to
                    select delegates to the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rev. C. W. McKeehan and Mr. O. C. Bowers have been hired as teachers at
                    the Chambersburg Academy. "They are both experienced teachers and will ably
                    second the efforts of the Principal, in giving our young men first-class
                    educations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Reformed Church, Mercersburg, will hold inauguration ceremonies for
                    Thomas G. Apple, President of Mercersburg College.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Counterfeit Twenties</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiteshew</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorwart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hallowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dieter</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A stranger registered at a Chambersburg hotel as "James Mercer, Reading"
                    passed counterfeit $20 notes at several Chambersburg stores. He left town before
                    his crime was discovered.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Candidates</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>French</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leidy</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>B. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reymer</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Vincent</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>H. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tritle</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllen</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clugston</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper lists names that have been spoken of for local offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Arrested on Suspicion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbon</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hodgson</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. A. Carbon was arrested on suspicion of horse theft after being seen with
                    a missing horse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>A Returned Missionary in the Court House</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Happer</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. Andrew P. Happer, who has been a missionary in China for the last
                    25 years, will preach in the Court House on August 29th. He will "throw light
                    upon the past history, present condition and future prospects of that great
                    nation which is now absorbing so large a share of public attention."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Swindling Peddlers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper warns people not to buy goods from the many peddlers that are
                    overrunning the county. The editors call them "liars and cheats" and assert that
                    anyone doing business with them will be "swindled." They also allege that such
                    peddlers are often involved in selling stolen goods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>The Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jeffries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                        <fn>Julius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazlett</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hagy</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flack</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>President Suesserott presided over a meeting of the Horticultural Society.
                    Jenkins and Hazlett were chosen as delegates to attend the American Pomological
                    Convention. The society made plans to publish a list of fruits and vegetables
                    suitable to Franklin County, and to hold a public exhibition in September. Some
                    fruits and vegetables were exhibited at the meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kadel</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adam Brown and Miss Annie M. Kadel, both of Fayettesville, were married on
                    August 18th by the Rev. L. A. Gotwald.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Sarah Barnes died in Chambersburg on August 21st. She was 8 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Emma Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leberknight</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Emma Jane Leberknight, daughter of Daniel C. Leberknight, died in
                    Chambersburg on August 22nd. She was 7 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.08.25.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
