<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.07.28">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/26/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-28">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Packer and Pershing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Democratic exchanges come to us filled with rejoicings over the work of
                        the State Convention. The nominations are satisfactory to everybody but the
                        Radicals. Honest people are hailing an honest ticket with delight. The
                        mismanagement and corruption which have characterized our State
                        Administrations for the last nine years have so disgusted the better portion
                        of the Radical party that they were ready to cut loose from Geary and
                        Williams the very moment a worthy ticket was put in the field by the
                        Democrats. Such men have no hesitation in saying that their wishes have been
                        gratified. The nominees of the Democratic Convention are not only men of
                        known ability but of recognized integrity. The Jeffersonian test, is he
                        honest, is he capable? was applied by the Convention, and the result is the
                        nomination of men whose honesty and capacity are universally admitted.</p>
                    <p>The Radical journals are at a loss for points of attack. The characters of
                        our candidates are so unexceptionable that they can find nothing to say
                        condemnatory of them. Failing to get hold of anything better, they are
                        attempting to prejudice the masses against our candidate for Governor by
                        writing about his immense wealth. They say the Democracy have nominated
                        twenty million dollars for Governor. They forget to tell the people how his
                        wealth was acquired. They omit to state that it is the fruit of honest
                        industry. Asa Packer was a poor boy. He received no pecuniary assistance
                        from his parents. He has been emphatically the architect of his own fortune.
                        He resolved in early life to look out for himself and, leaving his New
                        England home, he came to the State of Pennsylvania, which he recognized as
                        the best theatre for the operations of his active mind. Here he toiled day
                        after day at an humble occupation. By saving his earnings, he acquired
                        sufficient capital to start in business for himself and soon developed that
                        wonderful sagacity and shrewd business tact, combined with an inflexible
                        honesty of purpose, which caused every enterprise in which he engaged to
                        yield him a handsome profit. He owes his wealth, therefore, to his own <emph
                            rend="italic">indefatigable</emph> exertions.</p>
                    <p>The Radical papers omit to give Asa Packer credit for the manner in which he
                        uses his money. He is not a miser who hoards up his money and finds his
                        highest delight in counting it. He is not a man in whose breast avarice and
                        covetousness have found a lodging place. On the contrary, his is a heart
                        overflowing with consideration for his fellow man. His ear is always open to
                        hear meritorious claims for aid and his hand always ready to supply the
                        wants of the needy. The poor are never turned away from his door. But he is
                        not satisfied with simply contributing to those who call upon him. With
                        munificent liberality he founded a University at Bethlehem which is not only
                        an honor to himself, but an honor to the State. There is no narrow
                        mindedness about him. Knowing well the soreness of the struggles through
                        which he passed, and that his labors were increased on account of the
                        limited education which he had received in boyhood, he took this step so as
                        to give to other young men the aid of a thorough education with which to
                        begin their careers. A gentleman who dispenses his money in this way, can
                        well endure the sneers and scoffs of politicians who call him a twenty
                        million dollar candidate. The State needs more such men.</p>
                    <p>It is no wonder, then, that the press is trumpeting the qualifications and
                        meritorious deeds of our candidate. His is a reputation compared to which
                        that of mintstick Geary sinks into utter insignificance.</p>
                    <p>The Convention was equally fortunate in its selection of a candidate for the
                        Supreme Bench. Cyrus L. Pershing is one of the brightest ornaments of the
                        Pennsylvania Bar. He is a gentleman of the most solid legal attainments. His
                        life, too, has been one of unceasing activity. He has given to his
                        profession the labors of his early years and now, when in the very prime of
                        life, and in the full vigor of his intellectual powers, he is to be called
                        to a position in which he will be of eminent service in the citizens of
                        Pennsylvania by the exercise of that sound judgment and legal acumen which
                        these labors have developed, and the practical use of that legal knowledge
                        with which his mind is stored so abundantly. The purity of his private life
                        is acknowledged by all who know him. Through five years in the lower House
                        of the Pennsylvania Legislature he passed, and his reputation has not the
                        slightest tarnish upon it. The man who could remain at Harrisburg for that
                        length of time and go away without so much as the smell of corruption upon
                        his garments, is unquestionably worthy of the confidence and respect and
                        support of the people. In these days, when Legislative halls are reeking
                        with corruption, when the most iniquitous legislation is carried by the use
                        of bribery and when many good men have fallen under the ban on account of
                        the bad company they have kept, we point with pride to our candidate who
                        bore himself throughout five years of Legislative experience without
                        reproach from any quarter. We whipped Judge Williams once with the
                        accomplished Sharswood. WE will best him the second time with the able and
                        honest Pershing.</p>
                    <p>Up with your banners, then, Democrats. Hang them on the outer wall. Carry
                        Packer and Pershing to victory.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the Democratic nominees for Governor and Supreme Court Justice.
                    Repeatedly stresses their honesty and qualifications for their respective
                    offices, and contrasts that with the corruption of the Radicals. Also stresses
                    the gubernatorial nominee's charity work and founding of a university in the
                    state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>White Boys in Blue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our neighbors of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>, both of them we
                        believe claiming to have seen service in their country's behalf, are already
                        after the White Boys in Blue. Doubtless they are impelled to this early
                        remembrance of them in their columns by a knowledge of the power wielded
                        against their party by this organization in former campaigns.--We think we
                        can account for their present uneasiness on the score of the prompt and
                        cordial ratification of Judge Packer's nomination by the friends of Genls.
                        Hancock and McCandless. Genl. McCandless, far from being dissatisfied with
                        his failure to receive the nomination for Governor, will, in his own words,
                        from a speech delivered on the evening following the Convention, "be found
                        supporting both flanks of Judge Packer during the campaign." We predict for
                        the gallant General and his White Boys in Blue heavy accessions from the
                        ranks of the enemy in the shape of deserters, who, now that they know the
                        shallowness and hypocrisy of radical love for our soldiers, will no longer
                        be made the dupe of such political gamblers.</p>
                    <p>Come now, gentlemen, be frank for once. Why is it that so many maimed and
                        crippled soldiers have been refused positions under the Grant administration
                        and the places they sought given to stay-at-home patriots, rebels and
                        negroes? Take for instance the case of Genl. Stephen McGroarty, of
                        Cincinnati, who lost an arm and was otherwise badly crippled in that
                        desperate struggle in which he and his brigade fought to resist the fierce
                        onslaught of the rebel Genl. Longstreet's corps, as it came fresh from the
                        valley of Virginia to turn the tide of victory against our army on that last
                        day at Chickamauga. Under Johnson General McGroarty held a position in
                        Cincinnati by which in his enfeebled condition he managed to support his
                        family, but when the patronage of the Government passed into Genl. Grant's
                        hands, this maimed veteran was ruthlessly thrust out of office and his place
                        given to a civilian. The same hand which wrote the order for his removal
                        signed a commission as Collector of the Port of New Orleans with a salary of
                        $30,000, to that rebel General in resisting whose attempts to overthrow his
                        government Stephen McGroarty was almost literally shot to pieces. But we
                        need not go so far from home in quest of illustrations of this kind. In our
                        own county we have seen two soldiers, both cripples, thrust aside to make
                        way for civilians. Col. Richie was not made Assessor because the Radical
                        Congressman of this district set a higher value on the patriotism of a man
                        who held this same lucrative office while he (Ritchie) was absent periling
                        his life on the field of battle. And Sergt. Lesher was refused a clerkship
                        in the Post Office at this place, because it was thought that he would vote
                        the ticket whether appointed or not, and for the additional reason that it
                        was necessary to take care of other gentlemen who were aspirants for the
                        Postmastership and who were presumed to have the power "to raise the devil"
                        about Cessna's ears if they were not provided for.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tries to stir up support among soldiers for the Democratic party. Gives
                    several examples of Republicans giving civilians government jobs instead of
                    crippled veterans. Also shows how a few prominent generals are supporting
                    Democratic nominees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Religious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gotwald</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. S. A. Gotwald will preach his introductory sermon as pastor of the
                    Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The African American community of Franklin County will hold a camp meeting
                    beginning on August 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Opera Troupe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A troop of strolling players will perform at Repository Hall. The
                    performances are not "of the highest order," and the paper suggests no ladies
                    should attend. The performers will introduce "exhibitions of the Black Crook
                    order into the rural districts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Indians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The showmen Hamilton and Rawdon have been exhibiting their "troupe of
                    'bloody Injins'" in Mercersburg, Greencastle, Waynesboro, Funkstown and
                    Fayetteville. They are playing to crowded houses. The paper gives it a bad
                    review, except for the scalping.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The English Burlesque Troupe</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Nellie Maskell Great European Combination Troupe will perform in
                    Repository Hall. The performers have been entertaining the public and
                    successfully making them laugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shade</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flinder</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Radical County Convention will meet in Chambersburg to nominate
                    candidates for county office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Mercersburg Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends itself from charges that it only promotes the interests
                    of Chambersburg. It asserts that it has supported plans for the Mercersburg
                    Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Franklin County Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Suesserott</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dechert</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillen</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elder</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin County Horticultural Society met. A number of new members were
                    inducted, and resolutions of thanks were tendered to those who contributed to
                    their recent Strawberry Festival. The Treasurer reported that the receipts of
                    the society totalled $122.78 and the expenses $67.90. A number of flowers,
                    fruits, and vegetables were exhibited.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumaker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haslett</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryder</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schofield</ln>
                        <fn>Josiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Horticultural Society met again on July 20th at the Ryder Nursery
                    Association. They discussed publishing a journal, and exhibited a number of
                    fruits, vegetables, and flowers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David Butler, formerly of Maryland, died in Montgomery Township on July
                    18th. He was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.07.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
