<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.03.10">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/22/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-10">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">10</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.03.10.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.03.10.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Inaugural Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The agony is over. The oracles are no longer dumb. Grant has spoken. His
                        inaugural address is before the American people. Those who have been waiting
                        in terrible suspense to know the nature of his utterances can rest satisfied
                        now.</p>
                    <p>There is no evidence of greatness in the inaugural address. True greatness,
                        while it is generally conscious of its strength, is nevertheless too modest
                        to boast of it. The position of the Chief Executive of the American people
                        is a very trying one. His labors are not few and his responsibilities are
                        great. The great men who have occupied the Presidential chair hitherto
                        entertained misgivings as to their ability to discharge properly the duties
                        of the place.--Washington, Adams, Jefferson, Madison, Monroe, all gave
                        expression to a consciousness of the greatness of the charge committed to
                        their hands and of their own weakness. And certainly they, above all others,
                        might have been looked upon as fitted for the discharge of their official
                        duties, as President. Some of them had assisted in framing the Constitution
                        and had debated its every section; others had taken part in the war of the
                        Revolution, understood thoroughly the spirit of the American people and
                        watched with eagle eyes everything that was done for the founding of the new
                        government. They were thus peculiarly fitted on account of the period in
                        which they lived to govern this people. Then, too, they were men of
                        undisputed strength of intellect.--The debates in the Federal Convention are
                        models. The state papers written by these men will ever be admired for their
                        vigor of thought and beauty of expression. And yet these men, great as they
                        were, shrank back with unfeigned diffidence and distrust from this high
                        position to which they were called.</p>
                    <p>Contrast the utterance of President Grant with their conduct, when he says,
                        "the responsibilities of the position I feel, <emph rend="italic">but accept
                            them without fear</emph>."</p>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">World</emph> suggests that "if Grant had
                        imitated the modest language of his <unclear>illustrious</unclear>
                        predecessor, his self-disparagement would have been so obviously just, that
                        there was great danger that he would have been taken at his word." If he had
                        said that he was <emph rend="italic">not</emph> equal to the position, the
                        people would have believed him. So, like the boy passing the graveyard who
                        whistles to keep his courage up, Grant, acting all the while, as every
                        sensible man <unclear>would</unclear> declare that he accepts the office
                        without fear.</p>
                    <p>Strong evidence of extreme littleness is to be found in such expressions as
                        the following;</p>
                    <p>On all <unclear>binding</unclear> questions agitating the public mind I will
                        always express my <del/> in Congress and urge them according to my judgement
                        and when I think it advisable, will exercise the constitutional privilege of
                            <unclear>instigating</unclear> a veto to defeat measures which I oppose.
                        But all laws will be faithfully executed whether they meet my approval or
                        not. I shall on all subjects <unclear>have a</unclear> policy for <del/>,
                        none to enforce against the will of the people.</p>
                    <p>The constitution provides that the President "shall from time to time, give
                        to the Congress information of the state of the Union, and recommend to
                        their consideration such measures as he shall judge necessary and
                        expedient." The constitution also vests in the President the veto power. The
                        President is bound, too, to execute faithfully all laws whether approved by
                        him or not. When President Grant, therefore, expressed his determination to
                        advise Congress, to exercise the veto and to execute the laws, he simply
                        announced his intention to do what every American citizen, who can read,
                        knows that he is bound to do.</p>
                    <p>When he says that he will have no policy to enforce against the will of the
                        people, he is simply striking a feeble blow at his predecessor and, to that
                        extent, has belittled himself in what ought to be a dignified state paper.</p>
                    <p>There are but two important positions taken by the President in his address.
                        The first is, that <emph rend="italic">every dollar of the government
                            indebtedness should be paid in gold unless otherwise expressly
                            stipulated in the contract</emph>. What will Senator Morton and Senator
                        Sherman say to this doctrine? How will all the Radical leaders of the West,
                        who have advocated the payment of United States bonds in greenbacks, relish
                        this <unclear>dose</unclear>?</p>
                    <p>The other important position is his recommendation of the proposed article
                        known as the fifteenth amendment. He has thus declared himself unequivocally
                        in favor of Negro Suffrage in all the States and has lent his name and
                        influence to the effort now being made by Congress to prevent the people
                        from passing directly upon this question.--It is a matter of the greatest
                        wonder to us that ever the Convention that framed the Constitution of the
                        United States incorporated such a provision in it as that which allows <emph
                            rend="italic">the Legislatures</emph> of three-fourths of the States to
                        amend the constitution. There has never yet been a time in the history of
                        our country when there was such great danger of the abuse of this power as
                        there is now. How the masses can cling to the leaders of a party which is
                        afraid to trust them with the decision of a question of such importance as
                        this question of negro suffrage, is a matter of astonishment to us, we
                        confess. The Democracy are making a noble stand all through the Union
                        against the degradation of the elective franchise. Time alone can tell
                        whether or not they will be successful in defeating this infamous
                        proposition. Grant could well say, "Let us have peace," when he intended to
                        ask the conservative masses to surrender everything of principle they
                        entertained in order to attain power. His "let us have peace" did not mean
                        any readiness on his part to compromise. It did not mean conciliation. No.
                        It meant that after he was firmly seated in the Presidential chair, he would
                        insult the white people of the country by advising them to make the negroes
                        their political equals and by telling them that <emph rend="italic">there
                            can be no peace</emph> until this is done.</p>
                    <p>We very much fear that the country will be <sic>wofully</sic> disappointed if
                        this address is a specimen of the statesmanship that is to mark the
                        administration of President Grant. The people have expected something better
                        than this from him. As he has kept his mouth closed so tightly ever since
                        the election, it was thought that when his time would come, he would have
                        something to say. But there is nothing in the inaugural address which is
                        calculated to cheer the hearts that are longing for a return of National
                        prosperity and the solution of the difficult problems that have grown out of
                        the war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives a very negative view of Grant's inaugural address. Claims Grant has
                    no clear policy and, unlike his predecessors, is not worthy of the Presidency.
                    Condemns his hard-money stance and his support of the 15th amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grant's Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republicans pronounced a very emphatic judgment against the Cabinet
                        selected by President Grant when the telegraph gave the names to the public.
                        From Maine to California, the announcement that it was made up of Washburne,
                        Stewart, Borie, Cresswell, Cox, and Hoar was regarded by them as a hoax!
                        Editors who put the names out on their bulletin boards were accused of
                        attempting to play off a joke on the public, and when they vindicated
                        themselves by producing the telegram, the conclusion was jumped at that the
                        telegraph companies had been victimized by some wicked wag at Washington.</p>
                    <p>When we stuck up the names, we found ourselves obliged to give the anxious
                        Republicans who crowded around an earnest assurance that we believed in the
                        genuineness of the telegram. It was amusing to see the perplexed look with
                        which they run over the list. In vain did they look into one another's face
                        for information. The best informed among them knew nothing about one half of
                        the appointees. Washburne and Stewart they had heard of, but of the rest
                        they knew absolutely nothing. Donnelly had made Washburne widely known as
                        one of the numerous family of boys, all of whom had been "born into the
                        world with <emph rend="italic">M. C.</emph> stamped on the widest part of
                        their body," and the newspapers had made Stewart's name familiar to the
                        public six months or a year ago, by publishing a paragraph stating that he
                        returned an income of $1,800,000 for 1867. But "Who is Borie?" "Who is
                        Cresswell?" "Who is Cox?" "Who is Hoar?" These were questions asked by all
                        and answered by none.</p>
                    <p>In truth, this Cabinet contains a greater number of obscure men than any
                        other that ever was formed since the foundation of our government. And those
                        who are the least obscure are no more fit than the others.--Everybody
                        expected Grant to give his old Galena crony, Washburne, one of the longest
                        teats on the national udder, but who on earth ever expected to hear of him
                        as Secretary of State? A dull man, without the slightest ability to
                        comprehend statesmanship, he endeavored to make a little reputation for
                        himself in Congress by playing the role of a rigid economist. This character
                        is produced in Congress as regularly as a Queen in a Beehive. When an old
                        economist goes out, a new one is brought forth. Many years ago, Jones of
                        Tennessee was the great Congressional economist. He was succeeded by Letcher
                        of Virginia, and he by Washburne of Illinois, whose successor will in due
                        time be forthcoming.</p>
                    <p>Whilst the great mass of Republicans are surprised at Grant's selection, the
                        leaders of the party are more than surprised. They are indignant. They
                        maintain that they had a right to expect General Grant to select as his
                        Constitutional advisors the men who had borne the brunt of the political
                        battle which resulted in his elevation to the Presidency. They were willing
                        he should evince his personal friendship for Washburne by giving him an
                        office out of which, by practicing the economy he preached, he might make a
                        fortune. They would not have objected to his acknowledging Stewart's
                        contribution to the purchase of his house by appointing that respectable old
                        gentleman a visitor to West Point, with a good dinner at Cozzen's Hotel at
                        the public expense. They would perhaps have forgiven him for rewarding
                        Borie's generosity in the same matter with an appointment as Naval officer
                        at Philadelphia with the run of the Loyal League party. But they were not
                        prepared to see him put these men in his Cabinet and thrust them forward as
                        representatives either of the intellect or the principle of the Republican
                        party. The "reticence" and "firmness" they have been accustomed to praise in
                        Grant, they are now disposed to set down as "stupidity" and "mulishness."
                        They say that if he had consulted just a few of the leading men of the party
                        and been governed by their advice, instead of shutting himself up like a
                        terrapin in his shell and offering cold insults to every prominent
                        Republican who ventured to approach him in relation to the matter, he might
                        have had a Cabinet that would have commanded the respect of the whole
                        country, whereas the one he has selected commands the respect of nobody,
                        because there is not even one man of real ability in it, and no confidence
                        can be felt that it will prove equal to the great task of administering the
                        government wisely.</p>
                    <p>The Cabinet is made up as follows:</p>
                    <p>ELIHU B. WASHBURNE, <emph rend="italic">of Illinois, Secretary of
                        State.</emph>--Mr. Washburne was born in Maine, is 53 years of age, lives at
                        Galena, is a lawyer and has been in Congress since 1853. He never attained
                        any distinction at the bar and was not considered of much account in
                        Congress.</p>
                    <p>ALEXANDER T. STEWART, <emph rend="italic">of New York, Secretary of the
                            Treasury.</emph>--Mr. Stewart was born in Ireland, is 74 years old, came
                        to this country fifty years ago, is avaricious and immensely rich, and cares
                        for nothing but money. He has taken very little interest in politics, but in
                        1866 signed an address calling on the people to support the policy of Andrew
                        Johnson.</p>
                    <p>ADOLPH F. BORIE, <emph rend="italic">of Pennsylvania, Secretary of the
                        Navy.</emph>--Mr. Borie is a native of Philadelphia, is 60 years old, is an
                        importing merchant and has made a large fortune. He is aristocratic and
                        exclusive, and "don't know" such <sic>plebeian</sic> Republicans as Col.
                        McClure. He swims on the cream of the Loyal League, and holds its skim milk
                        in abhorrence.</p>
                    <p>J. A. J. CRESSWELL, <emph rend="italic">of Maryland, Postmaster
                        General.</emph>--Mr. Cresswell is a native of Maryland, is 41 years old and
                        is a lawyer by profession. The first steps he took when the war broke out
                        were taken in the interests of the rebellion, but he soon turned around and
                        became a supporter of the Lincoln administration. This happy change (which
                        was probably the result of a calculation of chances) carried him into the
                        United States Senate, where he cried "blood and thunder" loud enough to gain
                        the favor of the vindictive portion of the Radical party.</p>
                    <p>JACOB D. COX, <emph rend="italic">of Ohio, Secretary of the
                        Interior.</emph>--Mr. Cox who was born in Canada, (of parents who were
                        citizens of the United States,) is 41 years of age, was a student of
                        divinity but was switched off into the law, went into the war as a Brigadier
                        General at an early day and served with distinction. He was elected Governor
                        of Ohio in 1865, and is said to have aided in defeating negro suffrage in
                        that State in 1867.</p>
                    <p>EBENEZER R. HOAR, <emph rend="italic">of Massachusetts, Attorney
                        General.</emph>--Mr. Hoar is a native of Massachusetts, is 53 years old, is
                        a Judge of the Supreme Court and was an original free-soiler. He "belted"
                        the nomination of Gen. Taylor for the Presidency in 1848, and wrote the
                        circular which called a State Convention that organized a party which broke
                        down Daniel Webster and elected Charles Sumner (then a Democrat with
                        abolition proclivities) to the Senate.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on Grant's choices for his Cabinet. Says Republicans are thoroughly
                    dismayed because Grant selected his Cabinet without consultation. Bitterly
                    attacks the nominations of Washburne and Stewart in particular. Gives a brief
                    biography of each member.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Andrew Johnson's Valedictory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson fired a parting salute to his Radical friends as he left the
                        White House. He published a farewell address to his countrymen which we give
                        elsewhere in our columns. It differs from the farewell addresses of
                        Washington and Jackson in this, that Washington and Jackson made theirs the
                        media through which to give to the American people words of advice and
                        warning in relation to the administration of the government and the ties
                        which ought to bind the States of the Union together. The address of Andrew
                        Johnson contains, chiefly, a vindication of his own administration and a
                        spirited arraignment of Congress for the sins of which it has been guilty.</p>
                    <p>There can be but little doubt that history will do Andrew Johnson justice.
                        And we have just as little doubt that it would have been as well for him to
                        leave the whole matter to history. Whilst all that is contained in his
                        address is unquestionably true, we do question the propriety of issuing it
                        at the time he did.</p>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson, we have not a particle of doubt, is a thoroughly honest man.
                        He has been sincere in his convictions. He has done his duty according to
                        his own notions and best judgment. When he allowed himself to be made a
                        military dictator in Tennessee, it was under a mistaken idea of the
                        necessity for arbitrary measures at that time. He was intensely, fanatically
                        patriotic, and his loyal emotions biased his judgment. His administration as
                        military Governor will never add much to his credit.</p>
                    <p>When he accepted the nomination as Vice President from the Republican party,
                        it was under the influence of a belief that patriotic and honest men were
                        its leaders. But a short experience at the National Capital satisfied him,
                        that the Radicals were bent on running the Governmental machine in their own
                        interest, with the purpose of making as much money out of it as possible,
                        without regard to the rights of the people of any section of the country.
                        With an independence that has ever been one of the noblest qualities of his
                        character, he cut loose from the organization and started to run a machine
                        of his own, or rather, to run the old machine in his own way.</p>
                    <p>He resolved to rally around him a party of his own. The disgraceful manner in
                        which he had deserted the Democratic party could not be forgotten, and that
                        proud, pure old organization made no haste to welcome him back to its fold.
                        He got up the Philadelphia Convention, but it proved a failure. The Radical
                        and Democratic parties maintained their organization intact and refused to
                        become disorganized or even demoralized at his bidding. His office holders
                        were a mixed crew taken from both parties. Andrew Johnson must have been an
                        unhappy man, politically, all through his administration. His break with the
                        Radicals gave him good cause and his excitable temper furnished him the
                        weapons with which to wage a bitter fight with his former allies.--He was
                        often indiscreet but nearly always in the right.</p>
                    <p>The Stanton-Grant imbroglio was disgraceful to him because it should have
                        been avoided by the removal of Stanton before the Tenure-of-office bill
                        became a law. The impeachment trial would thus have been an impossibility.</p>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson's Cabinet was a source of perpetual annoyance to him. They
                        were not congenial spirits. If he had turned the whole Lincoln Cabinet out
                        and appointed men who were in full sympathy with his opinions and purposes,
                        Congress would not have become as defiant and proscriptive as it did.</p>
                    <p>But no matter what his faults were, in this Andrew Johnson will ever be
                        great, that he took the constitution as his guide whilst President, and
                        allowed no threats or intimidation to drive him from the plain path of duty.
                        His will was stubborn because it was honest. He was firm because he was
                        satisfied that he was right. His vetoes are so many monuments which he has
                            <unclear>rendered</unclear> to perpetuate his own memory, and when the
                        passions of this epoch have subsided and impartial justice comes to
                        scrutinize those papers, they will receive their full <del/> of praise for
                        nobility, patriotism and sound constitutional doctrine.</p>
                    <p>Andrew Johnson has many political errors to be ashamed of but his enemies
                        have many more political sins of which they should speedily repent. He has
                        been more sinned against than sinning. He has been persecuted with a vigor
                        and zeal scarcely equaled, certainly not surpassed, in history. He has been
                        held up to public ridicule, contempt and hatred, and what is strange about
                        it is, that the acts for which he is justly censurable were allowed to pass
                        by, whilst those that are commendable have called down upon his head the
                        vilest obloquy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents a recap of Johnson's presidency. Points out his accomplishments
                    and failures but generally gives praise to most of Johnson's actions. Insists
                    history will do him justice even though Radicals treated him so unfairly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.03.10.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Damage Claims</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of McConnellsburg, Fulton County, are holding a meeting to
                    support the movement begun in Franklin to demand that the state reimburse
                    damages sustained during the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Committed to Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branch</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Branch, "a young negro who had been in the employ of Henry Shank"
                    was arrested near Waynesboro and charged with the attempted rape of the 13
                    year-old daughter of John W. Zook. George Binder, Justice of the Peace, took him
                    into custody.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Wilson College</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raffensperger</ln>
                        <fn>E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. E. B. Raffensperger accepted appointment as Financial Secretary of
                    the Wilson Female College. He will begin working on completing the proposed
                    endowment of $300,000. He will work and reside in Chambersburg. The paper
                    applauds the project and looks "forward to the time when Chambersburg shall
                    become a great educational centre, like New Haven or Princeton; where families
                    of wealth and influence shall come to reside for the sake of educating their
                    children, and the benefit shall be felt by the entire community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Auld</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Hugh Auld died in Chambersburg in his residence on North Front Street.
                    "He was well known to the people of this county, having filled, for several
                    terms we believe, the office of County Surveyor. He was one of our most highly
                    respected citizens. He has been in very feeble health during the last year owing
                    to a pulmonary affection."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Horticultural Society</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snesserott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkins</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heffron</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Franklin Horticultural Society met and discussed fertilizer, manures,
                    and strawberry cultivation. Some members also displayed fruits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Corner Loafing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper asks that town authorities take action against "corner loafing."
                    "Young men and boys congregate on the street corners and not only obstruct the
                    passage on the pavements, but indulge in obscene and profane language, to the
                    great annoyance of ladies and gentlemen passing by. They squirt out their
                    tobacco juice upon the sidewalks so that the dresses of the ladies trail in it,
                    and if they are spoken to on the subject, they curse the speaker for
                    'meddling.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The St. Thomas School Trouble</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We call attention to the following statement of facts relating to a matter
                        about which the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> raised a great outcry
                        a couple of weeks ago. It will be seen that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Repository's</emph> attack upon the School Directors of St. Thomas
                        township was uncalled for and not warranted by anything they had done. The
                        only thing we find room to object to in this affair, is that the negro was
                        permitted to enter the same class with white children. This should never be
                        allowed, as its tendency is to develop ideas of social equality between
                        negroes and whites. It is enough to receive negroes into the same schools
                        with white children. When so received, they should be taught separate and
                        apart from the whites. A teacher can instruct them without impairing his own
                        self-respect, but children cannot associate with them on equal terms and yet
                        maintain that sense of superiority which it is to be hoped the white race
                        will never lose--which indeed it cannot lose without detriment to itself and
                        to civilization.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Valley Spirit:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>By request of the Honorable Board of School Directors of St. Thomas township,
                        I hereby make a statement of some facts concerning the difficulty that
                        occurred in my school between the whites and the colored children of Mr.
                        Joseph Winters. I received them kindly, and had not the least aversion to
                        teaching them. I taught the little boy the alphabet, having no others to
                        class with him. I procured the necessary books for Miss Lucy, and placed her
                        in those classes that her attainments demanded. She was at least two years
                        the senior of any other in the classes. I allowed her to trap and persisted
                        in it until parents and pupils began to complain. I then brought the matter
                        before the Board; they took no action, but told me to manage the affair in
                        such a manner that I could have peace and harmony in the school. Some of the
                        members of the Board however, spoke to Mr. Winters in regard to the matter.
                        He said I could dispose of them as regards the trapping and classification
                        as I saw fit. He only desired me to give them the same attention that I gave
                        the others. Taking it for granted that Mr. Winters was perfectly satisfied
                        with the arrangements, I made the change. Miss Lucy being absent for a few
                        days returned. Her place of course was at the foot; I then kindly told her
                        that, in order to remedy a disturbance that had been existing in the school
                        for some time, she should keep her place at the foot. After disposing of her
                        in this manner, we got along very smoothly in school. The young ladies who
                        previously shunned her, now associated to a greater extent with her and we
                        had peace.</p>
                    <p>Previous to this change, the whites would not drink out of the same drinking
                        vessel. I told them to bring a vessel along. They did so. I did all I
                        possibly could to have peace and harmony to reign. So far as I understand,
                        Mr. Winters cherishes the highest regard for me. I desired peace and harmony
                        to reign in my school, and in order to have it so, I found it necessary to
                        dispose of her as I did. It was a painful duty that devolved upon me, and I
                        dealt with it to the best of my judgment and ability. Hoping these few
                        isolated facts will suffice, I will close.</p>
                    <p>JNO. CALVIN DEATRICH.<lb/> St. Thomas, Pa., March 8, 1869.</p>
                    <p>We, the undersigned, Teachers of St. Thomas township, were present at the
                        meeting of the Board of School Directors when the Teacher brought the
                        difficulty that occurred at the Bratten School before them. The Board took
                        no action in the matter, but told the Teacher that he should do the best he
                        could to keep peace and harmony in the school, and not to make any change if
                        he could possibly get along without it.<lb/> JNO. F. REESE.<lb/> JOHN W.
                        CORLE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winters</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrich</ln>
                        <fn>John Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corle</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on an incident at a local school involving trouble with interracial
                    classes. Prints the letter of the teacher of the class, who defended his
                    actions, and another letter from other teachers supporting their colleague.
                    Editor takes the view that white and black children should never be taught
                    together since it would degrade white superiority.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houck</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John F. McCleary and Miss Ellen V. Keefer, both of Chmabersburg, were
                    married on March 7th at the M. E. Parsonage in Shippensburg by the Rev. A.
                    Houck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehrer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Lehrer of Chambersburg died on February 7th. He was 65 years old.
                    "The deceased was a highly respected citizen, a consistent christian, an
                    affectionate husband and a kind father."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>Lydia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary E. Powell, daughter of Daniel and Lydia Powell, died in Pleasant Hill
                    on February 15th. She was 3 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sowers</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hiram Sowers died in Fayetteville of consumption on February 21st. He was
                    34 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bomberger</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Bomberger died in his residence near Shippensburg on March 9th. He
                    was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.03.10.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
