<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1869/pa.fr.vs.1869.10.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1869-10-27">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Border County Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of York, Adams, Franklin, Cumberland, Fulton and Bedford counties
                        suffered greatly from the depredations of the enemy during the late
                        rebellion. They have always entertained a hope that the losses they
                        sustained would some day be made good by the National or the State
                        government. The application made in their behalf to Congress received no
                        consideration from that body, but this did not lead them to abandon all hope
                        that their just claim to indemnification would finally be allowed.--As the
                        inaction of Congress weakened the hope they had entertained that the
                        National government would come to their relief, their faith grew stronger
                        that <emph rend="italic">the State</emph> would do something for them. The
                        Border Counties were the break-water against which the waves of the
                        rebellion had expended their fury. Behind them the balance of the State had
                        reposed in safety. Every consideration of justice and of gratitude seemed to
                        furnish a guarantee that the three millions of people who had escaped the
                        ravages of the invading foe, would offer to make good the losses of the few
                        thousands upon whom that foe had expended his fury. But though more than
                            <emph rend="italic">seven years</emph> have elapsed since the first
                        depredations were committed and it will soon be five years since the war was
                        brought to a close, no relief has been given to these plundered people,
                        except the half million dollars appropriated to the Chambersburg sufferers.</p>
                    <p>If our National and State governments had been pinched for funds, and if
                        those who administer them had been making a struggle to relieve the people
                        from taxation, there might be some excuse for the failure to do justice to
                        the Border Counties. But it is well known that Congress appropriated from
                        ten to fifteen million dollars a year, for several years in succession, to
                        feed and clothe Southern negroes who were abundantly able to work and
                        maintain themselves, and it is equally well known that the State Treasurer
                        of Pennsylvania has kept from one to two millions on hand all the time, for
                        the exclusive benefit of the "treasury ring" of which he is the central
                        figure.</p>
                    <p>If this "treasury ring" had not been in existence, the appropriation to
                        Chambersburg would have been a million instead of only half that amount.</p>
                    <p>Now, who are responsible for the denial of justice to the Border Counties?
                        The answer is plain. The Republicans have been in power in every branch of
                        the State and National governments. They could at any time have given us
                        compensation for these losses. They had full and complete command of the
                        means, and all they lacked was the disposition. Generally speaking, "where
                        there is a will there is a way." In this case <emph rend="italic">the
                        way</emph> was clear enough, but <emph rend="italic">the will</emph> did not
                        exist.</p>
                    <p>We presume the claims of the Border Counties will again be presented to the
                        State Legislature at its next session. What probability is there that the
                        Republican majority in that body will take them into favorable
                        consideration? Suppose a few prominent Republicans go from this section to
                        Harrisburg, to importune their political friends in the Legislature to make
                        an appropriation for the benefit of the border sufferers--what answer will
                        they be likely to get? Will not Senators and Representatives from the
                        Northern, Eastern and Western parts of the State say to them: "Gentlemen, we
                        suppose you are not in earnest about this matter. We take it for granted you
                        are only playing off on the people of your section.--John W. Geary has been
                        Governor of this Commonwealth for the last three years.--During all this
                        period he has never said one word in favor of compensating the border
                        sufferers, either in his official communications to the Legislature or in
                        private conversation with any of its members. He was a candidate for
                        re-election last October. You and the Republicans of the Border Counties,
                        whose interests you pretend to represent here, voted for him. Actions speak
                        louder than words. Your votes weigh heavier than anything you can say to us.
                        For three years Gov. Geary has persistently refused to endorse these border
                        claims, and yet the Republicans of the Border Counties have voted for him.
                        We interpret your real desires from your votes, and we will stand by Gov.
                        Geary in opposition to your claims. We are thankful for the support you have
                        given us. Without the twenty thousand Republican voters of the Border
                        Counties we should have been badly beaten. Go home and continue to humbug
                        them. You will have another chance next fall. Like Governor Geary,
                        Congressman Cessna has not crooked a finger in favor of your border claims.
                        He will be a candidate for re-election. A few of our friends may be disposed
                        to inquire why he has not brought your claims before Congress. Your
                        ingenuity in glazing over the matter in Governor Geary's case gives us great
                        confidence that you will succeed in covering Cessna's tracks. Go home,
                        gentlemen, and take with you the blessings of the treasury ring."</p>
                    <p>What reply could a Border County Republican make to a speech like this? There
                        stands the fact that Geary has never opened his mouth in favor of the
                        suffering people of the Border Counties, and there also stands the facts
                        that the Republicans of those counties voted for him only two weeks ago.
                        Have not the people of other parts of the State a right to infer that those
                        who have so voted do not desire compensation for their losses? We must admit
                        that the inference would be a fair one, and we have serious apprehensions
                        that it will be drawn.</p>
                    <p>We allude to this matter after the election, in a time of perfect freedom
                        from political excitement in the hope that the Republicans of the Border
                        Counties will look at it in its true light. With scarcely an exception, the
                        Democrats in the Legislature have been favorable to the payment of these
                        claims. With few exceptions, the Republicans in that body have been against
                        their payment. At the last session, there was a solid Democratic vote in the
                        Senate in favor of Duncan's motion to print the report of the Damage
                        Commissioners, and a solid Republican vote against it. We are thoroughly
                        convinced that unless the Republicans of the Border Counties lay aside their
                        political prejudices for a season and vote as their interests demand,
                        payment of the Border Damages never will be obtained. They must make their
                        political friends in other parts of the State <emph rend="italic"
                            >feel&gt;</emph> the danger they incur by denying the just demands
                        of the plundered people of the Border Counties. Unfortunately the favorable
                        opportunity presented by the late election was not improved as it should
                        have been, and this important matter is enveloped in the thick fog of the
                        future. With Asa Packer in the Governor's chair and a Democratic majority in
                        the Legislature, relief would speedily have come to our long-suffering
                        people. With Geary and a Republican majority, what promise does the future
                        hold out when viewed in the light of the past?</p>
                    <p>It is time for the Republicans of this section to take a decided stand in
                        this matter? What will they do? Can any of their organs inform us?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Makes another complaint about the refusal of the State and National
                    governments to compensate border counties for losses incurred during the war.
                    Blames Republicans for this, claims Democrats would speedily provide relief if
                    they were in power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Gold Gamblers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper demands explanations from President Grant regarding charges that
                    he had been involved in gold speculation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Election. The Full Official Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Results of the election in Pennsylvania. In the gubernatorial election,
                    Franklin cast 4006 votes for the Democrat, Packer, and 3698 for the Republican,
                    Geary. In election for Supreme Judge, Franklin cast 3974 votes for Democrat
                    Pershing and 3707 for the Republican Williams. Statewide, Geary won 290,552 to
                    Packer's 285,956 and Williams won 291,278 to Pershing's 282,575. In elections
                    for legislature, Franklin recorded 4157 votes for George W. Skinner; 3950 for D.
                    B. Milliken; 3741 for William C. M'Knight; 3559 for Jesse L. Gantt. The total
                    vote for the district comprised of Franklin and Perry showed 6538 for Skinner;
                    6378 for Milliken; 6116 for M'Knight; 6005 for Gantt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Law Partnership</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>C. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Senator C. M. Duncan and Col. Theodore McGowan have formed a partnership to
                    practice law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death of Capt. Brand</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. A. J. Brand died in Harrisburg on Wednesday and his remains were
                    brought to Chambersburg the following day. Brand had served as commanding
                    officer of Co. K, 107th PA. "He was a good officer and a brave soldier. His
                    regiment was distinguished for its excellent fighting qualities, being engaged
                    in the battle of second Bull Run, South Mountain, Antietam, and Fredericksburg."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Public Meeting--The Border Damages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The convention on war damage claims that met in the Chambersburg Court
                    House has adjourned to meet in November. Though the paper doesn't entertain high
                    hopes of the claims being met, it urges citizens to attend and continue
                    agitation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Special Term of the Court of Common Pleas began on Monday, the 18th inst.,
                        his Honor, Judge Rowe on the Bench. The following cases were tried during
                        the course of the week:</p>
                    <p>Frederick Forem vs. Isaac Cushwa. <emph rend="italic">capis ad
                        respondendum</emph>. Verdict for plaintiff, $189.37.</p>
                    <p>Etter, Strealy &amp; Eyster vs. Samuel Reisher, owner or reputed owner,
                        with notice to D.S. Reisher <unclear>terre</unclear> tenant and present
                        reputed owner. <emph rend="italic">Sotre Facis</emph> on Mechanics Lien.
                        Verdict for the Plff., $287.42.</p>
                    <p>David X. Hoffman vs. Samuel Hoffman's Administrator. Summons in Assumpsit.
                        Verdict for the Plff., $355.63.</p>
                    <p>Wm. D. Dixon &amp; Martha, his wife, in right of said Martha, and John
                        Walker &amp; Sarah Ann, his wife, in right of said Sara Ann vs. Wm.
                        Gillan, John Gillan, Jr., and Samuel H. Gillan. Amicable action in
                        Assumpsit. Verdict for Plff., $1485.56.</p>
                    <p>Mary Thompson, David Kyner, Alexander Duncan &amp; Euphemia, his wife,
                        John D. Coldsmith &amp; Catharine, his wife, Jane Ann Marshal, James
                        McCormick &amp; Georgiana, his wife, children of George Kyner dec'd, and
                        John Kyner, James Kyner, Jane Kyner, Margaret Kyner, Rebecca
                        Kyner,-------Reside, children of Margaret Kyner and grandchildren of said
                        George Kyner vs. Alexander Kyner. Summons in Ejectment for a farm in
                        Southampton township containing 146 acres, being the Mansion Farm of said
                        Geo. Kyner, dec'd, a tract of timber land in same township containing twelve
                        acres, and a tract of mountain land <sic>containg</sic> twenty-three acres.</p>
                    <p>This last case was begun on Wednesday afternoon and was still on trial on
                        Saturday evening, and the Court adjourned until Monday of this week. The
                        case was argued on Monday by Messrs. Stewart and Sharpe for the Plaintiffs
                        and Messrs Brewer and Cessna for the Defendant. It was given to the jury
                        about three o'clock on Monday afternoon. The jury after being out all night,
                        returned a verdict on Tuesday morning for defendant, sustaining the will.</p>
                    <p>At the conclusion of the Kyner case, his Honor, Judge King took his seat upon
                        the Bench and after the Constable had made their returns, and motions of
                        Counsel had been heard, the case of the Com. vs. John Henninger was taken
                        up. This was a case of Surety of the Peace in which David Teeter was the
                        Prosecutor. The threats made grew out of difficulties in relation to a
                        division fence between the lands of Teeter and Henninger. The case was
                        dismissed and each party ordered to pay his own costs.</p>
                    <p>A <emph rend="italic">nolte prosequi</emph> was entered in the following
                        cases: Com. vs. Philip Weisner--Maintaining a Nuisance. Com. vs. John
                        Sites--Larceny. Com. vs. Alfred Mohler--Larceny. Com. vs. Napoleon Beard.
                            <emph rend="italic">et al</emph>.--Riot, and Assault and Battery. Com.
                        vs. Hezekiah Palsgrove--Fornication and Bastardy. Com. vs. John
                        Lantz--Disturbing Religious Meeting.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushwa</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strealy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>David X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoffman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillan</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Euphemia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coldsmith</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshal</ln>
                        <fn>Jane Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCormick</ln>
                        <fn>Georgiana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cessna</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeter</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisner</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sites</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mohler</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Napoleon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palsgrove</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lantz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives a brief summary of a special term of the County court, naming cases
                    and verdicts. Gives a more detailed description of one particular case involving
                    a Kyner family will. Ends by listing cases to be taken up later.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Elections held on the 12th inst., for borough, ward and township
                        officers, resulted in the election of the following persons:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Chambersburg--Borough</emph>--Burgess, E J Bonebrake;
                        Town Council, F S Gillespie, L B Kurtz, S F Greenawalt, Peter Creighbaum;
                        School Directors, Jacob Henninger, Calvin Gilbert; Auditor, R P Hazelet.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">North Ward</emph>.--Judge, Samuel Etter, R; Inspectors, D
                        M Desher, W H Boyle; Constable, Philip Hamman.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">South Ward</emph>.--Judge, John Gerbig. D; Inspectors, W
                        F Eyster, J N Sillito; Justice of the Peace, H B Davidson; Constable, George
                        M'Geehan.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Antrim</emph>.--Judge, Benj Snivel, R; Inspectors, John
                        Wilhelm, Joseph Paxton; Supervisors, Abraham Bowim, Issac Kuhu, John Stover,
                        Christian Hege; School Directors, D S Barnhart, I N Zimmerman; Constable,
                        Henry Balsy; Auditor, A A Miller; Township Clerk, E D Detrich.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Greencastle</emph>.--Burgess, Joe A
                        <unclear>Davidson</unclear>; Town Council, Joseph B Strickler, Wm Osbraugh,
                        John Bert, C F Bonner, Theodore Koontz; School Directors, D Watson, <del/>
                        Rowe, William Kreps; Justice of the Peace, A K Weir; Constable, Henry
                        <del/>; Auditor, Jacob L Detrich; Town Clerk, E D Detrich.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Green</emph>.--Justice of the Peace, C W <del/>;
                        Constable William Bittinger; Supervisors, Henry Lutz, Michael Riley, Daniel
                        <del/>; School Directors, William Brandt, Jacob Kauffman, A M Criswell;
                        Auditor, Henry Sleichter; Township Clerk, Frank Besore.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Greenvillage</emph>.--Judge, William <del/>, R;
                        Inspectors, C M Ditslear, William <unclear>Wallace</unclear>, Sr.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fayetteville</emph>.--Judge, Samuel C <del/>, R;
                        Inspectors, Adam B Winger, John <del/>.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Guilford</emph>.--Judge, David Overcastle; Inspectors, J
                        C Snyder, A S <del/>; School Directors, Samuel Bender, August Frommeyer;
                        Supervisors, C J <del/>, John Reichard, Michael Ebersole; Auditor, John
                        McFerren; Treasurer, Jeremiah <del/>; Township Clerk, Samuel C Weaver;
                        Constable George Stever.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Letterkenny</emph>.--Judge, Jeremiah Ashford, D;
                        Inspectors, Wm Forbes, James S <del/>; School Directors, Solomon <del/>,
                        Fred'k Rife, John Besore (1 year); Supervisors, David Guyer, John S Brake,
                        <del/> Franklin; Auditors, Peter Creamer, <del/> C M'Clellan; Township
                        Clerk, J V B <del/>; Justice of the Peace, Daniel Gelwith; Township
                        Treasurer, Joseph Gilmore; Constable, Joseph Gabler.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Funnett</emph>.--Justice of the Peace, William Moulder;
                        Constable, James M'Enes; School Directors, William Shearer, John Fleck;
                        Supervisors, George Myers, Joseph Eckenrode; Auditor, Rober Price.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Concord</emph>.--Judge, John E Campell; Inspectors, Adam
                        B Seibert, George M'Mullen.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dry Run</emph>.--Judge, David Bair, R; Inspectors, T B
                        Gasten, John Harkins.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Sulphur Spring</emph>.--Judge, Conrad Eckerod, D;
                        Inspectors, Ezra Shoemaker, M M'Vitty.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Lurgan</emph>.--Judge, S P Shields, D; Inspectors, John H
                        Reed, J P Miller; Supervisors, Samuel Mowery, Daniel Cover; School
                        Directors, David Shoemaker, E D Weaver; Auditor, J H Thomas; Township Clerk;
                        Josiah Shuman; Constable, John Breckenridge; Treasurer, John Pisle.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Metal</emph>.--Judge, A A Skinner, R; Inspectors, Frank
                        Rosenberry, James Seibert; Justice of the Peace, Wm Noonen; School
                        Directors, S O McCurdy, J J Hill; Supervisors, Samuel R Jones, George A
                        Miller; Auditor, William S Harris; Treasurer, Jacob J Besore: Township
                        Clerk, R E Typer; Constable, Adam Flagle.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Montgomery</emph>.--School Directors, James G. Rhodes,
                        John K Keyser, John W Kuhn, Joseph M Brewer; Supervisors, John W Carbaugh,
                        James Witherspoon, Samuel Speer; Auditor, J B Angle; Township Clerk, G W
                        Kennedy; Constable, Thomas M Geeseman.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mercersburg</emph>.--Judge, W Hays M'Clellan, R;
                        Inspectors, David M'Connel, C <del/> Louderbaugh.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Welsh Run</emph>.--Judge, Louis H Henkle, D; Inspectors,
                        D E Wolf, Daniel Brewer.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Peters</emph>.--Judge, Wm E McDowell, R; Inspectors, Geo
                        W Etter, John Hay; Constable, Jacob Haulman; School Directors, Henry Etter,
                        Samuel Baker; Auditor, Jacob Blattenberger; Supervisors, David Vance, Geo H
                        Potter, James Campbell; Township Clerk, Henry Garns; Justice of the Peace,
                        Jacob Snyder.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Loudon</emph>.--Judge, George M Stenger, D; Inspectors,
                        Eli McCullough, Mordecai Duncan.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Quincy</emph>.--Judge, James A Cook, D; Inspectors, D D
                        Monn, E J Shank; Justice of the Peace, Wm B Ruby; Constable, Levi Heefner;
                        Auditor, Geo Knepper; Supervisors, John Bushman, Joseph Rock, Jacob Welsh;
                        School Directors, Ephraim Snyder, John Henninger.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Southampton</emph>.--Justice of the Peace, Simon Bitner;
                        School Directors, S G Breckenridge, Robert C Johnson; Supervisors, Jacob
                        Mohler, Sr, Geo W Kable; Auditor, John Powders; Township Clerk, John N
                        Hamilton; Constable, Hugh Smith.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Orrstown</emph>.--Judge, W A P Linn, D; Inspectors, H H
                        Hoover, Levi Kendig.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mt. Rock</emph>.--Judge, John Miller, D; Inspectors,
                        Jacob Hamsher, Reynolds Wallace.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">St. Thomas</emph>.--Judge, Daniel Coble, D; Inspector, F
                        H Kerling, John V Small; Supervisors, Daniel Kunkle, Henry, Defendarfer,
                        John Myers; School Directors, Geo Sellers, Thomas Gillan; Township Clerk,
                        Alexander Martin; Constable, Amos Detrich; Auditor, Alburtus Hicks.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Warren</emph>.--Judge, J C Cook, D; Inspectors, Abe
                        Zimmerman, Henry Yeakle; Constable, Joseph Phenicie; Supervisors, Jacob
                        Bear, Peter Zimmerman; School Directors, Wm Suffacool, David Fenley,
                        Jonathan Yeakle; Auditor, Jacob Yeakle; Township Clerk, Henry Cole; Justice
                        of the Peace, Issac Suffacool.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Washington</emph>.--Judge, Isaac Hoke, R; Inspectors,
                        George Summers, Henry Oaks; School Directors, David M Stoner, Christain
                        Lesher; Supervisors, Geo T Mong, Abraham Deardorf, Daniel Potter, John
                        Rodgers; Auditor, Henry Gilbert; Constable, H A Fisher; Justice of the
                        Peace, George Bender.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Waynesboro'</emph>.--School Directors, E A Herring, J H
                        Johnston; Constable, Wm F Horner.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Hamilton</emph>.--Judge, Abraham Hafer, D; Inspectors,
                        Samuel Gillan, Henry Keeffer; School Directors, B B Picking. Samuel
                        Overcash; Supervisors, John Rowe, Frederick Mish, William Hafer; Constable,
                        Samuel West; Auditor, B B Picking; Township Clerk, David C Ward.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the names of all people elected to local office in every township in
                    Franklin county. First half of the article was cut off to a degree so some of
                    the names were indistinct.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gossert</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fohl</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Gossert and Mrs. Catharine R. Mentzer, both of Franklin, were
                    married on October 17th by the Rev. John Fohl.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dieter</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schenck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Wingert and Miss Annie Dieter, both of Franklin, were married on
                    October 14th by Rev. Dr. Schenck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schenck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Gordon and Josephine Wingert, both of Franklin, were married at the
                    same time as the above on October 14th by the Rev. Dr. Schenck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowers</ln>
                        <fn>S. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Maria C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. S. A. Mowers, of the Pennsylvania Conference, and Miss Maria C.
                    Gelwicks, daughter of Frederick Gelwicks from near St. Thomas, were married on
                    October 14th at the Pleasant Retreat Parsonage by the Rev. J. M. Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shire</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karper</ln>
                        <fn>Mary I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherts</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel Shire of Guilford and Miss Mary I. Karper of Letterkenny were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on October 19th by the Rev. A. H.
                    Sherts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beumont</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tripner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Beumont and Miss Mary C. Evans, both of Franklin, were married on
                    October 21st by the Rev. A. Tripner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Fisher and Mrs. Barbara Grove, both of Shady Grove, were married on
                    October 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elden</ln>
                        <fn>Ezekiel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weagly</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buhrman</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ezekiel Elden and Miss Caroline Weagly were married on October 12th at the
                    residence of the bride's parents in Waynesboro by the Rev. A. Buhrman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoeflich</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Resser</ln>
                        <fn>M. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hibshman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John R. Hoeflich and Miss M. C. Resser were married on October 19th at the
                    residence of the bride's parents in Waynesboro by the Rev. Hibshman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calemore</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Nervina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Russell</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Calemore and Miss Nervina Patterson, both of Quincy, were married on
                    October 19th by D. B. Russell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritten</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis Ritten died in Fayetteville on October 7th. He was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brake</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Annie Brake died in her home in St. Thomas on October 16th. She was 34
                    years old. "Sleep gently, dear mother, sleep,/Beside thy little boy,/Who was
                    once thy tender care,/Thy fondness and thy joy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1869.10.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
