<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.04.07">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/04/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-07">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">7</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The people of Baltimore have by vote, authorized, if not instructed the city
                        to authorize to subscribe one million of dollars to the stock of the Valley
                        R.R. This subscription is, however, subject to two conditions. 1st that the
                        Baltimore &amp; Ohio R.R. Company shall subscribe one million, and the
                        counties along the line from Harrisonburg to Salem shall subscribe twelve
                        hundred thousand dollars--of this latter sum Staunton has authorized a
                        subscription of $100,000, Rockbridge $100,000, Botetourt $200,000--leaving
                        $300,000 to be raised by Augusta and $200,000 by Roanoke.</p>
                    <p>We presume that when it is reduced to a certainty that Baltimore and the
                        Baltimore &amp; Ohio R.R. are ready to advance their two millions,
                        Augusta and Roanoke will not hold back.</p>
                    <p>But it is said that there is likely to be a "hitch" in the matter growing out
                        of a bill pending in the Legislature known as the consolidation bill, by
                        which all the Railroads from Norfolk to Bristol are to be consolidated into
                        one company. By the terms of this bill it is apprehended that discrimination
                        will be made in favor of the consolidated company, which will prevent the
                        transshipment of freight at Salem, from what is now the Lynchburg and
                        Tennessee Road, to the Valley Road. Such discrimination will, it is feared,
                        prevent the Valley Road from participating in the freight and trade of the
                        Southwest. Should this be the case, it is very questionable whether either
                        Baltimore city, or the Baltimore &amp; Ohio R.R. will subscribe at all,
                        and thus the Valley Road may fail. It is particularly annoying, to be thus
                        disappointed when we were just about to clutch the prize for which we have
                        been struggling for more than forty years.</p>
                    <p>It behooves the people of the valley to keep a sharp look out on the subject.</p>
                    <p> As for consolation we feel no interest in it either way. We do not intend to
                        be parties to the animated contest which is now going on in regard to it.
                        But we are for fair play. We are against all unjust discriminations in favor
                        of one part of the State against another. We are for equal justice to all.
                        We are for <emph rend="italic">pro rata</emph> rates of freight and travel
                        on all our roads. We are for opening the doors of competition and against
                        all narrow selfish policy in the management of any great thoroughfare.
                        Railroads were intended for the public benefit--not for the advancement in
                        this or that particular city. They were intended for the benefit of the
                            <emph rend="italic">producers,</emph> the great agricultural class. They
                        were intended to <emph rend="italic">promote</emph> trade--not to <emph
                            rend="italic">warp</emph> and <emph rend="italic">shackle</emph> it, by
                        forcing it into unnatural and artificial channels. The cotton, flour, bacon,
                        iron, and other products of the country ought to be allowed to seek the best
                        markets, with the least possible restriction and cost. Half a million of
                        producers certainly have a stronger claim to be accommodated, than fifty or
                        a hundred commission merchants, either in Richmond, Norfolk or Baltimore.
                        Let us have <emph rend="italic">free trade</emph> over our Railroads, in
                        every direction. Let the planters and farmers and grazers be at liberty to
                        see where they can get the best terms. We want no privileged classes, and no
                        privileged places. Railroads were not built for the exclusive benefit of
                        commission merchants or cities. They are for public accommodation, and they
                        should be so managed and regulated as to confer the greatest good on the
                        greatest number. </p>
                    <p>The people, and their Representatives should bear this great truth in mind.
                        If representatives forget it, the people should remind them of it, and if
                        they do not heed the admonition, they should choose others who will--unless
                        they do we shall soon have railroad "Rings" which will sacrifice the public
                        good in their insatiate desire for gain, and constitute themselves into a
                        sort of moneyed aristocracy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article outlines the possible "hitch" that would prevent the
                    completion of the valley Railroad. A bill, now being proposed, would consolidate
                    all the lines between Norfolk and Bristol. A consolidation of this sort would
                    cut the Valley road out of trade with the Southwest. The author argues that this
                    consolidation runs counter to the intentions of rail commerce. They are for the
                    good of the whole public, and discrimination in favor of one line would not
                    "confer the greatest good on the greatest number."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that the memory of John Brown was celebrated at a recent
                    Fifteenth Amendment jubilee meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that the founder of the Valley Virginian, Maj. A. M.
                    Garber, Jr., paid a visit to the offices of the paper to celebrate the newest
                    volume.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Ladies and Gentlemen of Staunton and Vicinity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shearer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hawkins and Shearer announce to the ladies of Staunton that they have
                    leased a room in which to set up a Wheeler and Wilson Sewing Machine Office.
                    They invite shoppers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Rail Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The terms upon which Baltimore offers to unite with us in building this road
                        are these: That her subscription of $1,000,000 shall be made so soon as, and
                        not until "the counties and towns in the Valley of Virginia" subscribe, at
                        least, $1,000,000 more to the stock, and, further more, not until other
                        corporations or persons, solvent and able to pay, subscribe $1,200,000 more,
                        so that, <emph rend="italic">before</emph> we can start we are bound to
                        raise $3,200,000 of capital stock subscribed, of which $1,000,000, at least,
                        must be subscribed by the counties and towns of the Valley. Of this sum,
                        only $700,000 have been subscribed, and if Augusta refuses to subscribe it
                        will be impossible to raise the amount elsewhere, and the whole grand
                        enterprise must fail. Jefferson county, in West Virginia, with two railroads
                        running right through its territory, and with two navigable roads, and a
                        canal on its borders has just voted $200,000 to another Railroad which is to
                        pass through it, and, this, too, while burdened with all the taxation which
                        West Virginia radicalism can impose upon its people, for free schools, and
                        for hordes of county officers, the support of whom we will escape. And shall
                        Augusta, who boasts of her enterprise and public spirit--of being a live
                        people, and full of the advanced ideas of modern progress--shall this great
                        county, by holding back, absolutely defeat a Railroad, which Gen'l Lee has
                        pronounced one of the most important and valuable works of the day! All the
                        rest of the Capital is ready: Baltimore with her $1,000,000; Capitalists
                        (some in England, we are informed) with $1,2000,000, Rockbridge having far
                        less wealth than Augusta, with $400,000, Botetourt with $200,000, and
                        Staunton with $100,000; all, await the action of Augusta. She is the
                        key-stone of the arch; without her, the great enterprise must lie in ruins;
                        with her aid, in ninety days, the contract will be at work in our midst. In
                        the course of eighteen months, more than a million and a quarter of other
                        peoples' money will be spent in the county; our farmers will have a home
                        market for their products; our merchants in town and country, will thrive
                        and prosper; money will circulate freely; hard times will become easy; and a
                        new impulse be given to every interest and industry of the courts. In a
                        word, as a shrewd business man remarked a day or two since: "The people of
                        the county <emph rend="italic">can clear</emph> the whole subscription in
                        eighteen months, if they can have a million and a quarter of dollars spent
                        in their midst at this time." </p>
                    <p> Let no man say, he will not vote for the road because it may not come near
                            <emph rend="italic">his</emph> farm, or until the road is located, or
                        until officers are chosen acceptable to them, (as if officers would be
                        selected or the road be located until the company is organized--as if the
                        company could be organized, until Augusta votes her subscription), or
                        because some body else, will make it for us, or it will make itself. Away
                        with such suggestions; let us come forward like men, make up the company,
                        choose the best men for office, (no body <emph rend="italic">owns</emph> the
                        offices <emph rend="italic">or those who are to fill them</emph>), select
                        the route best under all the circumstances, (that will be most likely to be
                        chosen, along which road has most friends) put our own, shoulders, like
                        Hercules, to the wheel, and push the car of our prosperity ahead, by helping
                        ourselves, being well aware that if we don't help ourselves no body else
                        will help us. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article lists the amounts of various subscriptions to the Valley
                    railroad. Importantly, the author expresses the need of further contributions
                    from Augusta County. Subscriptions from other areas are contingent upon
                    Augusta's contribution. Without it, the whole enterprise will fail. The article
                    admonishes those who make excuses against the road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William B. Dunlap and Miss Sarah C. Brown, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 20th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trainum</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Francis L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David C. Trainum and Miss Frances L. Smith, both of Augusta, were married
                    on March 24th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James L. Dunlap and Miss Mary A. Kerr, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 27th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine McKee, wife of Samuel McKee, died near Middlebrook, Augusta
                    County, on March 18th after a "painful illness of three weeks, which she bore
                    with Christian patience."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
