<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.09.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/11/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-08">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Nomination for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As we stated last week, the choice of Congressmen is restricted to two
                        classes, to wit. Those who can take the iron clad oath, and those whose
                        disabilities have been removed, and who consequently, are not required to
                        take it. There are not, in this District at least, a great many of either
                        class who possess the other requisite qualifications to make suitable
                        representatives in the National Legislature. We should be represented by the
                        very best that can be selected from the few who possess the requisite
                        qualifications.</p>
                    <p> Without any discouragement to others in other portions of the District, we
                        think we are justified in saying that Augusta county can present in the
                        person of one of her sons, whose disabilities have been removed, the peer,
                        in talents, character, public service, legislative experience, and claims to
                        popular support, of any that can be presented by any county in the District.
                        As the reader has no doubt anticipated, we allude to Hon. A.H.H. Stuart, who
                        was a few years ago elected, by a triumphant majority, to represent this
                        District in Congress, but was refused admittance because he could not and
                        would not take the iron clad oath. This would not be required of him now, as
                        his political disabilities have been removed by act of Congress. We suppose
                        the delegates to the Harrisonburg Convention from this county, will vote to
                        secure the nomination of Mr. Stuart, if he be willing to accept it. [We
                        write in ignorance of his wishes upon this subject.] He was elected, but was
                        prevented from serving by a cause which did him honor--it was because his
                        sentiments were in accordance with those of the great mass of citizens of
                        the District--because he was a true exponent of the people whom he was
                        elected to represent. The fact that he would, in truth, <emph rend="italic"
                            >represent</emph> the people of this district, was the reason why he
                        was, by Radical policy, prevented at that time from acting as their
                        Representative. Besides his indisputable qualifications to make an able and
                        faithful representative, the fact that he was prevented from serving, for
                        the reason we have stated, gives him <emph rend="italic">special</emph>
                        claims to the support of the people--such as no other in the District can
                        present. </p>
                    <p>It seems to us that it is due to themselves that the voters of the District
                        should re elect Mr. Stuart. The right which was wrongfully denied them, they
                        now have an opportunity to exercise, and we think it is their duty to do so.
                        The right to be represented in Congress by the person of their choice was
                        then denied the voters of the District. That right, if their choice be the
                        same, cannot be denied them now. If elected, he must be admitted, and that,
                        too, without taking the oath. This would be a victory over the body which
                        had violated the rights of the people of the District--"a consummation
                        devoutly to be wished."</p>
                    <p> The above is taken from the last issue "of the Staunton <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spectator,</emph> and heartily endorsed by us. We hope it may be the
                        pleasure of the Harrisonburg Convention to do themselves the honor of
                        nominating the honorable gentleman, who possesses, in a pre-eminent degree,
                        all the necessary qualifications, to faithfully and efficiently represent
                        us. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article advocates the election of A.H.H. Stuart to represent Augusta
                    County in Congress. While he had previously been elected, he was disallowed his
                    seat because he neither could nor would take the iron-clad oath. Now, however,
                    his political disabilities have been removed by an act of Congress, therefore,
                    the author states that it is Stuart's duty to attempt reelection. He hopes that
                    the Harrison Convention delegates cast their votes for Stuart, one of the few
                    who possess the qualifications necessary to represent the District.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Yates will replace Mrs. Catherine Ewing as postmaster at Long
                    Glade, Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Piper</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. T. Parent, town sergeant, arrested two African American youths for
                    allegedly stealing a gold watch from James A. Piper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Not Quite</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that an African American man was arrested near Hebron
                    Church for attempting to set fire to a straw stack. "That darkey, being tired of
                    his freedom, is hankering after a quiet home within the walls of the
                    penitentiary."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNut</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John McNut, a stonemason at Siberton, died after suffering typhoid fever
                    and pneumonia for three or four days. He had recently taken out a $1000
                    life-insurance policy with St. Louis Mutual, Capt. H. H. Peck, agent. His wife
                    will get the money. "Could a stronger argument be presented in favor of life
                    insurance?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Address by Gen. Gordon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. J. B. Gordon delivered an address in Staunton on Tuesday at the M. E.
                    Church. "The object of the address was to urge the importance of supplanting the
                    present books, (histories, geographies, etc.) written by northern men, and of
                    course from a northern stand-point, in use in Southern schools, with school
                    books by our own people. A Company has been formed, the books have been written,
                    and a considerable number already sold, and all that now remains to be done, to
                    make the enterprise a permanent success is, for Southern men to come forward,
                    with their characteristic liberality and sagacity as business men, and subscribe
                    to the stock of the company." Gordon will be in Staunton for a few days taking
                    subscriptions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stogdale</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransbottom</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Benjamin T. Stogdale and Miss Mary C. Ransbottom, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Churchville on August 31st by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Collins</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nannie R. Collins, daughter of Richard and Mary Collins, died in Staunton
                    on September 5th. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
