<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.01.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/03/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-01-27">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Peace!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We have not forgotten the promise we made to our readers some time ago - nor
                        do we intend now to impose upon them a political article, but the time and
                        the occasion is soon, that we feel constrained to discourse them for a
                        moment on <emph rend="italic">the</emph> Peace which we have to day! </p>
                    <p> Old Webster says first, Peace is harmony; concord; a state of reconciliation
                        between parties at variance - freedom from internal commotion or civil war,
                        public tranquility; that quiet, order, and security which is granted by the
                        laws * * *--and may we add--of a <emph rend="italic">just</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">pure</emph> government, such as the United States
                        Government is not! Yes this is Peace. We are quite sure that in taking him
                        as our guide we will not be far from the right track, and it is surely to be
                        regretted that his interpretation does not exist in these days and times,
                        and at glancing at the Peace of 1779, and this Peace of 1870, there is a
                        marked and painful difference, that we are almost disheartened before we
                        have regarded it in any light. We are well aware that we <emph rend="italic"
                            >cannot</emph> realize any of the hopes which were pictured to us, after
                        our successes in Maryland and Pennsylvania. We know full well that we are
                        never to have the peace which we believed would be the final result of those
                        successes. We know to our regret, that the quiet which we hoped for after
                        the "seven days before Richmond" and the horrors of the "crater" has long
                        since been taken from us, and all of our castles have tumbled down and are
                        now mocking us with their unnatural smiles, but we had hoped that when in
                        good faith we had accepted the situation there would come to us that
                        tranquility, that quiet, that order, that harmony, and that security, which
                        is granted by the laws--of our just government of which Mr. Webster speaks.
                        We had hoped that the time was not far distant when there would be a peace
                        for our country which would raise up and cheer every heart, in every State,
                        which have for so long a time been manacled and bound down to the earth and
                        spit upon. We had hoped the present session of Congress would be one which
                        would be handed down in future years filled with magnanimous actions and
                        marked by good deeds and resolutions towards those who have so long been
                        oppressed. We had hoped that the re-admission of Virginia would be a sign of
                        peace for which we have so long prayed--but alas! there is little peace for
                        us yet. We are told that it was reported of two noble Lacedarmonians that
                        being at mortal hatred, were met by Arahidamus, their king, in the temple of
                        Minerva; he required them to put the matter to an indifferent umpire; they
                        chose the king himself, he makes them swear to abide his order, which
                        accordingly they do: Now saith the king, I order that you shall not go out
                        of this temple until you be friends. And so they parted friends (for an oath
                        taken in that temple was unlawful to be broken).--Surely we have sent a
                        sufficient number of umpires and arbitrators to treat with Congress and with
                        what result? </p>
                    <p> There can be but little doubt that Mr. Sumner will never be reconciled to
                        the southern people, his hatred has grown and increased to such an extent,
                        that time can scarcely effect a change in his hardened heart, and until this
                        time, his sway in Congress will promote every thing else but peace, and our
                        friends need not expect any good ever from him.--We have recently seen in an
                        exchange, a short paragraph describing a meeting which took place in
                        Savannah, between Admiral Buchanan, Commodore Tadnall and General Joseph E.
                        Johnston who had been comrades together in the services of the United and
                        Confederate States; and also on the sea.--The meeting was a chance one, and
                        is described handsomely by the <emph rend="italic">Savannah News.</emph>
                        Could we have such hearts as theirs in Washington, perhaps there might be
                        some peace for us. </p>
                    <p>We had hoped before another session of Congress closed, to be able to
                        chronicle in our columns such work of theirs, that we could rely on that
                        body as a just and patriotic set of men--liberal in all their views, but our
                        experience thus far is of a different sort, and the peace that will come
                        from them will only be read to us through bars and sounded by the tinkling
                        of our chains which each day bind us closer and closer.</p>
                    <p> Where, oh! where is the peace that comes to the widow's heart this New Year?
                        Where, oh, where is the peace for which she prayed as the tide of battle
                        drew near to her mountain home, which alas has never been seen by him who
                        paid his quota to the war? Where is the peace that comes to her heart as she
                        remembers the vine covered Porch, once hallowed with tender memories and now
                        a pile of blackened ruin, and laid low by the hand of Hunter's heroes?
                        (!)Where is the peace that comes to the gray hairs of him, who has long
                        since given his only son, and now sadly gives out breath by breath the
                        remaining life which was once blessed with the comforts of a smiling home?
                        Where is the peace that comes to the young men of our land who toil day
                        after day, and at the death of each year, pay their last earnings to the
                        Revenue and State officers of the "best Government the world ever saw?" Is
                        this peace--is this the tranquility and rest which we long for? If so, we
                        have enough peace, we ask no more of this sort of concord! Coming
                        generations may see the peace which we were promised when Grant offered his
                        terms to Gen. Lee on the 9th of April 1865; and the boys of 1900 <emph
                            rend="italic">may</emph> have the peace we <emph rend="italic"
                        >expected</emph> when the little band of eight thousand were paroled on that
                        memorable 10th but there is no peace in our day for Virginia! </p>
                    <p> There is a pleasure and a comfort in spending a life in peace, which is far
                        more easily imagined than described. Would to God we might in our declining
                        years realize that comfort, alas! a few more chains! a few more groans! a
                        few more sighs--with no Peace, and we will be gathered hence to our Father
                            <emph rend="italic">where there is a peace that passeth all
                            understanding!</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article takes a skeptical look at the "peace" that supposedly prevails
                    across the country. Any peace, according to the author, would rest on sectional
                    reconciliation. Here, peace is described as a farce. Congress has continued to
                    antagonize the defeated section since the conclusion of the war, despite
                    promises made by Grant at Appomattox.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>In the Union!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The bill to admit Virginia as published elsewhere, has passed both houses of
                        Congress, and we are once more in the Union. Of course the emigration which
                        we have all along been told was repelled by the Canby government under which
                        we have been for some time living, will now commence and continue until
                        there will not be "room to contain them." All that capital which has been so
                        long <sic>futilly</sic> seeking investment in this State will now glide in
                        with such rapidity, and in such vast quantities, that our delighted citizens
                        will be compelled to cry, "hold, enough!" for, don't you see, we are in the
                        Union, and there, too, upon such easy terms. Our hearts are overflowing with
                        gratitude, and two nice little streams have commenced rippling down our
                        cheeks, because of the beneficence and magnanimity of Congress and the great
                        I Am, Grant. The question will no longer be with the citizens of the Valley,
                        "where shall we raise a sufficient amount to complete the Valley R.R.?" but
                        who shall we <emph rend="italic">allow</emph> to build it? In point of
                        wealth and population we may confidently expect soon to see Staunton ahead
                        of the great metropolis New York, and the queen city--not only of the
                        Valley--but of the great glorious Union which we very naughtily tried to
                        "bust up," and for which little peace of naughtiness, we have, for some
                        months past, been doing penance, eating a little dirt, and kneeling, for
                        absolution, before the great Commoner, spoon dealer and "soger' Hon. B.F.B.,
                        of Bethel celebrity. </p>
                    <p>We've actually been down on our knees praying Congress and the "Young
                        Napoleon" for admission on "those terms," and we guess it was in answer
                        thereto that we got in so soon.</p>
                    <p> Every body now ought to lift up his voice, and cry, great! great! art thou,
                        oh! magnanimous Congress! <emph rend="italic">and do please excuse us</emph>
                        for not recognizing this fact before! </p>
                    <p>We're in the Union!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In this article, more than a hint of sarcasm describes Virginia's
                    readmission to the Union. Most important, is the author's acknowledgement of the
                    vast sources of outside capital soon to support the region owing to the
                    "beneficence and magnanimity" of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Virginia Reconstruction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We make the following extract from an excellent article in a recent number
                        of the Richmond <emph rend="italic">Enquirer:</emph></p>
                    <p>"With the passage of the Virginia bill by the Senate we have also the
                        announcement that a negro named "Luther Lee" has been appointed collector of
                        customs at Norfolk in this State. Notwithstanding this announcement, our
                        impression is that Luther Lee is not a negro--but a carpetbagger. We already
                        have a negro postmaster in Manchester; and General Canby has just appointed
                        some negro justices of the peace in Amelia county.</p>
                    <p>We learn also that General Ames, a Yankee officer, has been selected to
                        represent Mississippi in the Senate along with a coal black negro, named
                        Revel, as his colleague.</p>
                    <p>This is the mild system of "reconstruction" to which the South is treated,
                        and which seems to delight some of our people so much that we understand the
                        admission of Virginia is to be signaled by the ringing of bells and the
                        booming of cannon--and we suppose illuminations. We left the Union with
                        salutes and fire-works and festive demonstrations; and we suppose it is meet
                        to atone for that sin by the most thorough abasement and by destroying our
                        work with the same brilliant emphasis which we gave to the doing of it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This extract from the Richmond Enquirer illustrated continued hostility
                    toward the oppressive forces that remain in the South. Although Virginia is to
                    be readmitted into the Union, and much of the citizenry is overjoyed by this
                    prospect, the author reminds his readers that trouble is still afoot. Blacks and
                    Yankees still hold high office throughout the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Judge Baldwin died at her Staunton residence last Tuesday at age 79.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association will perform "Daniel" in February.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>G. W. Wright and Miss Sarah M. Cox, both of Augusta, were married on
                    January 20th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret Hays died in Augusta on December 29th. She was 86.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miss Mary Crist died near Mint Spring on December 26th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Poage, wife of James Poage, died in Augusta on January 8th. She
                    was 58 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Nannie R. Hanger died at Churchville on December 31st. She was 31
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
