<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.05.19">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-05-19">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Worthy of Attention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There are some important lessons which the Southern people have yet to
                        learn--Among these, one of the most necessary, is, a proper appreciation of
                        the value of time. While every body is ready to admit the truth of the
                        abstract proportion that "time" is the most valuable of all God's gift's to
                        man, very few act as if they thought so. Most people seem to regard time as
                        a thing to be gotten rid of, rather than a "talent" to be improved.</p>
                    <p>In this respect there is the important difference between the people of the
                        north and those of the south. In the north people seem to realize the fact
                        that "time is money," while in the south it is a burden that is laid on
                        men's shoulders. We presume the difference results mainly from the different
                        labor systems which have prevailed in the two sections.</p>
                    <p>In the north, people had to work for themselves, while in the south, they had
                        others to work for them. Northern people therefore studied how they could
                        accomplish most in the least possible time, and with the least possible
                        expenditure of effort; while the people of the south employed their efforts
                        as to how they could amuse themselves while other people were doing their
                        work.</p>
                    <p>The labor system of the south has now been changed. Slavery is dead. People
                        no longer have others to work for them. They must now work for themselves,
                        and it is time they were beginning to accommodate their habits to the new
                        condition of things. Idleness is no longer respectable. The stay law has
                        expired and execution now goes forth in primeval judgment against man that
                        he shall earn his bread in the sweat of his brow!</p>
                    <p>It is hard to get rid of old habits. But we must do it. We must "realize the
                        situation" and conform to the new condition of affairs. We must learn to
                        work. We must set a proper estimate on the value of time.--We must neither
                        waste our own, nor rob other people of theirs. When we have business to
                        attend to with others we must do it promptly, and leave them to pursue their
                        occupations.</p>
                    <p> Our people are generally too slow and <emph rend="italic">"poking"</emph> in
                        their ways of transacting business. They talk too much and sit too long.
                        They must learn that if they have business with a merchant, or a lawyer, or
                        a doctor, or a mechanic or a preacher, they should attend to it promptly,
                        and give place to others who may have occasion to see them. </p>
                    <p>In this fast age "time is money" and we may with as much reason steal from a
                        man of business his money as his time--for one is, to him as valuable as the
                        other. Every hour of a business man's time, between 9 A.M. and 3 P.M. is
                        worth from two to five dollars according to the nature of his occupation.
                        The man, therefore, who forcibly robs him of his time robs him of time's
                        worth--money.</p>
                    <p>In business matters there is nothing like coming to the point at once.
                        Talking round and round the matter in issue leads to no good end. It is
                        always best to strike right into the joint, at once, instead of haggling all
                        along the bone. There is philosophy even in cutting a chicken leg. We always
                        strike for the joint in that operation. Why may we not do the same in all
                        our business transactions!</p>
                    <p>A word to the wise is sufficient.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article attacks those who waste time. In this new age, the author
                    suggests, time is money. Southerners should behave more like their northern
                    counterparts and not let time slip away through idleness. "We must neither waste
                    our own," he say, "nor rob other people of theirs." Idleness is merely an old
                    habit that must be broken, especially now that slavery is dead and there is no
                    one to do the work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Editor of Virginian:</p>
                    <p>Sir--At the suggestion of many fellow-townsmen, who recognize the necessity
                        for immediate action in view of the near approach of our municipal election,
                        the importance of the functions to be exercised by the successful
                        candidates, and the danger to be apprehended from any division of the
                        Conservative vote, I take the liberty of asking that you will announce
                        through the columns of your paper that a public meeting of the voters of the
                        town of Staunton will be held at the Court-house, on Saturday, 21st inst, at
                        8 o'clock P.M., for the purpose of making nominations for the offices to be
                        filled by election on the 4th Thursday of this month.</p>
                    <p>The officers to be chosen are as follows.</p>
                    <p>A Mayor, whose term is yet to be fixed by law, and who is invested with full
                        power to suspend or remove the other city officers, being himself the chief
                        Executive; eleven Councilmen, to hold for one year, who have the authority
                        to impose taxes, order levies, grant licenses and legislate almost at
                        discretion within the Corporation jurisdiction. A Clerk of the Corporation
                        Court, with the term of six years. An attorney for the Commonwealth, elected
                        for two years. A city Sergeant, same term. A city Treasurer, elected for
                        term of three years, and a Commissioner of Revenue for the Corporation.</p>
                    <p>This is peculiarly a time when the interests of our town require the best
                        abilities we can command to be exercised to the public service, and it is to
                        be hoped that there will be a full attendance of our people at the time
                        mentioned, and a general disposition to yield any private preference to the
                        general good.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article announces a town meeting for the purpose of nominating
                    candidates for the upcoming election. The author lists the various offices to be
                    filled and stresses the danger of splitting the Conservative vote. He suggests
                    that voters yield "private disposition" to public good.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>According to notice, a meeting to nominate officers for Beverley Manor
                        Township, was held at the Court House, May 14th.</p>
                    <p>On motion of E. M. Cushing, Jacob Baylor was appointed Chairman and H. W.
                        Waddell, Secretary.</p>
                    <p>On motion of D. S. Young, a committee of ten--two from each precinct, was
                        appointed to nominate suitable candidates. The Chair appointed the
                        following: Hebron Church--Capt. Palmer and Washington Swoope. Peaco's
                        Mill--L. R. Waddell and A. Kinney. Folly's Mill--T. P. Eskridge and A. A.
                        McPheeters. Bolivar--David Doom and H. P. Dickerson. Sandy Hollow--H. L.
                        Opie and W. J. D. Bell.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Washington Swoope, D. S. Young was appointed Chairman of the
                        committee.</p>
                    <p>E. M. Cushing was offered the following resolutions which were adopted:</p>
                    <p>Resolved 1st., That in view of the importance of having the best men selected
                        to fill the Township offices, it is necessary to secure the election of such
                        men, that the conservative voters should act in concert and cast a united
                        vote.</p>
                    <p>Resolved 2nd, That this meeting regards it as indispensable to secure concert
                        of action, that we agree in advance of the report of the committee on
                        nominations, to abide by the nominations when made, and to work for their
                        election regardless of personal preference or prejudice.</p>
                    <p>The committee reported the following ticket:<lb/> Supervisor--John Paris<lb/>
                        Assessor--John M. Kinney<lb/> Collector--St. Francis C. Roberts<lb/> Road
                        Commissioner--James Henderson<lb/> Clerk--Jos. R. Merriken<lb/>
                        Magistrates--A. W. Harman, L. R. Waddell, and David Hinkle<lb/>
                        Constables--Wm. S. Young, John A. Stuart, and J. T. Little<lb/> Overseer of
                        Poor--Michael McAlear--Adopted</p>
                    <p>On motion of E. M. Cushing, the Chair appointed the following committee to
                        attend at different precincts to urge upon all, the duty of registering, and
                        to see that they voted:</p>
                    <p>Hebron Church--Geo. W. Swoope, Wm. Bell, and John Keller. Peaco's Mill--Arch
                        Kinney, Capt. Fulcher and R. Henderson. Bolivar--J. Meriken, Robt. Bell and
                        David Doom. Folly's Mill--H. P. Dickerson, R. P. McPheeters and Calvin
                        Swink. Sandy Hollow--Jas. Bumgardner, John Opie and Lewis Harman.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Capt. Bumgardner, it was</p>
                    <p>Resolved, This meeting earnestly recommend and urge all of the voters of the
                        Township who have neglected to register, to do so without fail on the days
                        appointed for the revision of Registration, viz: on the --- days of May, at
                        Bolivar; and that each member of the meeting will use all his efforts to
                        induce the voters to register.</p>
                    <p>At the suggestion of Major Christian, the Chair requested Mr. McPheeters to
                        see the Registrar, and get him to attend one of the days appointed for the
                        revision of registration at Peaco's Mill, instead of Bolivar.</p>
                    <p>On motion the Spectator, Vindicator and Valley Virginian were requested to
                        publish the proceedings of this meeting.<lb/> Jacob Baylor, Chairman.<lb/>
                        W. H. Waddell, Secretary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>T. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickerson</ln>
                        <fn>H. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>St. Francis C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merriken</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hinkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAlear</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Arch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulcher</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meriken</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickerson</ln>
                        <fn>H. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McPheeters</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints the proceedings of a public meeting at which candidates
                    were selected for public office in Beverley Manor township. A committee was also
                    appointed to encourage citizens to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>To the People of Staunton and Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nickolas K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Fincastle in Botetourt County appeal to the citizens of
                    Augusta for aid after a devastating fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deakius</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Elisha J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shipman</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowman</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hizer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Chesley Kinney assisted by Capt. John N. Clarke, secretary, chaired a
                    meeting in Moscow of the conservatives of North River Township to nominate
                    candidates for local office. The following were nominated: John G. Fulton for
                    supervisor; A. J. Deakius for clerk; John H. Stover for assessor; Elisha J. Bell
                    for collector; J. H. Ervin for road commissioner; John C. Rusmisel for overseer
                    of the poor; J. W. Crist, Thomas S. Hogshead and R. A. Curry for justice of the
                    peace; Jonathan M. Shipman, Jonas Lowman, and William Hizer for constable.
                    Samuel Paul would have received nomination for collector, but it is thought he
                    will run for county treasurer. R. M. Byers will run independently for collector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>For the Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Kennerly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterritt</ln>
                        <fn>F. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lickliter</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quidor</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhyan</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lange</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boswell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of Pastures Township met at Churchville to nominate committees
                    from each voting precinct who will choose candidates for local office. The
                    committees are listed. Buffalo Gap: Joseph B. Trimble, L. Sibert, S. H. Bell, B.
                    Crawford, Capt. J. Hoover, David Hanger. Deerfield: W. W. Newman, Konnerly
                    Craig, J. S. Guy, C. A. McCutchen, A. K. Clayton, D. B. Taylor. Churchville: F.
                    F. Sterritt, S. C. Wilson, J. M. Lickliter, J. M. Huff, J. B. Quidor, J. F.
                    Keller. Lebanon: N. Rhyan, William Lange, James Cross, Thomas Cross, William
                    Greiner, George W. Rodgers. Craigsville: R. S. Craig, L. R. Boswell, William
                    Armstrong, William R. Wallace, William Crawford, William Kunkle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dellinger</ln>
                        <fn>F. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raymond</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haines</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haines</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The voters of South River Township held a meeting in Waynesboro to nominate
                    candidates for local office. Dr. F. D. Dellinger chaired the meeting and Dr. J.
                    S. Myers served as secretary. The following were recommended: Dr. T. W. Shelton
                    for supervisor; Hugh N. Fry for clerk; J. S. Raymond for assessor; C. R. Haines
                    for collector; Elijah Bateman for commissioner; Phillip Killian, David W.
                    Koiner, and John Huff for overseer of the poor; Moses Alexander, C. R. Haines,
                    and William Grooms for constable.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaho</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larne</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphrey</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The precinct delegates for Riverheads Township met at Broadhead School
                    house and nominated candidates for local office. The following were chosen: M.
                    W. D. Hogshead for supervisor; John S. McCorkle, clerk; Thomas M. Donaho,
                    assessor; John J. Larne, collector; Col. John D. Lilley, commissioner of roads;
                    James E. Beard, overseer of poor; William F. Smith, William T. Rush, and A. A.
                    Sproul, Justices of Peace; J. B. Smith, W. H. Cale, William Black, constables.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The voters of South River Township write Capt. John D. Brooks and express
                    their wish that he offer himself as a candidate to replace A. B. Cochran as
                    representative in the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Siberton Steel, Iron Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is the expectation of this company to commence blasting this week. Several
                        days ago we were taken through the furnace, and shown the large amount of
                        machinery which is operated in smelting the ore; and we must confess our
                        astonishment at the vast amount of work that has been done. Their fire
                        department, with five hundred feet of gum hose is far superior to that of
                        the City, and everything about the establishment has been arranged with
                        strict regard to convenience. A tram road, one mile and a half in length,
                        has been constructed from the various ore banks on the mountain, to the
                        furnace; and a large number of houses built for the accommodation of
                        operators. We have no hesitation in giving it as our opinion that they will
                        turn out more metal than any other iron company in the State. There is every
                        reason to believe that the enterprise will be perfectly successful.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article describes the Siberton iron firm that is soon to begin
                    operation. It discusses the new furnace, roads, and houses constructed. The
                    paper assumes a successful enterprise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> We have been requested by the ladies of our Memorial Association, to make
                        known their selection of Thursday, the 9th of July, as the day for the next
                        annual observance of appropriate ceremonies at the graves of our Confederate
                        dead. At 9 o'clock, A.M., the procession will form, in column by twos, on
                        Main Street, the head resting at the Town hall and facing towards the
                            <sic>Cemetry,</sic> whither it will proceed with as little delay as
                        possible. Music will be in attendance. The schools are invited to be
                        present, and to join the procession.</p>
                    <p> We trust all will unite in doing honor to our departed comrades. Let it
                        never be said that their gallant deeds are fading from our memory. The
                        survivors owe this simple tribute to our bravest and our best. The world
                        should see that their epitaphs are written on <emph rend="italic">our
                            hearts,</emph> if not on costly monumental stone. It is fitting, too,
                        that with each returning spring the hands of lovely maidens from every
                        quarter of our Southern land should strew fresh flowers on the sod that
                        covers them. Soldiers from every State where floated the Southern cross, are
                        gathered there in the silent brotherhood of death. But keep up such gentle
                        homage, and the <emph rend="italic">spirit</emph> of true chivalry will
                        never perish from the land. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This announcement for the Ladies Memorial Association outlines the events
                    and participants of an upcoming procession in honor of the Confederate dead.
                    Included is a sentimental tribute to the "bravest and the best."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Peoples Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For Mayor, <lb/>Wm. H. Gorman. <lb/>For Clerk,<lb/>Jas. E. Hanger. <lb/>For
                        Treasurer, <lb/>Maj. J.W. Newton. <lb/>For Attorney, <lb/>Col. J.M. Skinner.
                        <lb/> For Sergeant, <lb/>Lt. A.N. Breckenridge. <lb/>For Commissioner,
                        <lb/>Geo. H. Hudson. </p>
                    <p>The above named gentlemen are all intelligent and deserving the support of
                        the voters of Staunton. They have the marks of their courage in the hour of
                        danger. Vox Populi.</p>
                    <p>Ticket for City Officers.</p>
                    <p> For Mayor <lb/>N.K. Trout, <lb/>For Clerk, <lb/>Jas. F. Patterson.
                        <lb/>Sergeant, <lb/> Jacob T. Parent <lb/>For Treasurer, <lb/>Jno. M.
                        Carroll. <lb/>Commissioner of Revenue, <lb/>Geo. H. Hudson, <lb/>Councilmen, </p>
                    <p>Wm. H. German, Wm. H.H. Lynn, J.S. Lipscomb, J.L. Timberlake, Dr. B.B.
                        Donaghe, S.A. Houshour, Jas. H. Waters, Wm. J. Nelson, R.S. Hawkins, J.W.
                        Alby, Jno. S. Scherer, Jr.</p>
                    <p>Town Officers.</p>
                    <p> Mayor <lb/>Jno. B. Evans. <lb/>Clerk, <lb/>Arch S. Kinney
                        <lb/>Commonwealth's Attorney, <lb/>S. Travers Phillips. <lb/>Treasurer,
                        <lb/>Heber Ker. <lb/>Sergeant, <lb/>J.T. Parent. <lb/>Commissioner of the
                        Revenue, <lb/>Geo. H. Hudson. <lb/>Council, </p>
                    <p>1st Ward--J.H. Blackley, H.T. Bagby, W.J. Nelson, P.B. Hoge, W.B. Kayser</p>
                    <p>2nd Ward--R.G. Bickle, J.W. Crawford, J.H. Waters, Jno. W. Alby, T.A.
                        Bledsoe.</p>
                    <p>We believe the interest of the town will be well cared for by the election of
                        the above ticket, which will be supported by MANY VOTERS.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This piece is a listing of the candidates on the ticket supported by the
                    paper. Included is a brief comment suggesting that their election will secure
                    what is best for the city.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sales</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>B. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A public meeting was held at the Court House to take some action on behalf
                    of the sufferers of the Fincastle fire. A. H. H. Stuart chaired the meeting and
                    W. H. H. Lynn acted as secretary. A central committee was appointed to solicit
                    donations, and a special committee formed to take other steps aimed at relief.
                    Central Committee: William Frazier, Robert Cowan, Col. M. G. Harman, P. B. Hoge,
                    R. W. Burke, N. K. Trout. Special Committee: Col. B. Christian, S. Travers
                    Phillips, W. H. Sales, Maj. B. T. Bagby, S. H. Hilb.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>Thornton G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cupp</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>N. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Sam T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterritt</ln>
                        <fn>F. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Brown</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>B. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blauth</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. St. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilb</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The central committee appointed the following sub-committees to raise funds
                    for the Fincastle fire sufferers. Beverly Manor Township: C. C. Francisco, Col.
                    A. W. Harman, Jacob Baylor, W. W. Donaghe, Jr., E. L. Edmondson. Middle River
                    Township: William Crawford, John H. Parkins, Thornton G. Stout, Thomas J. Burke,
                    Dr. W. W. Ewing. North River Township: J. J. Cupp, N. L. Blakemore, Thomas S.
                    Hogshead, J. H. Plecker, Samuel Forrer. South River Township: Dr. T. W. Shelton,
                    George A. Bruce, Maj. Absalom Koiner, James W. Patrick, B. F. Cochran. The
                    Pastures: Col. F. F. Sterritt, Brown Allen, B. O. Ferguson, Lorenzo Sibert, John
                    S. Guy. Riverheads: A. Blauth, M. W. D. Hogshead, John J. Larew, A. St. T. Turk,
                    William E. Logan. City of Staunton: Robert Cowan, S. H. Hilb, William A. Burke.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoveler</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ware</ln>
                        <fn>Frank T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sawyers</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Claxton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The special committee appointed the following to canvass the African
                    American community for aid to the Finscastle fire sufferers: Aaron Shoveler,
                    Staunton, 1st Ward; Frank T. Ware, Staunton, 2nd Ward; Henry Norris, Beverley
                    Manor; Joseph Black, Middle River; Joseph Sawyers, North River; Rev. Phillip
                    Brown, The Pastures; Rev. William Claxton, and Thomas Jefferson, South River;
                    Alexander Bumgardner, Riverheads.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmitt</ln>
                        <fn>P. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitzgerald</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>P. F. Schmitt of Staunton and Miss Maggie S. Fitzgerald of Washington were
                    married on May 9th by the Rev. Father McCarty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharp</ln>
                        <fn>Alex A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Dorcas B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex A. Sharp of Tennessee and Miss Catharine L. Thompson, daughter of
                    Dorcas B. Thompson, formerly of Augusta, were married in West Virginia on May
                    5th by the Rev. Dr. Young.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ott</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Sue G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D. A. Ott of Augusta and Miss Sue G. Moore of Fairfield were married at
                    Fairfield on April 28th by the Rev. Harvey Gilmore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyden</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deffenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deffenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Heyden and Miss Lizzie Deffenbaugh, daughter of Lewis Deffenbaugh,
                    all of Augusta, were married on May 10th at St. Francis Church by the Rev.
                    Father Weed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croson</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drawbond</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Croson and Miss Sarah M. Drawbond, both of Augusta, were married
                    on May 12th at the residence of the bride's father near Sherando by the Rev.
                    John N. Lockridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Merritt, wife of John Merritt, died at Oakland, near Greenville,
                    Augusta County, on May 2nd. She was 78 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William Bailey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sallie C. Dunlap, wife of William Bailey Dunlap and daughter of John
                    Brown, died at the residence of her father near Swoope's Depot on April 23rd.
                    She was 25 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Adams</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary M. Lushbaugh, wife of Adams Lushbaugh of Staunton, died at her
                    residence on May 12th after a severe illness. She was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles A. Dunlap died at his residence in Deerfield on May 6th "after a
                    brief illness of a few hours of epilepsey and heart disease combined." He was 56
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
