<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.03.17">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/02/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-17">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">17</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.17.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.17.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Governor's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The length of Governor Walker's message published in our issue of the 19th,
                        precluded any comment on the subjects therein discussed, and will doubtless
                        prevent such perusal on the part of many of the patrons, as the importance
                        of its suggestions deserves. For the benefit and information of such as have
                        not the time or inclination to wade through its accumulated statements and
                        arguments, we propose to give a brief synopsis of its contents.</p>
                    <p>Being mainly devoted to a consideration of the financial condition of the
                        State, it sets out with an enumeration of the liabilities she has incurred,
                        amounting in the aggregate to near $16,000,000 to meet this large
                        indebtedness the State has assets and resources estimated by the Governor in
                        the aggregate at nearly $34,000,000, but unfortunately a large proportion of
                        these assets are not now, nor are they likely in the future to become really
                        available. The estimate of Governor Walker, which is certainly as favorable
                        as the facts justify, fixed the sum at $2,622,776 as solvent and immediately
                        available for the redemption of the State debt, and he estimates that a
                        further sum of about $10,000,000 will become available in the course of a
                        few years, thus leaving a balance of upwards of $21,000,000 which is not
                        now, and probably never will become of much value to the State. The bulk of
                        this indebtedness on the part of the State has its origin in State aid
                        extended to various internal improvement companies, and the Governor
                        criticizes severely and properly the policy which heretofore controlled the
                        action of the State in this particular. He discusses at some length the
                        propriety of dissolving the partnership existing in many internal
                        improvement companies between the State and the private stockholders, and
                        advocates as speedy a severance of this connection as is compatible with the
                        welfare of the various companies and the best interests of the State. He
                        believes that this can best be affected "by permitting each company to
                        redeem the interest of the State in such company, by surrendering to the
                        State, (to be called,) the Bonds of the State to an amount equal to such
                        interest." If this authority be granted, he believes that in a few years
                        about $10,000,000 of State bonds will thus be redeemed, and the State debt
                        diminished by that amount.</p>
                    <p>Our readers will doubtless remember that this is precisely the policy adopted
                        by the Legislature in the acts authorizing the formation of the "Atlantic,
                        Mississippi and Ohio Railroad Company" in April, 1867, as well as the more
                        recent formation of the "Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company." With regard
                        to the authority given the first named company, so far as we are advised, no
                        action whatever has been taken under it, and the sanguine predictions of its
                        friends, that the measure would speedily relieve the State several millions
                        of indebtedness has thus far failed of fulfillment. Whether the experience
                        of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, will furnish a different result
                        remains to be seen, although that company may pay off in State bonds, the
                        amount of its indebtedness to the State, without at the same time purchasing
                        the stock held by the State in the improvement, a privilege which the
                        Governor properly advises should not be hereafter extended to any company.</p>
                    <p>For the purpose of aiding in paying the interest on the debt, and defraying
                        the ordinary expenses of government, Gov. Walker proposes to tax the
                        incomes, or capital stock of the Internal Improvement Companies, or by
                        imposing a capitation on tonnage tax, a suggestion in our opinion of
                        doubtful expediency and calculated to further embarrass and cripple the
                        operations of the Companies, many of which are now struggling to bare
                        existence.</p>
                    <p> The expenditures of the State Government for the final year, <emph
                            rend="italic">exceed the receipts</emph> by $66,000, the regular and
                        ordinary expenses of the State Government being $700,000, <emph
                            rend="italic">exclusive of legislative expense,</emph> which from the
                        present prospects will add very largely to this amount. The whole sum
                        required to be raised by taxation during the present fiscal year is
                        $3,310,000--an amount greater by <emph rend="italic"> more than a million
                            and a half</emph> than was paid into the Treasury the past year. Our
                        people may see in this the first turn of the taxation screws, the taxes
                        increased <emph rend="italic">one-third,</emph> and that too before the
                        largely increased burthens imposed by the new Constitution become operative.
                        When these shall have been provided for, then, indeed, will our people begin
                        to open their eyes to the beauties of reconstruction under the Underwood
                        Constitution, and realize its acceptance by the people of Virginia. </p>
                    <p> By a reassessment of the real estate and personal property of the
                        Commonwealth, and adopting an <emph rend="italic">ad valorem</emph> system
                        of taxation, the Governor believes that "we shall be able at a day not far
                        distant to resume the regular payment of interest upon our State
                        indebtedness." This time he fixes as 1st of July, 1871. </p>
                    <p> With the laudable object of <emph rend="italic"> re-organizing the State
                            debt, </emph> the Governor recommends the funding of all the liabilities
                        of the State, both principle and interest, except the sterling debt, into
                        one uniform class of new bonds, running from 10 to 30 years, with the
                        interest payable semi annually in the city of New York, all the new bonds to
                        be coupon bonds, and the coupons after maturity receivable for all debts due
                        the State, which facts shall be stated on their face, thus giving them a
                        current value, which would cause them to pass from hand to hand as readily
                        as greenbacks. </p>
                    <p>A change in the percent system of the collected revenue is advised, in which
                        we heartily concur, by providing a system of State depositories for public
                        funds, and making it a felony for any individual to make use of them for
                        private purposes; collectors required to deposit the sums collected at least
                        twice in each month taking a certificate therefore from the depositor, which
                        certificate shall be at once forwarded to the treasurer, who shall charge
                        the same to the depositor, and draw upon it whenever needed for use.</p>
                    <p>The Governor is opposed to the charter of Joint Stock Companies or Banks with
                        special privileges, and thinks the number of applications for such charters
                        would be very much restricted by requiring a deposit of $500 with every
                        application.</p>
                    <p>The solution of the great problem of the hour, viz: THE RELIEF OF THE
                        DEBTORS, Governor Walker believes can be found in the enforcement of the
                        Homestead provision of the Constitution, and the passage of an act
                        forbidding the sale of real estate at less then its assessed value, giving
                        the creditor the privilege, if no greater amount is offered, of taking the
                        property at its assessed value in liquidation of his claim.</p>
                    <p> The Governor thinks the Homestead law will secure to debtors from $3,000 to
                        $4,000 worth of property, which cannot be reached by any creditor, and <emph
                            rend="italic">if correct in this assumption,</emph> we admit the force
                        of his argument; but with all due deference we venture to opine, that the
                        Courts will rule differently with regard to the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Homestead exemption as applied to old debts,</emph> unless a mighty
                        change has come over the minds of the Judges and lawyers, unless the
                        decisions of the highest legal tribunals of the country, both State and
                        Federal be erroneous, this portion of the Homestead law will be pronounced
                        at variance with the Constitution of the United States, as well as the State
                        Constitution of which it forms a part and consequently will be declared null
                        and void, so soon as a decision by the Courts can be arrived at. The debtor
                        therefore who trusts to this method of relief will manifestly lean upon a
                        broken reed. The remedy proposed for preventing the sacrifice of real
                        estate, is effective however, and should be made to apply to personal
                        property as well. </p>
                    <p> The Governor recommends that the Land scrip donated by the State for
                        educational purposes, amounting to 200,000 acres, be divided between some
                        existing College to be selected by the General Assembly, and a High School
                        or College to be hereafter organized for the education of colored students.
                        However repugnant such a suggestion, to many, there is manifestly much force
                        in the argument that as the colored race are now invested with political
                        rights co-equal with the whites, it is to the interest of whites as well as
                        blacks, that they shall be placed, so far as education can do it, in a
                        condition to discharge intelligently and understandingly the duties thus
                        devolved upon them, and though we can not subscribe to the dogma so
                        authoritatively and sophomorically announced by the Executive of the State,
                        that "if the death knell to American liberty is ever sounded, ignorance will
                        pull the bell cord," we yield our hearty assent to his concluding
                        recommendation, that the schools <emph rend="italic"> for whites and blacks
                            shall be kept separate and distinct, </emph> a principle demanded alike
                        by the interests of the white and colored races. </p>
                    <p> We bring our somewhat extended notice of the Message to a close, with the
                        remark that it is by far the most important and judicious State paper which
                        has yet been emanated from our Executive, and though we dissent from many of
                        his views and deductions, yet in the main we commend the paper as affording
                        evidence of a sincere desire to advance the interest of the State, and
                        promote the prosperity of the people over whose destinies he has been called
                        to preside.--<emph rend="italic">Lynchburg News.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article summarizes the several views and proposals made by Governor
                    Walker in a recent message to the state. The author's review is somewhat mixed,
                    disagreeing with some of the Governor's opinions, such as protection from
                    creditors through the Homestead Law. Overall, however, this article praises the
                    Governor's efforts to provide the best for all Virginians under adverse
                    conditions, as well as secure for Virginia a prosperous future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Radical Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of a Republican Party meeting in Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.17.03" exists="no">
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martha A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Baldwin and Miss Martha A. Garber, daughter of Albert Garber of
                    Staunton, were married in Trinity Church on March 15th by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rothwell</ln>
                        <fn>Eddie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William S. Boyd and Miss Eddie G. Rothwell, both of Augusta, were married
                    at New Hope on March 10th by the Rev. John H. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.17.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
