<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.01.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/03/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-01-20">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>A Christian Association for Young Men</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Staunton is evidently growing rapidly. We have daily proofs of this fact,
                        and with its growth and evident improvement, why can't we have those
                        institutions and organizations which characterize a town and add to its
                        moral character. We have Temperance Societies, Building Associations, Moral
                        Lectures sometimes, Masonic Halls, Amusements occasionally and the ladies
                        have of late started a "Circulating Library." Why can't we have a Young
                        Men's Christian Association? In almost every city and town North and South
                        there is an association of this kind. Surely Staunton is large enough and
                        her young men ought to be willing to give their aid in such a work. Look at
                        New York, because the great city of America she ought to a certain extent be
                        an example - her "association" was too small and with the energy of the
                        people they have just now completed a magnificent building on the corner of
                        Twenty Third Street and Fourth Avenue. Surely we will not let the Yankees be
                        ahead of us in good works. We extract the following from the <emph
                            rend="italic">Herald</emph> of Nov. 30th: </p>
                    <p>The objects of the association are, in the first place, to offer safe and
                        attractive resort to the thousands of untried young men who come as
                        strangers to the city, with limited means, who are crowded into
                        uncomfortable, cheerless boarding houses, and exposed to great temptations;
                        second, to amalgamate this great class with those of like age who are
                        residents of the city, so that they may be benefited by each other's
                        acquirements and companionship; and lastly, so educate and elevate all these
                        young men that their force and enthusiasm may be turned into the channels of
                        morality, benevolence and Christian activity. To this end, the association
                        embraces not only church members, but all whom it can reach and the dues and
                        fees, amounting altogether to five dollars a year (adding only ten cents per
                        week to board), are made so moderate that none need be excluded. By
                        confining the direction to men connected with churches, a sufficiently
                        restraining influence is attained. As years pass by, and those who come as
                        poor boys to this city and forming their fellowship and sympathy here, take
                        their places in its prominent trades and business, the true importance of
                        the labors of the association will be appreciated. - The Committee say that
                        "Large expense has been incurred on the erection of this building; but it
                        must be remembered that in securing the objects it has in view it comes into
                        direct competition with the theatres, the gambling house, the barrooms and
                        other places of even worse character, which spare no effort and hesitate at
                        no expenditure in attracting the thousands of young men who find themselves
                        in this great city without homes, family influence or restraints. It is
                        needless to say that the character and training of this very class are of
                        incalculable importance to the well being of the city. If, while their
                        habits are yet unformed, they can be brought under Christian and manly
                        influences, the money is well spent, as the entire cost of the building does
                        not equal that of any of the theatres."</p>
                    <p> As a matter of course we do not expect in so small a town to begin on a
                        grand scale - or even to approach New York in her Institution, but we do
                        think one might be started here in a small way and, in course of time, rival
                        that of our neighbors. We copy below a general description from the <emph
                            rend="italic">Herald:</emph></p>
                    <p> "The building occupies a lot of eighty six feet nine inches on Fourth
                        avenue, by one hundred and seventy five feet on East Twenty third street.
                        The main entrance and stairway are in the centre of the Twenty third street
                        front. At the head of the main stone stairs, to the right, is the great
                        hall, with comfortable chairs for 1,500 persons, so arranged that each seat
                        has a direct view of the platform. It is thoroughly ventilated by flues
                        running under the floor, connected with large ventilating shafts heated by
                        steam coils. On the right are three committee and dressing rooms, and on the
                        left a grand organ. - This organ, with a grand piano, have been presented to
                        the association by the musical committee from the proceeds of concerts given
                        under their direction. The hall will be used for lectures on practical and
                        scientific subjects, under the care of the lecture committee, and for
                        popular concerts, as well as for the public religious meetings of the
                        association. When not used by the society it will be rented for various
                        purposes, and supply a great need in this section of the city. On the left
                        of the main stairs is the reception room, to be used as a conversation room,
                        and for the office of the association. Opening from this is the reading
                        room, supplied with all the best newspapers and magazines of this country
                        and Europe. On the same floor are three parlors, to be used for
                        conversation, informal meetings and committee work, and to be made
                        attractive as evening resorts; also a hat and wash room. There is also a
                        room over the entrance hall for the secretary, who is the executive officer
                        of the association. - A short stairway from the reception room leads down to
                        the gymnasium - a large well ventilated room, carefully fitted with the most
                        perfect apparatus, where regular classes for instruction will be
                        established. On the lower floor are comfortable bath rooms, for the use of
                        the large numbers of young men whose boarding houses afford them no
                        convenience of this kind. On the second floor is the library, extending
                        through two stores, enclosed in fire-proof walls, and capable of containing
                        10,000 volumes. In addition to a careful selection of useful and safely
                        entertaining books, it is intended to add, as soon as means will allow, a
                        complete Biblical library, which will be of great service to Sunday school
                        workers and clergymen. Adjoining is a small lecture room, seating 200
                        persons for religious meetings, meeting of the Literary Society, musical
                        classes, special lectures and for the larger committees. On the <del/> floor
                        are four rooms for the evening classes, viz: Writing, bookkeeping, French,
                        German, Spanish, music, drawing and the natural sciences. The remainder of
                        the upper floor is for the present rented for artists' studies. The stores
                        on the street front and basement are to be rented for business purposes. The
                        income from these is appropriated to the sinking fund and the expenses of
                        the association. The building is most nearly constructed and divided into
                        three sections by fire walls and iron doors, and heated throughout by
                        improved steam apparatus placed under the sidewalk." </p>
                    <p>In conclusion we trust some of our young and energetic gentlemen will look
                        into this matter and make a start which will redound to the good of old
                        Staunton.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article recommends, for the benefit of the young men of
                    Staunton, the immediate construction of a Young Men's Christian Association.
                    First, the article illustrates the many moral benefits of such an association,
                    for example, it will keep energetic young men from going astray. Second, an
                    excerpt from a New York paper, describes in great detail all the many uses for
                    such a building, including moneymaking opportunities that will finance building
                    expenses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B. F. Fifer has been appointed to replace George W. Britt as Staunton flour
                    inspector.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Beard had been appointed to replace Miss Atkinson as postmaster
                    for Mint Spring, Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The protracted meeting at the Methodist Episcopal Church South has
                    attracted widespread interest. Ten people have joined the church, and more
                    conversions are expected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Oh! The Wind</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A terrible calamity befell Philip Rossell on Friday. Philip is an energetic
                        man, and by industry, and frugality he last winter accomplished a purpose he
                        has had ever since he emerged from a state of bondage, and stepped forth
                        free as air into the glorious privileges of freedom - he built a house. It
                        was not particularly noticeable for its elegance of structure, on the
                        contrary, it was quite an unpretending building. In it Philip and spouse had
                        enjoyed all the blessings of the marriage state up to last Friday, when a
                        Northeastern wind, at one cruel blow, laid it level with the earth. There
                        was, we are happy to say, no one injured by the fall. We have no doubt that
                        Philip will be able to raise among our charitable citizens a sufficient sum
                        to re build; and it is to be hoped, that he will profit by his experience,
                        and lay a better foundation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rossell</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article describes the unfortunate incident in which a former slave,
                    Philip Rossell, lost his house in a sudden windstorm. The author expects that
                    "charitable citizens" will provide funds for Rossell to rebuild, and he strongly
                    recommends that the new house be built on a firmer foundation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Ye Local at Church</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Representatives of the Valley Virginian attended Staunton's M. E. Church to
                    observe the protracted meeting in progress. The Rev. George Kramer and the Rev.
                    William A. Harris spoke following hymns and prayers. Several people were
                    converted. "These services are solemn and impressive, and we were glad to
                    perceive the recognition of this fact on the part of the congregation in their
                    strict attention to the preacher, and an entire absence of levity, which, alas,
                    is too often observable in promiscuous assemblies, on the occasion of a series
                    of religious meetings."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Slightly Unpleasant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It becomes our painful duty this morning to chronicle the dissolution of
                        co-partnership, in a most violent manner, between Dolphus Dorsey and Robt.
                        Truss, who have for a very short time, driven a highly lucrative business in
                        Gallowstown. The presumption is, that the above named colored individuals
                        were endeavoring to effect an equal division of the profits on their sales
                        for the year 1869, when a dispute arose as to who the devil took in "dat dar
                        raged money." Each swore he didn't receive it, and therefore would not
                        accept any portion of it in the present division. Words having failed to
                        convince either of ever having been so foolish as to exchange goods for
                        naught - for that's what the mutilated currency amounted to - both arose up
                        on their feet, and went it heavy on their muscle. This very pleasant
                        entertainment was kept up to the infinite amusement of the bystanders, each
                        doing their best to overcome the other, until Alex Nellon's desire for a
                        termination of the contest overcame his discretion and caused him to draw a
                        knife and undertake to relieve both of the hostile parties of whatever
                        superfluous flesh there might be cleaving unto their bones. At this juncture
                        John Curts and Andrew Sheets put an appearance in upon the scene and brought
                        the affair to a hasty conclusion. All parties were arrested and taken before
                        Mayor Allen who fined them $5 each, made them pay costs, and required a
                        security of $800 for their appearance at the setting of the next Grand Jury
                        to answer an indictment. If the colored troops did fight bravely they
                        certainly paid heavily therefore.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorsey</ln>
                        <fn>Dolphus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Truss</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtz</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article recounts the events that led to the dissolution of a business
                    owned by two black men in Gallowstown. A fight over the acceptance of mutilated
                    currency escalated until both parties were arrested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shultz</ln>
                        <fn>Molly E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. J. W. Berry and Miss Molly E. Shultz were married in Greenville at the
                    residence of the bride's father on January 11th by the Rev. William Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Altwaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas E. Gilkeson and Miss Sallie J. Altwaffer, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Parnassus on January 11th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Josie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bullock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. A. Richardson and Miss Josie Brooks, both of Staunton, were married at
                    the Eutaw House, Baltimore, on January 12th by the Rev. Dr. Bullock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Caroline Bryan, wife of Reuben Bryan, died at her residence in
                    Sangersville on January 6th. She was 52 years old. She was a long-time member of
                    the Presbyterian Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Beard died at the Augusta County residence of his daughter, Mrs.
                    Baylor, on December 30th. He was 85 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tapescott</ln>
                        <fn>B. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sale</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. B. G. Tapescott died in Staunton at the Virginia Hotel on January 15th.
                    He was in poor health when he checked in, but refused medicine. He lingered for
                    six weeks under the care of Dr. C. R. Harris and Capt. Sale, hotel proprietor.
                    The Rev. Kramer of the Methodist Church ministered to him. "These facts we
                    mention for the information of his friends, if he leaves any surviving him, for
                    he came amongst us an entire stranger, and nearly destitute of means, nor has
                    any one visited him from a distance or appeared to take an interest in his
                    fate."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.01.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
