<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.03.24">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/04/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-24">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">24</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.24.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.24.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Reorganization of the Public Debt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been favorably impressed with the practical wisdom displayed by
                        Governor Walker in his recommendation of a consolidation and reorganization
                        of the public debt of Virginia. At present, the debt is a confused mass of
                        obligations, issued under the authority of ninety-five separate acts of the
                        General Assembly. The larger portion is in the form of coupon bonds, but
                        probably ten or fifteen millions is issued in registered bonds, which do not
                        pass by delivery, and can only be transferred by formal assignment on the
                        books of the 2nd Auditor's office.--In consequence of the more convenient
                        form of the coupon bonds, and the facility with which they can be
                        transferred, by mere delivery, like a bank or treasury note, the coupon
                        bonds have a much greater market value than the registered, though,
                        intrinsically, one is worth as much, and no more, than the other. We
                        accordingly find, that, while coupon bonds are quoted in the prices current,
                        at $71 to $72, the registered bonds stand at $55 to $56.</p>
                    <p>To remove this disparity, and place the whole debt of the State on the same
                        footing, the Governor wisely proposes, that the whole debt shall be
                        consolidated, and reorganized, under the authority of one general law.
                        According to his plan, the old bonds will be called in, and new coupon bonds
                        will be issued for the whole debt, registered, as well as coupon. The effect
                        of this will be, to carry up the market value of the registered bonds, to
                        the level with the coupons, or, in other words, to raise the price of the
                        registered bonds, from $55 or $59, to $71 or $72. This increase in saleable
                        value, will be effected, with out adding one dollar to the amount of the
                        indebtedness of the State. The change is in the form of obligation, and not
                        in the amount or character of the debt.</p>
                    <p>The importance of this measure to the people of Virginia, and especially to
                        widows and orphans whose estates are invested in registered bonds, will be
                        readily appreciated, when it is known that a very large proportion of the
                        registered debt of Virginia is held by the people of Virginia. Assuming that
                        ten millions of it are held by our own citizens, it will readily be seen
                        that the plan of Governor Walker, if carried into effect, will add between
                        one and two millions of dollars, to the market value of their stock, without
                        entailing on the people of Virginia, an increase of the debt.</p>
                    <p>We believe that a bill has already been reported to give effect to the
                        recommendation of the Governor, and we earnestly hope that at an early day,
                        it will become a law.</p>
                    <p>In these times of sore distress, an addition of near two million, to the
                        available means of our people, without any increase of taxation or debt, is
                        no small matter. We tender to Governor Walker, our thanks, and the grateful
                        acknowledgements of our people, for his timely and judicious suggestion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article outlines a proposal by Governor Walker that would consolidate
                    and reorganize the state debt into one form of coupon bonds. The author explains
                    how this consolidation will increase the means available for Virginia citizens.
                    It will neither generate new taxation or increase the state debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.24.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A delegation from Staunton left for Baltimore to campaign for a 1 million
                    dollar subscription by that city to the Valley Railroad. The citizens of
                    Baltimore will vote on the question today.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Progress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Onward! seems to be the watchword of our enterprising people. They mean to
                        take no stop backward. We are happy to state the spirit of enterprise which
                        characterized our town last year seems to have suffered no abatement. Before
                        the spring has fairly opened, we hear a number of important improvements
                        which are on foot. Already, probably a dozen costly brick buildings are
                        contracted for, or are in process of being contracted for.</p>
                    <p>Our enterprising fellow-citizen Mr. B.T. Bagby has already torn down the
                        former residence of the late Dr. Addison Waddell, and commenced the
                        foundation of a spacious and elegant brick building with two large store
                        rooms on the ground floor and a handsome residence with six or eight large
                        rooms behind and over them.</p>
                    <p>Across the street from the post office Mr. S. Hendry is about to erect a
                        spacious and handsome three story brick building with store room on the
                        ground floor and a dwelling above.</p>
                    <p>On the old P.O. corner, at the intersection of Main and Augusta streets, Miss
                        Henrietta Brooks will shortly commence the erection of a large and handsome
                        three story house fronting near 40 feet on Main Street and 70 feet on
                        Augusta Street.</p>
                    <p> A little lower down on Augusta Street, Mr. R.G. Bickle who already numbers
                        his houses in town by the score and whose rent roll fills us with envy
                        whenever we think of its sum total, will in a few weeks commence the
                        erection of two handsome brick store houses, nearly opposite the office of
                        our contemporary the <emph rend="italic">Spectator.</emph> Here we must take
                        occasion to remark, that no one citizen of our town has contributed more
                        largely to its improvement than Mr. Bickle. He knows well how to employ his
                        ample means and we trust he may long continue to reap the reward which his
                        energy and public spirit have so richly earned. </p>
                    <p>Mrs. Hall is about completing a handsome and commodious dwelling house South
                        of Kalorama and Mrs. Funkhouser has already laid the foundation of another
                        spacious and tasty residence on a lot nearly opposite Mrs. Halls.</p>
                    <p>We have also learned that Mr. McClure and Clinedinst will, each, at an early
                        day erect handsome dwellings on the vacant lot fronting on Augusta Street
                        north of the Catholic church.</p>
                    <p>These are some of the improvements of a private character which are to be
                        commenced as soon as the weather will allow. We have heard of others which
                        are in contemplation, but have not yet been definitely determined on.</p>
                    <p>But we must not omit to mention another and the most important of all the
                        improvements that have been projected. We allude to the new Presbyterian
                        church, upon which work is about to be commenced. We have reason to believe
                        that this church will be a model of architectural beauty, and that it will
                        do honor to the taste, liberality and piety of the congregation, which, amid
                        all their trials, and troubles and destitution, have not hesitated to devote
                        a large share of their means to do honor to Him who is the Giver of every
                        good and perfect gift!</p>
                    <p>But we have no room for more at present. We may chronicle other improvements
                        as they may be developed. But we think that what we have already stated is
                        enough to show that the spirit of improvement is still abroad in our
                        enterprising little community.</p>
                    <p>By and bye we shall have our Railroad finished to San Francisco so as to
                        bring to our doors the trade of China and Japan! After that is accomplished,
                        we shall build a market house and lateral roads to Harrisonburg and
                        Lexington!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an effort to illustrate the vast improvements either currently underway
                    or proposed, the author enumerates various plans of local citizens.
                    Concentrating on private dwellings, prominent Stauntonians such as R.G. Bickle
                    and B.T. Bagby are listed as "handsome and commodious" brick buildings in the
                    city. Further, the author describes the construction of a new church, and the
                    potential for future rail lines that would link Staunton to the Pacific and
                    ultimately the Orient.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Carter and Miss Bettie Taylor, both of Staunton, were married on
                    March 9th by the Rev. Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crosby</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry C. Hill and Miss Rebecca V. Crosby were married near Staunton on
                    March 13th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyden</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret Hyden died near Mint Spring on March 5th. She was 61 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marshall Ward died at Elizabeth Furnace on March 10th. He was 22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary V. Houff, wife of John F. Houff, died suddenly near Staunton on
                    March 19th. She was 20 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.24.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
