<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.04.21">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-21">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">21</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.21.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.21.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Page or Shenandoah Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our people have heretofore regarded this enterprise as a shadowy myth--a
                        thing rather to be talked of, than executed. But it begins to look as if
                        there was some substance in it. Two parties of Engineers are now actively
                        engaged in surveying the route from Front Royal to some point on the
                        Lynchburg &amp; Tennessee R.R. at or near Salem. One party commenced
                        operation at Front Royal, and will proceed to survey the route, with all
                        practicable dispatch up to Port Republic. These two points seem to be
                        established to a moral certainty. The second party will survey the road from
                        Port Republic to the Southern terminus. The line of the road from Port
                        Republic to the Tennessee Road is yet undetermined. Three routes are spoken
                        of, viz.,</p>
                    <p>1st. The Eastern route up the Valley of the South River, by way of
                        Waynesborough along the pine flats South of Greenville to the interlock
                        between the head waters of the South River of Rockbridge--thence along the
                        Valley of the latter stream to its confluence with North River and Buffalo
                        Creek or James River (as may be found most expedient) to Buchanan.</p>
                    <p>2. The middle route which would commence at Port Republic and follow the
                        Valley of Middle River for a short distance and then diverge from it and
                        pass west of New Hope on to Fishersville, and thence by the most practicable
                        route to Rockbridge.</p>
                    <p>3. The Western Route along the Valleys of Middle River and Lewis Creek to
                        Staunton, and thence by the easiest grades to Rockbridge.</p>
                    <p>We understand that each of these routes will be carefully surveyed, and the
                        decision of the Board in regard to the route to be adopted will be governed
                        by the developments of their comparative merits which may be made by the
                        actual application of the instruments.</p>
                    <p>From what we hear it is the purpose of the company to seek the route which
                        shall be found to possess in the highest degree the following important
                        requisites--1 shortness of distance--2 ease of grades and 3 absence of
                        curves.</p>
                    <p>There will of course be much anxiety felt by the people along the several
                        routes, as to the ultimate decision of the Board. As for ourselves we cannot
                        pretend to say which route is best. The compass the chain and the Theodolite
                        alone can furnish the data on which an intelligent judgment can be founded.
                        Of course we hope the Road may come to Staunton, but we shall not be so
                        unreasonable as to wish that the company should make a sacrifice of their
                        important interests for local accommodations. Let it take which route it
                        may, it will be an important matter for our county, and so viewing it, we
                        shall rejoice to see it constructed. But we think the interests of the
                        majority would be best subserved, if it can be conveniently brought to
                        Staunton. The junction of the two roads at that point (to say nothing of the
                        Valley Road) will very soon cause our town to grow to such dimensions as to
                        afford a home market for much the larger portion of the products of our
                        farms and thus the people of all sections would be benefited.</p>
                    <p>The engineers engaged in the survey, are gentlemen of character and
                        professional skill and in all respects worthy of the favorable regard of our
                        people, and we hope they will, in their transit through our county, receive
                        all those attentions and hospitalities which they doubtless deserve. It
                        would be well if the intelligent gentlemen in each neighborhood would ride
                        with them, and give them full information in regard to the topography of
                        their respective neighborhoods. Much useful knowledge may thus be imparted,
                        and we would be gratified if the opportunity could be afforded to these
                        intelligent strangers to understand something of the disposition and
                        character of our people as well as of the topographical features of our
                        noble Valley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article outlines the various possible routes currently being surveyed
                    for the Valley railroad. The author hopes that the line will pass through
                    Staunton. While he stresses that the people of the city do not expect to make
                    any sacrifices on their account, he invites surveyors to closely inspect the
                    surrounding area to assure them that a route passing through Staunton will be
                    best. Of course, he also points out the many benefits a railway would bring to
                    Stauntonians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Reorganization of the Public Debt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper applauds the suggestion of the governor that the public debt draw
                    immediate attention from the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Communicated</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> More than half the session of our Legislature has passed, and the members
                        have not lost sight of taking care of each other, yet so far, have been
                        entirely oblivious of the wish of <emph rend="italic">nineteen
                        twentieths</emph> of the people of the State that some <emph rend="italic"
                            >relief</emph> should be provided for them, against that monster, the
                        crushing <emph rend="italic">incubus</emph> of <emph rend="italic">Fifteen
                            millions, five hundred and fifty-seven thousand, three hundred and
                            thirty-six dollars and thirty seven cents,</emph> of <emph rend="italic"
                            >anti-war debt,</emph> now in a situation to be collected by compulsory
                        process. The members when at home, profess to be in favor of some mode of
                        relief. The <emph rend="italic">Enquirer &amp; Examiner</emph> well says
                        the <emph rend="italic">weight</emph> of argument is in favor of relief,
                        whilst the influence against it is concentrated and powerful. In support of
                        this declaration scan the names of the <emph rend="italic">two hundred and
                            seven</emph> petitioners from Augusta lately sent to the Legislature
                            <emph rend="italic">against</emph> relief, and single out those who
                        before, during and especially since the war have <emph rend="italic">cut
                            deeply,</emph> in collecting interest, &amp;c. Hear the <emph
                            rend="italic">clap trap</emph> they use about widows and orphans being
                        made the sufferers, if relief is extended to the people, when it is
                        notorious that more of this class than any other lost everything by the
                        investment by fiduciaries of their funds in Confederate securities. </p>
                    <p>You hear it said the dead husbands and brothers cannot be brought back, yet
                        the houses they left to their wives and little ones can be saved to them.
                        See a case exactly in point in this town, in which executions now hang over
                        the homes of two young widows whose husbands fell in defense of him and his
                        broad acres, for whose benefit, they and their young are to be sent adrift
                        on a cold and heartless world. Whilst this case is mentioned as existing
                        here, there are thousands of similar cases all over the State.</p>
                    <p> As some writer justly says: "Woe be to the unlucky representative who fails
                        to secure some mode of substantial relief, to the great majority of the
                        people of the State." A <emph rend="italic">desire</emph> to do right
                        suggests the way to perform it, and the Legislature, if it can find or
                        originate nothing better, let it adopt the popular plan known as the Georgia
                        law "for the relief of debtors and a settlement of debts on principles of
                        equity." It has obtained the sanction of the Supreme Court and has been
                        sustained by the popular sentiment as an approximation of justice. Believing
                        it to be the wish of <emph rend="italic">ninety-nine hundredths</emph> of
                        the people of this county, they will, as soon as a vacancy occurs in the
                        resignation of Mr. Cochran, give evidence of this sentiment in the support
                        of Robt. W. Burke, Esq., at THE POLLS.<lb/> Enquirer copy </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article condemns the state legislature for not having provided relief
                    for those suffering under the burden of the enormous debt soon to be collected
                    by a "compulsory process." The author suggests that although husbands and
                    brothers killed in the war cannot be brought back, their houses and lands can be
                    saved for their families. He stresses that these are the wishes of an
                    overwhelming majority of Augustans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.21.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Inspector B. F. Fifer inspected the following number of barrels of flour
                    since January: 1157 family; 7889 extra; 809 superfine; 84 fine; 29 middlings;
                    10,468 total.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Dramatic Reading</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof.. Scharf will give a dramatic reading in the Town Hall on Tuesday
                    night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grady's Circus will perform in Staunton on Tuesday. It is rumored to be one
                    of the best in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Judge John N. Hendren</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are gratified to be able to announce to our readers the election of John
                        N. Hendren, Esq., as Judge of the County Court of Augusta. The election took
                        place on Saturday last.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Hendren is known to the people of Augusta as an educated and accomplished
                        gentleman; a sound and learned lawyer, and a man of strong well-balanced and
                        masculine intellect. All his pursuits and habits of life, as well as the
                        structure of his mind, qualify him, in a high degree, for a judicial
                        position. He has never cultivated the arts of an advocate, and therefore, he
                        has not been addicted to one-sided views of cases. His duties as master
                        commissioner in chancery, have led him to weigh dispassionately, the
                        evidence adduced before him, and to endeavor to arrive at truth and justice
                        in every case. His success as a commissioner is attested by the fact that
                        after Mr. Hendren had reported in a case, which was fairly presented before
                        him, counsel rarely thought it prudent to except to his rulings.</p>
                    <p>No man in Augusta county possesses a larger share of the confidence of her
                        people, than Mr. Hendren, and we think we hazard nothing in saying that this
                        election will be hailed with sincere pleasure by almost every man in the
                        county.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article welcomes the election of John N. Hendren as
                    Judge of the County Court. Listed are Hendren's several virtues as well as the
                    assurance that every man in the county will be satisfied with the Judge's tenure
                    in office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The combat deepens! Oh ye brave <lb/> Who rush to glory or the grave <lb/>
                        Wave Munich! All thy banners wave; <lb/> And charge with all thy chivalry!" </p>
                    <p>Some months ago we adverted to the animated contest which was imminent
                        between the directors of the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio R.R. on the one hand,
                        and the Street Commissioner of Staunton on the other. The matter in issue
                        between the high contending parties was, whether the Rail Road to the Ohio,
                        or the extension of Lewis street from Spring Lane to the Middlebrook road,
                        shall first be completed. The antagonists have been surveying each other
                        with jealous eyes, for some months past, apparently measuring each others
                        strength, before they engaged in the death-grapple!</p>
                    <p>New interest has recently been imparted to the contest by the introduction of
                        new parties, which gives to the struggle a four-sided character. The
                        Baltimore &amp; Ohio R.R. Co., and the Page Valley Company, attracted by
                        the fame of the forthcoming tourney, have also entered the list as
                        contestants for the laurels of Victory!</p>
                    <p>Vigorous preparations have been made on all sides. The Chesapeake &amp;
                        Ohio Co., are daily sending crowds of operators to work on their road. The
                        Baltimore Company have a corps of skillful engineers surveying a route for
                        the extension of their road from Harrisonburg to Salem. The Page Valley Co.
                        determining not to be outdone, have three corps of equally scientific and
                        accomplished gentlemen, with compass in hand, endeavoring to find the best
                        track for a road from Front Royal to Bonsacks or Salem--to be built
                        forthwith.</p>
                    <p>We have heretofore expressed our confidence in the ultimate success of our
                        Street Commissioners in accomplishing their Herculean task! This confidence
                        remains unshaken! We believe they fully realize "the situation!" They know
                        that the eyes of the world are on them! And nothing daunted by the gigantic
                        preparations of their adversaries, they will, gallantly, "come to time!"
                        They are not the men to be caught napping! It is confidently asserted in
                        well informed circles, that the senior member of the Commission was seen a
                        few days ago, entering Spring Lane, with a Jacob's staff under his arms!--
                        another was observed, in a meditative attitude, on the corner of the street,
                        with a cigar in his mouth!--and the third, it is rumored, walked rapidly up
                        the street, (on the shady side) with a paper (whether written or printed is
                        not certainly known) in his right hand!</p>
                    <p>From these insignificant facts, we infer, that the most vigorous measures are
                        being adopted to push through Lewis street, at an early day, and thereby win
                        the Victory in the great contest which now occupies so large a share of
                        public attention!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article describes the various contending parties involved in public
                    improvements, including designs for street extensions, and various railway
                    companies. The author offers his ideas of which improvement will first be
                    completed. Based on some seemingly insignificant evidence, he suggests that the
                    city's street commissioners will ultimately triumph by successfully pushing
                    through legislation in their favor. Thus, the extension of Lewis Street will win
                    the "great contest."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>J. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>S. Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Henry Clemmer and Miss S. Jennie Snider, daughter of Adam Snider, all of
                    Augusta, were married on March 24th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Rivercomb, late of California, and Miss Mary Jane Blakemore of
                    Augusta were married in Mt. Solon on April 7th by the Rev. James M. Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Catharine Calhoun died at Glen Allen, Augusta County, the late
                    residence of her brother-in-law, Gen. Kenton Harper, on March 27th. She was 76
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Willie Welch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Welch Bumgardner, infant son of Capt. James and Mollie Bumgardner,
                    died near Staunton at the residence of his parents on April 11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>Justis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Justis George died at his residence near Waynesboro on April 8th. He was 78
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hazel</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garner</ln>
                        <fn>David P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Ann Hazel, daughter of David P. Garner, died near Sherando on
                    April 8th after an illness of 12 hours. She was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Henry T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry T. Sheets, son of Benjamin E. and Mary A. Sheets, died in Spring Hill
                    on March 11th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garland</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garland</ln>
                        <fn>Caroline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Garland, daughter of J. R. and Caroline Garland, died in Augusta
                    County on April 11th. She was 27 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.04.21.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
