<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.12.08">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/17/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-12-08">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.12.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.12.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>To the Patrons of the Virginian</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pemberton</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. D. Stoneburner and J. B. Pemberton announce that they have sold the
                    Valley Virginian to Maj. S. M. Yost.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> By the notice at the head of this column, it will be seen, that the
                        undersigned has become the editor and proprietor of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Valley Virginian</emph></p>
                    <p> In resuming his connection with the press of the Valley, it would hardly be
                        necessary for him to do more then simply announce the fact, were it not that
                        since he last communed with this public, as the editor of a public journal,
                        the institutions of the country have undergone great changes, the
                        fundamental structures which, were at the base of parties have been
                        swallowed up by new issues, the social organism of the South up rooted, and
                        the physical and intellectual energies of the people diverted into new
                        channels. A new order of things is upon us. The ideas and opinions advanced
                        and maintained ten years ago in support of parties, whose politics were well
                        defined, find now but little applicability. The chief source of political
                        and sectional antagonism then has been destroyed, and we must now look to
                        the future for the full development of the issues upon which parties will be
                        formed and divided. The necessities of an economical administration of
                        government will create those issues. As yet, they are merely in the
                        chrysalis state, without the lines and lineaments fully drawn. The events,
                        hidden in the womb of the future, from which the policies of parties will be
                        shaped, cannot with satisfactory distinctness be foretold. We must await
                        developments and be guided by the lights which promise to the people of
                        Virginia, the South, and the nation, the greatest good. In broad and general
                        terms the writer may say, however, that all projects of governmental reform
                        which harmonize most nearly with the theories of the Democratic party will
                        receive the cordial and earnest support of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Virginian</emph></p>
                    <p>But, at this time, the people of Virginia, and especially of this great and
                        affluent Valley, are more interested in the paramount consideration of
                        material development. The completion of the great lines of public
                        improvement, now in the process of construction, as well as the inauguration
                        of those in contemplation, is of far more importance than mere political
                        theories or the fashioning and working of party machinery. The controlling
                        minds of the State are now fully engrossed with the great public enterprises
                        whose prosecution must open up new sources of wealth, enlarge the power, and
                        extend the influence, of the Commonwealth, than they are with the
                        organization of parties for the advancement of personal ambition.</p>
                    <p>We here in the Valley look forward with cheerful hope to the completion of
                        those great channels of trade and travel between the Atlantic seaboard and
                        the vast productive regions of the Middle and Northwest, the Chesapeake and
                        Ohio Railroad and the James River Canal--which are destined in the future to
                        command the rich commerce not only of those sections, but to share in the
                        profits arising from the growing wealth and importance of the Pacific
                        States, and their trade even with the affluent cities of the oriental world.</p>
                    <p> The Valley Railroad and the Shenandoah Valley Railroad, are projects of
                        internal improvement, in which the people are deeply interested, and while
                        the citizens of this immediate locality and the central valley are more
                        intimately concerned about the Valley Railroad and its completion, they do
                        not consider that there is any necessity for an acrimonious rivalry. The
                        wealth of the Valley which must spring into existence on the construction of
                        these roads, and the connections they will make with Southern lines of trade
                        and travel, cannot fail to command remunerative employment for both. To this
                        subject more minute allusion will be made in future numbers of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Virginian</emph></p>
                    <p> It will be the aim of the editor to conduct the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Virginian</emph> upon high principles of journalistic propriety. He has
                        no personal ends to attain, save that of making an honest living by
                        legitimate means and industrious application. He will fearlessly maintain,
                        in these columns, what he believes to be right, and promotive of the best
                        interests of the community and the State. He will coalesce with no man, or
                        set of men, for the accomplishment of purely selfish objects, but will
                        endeavor to maintain the dignity, honor and independence of the press, and
                        his own self-respect, in all that he may write or publish. He desires to
                        publish a paper that will meet the sympathy and approval of good men, and
                        that will be an acceptable visitant to every fireside. </p>
                    <p>In discussing questions of public policy, he does not expect to please all
                        classes of minds. An honest difference of opinion is tolerated by every
                        honest man. He can readily accord to dissenting minds the same purity of
                        motives as those he himself profess, and this he shall always take pleasure
                        and feel a pride in acknowledging.</p>
                    <p>He will aim at no ungenerous or unmanly rivalry with the Press of Staunton or
                        of the Valley. There is a public spirit and liberality sufficient to give
                        all a decent living who will work for it and who deserve it. But he will
                        earnestly and cordially unite with his conference in the advocacy of every
                        scheme and proposition whose practical operation will ensure to the common
                        interest of the city, the county, the section, the State and the country.</p>
                    <p>The editor expects to take a decided position upon every question of public
                        interest that may present itself. He recognizes in a public journal no
                        passive agent, governed by negatives, uncertainties and indecisions, but he
                        regards it as designed to direct and educate popular sentiment--as means of
                        diffusing information and stimulating public enterprise. S.M. Yost</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article announces the first issue of the Virginian under the new
                    editorship of S.M. Yost. Yost's principle interest is "the new order of things."
                    He claims that issues defining political parties of the past are no longer
                    relevant. Therefore, all must "look to the future" and properly analyze the
                    issues that will shape political parties now merely in "chrysalis" form. Yost
                    promises that the paper will always take a position on whatever issue is at
                    hand.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Political</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is very evident that a process of disintegration, and exfoliation is now
                        going on in the Republican party. Springing into existence upon a one ideal
                        view of a great political and social question--having accomplished the
                        original purpose of its creation, and the cause of its formation and the
                        motive of power of its vitality destroyed, there would seem to be no further
                        occasion for the cohesion of the elements which compose it. But the
                        infatuation of power--the charm of unchallenged control and distribution of
                        vast revenue, are sufficient incentives to stimulate parties in exertion for
                        the supremacy of their organization. Indeed, we but express our honest
                        conviction when we say, that with parties, as such, whether in power or
                        battling to gain power, the mastery and manipulation of the Treasury and the
                        offices of the government, are the secret sources of cohesion, and the
                        propelling agent of action. Of course, with a view to capturing and securing
                        the popular vote, theories of government are maintained and political tenets
                        advocated, which harmonize with the natural bearings of the popular wind;
                        for the elementary and normal idea of the people is for a liberal and
                        economical administration of government--as nearly democratic as is
                        consistent with stability and durability. This idea, however, as a general
                        proposition, is entertained in a musty, foggy state. The popular mind does
                        not elaborate and digest, nor reduce it down to a point of demonstration
                        and, therefore, it is not prepared at all times to embrace the means to
                        attain the end. It was in one of these periods of popular clamor and
                        demagogical appeal for liberalizing government, without reference to a
                        parallel progress of intelligence and education, that John Randolph declared
                        "every change is not reform." And while no reform can be effected without
                        change--no revolution in parties or the administration of government can be
                        accomplished, without party condemning its own action or the people
                        condemning party--it does not follow that the party proposing the reform is
                        any purer in the motive that stimulates it than the organization which
                        committed the alleged wrong. The intellectual conviction may be clear as to
                        the necessity, for the good of the people, for the practical enforcement of
                        certain ideas of government, but the corrupt and debased motive of party
                        unity and supremacy, with a view to public spoils and public plunder, may
                        obey the dictation of that conviction. It is only when abused power--power
                        devoted to self-aggrandizement and party supremacy, is threatened to be
                        wrecked by the mandate of an indignant popular voice form the party thus
                        misdirecting it, that the shift is made from a transparent and unblushing
                        policy and practice of corruption and fraud to a seeming embracement of a
                        theory long before lodged in the mind, as in consonance with the truthful
                        idea of our system of government. It is a spurious virtue, enforced by an
                        inexorable necessity.</p>
                    <p> It is in this light we regard the recent movement of prominent members of
                        the Republican party, lead by the Chicago <emph rend="italic"
                        >Tribune,</emph> to either tongue and groove into the Republican platform
                        the doctrine of civil reform and retrenchment--a revolution in the revenue
                        system of the government, and a vast abatement in the financial outgoings,
                        and a consequent lightening of the burdens of taxation; or to create a new
                        party based on this idea. </p>
                    <p>We cannot see the necessity of this latter alternative nor do we acknowledge
                        the legitimacy or disinterestedness of the former suggestion. These reforms
                        are part and parcel of the fundamental creed of the Democratic party. The
                        idea is coexistent with the birth of that party; and if its practical
                        operation is deemed essential to the welfare of the country, it must be a
                        hallow and insincere declaration of principle, if those who declare it are
                        not willing to unite with the party which, from its organization, has made
                        the proposition now ostentatiously paraded as something new, one of its
                        cardinal dogmas. There is nothing particularly significant in a name itself,
                        unless that name is associated with ideas and principles as to almost become
                        part of them. It is a false pride--a doubtful patriotism, that will not
                        leave an inane monosyllable to grasp a great public good, or that will
                        permit a party nomenclature to control an intellectual convention affecting
                        a vital principle of government.</p>
                    <p>Vast numbers of the most prominent and intellectual members of the Democratic
                        party, cut loose from that organization and united with the Republican
                        party, because of their relative positions on the question of slavery. They
                        thought the time had come for that question to be settled--that the
                        irrepressible conflict" was upon us--and that bone of contention ought to be
                        disposed of. We all know the result. Of this number are Gratz Brown and
                        Frank Blair of Missouri, John A. Logan of Illinois, and others equally
                        prominent in the recent political conflicts of the country. They were
                        Democratic upon all the dogmas of administrative policy, save this one. That
                        being disposed of, they are Democratic still, and will unite with the
                        Democratic party in the restoration of the government to a healthy and
                        legitimate basis of administration. If exfoliating Republicans, who in the
                        past never sympathized with the theories of the Democratic party, but now
                        acknowledge their essentiality to the good of the country, are honest, and
                        are not attempting to appropriate these well know popular ideas as a means
                        of saving their organization, let them do as Democrats did on the slavery
                        question--unite with the party whose history is identified with them. Indeed
                        let all who are jealous of the country's honor--of the peoples'
                        welfare--band together and carry into practical operation the great cardinal
                        dogma of the Democratic party--Civil Reform and financial retrenchment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article looks into the current state of the Republican Party. The
                    author points out that fissures over civil and financial reform could lead to
                    different ends. Either the party is currently in the process of blending these
                    reforms into their platform, or certain elements of the party are breaking off
                    into a new party. The author has two important things to say about this. First,
                    these reforms are originally part of the Democratic party dogma, second,
                    Democrats had split before, over the slavery question, and reunited once those
                    issues had been settled. This article calls for honest Republicans to do as the
                    Democrats did, and unite with the party whose "history is identified with them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>A Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The growing importance of Staunton, as a central and distributive point west
                        of the Blue Ridge, the remarkable increase of its population and trade since
                        the late civil war, the marvelous energy displayed by its business men,
                        mechanics, merchants, and capitalists of all descriptions, both in labor and
                        means--the enterprise thrift and judgment exhibited by the farmers of
                        Augusta county--the geographical location of this immediate vicinity, which
                        is destined to make it the great crossing point for the trade and travel of
                        the continent, from the Gulf to the Potomac, from the Atlantic to the
                        Pacific suggest the appositeness of an application to the Federal
                        Government, for an appropriation to erect, in this place, a public building
                        for the accommodation of the Post office, Internal Revenue and Judicial
                        Departments of the United States. The business of the Post Office
                        Department, at this point, is considerably larger than at any other place
                        East of the Blue Ridge. This building, for that purpose, has to be erected
                        and paid for by the Government. The offices for the Collector and Assessor
                        for the 6th District are procured in a like manner, and the United States
                        Court, which meets in Staunton twice each year, has no place to sit except
                        in the Court House. This is attended with more or less inconvenience both to
                        the Courts of the County and Circuit, and the United States, for their times
                        of meeting sometimes come in conflict.</p>
                    <p>There are eligible sites in the city for a building, such as is here
                        suggested, that could be purchased at reasonable rates. The building itself,
                        erected upon a judicious place could be made to yield to the United States,
                        a handsome percentage, independent of the amount saved, which is now paid
                        for the rent of the Post office and the offices of the Collector and
                        Assessor of Revenue. Were a prominent location selected, the first floor
                        could be made to bring revenue of at least 31,000, in addition to the
                        reduction of expenses at this point for Postal and Internal Revenue offices.
                        In these particulars, a saving would be effected of at least 8600, making a
                        total of $1,600, or 10 per cent on $16,000, besides the accommodation of the
                        United States District Court. Twenty thousand dollars would purchase an
                        eligible site, and complete the building.</p>
                    <p>We are satisfied, if this matter were brought prominently before the proper
                        committee, by our Senator and Representative, there would be no difficulty
                        in securing the appropriation of comparatively so insignificant an amount as
                        $20,000, especially when it could be demonstrated that it would be a
                        remunerative investment.</p>
                    <p>We call the attention of Senator Lewis and Representative Milnes to this
                        suggestion, and hope they will deem it of sufficient importance to at once
                        throw it into shape and give it energetic direction.</p>
                    <p>Our citizens should also move in the matter, and by concerted action bring
                        the question before the proper authorities in such a manner as will insure
                        the necessary appropriation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article calls for an appropriation for the erection of a public
                    building in Staunton to accommodate a variety of public offices, including a
                    Circuit Court, Post office, and Internal Revenue Office. Since Staunton has
                    grown in importance since the close of the war; since the population has
                    increased and Staunton has become geographically central to a great deal of
                    trade and travel, the author feels justified in calling for this appropriation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.12.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. James McClung died in Staunton at the residence of Joseph A. Waddell.
                    McClung had overseen the Exchange Hotel in Richmond, the Virginia House in
                    Staunton, and the Augusta Hot Springs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Murder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>Bill</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Harris, an African American man, was found murdered on the railroad
                    track at the Greenbrier White Sulphur Spring. Money was taken from the body.
                    Bill Ross, a black man from Salem was arrested and confessed to the crime. "The
                    colored people talk of lynching him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Mr. Baldwin's Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Baldwin's recent address was very well received. "It tended to
                    produce lasting impressions upon the minds of the young and of turning the old
                    inebriate into the 'pleasant fields and green pastures' of the land of
                    sobriety."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. James Norris, Staunton insurance agent, plans to go to an infirmary in
                    Baltimore where he will have his eyes operated upon. He has lost sight in one
                    eye and is losing it in another.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Baptist Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The ladies of the Baptist Church will hold a fair at the Town Hall to raise
                    money for repairs to their church. They will sell a variety of luxuries. The
                    paper encourages all to support the effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>J. I. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. A. W. Harman has taken control of the stage line between Staunton and
                    Harrisonburg formerly run by J. I. A. Trotter. Mr. Allen of Staunton will remain
                    local agent. Stages will leave Staunton every day at 9:00am and 5:00pm, and will
                    leave Harrisonburg at 9:00am and 7:00pm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxwell</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John C. Troxwell and Miss Sarah J. Price, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Newport on November 16th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Ellinger and Miss Sarah M. Gordon, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Newport on November 17th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Handy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Crawford and Sadie E. Crawford, daughter of William Crawford of
                    Augusta, were married at the house of the bride's father on November 30th by the
                    Rev. Isaac W. K. Handy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Shumate of Staunton and Miss Jennie M. Shafer, daughter of the late
                    David Shafer of Rockbridge, were married on November 30th at the residence of
                    the bride's mother by the Rev. Platt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Nimrod</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nimrod Gordon and Miss Nancy J. Swink, both of Augusta, were married on
                    November 10th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Clara C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Brown and Miss Clara C. Lamb, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 1st by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel A. Dunlap and Miss Eliza D. Rohrer were married near Churchville on
                    December 1st by the Rev. J. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>Willie Graham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>M. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Graham Cootes, daughter of B. F. and M. E. Cootes, died in Staunton
                    of croup. She was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wald</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Wald died at Newport on November 27th of consumption. He was 27
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Archart</ln>
                        <fn>Lieucetta H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Archart</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieucetta H. Archart, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Archart, died on
                    November 25th. She was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.12.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
