<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.09.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/12/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-22">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton, VA. Sept. 20th, 1870.<lb/>Mr. G. P. Fitzgerald</p>
                    <p>Dear Sir:--Your favor of the 16th just received, and it gives us pleasure to
                        respond. The class of settlers in behalf of whom your inquiries are made, is
                        just the sort we want among us. As for the character of inducements offered
                        to immigrants--we Valley people are vain enough to think that the sun of
                        Heaven never shone upon a country combining more natural advantages. With a
                        delightful climate, a generous soil, inexhaustible store of minerals,
                        abundant water power, and, just here particularly, a geographical position
                        most fortunate, in view of the rival railroads approaching from the North,
                        and to intersect here with the great trunk line of the West. All we want for
                        the development of our country is more of the right sort of people. This
                        section is rallying fast from the general prostration which followed the
                        war. There is a greater demand for skilled labor--especially house-builders
                        and machinists, than ever before.</p>
                    <p>Staunton is a live town, population some five thousand, exclusive of the
                        large number of strangers from all quarters brought here by our Female
                        schools, now at six in number, and all first-class. Within a few hours ride
                        we have Washington College and the University of Virginia. So you see we do
                        not lack educational advantages. Our bar is inferior to none in the State,
                        and numbers some forty practitioners. Of course, no professional man of
                        standing would associate himself with a stranger, without opportunity to
                        judge of his capacity and merits, but if your son should come he will find
                        among them none but courteous antagonists. We have also some twenty
                        practicing physicians, but room for more.</p>
                    <p>Honest, well meaning, and industrious men are always welcome among us,
                        whatever be their country or calling. The people here are decedents of the
                        old Scotch-Irish stock--frugal and industrious themselves. They have not
                        been so active in politics as our neighbors East of the Blue Ridge--they
                        recognize the right of every man to entertain his own opinions, so he does
                        not thrust them down the threats of the "Klu Klux spirit prevailing," that
                        is all stuff and nonsense, and serves for a jest with our northern friends
                        who have taken the trouble to inform themselves. The men who fought with
                        Stonewall Jackson are not the sort to become midnight marauders; and now
                        that we are suffered to govern ourselves, no occasion ever arises for the
                        strong arm of the Law to put down any such disturbances.</p>
                    <p>Hoping that any of you who think of moving to Virginia will just come and see
                        for themselves, we are</p>
                    <p> Very Respectively, &amp;c, <lb/>Editors Valley Virginian. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article responds to a letter of inquiry from a potential immigrant to
                    Staunton. The author lists many of the advantageous aspects of the area
                    including geographical position, mineral and water power, and soil quality.
                    Further, he lists several professional opportunities and educational advantages.
                    Finally, the author insists that the area is free from Ku Klux Klan
                    difficulties. He invites all who wish to move to Virginia to come and visit the
                    region to see for themselves.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper takes offense to reports that the New York Times is criticizing
                    the "scum and riff-raff" that filled the Confederate armies. "The people south
                    of the Potomac had occular evidence of an amount of 'scum and riff-raff' which
                    came across that river during the war surpassing in foulness almost anything
                    ever before seen or heard of."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Valley District</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article reporting that the citizens of Augusta have asked Mr. A. H. H.
                    Stuart to announce himself a candidate for Congress. "It is no news to say that
                    Mr. Stuart is one of the most accomplished statesmen in the Union; that he is
                    sagacious, prudent and indefatigable, and would make a worthy representative of
                    any district in the land."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Precinct Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin orders that the voters of the precincts that did not hold
                    primary meetings are requested to gather on September 24th to appoint three
                    delegates to the County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A vote was taken in Staunton on Saturday on the question of a further
                    subscription by the city of $50,000 to the Valley Railroad. 286 approved and 90
                    disapproved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterritt</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton Wards numbers 1 and 2 held meetings on Saturday to elect delegates
                    to the county convention. The First Ward chose William G. Sterritt, Bolivar
                    Christian, and Richard Fisher and the Second Ward chose H. M. Bell, M. G.
                    Harman, and J. M. Hardy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gratian</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilespie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merickan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>St. F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Abney</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>P. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caldwell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Baxter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The various precincts chose delegates to the county convention. New Hope:
                    S. B. Finley, Charles Gratian, Dr. Gillespie. Mt. Sidney: William Crawford,
                    Thomas Burke, Charles Roller. Bolivar: A. W. Harman, Joseph Merickan, S. Croft.
                    Hebron: Jacob Baylor, St. F. C. Roberts, J. T. Mitchell. Barterbrook: A. G.
                    Christian, William A. Abney, H. G. Guthrie. Fishersville: David S. Bell, P. T.
                    Burkholder, William Caldwell. Buffalo Gap: William M. Tate, Baxter Crawford,
                    Lorenzo Sibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scrogham</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humbert</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel T. Scrogham and Miss Elizabeth F. Humbert, both of Augusta, were
                    married on September 8th by the Rev. Martin Garber.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keneday</ln>
                        <fn>Henry S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhineheart</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rhineheart</ln>
                        <fn>Oliver</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry S. Keneday and Lucy C. Rhineheart, daughter of Oliver Rhineheart, all
                    of New Hope, were married on September 14th by the Rev. John H. Wolfe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yarbrough</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Yarbrough died in New Hope on September 4th. He was 81 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>E. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Lucy A. Edmondson died near Staunton at the residence of her brother,
                    E. L. Edmondson, on August 24th. She was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
