<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.05.05">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/09/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-05-05">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">5</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.05.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.05.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Usury Laws--Twelve Per Cent!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There has been a great difference of opinion in regard to the wisdom of laws
                        restricting the rate of interest on money to six per cent. The debtor class
                        have generally been anxious to stay the hands of the grasping creditor. Men
                        who have money to lend, have, on the other hand, contended that they ought
                        to have the right to dig the people as deeply as they chose. In the radical
                        convention the wishes of the moneyed men prevailed, and the Legislature is
                        now prohibited, by the Constitution, from passing any law limiting the rate
                        of interest to less than twelve per cent, where the parties choose to
                        contract for it.</p>
                    <p>We are among those who regarded this change in our system as disastrous. The
                        experience of the world has been, that the money lender will oppress the
                        borrower, unless the law intervenes for his protection. And we apprehend it
                        will be found that our views are correct. Creditors will now take debtors by
                        the throat, and say "pay me what thou owest," or give a new bond for 12 per
                        cent instead of six. Men having money to lend, will avail themselves of the
                        pressure in the money market, and demand the highest premium allowed by law.
                        Debtors are proverbially sanguine. They think, if they can only get relief
                        from the present pressure, or obtain the command of a little active capital,
                        they can do wonders. Misled by this delusive hope, they will borrow, at
                        extravagant rates of interest, and put off the evil days as long as they
                        can. But it must come at last, and come with all its accumulated burthens.
                        Ruin will be the consequences; and then men will begin to see the folly of
                        their course, and the iniquity of the laws which let lose the Shylocks to
                        prey on the community. Better, far better, let loose so many lions and
                        tigers in our streets, than half a dozen money lenders, with full liberty to
                        fatten on the distresses of the community. The lions and tigers might rend a
                        few unfortunate individuals before they were shot, but the money lenders
                        will devastate whole households, and bring ruin and anguish to the
                        hearthstones of helpless women and children.</p>
                    <p>Under the present disastrous law authorizing 12 per cent, we expect northern
                        usurers to become, as it were, absolute landlords of a large portion of our
                        landed estates.--The sanguine land-holders will mortgage them at a rate of
                        interest which will be equal to a fair rent, and thus in effect, become mere
                        tenants. When the seasons are good, the tenant may pay his rent (called
                        interest) but when an unlucky frost or drought comes, or from any cause, the
                        crop fails, the rent (alias interest), cannot be paid, and then the mortgage
                        will be enforced, and the unhappy tenant sold out of house and home.</p>
                    <p>Have our readers thought of what a fatal cancer interest at 12 per cent is?</p>
                    <p>Make the calculation, and you will find that the man who borrows $100, at 12
                        per cant payable annually, will, if it be so compounded have to pay, at the
                        end of six years, more than $198 to discharge his debt. If the interest be
                        payable semi-annually, the debt will be more than doubled in six years!</p>
                    <p> We warn our people to beware of this ruinous rate of interest. It will be
                        fatal to all who borrow, for any length of time, at that rate. A trading man
                        may borrow, for 60 or 90 days, at that rate, to make a speculation, which
                        will yield a quick return. But no regular business will bear it. Merchants
                        cannot borrow at that rate and thrive. Mechanics cannot. And woe! to the
                        farmer who makes the rash experiment! Ruin is to him a certainty. Large
                        farms will not, as a general rule support a family <del/> will hardly
                        suffice to pay family expenses. </p>
                    <p>We implore our farmers then "to touch not, taste not, handle not" the unclean
                        thing. It is worse than leprosy or the small pox. These loathsome diseases
                        waste the body, and bring death in their train. But twelve per cent interest
                        impoverishes the family--saps the foundation of the moral nature--turns
                        wives and children out of house and home--drives the desperate to
                        drunkenness, and spreads misery and ruin broad-cast over the land. Where
                        people are involved in debt, it will be far better to face their
                        difficulties squarely, at once, and sell property, at a heavy sacrifice,
                        rather than submit to the torture of protracted suffering. Better sell half
                        you own, and have the residue clear of all incumbrance, than hold the whole,
                        subject to a mortgage for half its value. The classic fable represents that
                        Prometheus stole fire form Heaven, and as a punishment, he was condemned to
                        live always, with vultures constantly tearing his vitals. We incline to
                        think that this fable typifies the man who borrows money at 12 per cent! The
                        vultures will gnaw his very heart-strings, as long as he lives!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article serves as a warning to any person considering borrowing money
                    at twelve percent. Recent laws have allowed northern "shylocks" means by which
                    they can offer loans at these exorbitant rates of interest. The author
                    calculates the amount the borrower will actually pay over a six year period. He
                    also outlines the near certain ruinous results that will befall all those (with
                    the exception of short term speculators) who borrow at these rates. His
                    particular concerns rest with how ruin will compromise not only the man, but the
                    family as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Public Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marquis</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>William H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A public meeting was held in Staunton's Court House to express grief for
                    the disaster in Richmond in which a number of people were killed and injured
                    when the floor of the capitol court room collapsed. A committee was appointed to
                    raise relief funds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.05.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large number of people attended a soiree to benefit the Richmond
                    sufferers. The event raised $25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper announces that the new registration act requires that those
                    previously registered must re-register in order to vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Businesses closed and churches held services in mourning for the tragedy in
                    Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmitt</ln>
                        <fn>Julia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmitt</ln>
                        <fn>Mathias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMahon</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weed</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Father</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia F. Schmitt, daughter of Mathias Schmitt, and John J. McMahon, both of
                    Staunton, were married in the Catholic Church on May 3rd by the Rev. Father
                    Weed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Agnes W. Logan, wife of Robert C. Logan, died near Fishersville,
                    Augusta County, on April 21st. "She died as a christian."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McComb</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Francis M. McComb died near Stuart's Draft on April 28th after a brief
                    illness. He was 24 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carrier</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Jr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Carrier, Jr., son of the late Henry Carrier of Rockingham, died at
                    the Western Lunatic Asylum on April 7th after a protracted illness of "affection
                    of the brain."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A committee representing Staunton Lodge No. 45, I. O. O. F., issued a
                    tribute of sympathy and respect upon the death of fellow-member H. H. Forsythe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.05.05.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
