<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.10.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/13/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-10-20">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Virginia's Troubles</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>When Virginia was first settled her people were subjected to the severest
                        trials of war, pestilence and famine. When those earlier troubles were over
                        past, a period of prosperity and happiness followed. Immigrants poured into
                        her borders, and she became the leading colony in these Western settlements
                        in the wealth, intelligence and heroism of her people. Then came other
                        sorrows of floods, political and religious repression and wasting wars. This
                        was followed by a development of prosperity--civil, religious and
                        material--far eclipsing all her former glory. Her sons were the framers of
                        bills for civil and religious liberty--Constitutions and wise and just
                        laws--leaders of armies, Governors of States and Presidents of the Republic.
                        From that beginning of the late war ever and anon some great calamity has
                        befallen her. The war came, and for four years her soil was drenched with
                        blood; her fields and towns were desolated and sacked, and finally, torn and
                        bleeding at every pore, she fell, crushed beneath the weight of overwhelming
                        odds, her means destroyed, her labor gone, her social system overturned and
                        the iron heel grinding her in the earth. Bravely, earnestly, quietly she
                        adapted herself to the new order of things and manfully she struggled to
                        meet the crisis. Then followed the memorable disaster to her Capitol, by
                        which so many lives were lost, which was succeeded by withering droughts,
                        destructive floods, and, last of all, the fall of her noblest, bravest,
                        purest and most beloved son. Oh! what a catalogue of sorrows--what a volume
                        of calamities!</p>
                    <p> Great calamities call out all the higher and nobler feelings of our nature;
                        crush self in sympathy with the general misfortunes, bind in a great
                        brotherhood a whole people; develop kindness, love, generosity, hospitality
                        and a loftiness of mind and magnanimity of soul which result in the
                        production of noble women and great men--prepared for every crisis and all
                        emergencies. They have made Virginians a peculiar people in other
                        days--peculiar people they will preserve them in times to come--<emph
                            rend="italic">Richmond Whig</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author of this article reassures his readers who are currently
                    overwhelmed by the difficulties facing Virginia. He points to other historical
                    events to prove that Virginians have always overcome troubles--periods of war or
                    oppression have always been followed by periods of prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>General Lee</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper publishes a tribute to Robert E. Lee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Augusta County Fair is in progress and drawing many visitors despite
                    the "impassable condition" of many of the roads in the county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Tribute to Gen. R. E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting of the citizens of the town of Staunton, held in the Court-house
                        on Friday the 14th inst., to express their deep concern at the death of Gen.
                        Robert E. Lee, and to appoint a committee to represent the town on the
                        occasion of his funeral.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. B. Christian, Thomas J. Michie, Esq., was called to the
                        Chair, and Col. Jas. B. Skinner was appointed Secretary.</p>
                    <p>Thereupon the following preamble and resolutions were offered and their
                        adoption moved by Hon. A.H.H. Stuart, who, in presenting them, paid an
                        appropriate tribute to the exalted genius and virtues of the illustrious
                        dead:</p>
                    <p>The citizens of Staunton having learned that the family of the late Gen. R.E.
                        Lee have expressed a desire that his mortal remains shall, for the present,
                        be deposited in the Memorial Chapel of Washington College, and that the
                        funeral obsequies will take place on Saturday, 15th inst., at 12 o'clock.</p>
                    <p>And the citizens of Staunton feeling a strong desire to testify in some
                        public manner, their profound love and veneration for the memory and
                        character of this illustrious man, who has shed so much honor, not only in
                        his native State but upon human nature.</p>
                    <p>It is therefore resolved that a delegation, on behalf of the citizens of
                        Staunton, be appointed to visit Lexington and unite in the ceremonies
                        intended to mark the deep sense of the great calamity that has befallen
                        Virginia, in the death of him, who next to Washington, enjoyed in the
                        largest measure the affection and gratitude of his fellow citizens.</p>
                    <p>Col. B. Christian seconded the resolutions and briefly explained to the
                        meeting the resolutions of the General Assembly of Virginia which had been
                        transmitted through him by the Legislature of Virginia, to the family of the
                        deceased, and the response made by Gen G.W. Custis Lee to the request
                        therein contained.</p>
                    <p>The preamble and resolutions were then unanimously adopted and the following
                        gentlemen appointed a Committee to attend the funeral obsequies: A.H.H.
                        Stuart, Boliver Christian, J.B. Baldwin, Dr. F.T. Stribling, F.M. Young,
                        N.K. Trout, Chas. C. Phillips, Chas. T. Arnall, Dr. Carter Berkeley, Wm. H.
                        Gorman, Frank Berkeley, Wm. N. Bumpas, I.S. Hendry, J. Howard, J. Wayne
                        Spitler, Rev. A.H. Kennedy, Ed. Echols.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Charles D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Charles C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumpus</ln>
                        <fn>William N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendry</ln>
                        <fn>I. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayne</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>Ed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article describes a meeting held by the prominent citizens of Staunton
                    to adopt a preamble and resolutions to be presented at the funeral of R.E. Lee.
                    Included is a list of the committee chosen to attend the funeral obsequies on
                    behalf of the town.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Russell N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batis</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Russell N. Wallace and Mrs. Mary Batis, both of Augusta, were married at
                    the American Hotel on October 15th by the Rev. H. H. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutchen</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo S. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dill</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lorenzo S. K. McCutchen of Augusta and Miss Hattie Dill of Rockbridge were
                    married on September 22nd by the Rev. Mr. Riley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Coyner, Jr., and Miss Lizzie V. Vanlear, both of Augusta, were
                    married on October 3rd at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev.
                    William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCommon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel D. McCommon of Rockingham and Miss Mattie D. Hailman, daughter of B.
                    F. Hailman of Augusta, were married on October 11th by the Rev. A. A. J.
                    Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>Josie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Josie B. Richardson, wife of C. A. Richardson, died in Staunton at the
                    residence of her husband on October 13th. She was 18 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>St. Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>St. Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>St. Mayer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert St. Mayer, son of William and Mary A. St. Mayer, died near Parnassus
                    on September 25th. He was 17 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Porterfield</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca F. Kinney, wife of the late William Kinney and daughter of the
                    late Gen. Robert Porterfield, died at her Staunton residence on October 7th. She
                    was 73 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ast</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Ast died at his residence in Staunton on October 17th. He was 75
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peter Frenger died at Arbor Hill on October 7th. He was 66 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
