<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.10.27">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/13/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-10-27">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="">27</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.27.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.27.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> There were croakers before the Flood which drove Noah into the Ark; there
                        were croakers when Adam entered Paradise on earth, the Garden of Eden, and
                        there have been croakers ever since. Then, is it all surprising that there
                        should have been some croakers on exhibition at the Augusta Agricultural
                        Fair! It is a well established fact in the law of physiology, that crying is
                        conducive to the health of babies. You may smile, dear reader, but it is so,
                        however disagreeable the infantile refrain may grate on your highly
                        cultivated taste for the divine art. The same theory will apply to the law
                        of croakers.--Now we are not disposed to deprive them of their rights, and
                        if croaking does them good, and they become fat on it, why, let them <emph
                            rend="italic">croak</emph> to their heart's content! </p>
                    <p>But at our recent Fair there were things our friends, the croakers, were
                        ominously dumb upon. The fine arrangements for the exhibition of stock of
                        every kind, and for the domestic and fancy articles of every industrious and
                        good housewife, which speaks well for the tact, judgment and foresight of
                        the officers of the society. The display of fine cattle, though not as
                        numerous as on previous years, was unexcelled, and the same may be said of
                        the blooded horses on exhibition. But the most attractive feature about the
                        Fair was the scintillating eyes, rotund forms, and blooming cheeks of the
                        mountain maids and lovely Valley girls. They were the admiration of all
                        visitors from other sections of our glorious old State. They at least--if
                        nothing else--were a decided success. Taking everything into
                        consideration--the scorching drought the last season, and the late terrible
                        and destructive flood--the fair was in every way a success; and the best
                        proof of all is the balance in bank to the credit of the treasurer.</p>
                    <p> But a word about Fairs. We believe, in Fairs of every kind, from the little
                        village church fair to the big State Fair. If there is any thing that acts
                        as an incentive to develop the rich resources of our State, it is
                        agricultural fairs. Men meet and exchange views and experiences on the
                        various and best modes of enriching and a successful cultivation of the
                        soil--what is best for that and this county or district; the yield of the
                        different <sic>cerials;</sic> the proper care and best breeds of the
                        different kinds of grazing and farming stock. In short, "what they know
                        about farming?" If they do not go back to their homes richer they certainly
                        do wiser men. Besides, the social annual reunions and cordial greetings of
                        long separated friends, more than doubly repays the expense and time spent
                        away from the firesides of "vrow" and "bairns," if you are so fortunate as
                        have them; if not it may be the means of your getting a wife or <emph
                            rend="italic">fair</emph> sweetheart. </p>
                    <p>It is not once in ten years that a country is blighted with a scorching
                        drought; it is not once in a hundred years that a country is visited with
                        such a flood as the destructive one that has recently swept through our
                        beautiful Valley carrying every thing before it; it is not once in a
                        thousand years that a country is afflicted with such a Ghoul and barn
                        burning villain as Swearing Phil Sheridan! Then, let us thank God for the
                        respite and take courage, redouble our energies and our beautiful and
                        fertile Valley will again bloom as the rose of Sharon.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article points out the many "fine arrangements" on display at the
                    August County Fair, despite the numerous "croakers" on exhibition. The author
                    points out the articles for the "industrious housewife," cattle and horses.
                    Further, he describes the beautiful women of the Valley in attendance. An
                    important aspect of this article suggests that despite all the difficulties
                    experienced in the Valley of late, including droughts, floods, and Yankees, the
                    spirit of the citizens has not flagged. Rather, these problems have pulled the
                    people together in an effort to "redouble [their] energies" and rebuild.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Nominee for Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> There is no disguising the fact that a large number of the Conservative
                        voters of Augusta are opposed to the election of Judge J.T. Harris. This
                        county was almost unanimously in favor of that purest of men and ablest of
                        statesman, who would dignify and adorn the highest office within the gift of
                        the people--the Hon. A.H.H. Stuart. But, unfortunately, fate was against us,
                        and we have nothing now to do, but gracefully submit to the decision of the
                        Convention, accept and heartily support the nominee. If we fail to do this,
                        we will not only increase the probabilities of the election of an avowed
                        Radical, lose, it may be, the valuable services of the Conservative
                        standard-bearer, but we will engender a bitterness against us, in the hearts
                        of the lower county men, who have shown such a decided preference for Judge
                        Harris, which will be hard to overcome in future elections when <emph
                            rend="italic">Augusta's choice</emph> is in the field. We must care not
                        to "bite off our nose to spite our own face." "What is sauce for the goose
                        is sauce for the gander," and if we go against <emph rend="italic"
                        >their</emph> choice they will as surely oppose <emph rend="italic"
                        >ours.</emph> No, let it not be said, that Augusta was the first to sow
                        discord in the ranks of the Conservative party, but let us, with a hearty
                        good will, make a united and determined effort for Harris. He has given us
                        every pledge that could be asked for or expected, and we will venture the
                        assertion that, if elected, he will with unswerving fidelity redeem them.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>While the author of this article points out that many Conservative voters
                    did not approve of the election of J.T. Harris to Congress, he nevertheless
                    calls for conservative voters of all stripes to offer Harris their support. His
                    point is that any opposition to Harris would split the Conservative party. Many
                    "lower county" conservatives supported Harris, and to alienate them now would
                    cause problems in later elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Conservatives Beware!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following card shows the game of the Radicals. They want division in the
                        Conservative party and hope thus to slip in.--Let every Conservative do his
                        duty and vote the regular ticket. Let none stay at home but come like true
                        men and defeat the radicals, by voting for Judge Harris, the nominee of the
                        party. Douglas Gray, Esq., is the regular candidate of the radicals and
                        every vote withheld from Harris, is a vote for Gray:</p>
                    <p>TO THE VOTERS OF THE 6TH CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT</p>
                    <p>I am a candidate to represent you in the next Congress of the United States.</p>
                    <p>I am a Republican, and if elected will act with the administration party in
                        Congress.--I am for universal suffrage and universal amnesty, we have the
                        one, I will, if elected, do my best to obtain the other.</p>
                    <p>I am for the honest payment of the National debt, and against repudiation in
                        all its forms.</p>
                    <p>I am for equal civil and political rights, for all men, and for carrying out
                        the new State Constitution in its letter and spirit, including the free
                        school system, and the homestead.</p>
                    <p>Fellow-citizens, I have not always been in accord with you in political
                        sentiment, it has been an honest difference of opinion. I have never
                        endeavored to deceive you and you have always known where to find me.</p>
                    <p> If elected I will try to serve you with honesty and fidelity.<lb/> C.
                        DOUGLAS GRAY. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>Douglas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article reveals the assumed evil designs of the radical candidate for
                    Congress. All division within the conservative party should be overcome,
                    otherwise, the divide and conquer plans of the Radicals will prevail. Voters
                    should ignore Radical promises and vote Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.27.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gwine to 'Sert Her Rights</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> A gentle colored maiden, through whose veins courses the purest and evenest
                        African blood, and who knows all about the 15th amendment, passed up on the
                        Chesapeake &amp; Ohio road, on Monday last, to Swoope's Depot where she
                        left the cars for the alleged reason that the Conductor wouldn't allow her
                        to occupy the ladies' car. She remained at Swoope's until yesterday when,
                        intending to resume her journey <del/> she again attempted to enter the
                        ladies car, but, alas, the Conductor happened to be in the immediate
                        vicinity of the door, and when he opened it, (he having previously heard of
                        her partiality for that particular car) he took her by the arm with one hand
                        and resting his other on her beautifully rounded shoulders, gallanted her to
                        another car, where she sat down and proceeded to tell him how she 'lowed to
                        fetch the 15th amendment on to him. The last the conductor heard was: "I
                        knows my rites an' am gwine to 'sert 'em." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article recounts the story of a black woman who was not allowed in the
                    ladies' car on the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio railroad. She protested to the
                    conductor and demanded her rights as protected by the 15th amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sad Case of Suicide</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nichols</ln>
                        <fn>A. Thompson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nichols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. A. Thompson Nichols of West Virginia shot himself on board a train of
                    the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad while travelling with his wife's casket to her
                    funeral in Waynesboro. Nichols' brother-in-law, Mr. Bell, accompanied him. "The
                    death of Mrs. Nichols was very sudden and unexpected, and cast a deep gloom over
                    the family circle, more especially her husband, so much as to produce insanity
                    on the cars." Dr. McChesney treated him upon arrival in Staunton but could not
                    save him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>Susan C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Frank Swink and Miss Susan C. Buchanan, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 18th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruebush</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Engleman and Miss Mollie E. Ruebush, both of Augusta, were married on
                    October 9th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. J. W. Nott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Marriages</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strayer</ln>
                        <fn>George G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kemper</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kemper</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George G. Strayer of Rockingham and Miss Fannie T. Kemper, daughter of B.
                    F. Kemper of Augusta, were married on October 18th by the Rev. John W. Wolfe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Hattie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hattie Brown, daughter of Cyrus Brown of Waynesboro, died on October 7th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Effie Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Effie Louis Ide, daughter of E. Louis and Sallie A. E. Ide, died on October
                    14th. She was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.10.27.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
