<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.03.31">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/04/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-03-31">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">31</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.31.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.31.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>General Amnesty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a rumor that the president is planning to offer general
                    amnesty to all Confederates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointments by the Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Governor appointed the following councilmen for Staunton: W. M. Allen,
                    George Baylor, James W. Crawford, Robert G. Bickle, James H. Waters, J. H.
                    Blackley, A. F. Gilkeson, William B. Kayser, William A. Burke, William J.
                    Nelson, W. S. McChesney, P. B. Hoge. The following were appointed Justices of
                    the Peace for Augusta: William J. Nelson, Henry Harrison, J. C. Marquis, F. M.
                    Young, B. O. Ferguson, George B. Rusmisel, A. A. McPheeters, William H. Cale, L.
                    Bumgardner, W. T. Rush, William Caldwell, James W. Patrick, James G. Patterson,
                    Thomas S. Hogshead, Jacob Trevy, Phillip Airheart, John S. Guy, Samuel C.
                    Wilson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The New Judicial Districts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Augusta has been included in the new western judicial district of the state
                    of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At the March Term, Wm. F. Bush, Henry Harrison, Wm J. Nelson, Thomas S.
                        Hogshead, Jas. W. Patrick, Jas. G. Patterson, Samuel E. Wilson and Chas. S.
                        Roller qualified as Justices of the Peace.</p>
                    <p>Thos. P. Ranson qualified as Notary Public, and Wm. H. Cale as Commissioner
                        for the 3rd district.</p>
                    <p>Wm. F. Fauber, Jas. F. Davis, John Parris, J. G. Stover renewed their bonds
                        as Notaries, and H. Burgess and Erasmus Houff theirs as Commissioners of the
                        Revenue. Also Sam'l Cline his as Clerk of the County Court.</p>
                    <p>The polls were opened on the 28th of April, to take the sense of the voters
                        of the county, as to whether the County Court of Augusta shall subscribe
                        three hundred thousand dollars to the stock of the Valley Railroad.
                        Commissioners and Officers were appointed to conduct the same.</p>
                    <p>The Grand Jury made thirty indictments, eight for housebreaking and petit
                        larceny and twenty two for assault and battery and petit larceny.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Henry H. Kenerly, white, and Rev. Jas. Ockman, colored, were severally
                        authorized to celebrate the rites of matrimony.</p>
                    <p>F.E. Town tendered his resignation as Commissioner in Chancery, which was
                        accepted.</p>
                    <p>The Court is still in session, with a large amount of business before it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ranson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burgess</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenerly</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cockman</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Town</ln>
                        <fn>F. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article lists the various proceedings of the County Court for the
                    month. Included are renewals of the bonds of Notaries Public, Commissioners of
                    Revenue and others. Also included is a brief list describing the nature of the
                    Jury's thirty-three indictments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.03.31.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
