<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vv1870/va.au.vv.1870.09.01">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Virginian</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/11/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-01">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.01.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Salutatory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With this issue of our paper the connection of Messrs. Burdett and Anderson
                        as part owners terminates. The subscribers having purchased the interests of
                        Messrs. Burdett and Anderson, will, henceforth, be exclusive proprietors and
                        Editors of the paper.</p>
                    <p>In assuming the new and responsible relation to the public, the undersigned
                        deem it proper to say a few words, to their readers, in explanation of what
                        will be the ends and aims of the paper in the future.</p>
                    <p>In the first place, they beg leave to tender to their patrons, their profound
                        acknowledgment for the generous support which their paper has heretofore
                        received. When the late proprietors assumed the direction of the VIRGINIAN,
                        its list of responsible subscribers, was small, and its advertising
                        patronage limited. Under the direction of its late owners, the number of
                        subscribers has swelled to 1400, with a proportionate increase of job and
                        advertising business.</p>
                    <p>It will be the aim of the subscribers, by diligent attention to the affairs
                        of their office, to merit a continuation of the liberal support which they
                        have hitherto enjoyed.--They are conscious of their own deficiencies. They
                        are young men, who have enjoyed, but to a limited extent, the blessings of
                        education. They have been obliged to work their own way, and have
                        encountered many difficulties. But they have never suffered themselves to be
                        appalled by them. No feeling of dependency has ever caused them to relax
                        their exertions. Familiar with work from boyhood, they have not been afraid
                        of it, and with increased duties and responsibilities, they will work the
                        more diligently to merit public confidence and favor, men can but do their
                        best, and the undersigned confidently promise their patrons, that they will
                        spare no pains to secure the approval and good will of their readers.</p>
                    <p>The political position of the paper will remain unchanged. When what was
                        called the "new movement" which has happily resulted in the rescue of
                        Virginia from military thralldom, and all the fearful dangers by which she
                        was surrounded, this paper was one of the first to give cordial support to
                        the undertaking. We shall steadily adhere to the line of "Conservative"
                        policy which was then inaugurated. We shall also give a hearty support to
                        the "Conservative" party through whose agency these beneficial results were
                        accomplished. We like the name "Conservative," and for the present at least,
                        we shall firmly oppose the adoption of any other.--We see no reason for
                        calling on the "Conservative" party to abandon either its name or its
                        organization. What the future may require, we cannot foresee, but with the
                        lights now before us, we can see no just cause for a change. On the
                        contrary, we would like to see the principles, and policy, and organization
                        of the "Virginia Conservatives" extended throughout the Southern States. We
                        believe, that if this were done, and the Southern States would cut loose
                        from both the great northern parties, and have nothing to do with their
                        platforms or nominations, and stand together as an independent organization,
                        they could secure the position of a "balance of power party" which would
                        enable them to give shape and direction to national policy.</p>
                    <p>Be this as it may, we are ready to praise the bridge that passed Virginia
                        safely over the Gulf of 1869. We must be very certain that a better is
                        provided, before we can consent to abandon that which has answered so well.</p>
                    <p>We believe, if this "Conservative" policy is persevered in, the day is not
                        far distant, when Virginia will again exercise a commanding influence in the
                        councils of the nation. In regard to domestic matters, we shall continue to
                        give an earnest support to every measure looking to the development of the
                        moral and material resources of Virginia--Rail-roads, good county roads,
                        schools, manufacturing establishments, and mining interests will find in us,
                        earnest and faithful advocates.</p>
                    <p>As soon as our new county system is thoroughly adjusted, we shall use our
                        best endeavors to secure the adoption of a good system of county roads, and
                        more especially of four or five McAdam roads, beginning in, and radiating
                        from Staunton, to the remotest borders of the county, so as to afford to the
                        people of all sections, convenient access to market, and to their county
                        seat.</p>
                    <p>We respectfully invite contributions on those subjects to our columns from
                        the pens of the many able gentlemen who are to be found in Staunton and its
                        vicinage.</p>
                    <p> Last, but not least, we shall devote our best efforts to advance the
                        interests of our beautiful and thriving "Mountain City." Our attachments,
                        our interests and our hopes are centered here, and it would be strange
                        indeed if we failed to exert ourselves to the utmost, to promote the
                        prosperity and welfare of Staunton.<lb/> C.D. Stoneburner, <lb/>J.B.
                        Pemberton. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burdett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pemberton</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This article announces the change in ownership of the paper, and outlines
                    the aims of the paper for the future. The new owners explain their determination
                    to increase profits through subscription and advertising. Most important are the
                    principles and political position of the paper. The new owners vow that this
                    will remain unchanged; they will "steadily adhere to the line of the
                    'Conservative' policy." Further, the paper will continue to support the
                    development of internal improvement such as rail lines and new roads. This, say
                    the authors, will promote the "prosperity and welfare of Staunton."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Robert E. Lee has been unanimously elected President of the Valley
                    Railroad and is currently in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Siberton Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>From time immemorial it has been a settled fact, that there never was, never
                        can be and never will be started an enterprise, no matter what its
                        character, nor how bright its prospects, but that some may be found to
                        declare it a forgone conclusion that it can never prove a success. Such
                        persons generally have wonderful optical powers. They can stand off fifty
                        miles and tell you what's at the end of that distance, without ever having
                        been there, with a nicer precision and a better understanding of the
                        character and extent of the thing than whose knowledge is based upon
                        personal observation! (We suppose this is one of the much spoken of
                        instances in which "distance lends enchantment to the view!") This brings us
                        to what we proposed to say in the first place. We have been to the iron ore
                        banks of the Siberton Company. We have never heard any one say as much, but
                        it is quite probable it has been at least <emph rend="italic">thought</emph>
                        that these banks are slightly mythical--that they exist in somebody's
                        imagination, but not in any of the spurs of North Mountain! "If there is
                        such a superabundance of ore there," they reason, "why is the furnace not
                        kept in operation?" Well, Rome was not built in a day, nor are huge
                        mountains removed in that time! and if any one desires to post himself as to
                        the amount of work that has been accomplished at the Siberton Works, or the
                        extent of the iron deposits in the neighboring mountains, if he will make a
                        trip up there, Mr. Sibert will take great pleasure in showing him around,
                        and in explaining what he may not be able to understand. We have seen eight
                        or ten of the ore banks (tram roads run by or to each of them), and, though
                        we do not profess to be profoundly versed in minerals, we think there is
                        ample there to run the Furnace for an indefinite time. So far as the quality
                        is concerned, if weight be any indication, we should think it very good. Mr.
                        S. is of the opinion that it contains sixty or seventy per cent of iron.
                        "All's well that ends well."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper defends the Siberton Company from critics. It argues that work
                    may be going slowly, but it is getting done steadily. The article attests to the
                    large size of the deposits of iron ore the company is mining.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorman</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tams</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houston</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>Edmond</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poague</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                        <fn>James E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patton</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders and board of directors of the Valley Railroad met in
                    Staunton on August 30th. They outlined responsibilities for the board of
                    directors and entertained a proposal from Botetourt County aimed at making
                    Fincastle a major point on the road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.vv.1870.09.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
