<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.08.03">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-08-03">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">3</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.03.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: -- I wish to say a little through the columns of your excellent
                        paper (of which I lately had the perusal) on the subject of Temperance, and
                        first I will tell you that I am a woman -- not a ranting "woman's rights"
                        woman -- not a strong-minded woman, contending for a seat in the
                        Legislature, but a woman with a woman's heart that can feel for the
                        distress, the anguish of others -- that can appreciate the scanty wardrobe
                        and desolate, comfortless home, made so by the cups of a drunken husband. A
                        heart, also, that can loathe, and despise the traffic, and were it not for
                        the love of Jesus, the men who carry on this traffic for the promotion of
                        such things as these. Neither am I a literary character, and it is only the
                        great weight that this subject has upon my mind, that now impels me to write
                        that I may possibly say something that may lead some one who has the power
                        to do something that will annihilate the Dram-shop, and all its concomitants
                        from our land.</p>
                    <p>When I see men of wealth renting their houses for this business, and giving
                        them favorable notice -- when I see the dram-seller, putting bread into the
                        mouths of his family by taking it from those of his neighbor -- when I see
                        him garnishing his own home by desolating the homes of others -- when I see
                        a dozen men enter this dram-shop on the Sabbath day -- when I see the blood
                        relative holding literally the bottle to his brother's lips -- when I see
                        the blear-eyed and bloated-faced wretch, stretched with shabby garments,
                        bare-footed, and bare-legged, upon a rude bench, forgetful of everything but
                        the fatal glass, whiling away the precious golden hours that ought to be
                        bringing food, clothing, and happiness to his family -- when I see his
                        pale-faced wife turn sadly from the door of her miserable home, whither she
                        has so frequently gone to look for the form of which she was once justly
                        proud but which she now is so often forced to meet with sickening horror. He
                        is not coming, and as she turns again to her plain duties and her children,
                        she lifts her eyes once more heavenward, and exclaims with the dying
                        crucified One, while the last drop of life-blood seems to be ebbing from her
                        crushed and withered heart -- "My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me."
                        When I see all this, it seems to me that were I to hold my peace, the very
                        stones would cry out.</p>
                    <p>The worst of all is, that these things are either disregarded entirely, or
                        treated lightly, by those in authority. They have failed to plead the cause
                        of the widow and the afflicted. To them we look for light, but behold
                        obscurity -- for brightness, but we walk in darkness.</p>
                    <p>Shall this continue? Something in my inmost soul seems to tell me <emph
                            rend="italic">it shall not.</emph> It seems to me God will not bear much
                        longer with the proud nation, whose land is indeed a land of milk and honey,
                        of countless mercies and luxuries. We have called the God of Heaven our God,
                        a being of infinite Purity and Justice. Can we be a pure people when such
                        impurity is practiced by us? Can we be a just people while we thus tempt our
                        fellow men by making and selling that which will ruin both his soul and his
                        body? Will not this great God, whom we have thus mocked avenge his own
                        elect, who cry unto him day and night? and if we do not as a people cease
                        from this sin, have we not reason to expect, that by reason of the prayers,
                        groans, cries and tears of those afflicted by it, God will come and will not
                        keep silent, that a fire shall devour before him and it shall be very
                        tempestuous about him. -- He may come suddenly and smite the earth with a
                        curse. Then may not even my feeble voice be heard calling for judgment and
                        pleading for truth? May I not plead with those whom we have been proud to
                        call our rulers, and to whom by a vote of the people we have given the <emph
                            rend="italic">Power</emph> (mighty word for good or for evil) to turn
                        back this rapid tide of iniquity.</p>
                    <p>Oh, may we not hope that the time will soon come when the nets for the feet
                        of the youthful and unwary will be broken and made to cease their dark
                        doings. Then shall many, very many, both old and young, both rich and poor,
                        rise up to call you blessed.</p>
                    <p>ORPHA T. SWINK</p>
                    <p>Rural Home, Warren county, Ohio.</p>
                    <p>July 13th., 1869.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Orpha Swink writes to the Spectator about the harm caused by alcohol. She
                    expects that God will soon take his vengeance upon the State that supports the
                    sale of alcohol, and asks those in authority to stop the trade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>STAUNTON, 26th July. 1869.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Messrs. Editors:</emph> -- As my ministerial labors as
                        pastor of the First African Baptist Church here, will close before the issue
                        of the first number of your paper in August, and I, in all probability,
                        already under instruction in the missionary school of the Baptist
                        denomination. I beg leave now to say, through your precious columns, I never
                        parted with a community, without regard to color, with so much reluctance in
                        my life. The countenance uniformly shown me by the whites, and the valuable
                        instructions I have received from many members of the legal profession,
                        together with the support I have received from my own color, lay me under
                        obligations of lasting gratitude, and whatever may be my destiny in the
                        future, whether favorable or unfavorable, I shall, with however much
                        humbleness, humility and meekness, ever bear the sweetest recollection of
                        the thousand kindnesses shown me by all.</p>
                    <p>May the Lord, in his tender mercies, bless all, old and young, composing the
                        entire community, is and shall ever be, my sincere prayer. HENRY DICKINSON,</p>
                    <p>Pastor First Baptist Church, Staunton.</p>
                    <p>P.S. -- Will the other papers here please copy? H.D.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The minister of the First Baptist Church, Henry Dickinson, will soon leave
                    Augusta. He wrote to express his sincere regret at having to leave, and praised
                    the white and colored citizens of the county for their kindness and charity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.03.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Complimentary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting was held at the Greenbrier White Sulphur Springs on last Tuesday,
                        composed principally of Southerners, at which a series of resolutions were
                        unanimously adopted expressing the gratitude of the southern people to
                        George Peabody for his munificent gift of $8,000,000 to the cause of
                        education.</p>
                    <p>In the hotel parlors, on the evening of the 28th, eight hundred persons, half
                        of them ladies, assembled to witness the presentation to George Peabody of
                        the resolutions adopted at the meeting yesterday. The resolutions were
                        presented by Jas. Lyons, Esq., in an eloquent speech. Mr. Peabody, in
                        response, alluded in a touching manner to the condition of the Southern
                        people, and spoke cheerfully and hopefully of coming and brighter days of
                        prosperity for the whole South. He said, incidentally, that though the
                        education fund was yet in its infancy, it had accomplished much good.</p>
                    <p>A grand ball will be given on the 11th of August in honor of Mr. Peabody.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reported that a meeting was held to present a series of resolutions
                    expressing the gratitude of the southern people to George Peabody for his gift
                    of $8,000,000 to the cause of education.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The colored laborers' convention passed resolutions affirming that the
                        objections of white men to working with negroes must be overcome, calling a
                        national negro convention to meet in December next, and invoking Congress to
                        drive Chinese labor out of the country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brief report on the activities of the Colored Laborer's Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Petersburg <emph rend="italic">Index</emph> asks, "why can we not have
                        peace. Why stand the test-oath, and the schemes of greedy office-seekers,
                        and the malice of disappointed candidates, and the partisan "influence of
                        extremists," between Virginia and the Union.</p>
                    <p>Has she not done all that has been asked? -- Complied with the strictest
                        letter of the law? Confirmed to the negro his right of suffrage? Accepted an
                        exaggerated construction of the Reconstruction Acts? Elected a Northern man,
                        and known loyalist, to the Executive chair of the State? Chosen a
                        Legislature not one of whom is open to objection under the Federal or the
                        State Constitution?</p>
                    <p>What more can be asked? If anything else is needed why not have specified it
                        before the election? We have done all, and more than was required. Now we
                        appeal to the President, to the Congress, to the People -- for the sake of
                        justice, of honesty, of humanity, of common prosperity -- for God's sake,
                        "LET US HAVE PEACE."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Index asked why Virginia cannot be admitted into the Union,
                    and appealed to the Federal Government to respect Virginia's good-faith efforts
                    to do everything required of her.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper argued that Virginia will be re-admitted to the Union "if right,
                    justice, and law are to prevail." The paper doubted whether that would happen,
                    given the state of the leadership of the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.03.03" exists="no">
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garland</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James R. Garland and Mrs. Barbara Vines, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Staunton on August 1st by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leckey</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. Leckey and Miss Maggie A. Dudley, daughter of R. H. Dudley, were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father on July 27th by the Rev. J.
                    Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Martha S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>R. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas F. Hall and Miss Martha S. Berry, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Craigsville on July 28th by the Rev. R. P. Kennedy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie V. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Venable</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Carrie V. D. Coleman, wife of Thomas E. Coleman, died at the Staunton
                    residence of Mrs. Venable on July 25th. She was 29 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridgway</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridgway</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ridgway</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stephen V. Ridgway, infant son of R. S. and M. L. Ridgway, died in Staunton
                    on July 18th. He was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Bettie Eidson, daughter of Henry Eidson, died in Baltimore on March
                    19th. "For more than four years a fatal malady had been slowly wasting away her
                    strength, and drying up, one by one, the springs of life; yet her sick chamber
                    was privileged beyond the common walks of life. With a heart made of tenderness
                    and with patient, cheerful, winning ways, she ever made her room the centre of
                    attraction for the household."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.03.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
