<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.11.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-11-30">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.30.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Good News!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper celebrated the ratification by the stockholders of a contract
                    ensuring construction of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad to the Ohio River. The
                    editor thanked Col. John B. Baldwin for his efforts in securing the contract.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Now that a contract has been entered into with Northern capitalists, which
                        secures the speedy completion of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, the
                        interest felt in improvements by our citizens will be concentrated upon the
                        Valley Railroad.</p>
                    <p>They will be pleased to learn, as stated by the Baltimore <emph rend="italic"
                            >Gazette</emph>, that, as the time approaches when an act, authorizing
                        the subscription by the city of Baltimore of the sum of one million of
                        dollars to the stock of the Valley Railroad company, is to be obtained from
                        the Maryland Legislature and to be submitted to the voters of Baltimore, the
                        feeling in favor of the completion of the road, and the conviction of the
                        necessity of its construction, are daily becoming stronger among those, at
                        least, who interest themselves in such matters and who have the welfare of
                        Baltimore really at heart. The continued developments of the wealth of
                        Virginia, which will become, by the construction of this road, a tributary
                        to Baltimore city, are simply astounding to those who have given no
                        attention to the subject. We do not allude to the rich agricultural produce
                        of a splendid and fertile region, which, if itself, yearly increasing,
                        demands an iron road, and would soon supply local trade and traffic
                        sufficient to support it; but to the vast mineral resources which have
                        remained so long almost untouched, simply from want of modern facilities of
                        communication. The extension of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad from
                        Staunton to the White Sulphur Springs has, however, finally attracted
                        attention to the immense deposits of valuable iron ore which exist between
                        the Blue Ridge and the Alleghany Mountains. new York and Pennsylvania and
                        Maryland capital has been invested near the line of the present road to a
                        large amount. Mineral property in Augusta, Rockbridge, and Allegheny
                        counties, has been purchased to a large extent, and within the past four
                        weeks we hear of additional transfers of real estate to Pennsylvania
                        masters.</p>
                    <p>From Staunton to the White Sulphur Springs there are, at intervals, splendid
                        deposits of ore, stretching away far to the north and the south of the lines
                        of the Chesapeake and Ohio Road. Indeed, it seems now to be an acknowledged
                        fact that there is a belt of land, lying along the Alleghany range,
                        extending 350 miles through Virginia, which is filled with iron ore deposits
                        of unusually good quality. It is directly through the heart of this region
                        that the proposed Valley Road will pass from Staunton to Salem. This of
                        itself would give an immense value to the road, would make it particularly
                        important to the State of Virginia and render it an unusually valuable
                        connection for the city of Baltimore. But recent developments have
                        demonstrated that this region is not only abundantly supplied with iron ore,
                        but that vast veins of anthracite coal also lie embedded in the earth,
                        beneath its surface. Explanations recently made by a Baltimore company,
                        which has bought largely and is actively at work near Buffalo Gap, have
                        resulted in the discovery of anthracite coal within a few rods of the
                        deposits of iron ore. On the opposite hill is a large quarry of limestone,
                        suitable for flux. So far, no such formation has been discovered in the
                        country, and if the veins of coal turn out as well as it is now confidently
                        anticipated they will, the Valley of Virginia will possess a region destined
                        to become more famous than the famous Gartsherrie district of Scotland, and
                        in which better iron will be produced for less money, and in larger
                        quantities than in any other civilized country in the world.</p>
                    <p>The development of mineral wealth in Virginia and West Virginia have, we
                        learn, virtually ensured the speedy completion of the Chesapeake and Ohio
                        Railroad through the Kanawha Valley to the Ohio river, and through the most
                        extensive deposits of cannel and bitumous coal that are known to exist. When
                        the Valley Road is opened to Salem, and the Chesapeake and Ohio Road is
                        completed to Ohio, the vast mineral resources of Virginia, the coal and
                        iron, which form by themselves two great and important elements in a State's
                        wealth, will begin to be developed. These two roads will be main stems, to
                        which hundreds of lateral roads will transfer the products of mines and
                        furnaces, for the accommodation of which they will be built. Coal and iron
                        will be the great substratum of Virginia's prosperity, and a great State,
                        which has always prided itself on its agricultural power, will become rich
                        and strong by the development of its mineral and manufacturing interests.
                        The days may yet return when pig metal, or more probably rolled iron, will
                        be shipped from the James river to the markets of Great Britain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Gazette described how the citizens of Baltimore were likely
                    to vote in favor of a subscription to the Valley Railroad Company. The Spectator
                    also reported that coal and iron deposits have been found along the line of the
                    Railroad; these deposits will further enhance the value of the Road and Virginia
                    as a whole.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Radical State Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phelps</ln>
                        <fn>E. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roselle</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herr</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Republican Party of Virginia held their state convention in Richmond. A
                    delegation from Augusta attended and denounced the current state legislature as
                    illegal and disloyal. They asked Congress to order a new vote on the
                    constitution and warned the legislature against passing educational and property
                    qualifications that would keep blacks from voting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A Mission (Retreat) will begin at St. Francis Church on December 5th. It
                    will last several days and be conducted by the Redemptorist Fathers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Concert at Mt. Vernon Iron Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Some ladies in the vicinity of Weyer's Cave inaugurated a series of
                    entertainments for the eastern portion of the county. These entertainments
                    include Tableaux, readings, and a concert to be held on December 8th in the hall
                    at Mt. Vernon Iron Works. The Staunton Musical Association will perform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Committee of Virginians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A number of conservative members of the Virginia State Legislature have
                    been appointed to petition Congress to re-admit the state. A. B. Cochran of
                    Augusta was part of the delegation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McAllister</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>James R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William M. McAllister of Warm Springs and Miss Maggie A. Ervin, daughter of
                    James R. Ervin, were married in Bath County on October 27th by the Rev. James M.
                    Rice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warren</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. Warren of Hot Springs and Miss Jennie A. Hopkins were married in Bath
                    County on October 27th by the Rev. James M. Rice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordan</ln>
                        <fn>Mitchell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hultz</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryland</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mitchell Gordan of Bath and Miss Ellen Hultz of Augusta were married near
                    Deerfield on November 11th by the Rev. J. W. Ryland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Sue E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marvin</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John W. Merritt of Staunton and Miss Sue E. Green of St. Louis, daughter of
                    James S. Green, were married at the residence of the bride's father on November
                    4th by the Rev. Bishop E. M. Marvin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Wingfield S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoutamoyer</ln>
                        <fn>Dorothy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoutamoyer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Wingfield S. Graham and Miss Dorothy Stoutamoyer, daughter of John
                    Stoutamoyer, were married at the residence of the bride's father near Mt. Solon
                    on November 18th by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thornton</ln>
                        <fn>Obediah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tridley</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obediah Thornton and Miss Hannah M. Tridley, both of Augusta, were married
                    at Buffalo Gap on November 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Cornelius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cornelius Koiner and Miss Mary Susan Koiner, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Waynesboro on November 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Phebe Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Junkin</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel N. Willson of Rockbridge and Miss Phebe Jane Thompson, daughter of
                    Charles S. Thompson, were married at the residence of the bride's father in
                    Glennevis, Augusta County, on November 23rd by the Rev. E. D. Junkin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlow</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Horn</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Franklin Harlow of Staunton and Miss Mary C. Cross of Augusta were married
                    at Lebanon, White Sulphur Springs, on November 25th by the Rev. J. R. Van Horn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Kate N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. G. Peyton and Miss Kate N. Woodward, daughter of J. N. and A. J.
                    Woodward, were married at Willow Spout on November 24th by the Rev. J. C. Wheat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James M. Crawford and Miss Mary M. Miller, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Mt. Sidney on November 24th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Colored</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cabbell</ln>
                        <fn>George L. Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>Rosalie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George L. Alex Cabbell and Rosalie Adams, both of Staunton, were married at
                    the residence of Miss Sallie Fuller by the Rev. Mr. Lewis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamner</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jesse B. Hamner died near Horeb Church, Augusta County, on November 21st.
                    He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.11.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
