<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.03.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/06/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-16">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.16.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Address of Andrew Johnson, to the People of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints Andrew Johnson's Farewell Address in full. He calls
                    attention to his accomplishments as president and commander-in-chief, and
                    deplores the subjugation of the southern states at the hands of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Radical Convention at Petersburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We devote a great part of our space this week to the proceedings of the
                        Radical Convention, composed of "black spirits and white," which assembled
                        in Petersburg on Tuesday the 9th inst., to nominate a State ticket. It will
                        be observed that they nominated for the office of Lieut. Governor a <emph
                            rend="italic">mulatto</emph> by the name of Harris, thus showing whither
                        that party is rapidly drifting. The proceedings, as might have been expected
                        from the character of those who composed it, were of the most disgraceful
                        character, and presented a scene unprecedented in the history of this State.</p>
                    <p>The negroes, it is due them to say, behaved better than the whites who sat
                        side by side with them, mingled together like black and white pigs in a
                        litter. This simile we are aware is not just to the pigs. It is not at all
                        surprising that the negroes should behave better than their white allies,
                        for the former are governed by some principle -- the latter by the want of
                        it. The whites in the Convention cared not a fig about the negro, but wished
                        to appropriate the spoils of office, and use the negro as the monkey did the
                        cat.</p>
                    <p>The proceedings, as they really occurred, are indescribable -- they beggar
                        description. They pulled and hauled each other, and behaved so badly that
                        the Mayor of the city -- himself a Radical -- by the aid of his strong
                        police force, dispersed the Convention, driving it out of the church, even
                        before it was organized by the election of a temporary chairman.</p>
                    <p>The scene presented by forty-thousand tom-cats tied by the tails to each
                        other in a garret, spitting, spluttering, cater-wauling, scratching, biting,
                        making the fur fly like a thousand twanging bows in a hatter-shop, would be
                        peaceful and harmonious as compared with that enacted in this Convention.</p>
                    <p>Wells, the so-called Governor of Virginia, was there working for himself like
                        a beaver. -- "For the first time in the history of Virginia politics," says
                        the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, "a man occupying the
                        gubernatorial chair, and a candidate, we not say for re-election, but for
                        continuance therein, was present, advocating his own cause, and actually
                        inciting to the disgraceful scenes that compelled the civil authorities to
                        intervene and disperse, the ruffians! -- We repeat it: no such disgraceful
                        scene was ever witnessed in Virginia until now. Yet, when we consider what
                        hands our politics have fallen into, it is not surprising. A set of Bowery
                        boys, Five Pointers, Plug Uglies and Wooden-Nutmeg Yankees -- all
                        adventurers -- united with negroes and scalawags, have taken it upon
                        themselves to "run the machine" in this State. It is no wonder, therefore,
                        that they cut "fantastic tricks" and enact the <emph rend="italic"
                        >role</emph> of the bull in the china shop. But it is astonishing that any
                        Virginian, respectably connected, will so far compromise himself and
                        friends, as to identify himself with such a set! We are utterly amazed, and
                        can only hope that if any gentlemanly instincts are left to them, they will
                        be so deeply disgusted with the acts of the Zebra Convention, that they will
                        shrink from any further connection with such a disreputable party."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors report on the Radical Convention, painting a scene of
                    tremendous chaos. According to the Spectator, the police, under orders from a
                    Radical mayor, were forced to break up the unruly Convention. Also claims that
                    the whites were only there to get themselves elected to office and did not care
                    for the blacks at all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>How the "White Trash" Treat the Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Time and again we have warned the negroes that those white men who have been
                        professing to be their special friends, and who have participated in their
                        meetings and talked glibly of political equality regardless of "race, color
                        or previous condition of servitude," have been using them as the monkey did
                        the cat, when he pulled the roasted chestnuts from the hot embers with the
                        cat's paw. They will learn after awhile that we have been telling them the
                        simple truth. The action of this class of whites at this time ought to be
                        sufficient to convince the most stolid negro. The negroes constitute
                        nine-tenths of the Radical party of this State, and if the white Radicals
                        were disposed to treat them fairly and justly they would be willing to allow
                        the negroes to hold that proportion of the offices at the disposal of their
                        party. But instead of this, they meet in Convention where four candidates
                        for office are to be nominated, and they nominate three white men and one
                        mulatto, instead of nominating three negroes and one white man, and then
                        because this mulatto, though only half negro, and though educated, receives
                        the nomination for one of the four offices, the white Radicals turn up their
                        noses in disgust, secede from the Convention, repudiate its nominations, and
                        issue a call for another Convention.</p>
                    <p>It will be observed that the Radical State ticket is just as it was before
                        except that for the office of Lieut-Governor the name of Dr. Harris
                        (mulatto) has been substituted for that of Clements who labored in vain to
                        get up a step higher on the ticket and to occupy Wells's shoes. These white
                        Radicals say that Harris will cause the defeat of the ticket, and to save
                            <emph rend="italic">their party</emph>, they will nominate another
                        ticket of more "respectable Republicans," hoping that the Conservatives will
                        assist them to elect it. The Conservatives, however, who constitute
                        nineteen-twentieths of the white voters of the State, have an excellent
                        ticket of their own.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the Spectator, the Radicals, who are dependent on the votes of
                    freedmen, betray them by seeking to run a ticket consisting solely of white men.
                    They hope that this will earn them the votes of Conservatives, but are mistaken
                    in this hope.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. W. T. Graham of Greenville, Augusta County, and Miss Lizzie J. Graham of
                    Missouri were married in Missouri on March 4th by the Rev. Mr. Pearson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Lyttleton</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lyttleton Waddell, Sr., died in Augusta County at the house of his son, L.
                    Waddell, Jr., on March 12th. He was 79 years old. A mourner calls for a
                    community tribute to Waddell as well as to the late Mrs. M'Clung. "There were no
                    two persons more generally known, more highly respected, or more sincerely
                    beloved by our people, than these bright and shining examples of all that is
                    lovely and of good report in the character of the Christian gentlemen and
                    gentlewomen of Virginia."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth McClung died in Staunton of pneumonia. She was 86 years old.
                    "She was a remarkable woman."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Betsy Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Betsy Ann Kinney, wife of Chesley Kinney, died on March 3rd at
                    Stribling Springs, Augusta County. She was 48 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubank</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Eubank died on March 10th at the Staunton residence of John
                    B. Hoge. She was 76 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Cochran died on February 15th at his residence near Greenville,
                    Augusta County. He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Almira</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Almira Wheat, daughter of the Rev. J. C. Wheat, died in Staunton
                    on March 12th. She was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craver</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Sarah Craver died at Barterbrook on February 28th. She was 63 years
                    old and a member of Hebron Presbyterian Church. She "died as a christian."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Turk died at Long Meadows on March 2nd. She was 61 years old
                    and a member of Tinkling Spring Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Rebecca Bush died near Waynesboro on March 5th. She was 81 years old
                    and was a member of Tinkling Spring Church. She "died in the hope of a glorious
                    resurrection."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
