<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.07.20">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-07-20">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">20</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.20.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.20.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Be Careful</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Both white and colored men must be cautious, says the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Petersburg Index</emph>, not to make any mistakes now in this the
                        supreme crisis of their histories. White people, do not neglect the
                        opportunity to win from error and ignorance the inevitable sharers of your
                        destinies; Colored men, do not fail to embrace the chance of peace offered
                        by the more powerful race.</p>
                    <p>Toe the mark, fellow-citizens, you of all colors and denominations, and do it
                        now! Conservatism of education and property is not always to be bullied and
                        harassed with impunity; neither can that conservatism, whose interest is
                        always peace, afford to court a conflict. There is a mutual welfare
                        involved, a mutual profit to be evolved. A house divided against itself
                        cannot stand. One branch of the family must surrender. Which shall it be?
                        The strongest protest against a contest. Colored people, you are the
                        weakest; will you, when we ask for friendship, throw down the gage of
                        battle?</p>
                    <p>For God's sake, not. That is what your enemy, the carpet-bagger, would have
                        you do.--That is what we, politically supreme now in Virginia, and anxious
                        to forward your moral and mental growth, beseech you not to undertake. Have
                        regard for yourselves in the view of policy as well as of duty. Be freemen
                        in fact as well as in name. Discard the despotism of faction, be ruled only
                        by conscience, and that instinct of self-preservation which is the best as
                        well as the first law of nature.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor called on both whites and blacks to denounce the carpet-baggers
                    and stand united. He also encouraged blacks not to start a race conflict, for
                    they would surely lose such a contest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sixth Congressional District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>MILNES, Con.</cell>
                            <cell>HARRIS, Ind.</cell>
                            <cell>PHELPS, Rad.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Frederick</cell>
                            <cell>1563</cell>
                            <cell>14</cell>
                            <cell>869</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Clarke</cell>
                            <cell>699</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Warren</cell>
                            <cell>368</cell>
                            <cell>296</cell>
                            <cell>134</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Page</cell>
                            <cell>749</cell>
                            <cell>313</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Shenandoah</cell>
                            <cell>478</cell>
                            <cell>1,186</cell>
                            <cell>227</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rockingham</cell>
                            <cell>1,937</cell>
                            <cell>822</cell>
                            <cell>403</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Augusta</cell>
                            <cell>3,469</cell>
                            <cell>962</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Highland</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                            <cell>413</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bath</cell>
                            <cell>357</cell>
                            <cell>92</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Botetourt</cell>
                            <cell>664</cell>
                            <cell>917</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alleghany</cell>
                            <cell>304</cell>
                            <cell>202</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rockbridge</cell>
                            <cell>1,320</cell>
                            <cell>1,633</cell>
                            <cell>56</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>12045</cell>
                            <cell>6853</cell>
                            <cell>1689</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>6853</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>5192</cell>
                            <cell>Milnes majority over Harris</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>In Shenandoah Conrad received 119 votes, Gray 4.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Listed returns for congressional elections in the Sixth District, with the
                    Conservative candidate coming out on top.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We desire, says the <emph rend="italic">Lynchburg Intelligencer</emph>, to
                        caution our people on one point. If they think the work of reconstruction is
                        all done, and that we have nothing to do but to exult over the result of the
                        election, they are very much mistaken. What we have done has got to pass the
                        ordeal of President Grant and of Congress, and powerful influences will be
                        brought to bear against us. First, the written opinion of Gen. Canby in
                        regard to the ineligibility of members of the Legislature is an obstacle to
                        be overcome, and is now engaging the attention of the President and his
                        Cabinet.--Secondly, if that is decided in our favor, then we have to await
                        the full endorsement and ratification of Congress with a strong Republican
                        majority against us. It becomes the solemn duty of our people, therefore, to
                        so deport themselves in the future as to favorably impress the President and
                        Congress with our loyalty and sincerity, and to compel them by the force of
                        public sentiment, North and South, to respect and confirm what we have done
                        toward reconstruction. We must cease to be governed in speech or in action
                        by the false glare of passion or prejudice--we must let the dead bury its
                        dead, while we take care of the living. We must not crow until we are out of
                        the woods, and we must cease to cry over spilt milk.--There are some
                        indiscreet men in all parties, and there are many in ours; but they must be
                        muzzled at once and kept muzzled. Any other course of action than we have
                        thus indicated will lead us into new dangers and troubles.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pleaded with Virginians not to celebrate prematurely until their
                    constitution and elected officials are accepted by Grant and Congress, which was
                    far from certain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carter</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corron</ln>
                        <fn>J. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. Carter, clerk of the First African Baptist Church, Staunton,
                    extends thanks on behalf of the congregation to J. P. Corron of the American
                    Baptist Home Mission Society for his visit to view the condition of the church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Election for Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Election results for Virginia Governor. Augusta gave 3,751 votes to Walker
                    and 1,171 to Wells. The state as a whole voted 115,109 for Walker and 96,446 for
                    Wells.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.20.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rippetoe</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. J. L. Rippetoe will preach at New Hope on July 25th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. P. Fletcher, with assistance from his daughter Miss Nannie
                    Fletcher, will open a school for girls and young ladies at his residence near
                    Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. A. F. Burke, wife of William A. Burke, died in Staunton on July 17th.
                    She was 32 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. William Ide, father of Prof. E. Louis Ide, died in Richmond. He was 60
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Hanger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Jewett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Hanger Henkel, infant son of Jewett and Virginia Henkel, died near
                    Mt. Crawford on July 6th. He was 10 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.07.20.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
