<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.08.31">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/08/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-08-31">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">31</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.31.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.31.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Preview of the Augusta County Fair. The town council appropriated $500 and
                    the County Court $1000 for widening, grading, and macadamizing the road to the
                    Fair Grounds. The trotting course has been improved and a rotunda for
                    exhibitions constructed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>"The New Constitution"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under the head of "General Canby and General Drought," the Baltimore <emph
                            rend="italic">Sun</emph> of the 26th, inst., says that "many of the
                        speculations upon the probable turn of political affairs in Virginia go upon
                        the exploded theory that the people of the State have an indefeasible right
                        to choose their own form of government. This is a fundamental mistake.
                        General Canby is the only constitution of Virginia. Canby is its organic
                        law. Canby exercises supreme power as a right. Canby is the depository of
                        all authority, and there is no provision inherent in him for his own
                        amendment. If Canby could be submitted to the people for adoption, rejection
                        or modification, we should like to see the result. The voice of Canby is the
                        supreme law in the Old Dominion. Canby is not restrained by precedents; in a
                        military despotism there can be no law or precedent. Canby creates a
                        precedent or destroys one, as circumstances require. Canby appoints his
                        agents and representatives, none of whom are held to a strict account for
                        their action. Canby is the Legislature, the Judiciary, and the Executive. In
                        this way Canby provides for the common defence, promotes the general
                        welfare, and secures the blessings of domestic tranquility. No one denies
                        that he is a source of political power, that government was constituted for
                        his good, and that his acts are above all judgment or review. There is
                        neither failure nor disappointment in the government of Canby. He is the
                        Resolution of '98 and '99 and the Alien and Sedition Law in one person. He
                        is the Bill of Rights, the Revised Code, the Statutes at Large, the <emph
                            rend="italic">Lex Scripta</emph>, the <emph rend="italic">Lex non
                            Scripta</emph>, the Court of Appeals, the Circuit Court, the Superior
                        Court, the County Court, the Common Council, the Justices of the Peace, the
                        Policemen and Constables, the Overseer of the Poor, and Superintendent of
                        the Penitentiary. There never was as cheap and efficient an organization as
                        Canby. The people of Virginia were put to no expense in the formation of
                        that constitution. The band of iron which holds them in their fixed
                        position, the inflexible instrument which places a limit upon thought,
                        speech, voting, progress, and improvement in district No. 1, which exhausts
                        its people of all their nervous energy and hope, was not of their own
                        fabricating, and has cost them nothing except their political and civil
                        franchises, which, in this era of civilization, have been made so common
                        elsewhere as to be supposed to have little appreciable value.</p>
                    <p>It is natural that the Constitution Canby, absordent of all other things,
                        should absorb the whole attention of the people of Virginia. Not until
                        lately has a rival arisen to dispute his place in their regards. This
                        competitor is the terrific dry spell, which is making the physical condition
                        of Virginia a type of her prostration as a State. General Drought is fast
                        throwing General Canby into shade. Political considerations are subjected to
                        the subject of breadstuffs. After all, the physical constitution is more
                        important than the political. Men often owe to nature the blessings which
                        they attribute to a system of government. Where harvests are plentiful,
                        wages good, and material prosperity prevails, men can tolerate almost any
                        form of authority. But when the earth fails to yield her increase, even
                        military rulers cease to be objects of interest. Let us hope that refreshing
                        rains will yet revivify the parched vegetation, and that kindlier impulses
                        on the part of the government will permit some political vegetation to
                        germinate and sprout in Virginia, if only to give a picturesque variety to
                        the grim and solitary structure of the Canby constitution."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Baltimore Sun mocked the Government of General Canby, describing it as
                    an authoritarian and uncompromising government. Also claimed that the drought
                    was competing with Canby for the people's attention, and hoped for both rain and
                    reform in government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Front Royal Outrage--Lynch Law</head>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Front Royal were thought to have lynched two black men
                    accused of assaulting a white woman. A party of men in disguises broke into the
                    jail and removed the two prisoners. They have not been heard of since.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.31.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We mentioned last week the sad occurrence of the killing of Jacob Scherer,
                        and that Jno. M. Stanley had been committed to jail charged with being the
                        person who fired the fatal shot. On Tuesday and Wednesday last, he had his
                        call trial before Justices Pierce, Anderson and Clinedinst. Col. Baldwin and
                        Geo. M. Cochran jr., acting as counsel for the prisoner and Capt. Jas.
                        Bumgardner, jr., and Judge H. W. Sheffey representing the Commonwealth. The
                        witnesses were examined on Tuesday, and the case was ably argued on both
                        sides on Wednesday. He was sent on for trial. No application for bail was
                        made.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanley</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Stanley appeared before the town justices for the killing of Jacob
                    Scherer. The justices decided the case would go to trial. George M. Cochran is
                    defending the prisoner and Capt. James Bumgardner and Judge H. W. Sheffey
                    represent the commonwealth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Philanthropy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Southern Methodist congregation, of this place, are still subjected to
                        the inconvenience of being deprived of their place of worship on every
                        alternate sunday in obedience to the military command which gives their
                        church to the Northern church on every other Sabbath. The Southern
                        congregation--Rev. Geo. Kramer, Pastor--is a large and respectable body of
                        good citizens, while that which attends upon the ministrations of Mr.
                        Forsythe, the preacher appointed by the Northern Conference, numbers about
                        half a dozen. Is it not a shame and a disgrace, not to say ridiculous, that
                        a large congregation, many of whom contributed largely to the erection of
                        the church edifice, should be deprived of their place of worship in order to
                        accommodate such a small handful. They seem determined, however, to act out,
                        most fully, the "dog in the manger" policy. <emph rend="italic">O tempora! O
                            mores!</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complained about the military order requiring the Northern and Southern
                    Methodist congregations to share the same church for their services. Pointed out
                    how the Northern church had such a small membership and so the Southern
                    congregation should have the building exclusively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>David T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David T. Sheets and Miss Sarah C. Huff, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 10th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Newton A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Eugene A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Newton A. Fry and Miss Eugene A. Brown, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Waynesboro on August 16th by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Bush and Miss Martha Terrell, both of Augusta, were married on
                    August 19th in Waynesboro by the Rev. W. T. Richardson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckise</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Schreckise died at the residence of Mr. Thomas Crawford on North River
                    on the 13th. He was 72.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company published a tribute of respect upon the death of
                    their comrade, Jacob Scherer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.08.31.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
