<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.04.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-04-13">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">13</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.04.13.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.04.13.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Vote on the Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It will be observed by the bill, published in another column, which was
                        passed on Friday last, that the President is authorized to submit, at such
                        time as he may deem proper, the Underwood Constitution to the vote of such
                        as will be registered voters at the time of the election, and to submit to a
                        separate vote such provisions of the Constitution as he may deem proper. So
                        it is now settled that we will have an election upon the ratification or
                        rejection of that instrument, with a vote at the same time upon striking out
                        some of the more objectionable features.</p>
                    <p>At the same time, elections will be held for members of Congress, members of
                        the State Legislature, and all officers of the State, provided for by that
                        Constitution.</p>
                    <p>All who vote on the question of ratification or rejection of the
                        Constitution, whether they vote affirmatively or negatively, should vote in
                        favor of striking out such clauses as may be submitted to a separate vote.
                        There will be three classes of voters:</p>
                    <p>1st. Those who will vote for ratification and for striking out the provisions
                        submitted to a separate vote.</p>
                    <p>2nd. Those who will vote against ratification and in favor of striking out
                        the clauses submitted to a separate vote.</p>
                    <p>3rd. Those who will vote for ratification and against striking out the
                        clauses submitted to a separate vote.</p>
                    <p>There is no apology for any one, white or black, who will vote with this
                        third class.</p>
                    <p>All those who are opposed to Wells and the unmodified Underwood Constitution
                        should be united in the support of a single State ticket, otherwise Wells
                        will probably be elected. -- There should be united action, if possible, on
                        the part of all those who are opposed to the ratification of the unmodified
                        Underwood monstrosity. Those who will vote for Wells and the Underwood
                        Constitution unchanged should be <emph rend="italic">anathema
                        maranatha.</emph> They will deserve to be ostracized and should be.</p>
                    <p>The time when the elections will take place, and the designation of the
                        clauses of the Constitution to be voted upon separately, remains to be
                        announced by the President.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator announces that the President can now submit a new state
                    Constitution to the people of Virginia. Also lists the separate categories of
                    voters on the question of ratification and asks Virginians to vote, at minimum,
                    against certain features of the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports the Enquirer and Examiner's opinion that if
                    African-Americans receive suffrage rights, whites will be driven from the South
                    and make the region a "Hayti" or "Santo Domingo." The only hope is to encourage
                    white migration to the region.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>B. F. Butler's Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A few weeks since, it was announced, says the Baltimore <emph rend="italic"
                            >Gazette</emph>, that Mr. Butler intended to make an effort to
                        conciliate the people he had so often outraged and plundered. He was about,
                        it was said, to bring a bill into Congress to relieve the ex-Confederates of
                        their political disabilities. It was to be just and generous in its terms,
                        and of general application. But people who expected kindness from Butler
                        forgot the truth of the old maxim that "men always hate those whom "they
                        have injured," and that the intensity of their malignity is in proportion to
                        the wrongs they have inflicted, or the crimes they have perpetrated. The
                        instincts of Butler are essentially devilish, and any act of betraying even
                        a gleam of nobility of soul would be as foreign to his nature as tenderness
                        was to that of Barabbas.</p>
                    <p>His bill for the restoration of the disfranchised Southern people to their
                        political rights and privileges is characteristic of the man. Under the
                        provisions of the bill, every Southerner, who seeks relief from his
                        political disabilities, must first prefer a petition to that end before the
                        District Court of the United States in the State where he lived during the
                        war. He must confess, to the minutest particular, "in what manner he had
                        given aid, "comfort, or assistance to the rebellion, either "voluntary or
                        involuntary."</p>
                    <p>He must further declare "that he "believes, and confesses, such acts were
                        wrongs, rebellious and wicked," and that the State, and Confederate
                        Governments, established by, and during the rebellion "were, in his belief,"
                        treasonable, and "ought not to have been sustained," and, finally, he must
                        say "that he truly repents of all "acts done in maintenance thereof, and
                        heartily desires to atone for any part he took in the same, by hereafter
                        acting and conducting himself as a true and loyal citizen of the United
                        States."</p>
                    <p>But the measure of self-degradation does not end here. The applicant has next
                        to affirm that his loyalty has been perfect and immaculate, since the 1st of
                        June, 1865; that subsequent to that date he has done no hostile act, or
                        committed any crime against the laws of the United States, or of any
                        individual State; "that he has not endeavored, by force or fraud, to
                        interfere with the civil rights of any citizen of the United States," or to
                        prevent the freedom of election or of speech; but that "he has behaved
                        himself as a man of good moral character," &amp;c., &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Having thus abjectly humbled himself with his face to the ground, and his
                        mouth in the dust, he has then to undergo another ordeal. -- His petition,
                        setting forth all these things, is to be published in a newspaper, so that
                        his utter ignominy may be made known to all his former friends and
                        acquaintances. When this penitential act has been accomplished, the next
                        thing required of him is that he shall get two Union men to stand his
                        sponsors, and who shall declare "that they verily believe each and every
                        fact stated in the petition to be true." But the process of purgation is not
                        yet complete. After all these steps have been taken, any citizen, whether
                        black or white, may appear on the day appointed for the return of the
                        notice, and if he object "that anything set forth in said petition is not
                        true in fact, thereupon an issue shall be framed by the Court," and the case
                        set for trial.</p>
                    <p>Such is the bill brought forward by this man Butler, ostensibly for the
                        purpose of relieving from their political disabilities large numbers of
                        Southerners who are now disfranchised. Its true title should be "a bill to
                        render the Southern people infamous forever."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on B. F. Butler's bill, which allows Southerners to regain their
                    political rights after swearing to certain facts. The Spectator outlines how the
                    wording of the bill will actually leave the mass of Southerners without any
                    political rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Politics, says the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph>, are in a
                        great muddle in this State. We have a <emph rend="italic">sans
                        culottes</emph> Radical party, composed of Wells, the carpet-baggers, and
                        their sable allies; a "respectable" Republican party, inspired by Mr.
                        Walker, the spirit of Rye, and "two dollars a day with roast beef"; and a
                        Conservative party so-called, that can hardly be considered a political
                        party, since it ignores office and looks only to the honor and welfare of
                        the State. For the first time in the history of parties in this State, one,
                        and perhaps the larger of the three, is not "held together by the cohesive
                        power of the public plunder." Its members do not ask for office; they only
                        want to see the Government administered upon just and honorable principles,
                        and with a view to the common welfare. They are prepared to take the
                        self-denying ordinance if need be; and certainly their conduct is not such
                        as to justify the imputation that they are influenced by considerations of
                        self-interest. If they regarded office as the supreme good, their action
                        would be such as to commend them to those who dispense patronage and control
                        the offices. Hence, we say, that the men who are numbered with this
                        Conservative organization can hardly be considered identified with any
                        political party. They are not Whigs; they are not Democrats; they are not
                        Republicans, in a party sense. They are simply Virginia patriots,
                        determined, as far as in them lies, to prevent the permanent ascendancy, in
                        this State, of a party that regards not the Constitution of law, integrity,
                        or truth, justice or virtue, when those conflict with their party
                        shibboleth, or stand in the way of preferment, or interpose obstacles to the
                        consummation of their nefarious purposes.</p>
                    <p>But what is to be the issue of these complications? That is the question.
                        Third parties, as a general thing, do not accomplish much; and it is the
                        fate of the weaker, frequently, to be absorbed by the stronger. It is
                        obvious that the "respectable" Republican party in Virginia can accomplish
                        nothing without the aid of the Conservatives. Theirs is a forlorn hope, so
                        long as the Wells party can control the negro vote and is backed by the
                        Federal Government, as it now seems to be. Their chance of success consists
                        in making such overtures to the Conservatives as will insure, if that were
                        possible, an alliance against the common foe. As we have said already, the
                        Conservatives are looking chiefly to the interest and honor of this State,
                        and regard these as vastly more important than the success of any political
                        tricksters. They will not yield their conventions on this subject at the
                        behest of any political party. What they might be willing to concede on the
                        score of policy, to insure the ultimate triumph of great principles, we are
                        not prepared, at this time, to indicate. There will be time enough for
                        negotiations of this character, while events shall be moulding themselves
                        into such a shape as will enable all to apprehend more clearly the
                        contingencies of the future. But, for ourselves, we may say that we desire
                        to see a union of all the Conservative elements of the State, whether they
                        stand now committed to Withers or Walker, in order to defeat the ends of
                        Radicalism, and the Underwood Constitution, as it is now presented to us.
                        And, surely, men who love their State, and regard the interests of her
                        people more than they do the interests of a party, may be able to find some
                        ground of compromise where-on they can stand together, and co-operate in the
                        work of defeating the most proscriptive, intolerant, and venal political
                        organization that ever existed in this country. This is a work that should
                        fire the heart and tax the energy of every man worthy of the name of
                        Virginian or patriot.</p>
                    <p>P.S. -- It would seem now that the Wells party is not backed by the
                        President, though the reinstatement of Wells certainly had that
                    appearance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the political situation in Virginia. The Conservatives are a
                    third party, but are nonetheless poised to make a powerful impact on the
                    policies of the Republicans and the Radicals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.04.13.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>Erasmus L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Erasmus L. Houff has qualified for Commissioner of the Revenue for
                    Staunton's 2nd District. He replaces John G. Stover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The citizens of Staunton will meet at the Court House on Tuesday to appoint
                    delegates to go to Baltimore to lobby for funds for the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Council, No. 47, Friends of Temperance, will hold a public
                    meeting with speeches and a procession. The Institution Band will perform.
                    Members are requested to wear regalia of the order.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burdett</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoneburner</ln>
                        <fn>C. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pemberton</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>N. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hewitt</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Valley Virginian has been re-issued under new ownership. The
                    proprietors are now J. H. Burdett, C. D. Stoneburner, J. B. Pemberton, and N. H.
                    Anderson. It is edited by J. H. Hewitt, professor of music. "Prof. Hewitt is a
                    good writer and has had considerable experience in editing newspapers--having
                    been connected with several. He has contributed a number of well written and
                    humorous articles to the Spectator which appeared under his nom de plume. He
                    will, doubtless, make the Virginian an entertaining paper."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>E. Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ide</ln>
                        <fn>August</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association will give a concert in the chapel of the
                    Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution on April 16th. "The programme will be new, and
                    will be made up of both vocal and instrumental pieces." The association has been
                    expanded and improved under Prof. E. Louis Ide. Prof. August Ide adds expertise
                    on piano, and Dr. J. L. Brown brings his skills as a bass singer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Fire Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>Charles W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickard</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peaco</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trayer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company elected new officers in the wake of the
                    resignation of Captain Waters. The paper reminds citizens and property holders
                    that the company is still not properly provisioned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Jared W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jared W. Spitler and Miss Sallie F. Eakle, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Mt. Sidney on March 25th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>Robert L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert L. Roberts of West Virginia, and Miss Margaret E. Shreckhise,
                    daughter of Jacob Shreckhise, were married on April 6th at the house of the
                    bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockwell</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Kate Crockwell, daughter of Dr. and Mrs. J. R. Crockwell, died in Staunton
                    on April 12th. She was 14 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Minnie O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Minnie O. Craun, infant daughter of George A. and Amanda E. Craun, died
                    near Centerville, Augusta County, on March 27th. She was almost 4 months old.
                    "Suffer little children to come unto me, and forbid them not, for such is the
                    kingdom of heaven."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Props</ln>
                        <fn>J. William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. William Props died near Moscow on April 5th of chronic rheumatism. He
                    was 29 years old. "The deceased had been on a visit to his uncle, some 8 or 9
                    days, and, in company with a cousin, was returning home when he was taken very
                    ill, a half mile from the former place, and died in a few minutes. The writer of
                    this notice was often in his company, and although he was a great sufferer, was
                    never heard to murmur at his fate. He received all the comforts that could be
                    bestowed by a kind mother and affectionate brother."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.04.13.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
