<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.12.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/12/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-12-14">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">14</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.14.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.14.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Admission of Virginia--Action of the Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Though the President, in his Message delivered to Congress on the 6th, stated
                        that Virginia had done "all that was required by the resolution of
                        Congress," in reference to the election submitting the Constitution, "and by
                        all the reconstruction acts of Congress, had abstained from all doubtful
                        authority," and thereupon "recommended that her Senators and Representatives
                        be promptly admitted to their seats and the State be fully restored to its
                        place in the family States;" and though, at noon on the 8th, in response to
                        the address of Mr. Turner, the Chairman of the Committee appointed by the
                        Legislature, the President said that he "<emph rend="italic">did not doubt
                            the speedy admission of the State,</emph>" yet this Committee on holding
                        an informal conference with Gen. B. F. Butler at his residence on the same
                        evening (the 8th), and learning that <emph rend="italic">he</emph> -- Butler
                        -- desired additional guarantees, promptly assented, and added the following
                        to their address to Congress:</p>
                    <p>"And the undersigned pledge themselves and those whom they represent that the
                        Constitution of Virginia, voted for by the people on the 6th day of July,
                        1869, shall be faithfully carried out in letter and in spirit."</p>
                    <p>We do not purpose now to comment upon the action of this committee,
                        presenting Virginia as a supplicant at the feet of B. F. Butler, "whom it
                        were base flattery to call a villian," whose malignity is gratified by the
                        humiliations and abasement of the "mother of States and of Statesmen" thus
                        effected through his instrumentality, but merely to protest that that
                        committee is not, and could not be invested with authority to restrict the
                        future action of Virginia. Though such action on the part of that committee
                        is wholly unauthorized, yet it may become the "direful spring of woes
                        unnumbered."</p>
                    <p>Congress may incorporate such pledges as the committee may make into the act
                        admitting the State as the conditions of admission, and may, at any future
                        time, claim that the conditions have been violated and that the act of
                        admission has been thereby abrogated.</p>
                    <p>Unless Virginia be admitted upon perfect equality with the other States of
                        the Union, she should spurn admission -- however desirable admission upon
                        terms of equality may be. -- When admitted, she will have the right to
                        change her organic law and her statute laws to suit herself, if by such
                        changes she does not violate the Constitution of the United States, for that
                        instrument affirms that, "the powers not delegated by the United States by
                        the Constitution, nor prohibited by it to the States, are reserved to the
                        States respectively and to the people." She will not only have the right to
                        change them, but it will be her duty to do so whenever she believes they can
                        be improved thereby.</p>
                    <p>On the morning of the 9th, three committees from the State appeared before
                        the Reconstruction Committee, representing respectively the Legislature, the
                        seceding wing of the Radical Convention, and the non-seceding wing, having
                        as their chairmen, respectively, Turner, Platt, and Porter.</p>
                    <p>The committee representing the Legislature, presented their views in writing,
                        briefly reciting what had been done in the State toward carrying out the
                        Reconstruction acts and asserting that what had been done by the people of
                        Virginia was in good faith and that the constitution, as far as adopted,
                        shall be carried out to the very letter and spirit of its intent and law.
                        This was briefly advocated by Turner and Crenshaw, of the House of
                        delegates, and by Hine. Platt, republican member of Congress elect from the
                        Second district, advocated the unconditional admission of Virginia, without
                        applying the test oath to members of the Legislature. He was followed by
                        Porter, republican member elect from the Third district, who opposed the
                        immediate admission of the State; but in order to facilitate reconstruction
                        advised that the test oath be administerd to members of the Legislature,
                        excluding members who could not take it, and supplying their places with
                        those who could from the next highest on the election returns. He also
                        suggested, as another plan of reconstruction, the submission of the
                        constitution, with the test oath and disfranchising clauses included. These
                        views were opposed on the ground that a new election would be rendered
                        necessary, as the application of that oath would reduce the number of
                        members to less than a quorum and also involve the re-election of United
                        States Senators.-- Bland, a colored member of the Legislature, made a speech
                        in favor of immediate admission without the test oath. He made an emphatic
                        address, declaring that the State had done everything she could do
                        consistent with her honor to testify to the national government her
                        obedience to its authority, and to the laws of Congress. He, therefore,
                        protested against administering the test oath to her Legislature, and
                        contended that the State was loyal to the core and fully entitled to every
                        privilege and right accorded to the other loyal States. -- Governor Walker,
                        who was present by request, addressed the Reconstruction Committee, and
                        strongly endorsed the declaration of the legislative committee that the
                        terms of the Constitution would be strictly adhered to, and spoke of the
                        loyalty of the people as deserving of a prompt recognition by the immediate
                        admission of the State into the Union.</p>
                    <p>The committees were requested to reduce their views to writing and present
                        their papers to the Reconstruction Committee at the meeting Saturday
                        morning.</p>
                    <p>At 10 o'clock on Saturday morning, the Reconstruction Committee met. The
                        different delegations from this State were present. Platt presented a long
                        address setting forth his views in favor of the admission of the State, and
                        Porter presented one against it. Our readers, who voted for Segar for
                        Congressman at large will be surprised to learn that he presented an address
                        to the Reconstruction Committee opposing the admission of Virginia as at
                        present constituted, and that Ex- Gov. Wells is in favor of the immediate
                        admission of the State without any further conditions, and favors the
                        passage by Congress, of an act of amnesty placing all citizens on the same
                        footing as to voting, holding office, serving on juries, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>Congressman Ward, of the committee, expresses the opinion that the committee
                        will report for the admission of the State on Tuesday -- today.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Described the actions of the Reconstruction Committee and the speeches and
                    messages made before it. Criticized B. F. Butler for his refusal to admit
                    Virginia, even though she had done everything required for readmission. Also, a
                    vigorous debate ensued in the legislature over whether to accept immediate
                    readmission to the Union or to wait for better conditions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Disabilities Removed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>Francis T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>R. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Senate removed the political disabilities of the following Augusta
                    citizens: Dr. Francis T. Stribling, Joseph N. Ryan, William A. Burnett, R. D.
                    Hill, B. F. Fifer, Robert G. Bickle, and David C. McGuffin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Warrenton Index</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. William T. Richardson of Waynesboro accepted a call to serve as
                    pastor of the Presbyterian Church of Warrenton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. John A. Harman turned down an appointment to serve on the Central
                    Executive Committee of the Republican Party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.14.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Free Pews</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Presbyterian Church of Staunton decided that their pews shall be
                    provided free of charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The first grand ball of the season will take place in Odd Fellow's Hall on
                    December 29th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Mitchell left her child in the hay-loft of Edward Burke's stable in
                    Staunton. She told her mother that the Gipsies had stolen the child. The baby
                    was found half-frozen.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbuckle</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>M. Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John D. Arbuckle of West Virginia and Miss M. Lizzie Vanlear, daughter of
                    the late Rev. John A. Vanlear, were married near Mt. Solon on December 8th by
                    the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheney</ln>
                        <fn>Lafayette D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dmasters</ln>
                        <fn>Martha C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lockridge</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Lafayette D. Matheney and Miss Martha C. Dmasters, both of Augusta,
                    were married at Wintergreen, near Sherando, on December 9th by the Rev. John N.
                    Lockridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiseman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Wiseman, formerly of Augusta County, died in West Virginia on November
                    24th. He was 84 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitlock</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Whitlock died at his residence in Stribling Springs on November
                    26th. He was 53 years old. "And we may add, for the benefit of all who knew the
                    deceased, that many years of his life were carefully employed in serving the
                    Lord--consequently his last moments were tranquil and happy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.12.14.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
