<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.03.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/07/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-30">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.30.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Set a Rogue to Catch a Rogue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The truth of the familiar saying -- "Set a rogue to catch a rogue" -- is now
                        being exemplified by the leaders of the Radicals in this State. Gov. H. H.
                        Wells, Judge H. L. Bond, Registrar in Bankruptcy, and L. E. Dudley, Clerk of
                        the Circuit Court in Richmond, are on trial in Richmond before United States
                        Commissioner, Mayor Chahoon, charged by W. H. Samuels and Edgar H. Allen
                        with feloniously obtaining and opening, contrary to the postal laws of the
                        United States, a letter written by Samuels to Allen and directed to the
                        latter at Farmville. These are all Radicals and being well acquainted with
                        each other, each thinks the other should be in the penitentiary, and that
                        there should be no Governor to pardon. This trial is a canine feast in which
                        dog eats dog, and the dogs belong to that class which deserve to have their
                        tails cut off just behind their ears.</p>
                    <p>The accused do not seem to be at all chop-fallen by the grave accusations
                        alleged against them, but rather to rejoice, as they anticipate it will add
                        to their popularity with their wing of their party. The accused threaten to
                        establish that their accusers deserve the ignominiously punishment which the
                        latter are trying to have inflected on the former. We concur in the
                        judgements of both parties. The verdicts are right -- let the sentence be
                        pronounced, and the penalty inflicted. Let justice do its perfect work.
                            <emph rend="italic">Fiat justitia.</emph></p>
                    <p>"The lame and impotent conclusion," we predict, will be -- "nobody hurt."
                        What is to be apprehended is, that the stolen letter will prove such a
                        letter of recommendation of Wells and his party that they will triumphantly
                        elect him. In his opinion, doubtless, it accelerates his speed in the
                        Gubernatorial race to such a velocipedic degree that it is not only folly to
                        expect a <emph rend="italic">Walker</emph> to beat him, but even<emph
                            rend="italic">Withers</emph> (,) the hope of the Conservatives.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the State governor and a Clerk of the Circuit Court are
                    charged with feloniously opening and tampering with a letter. Believes this
                    reveals the true character of the Radical party, who fight endlessly with each
                    other.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>David Fultz, Esq. of this place, has been appointed Judge, vice Judge H. W.
                        Sheffey removed. On the same evening on which he received his Commission, he
                        qualified by taking the necessary oath, and the next morning was on his way
                        to Amherst county to hold Court. -- This <emph rend="italic">promptness of
                            decision</emph> would seem to indicate that he possesses in an eminent
                        degree one of the chief requisites of a judge. He is the only lawyer of this
                        place who could qualify, and his appointment is more acceptable to our
                        people <sic>that</sic> would have been that of any other person within or
                        without the circuit who would consent to take the iron-clad oath. He has had
                        a good practice at the bar for many years, and has devoted his studies
                        assiduously and almost exclusively to his profession.</p>
                    <p>We published the fact last week that Sam'l A. East had been appointed Clerk
                        of the County Court of Augusta, vice Wm. A Burnett removed. Mr. East
                        declined to qualify, and resigned his commission.</p>
                    <p>The appointment was then conferred upon Mr. Sam'l Cline, who, we suppose,
                        will be able to qualify. Mr. Cline is one of the most worthy citizens of
                        this county. It would be fortunate for the State if all the appointments
                        could be conferred upon citizens as worthy as Mr. Cline. We suppose that he
                        will engage the services of the late faithful, capable and efficient Clerk,
                        Wm. A. Burnett, as Mr. Robert D. Sears, appointed Clerk of the Circuit
                        Court, engaged those of Mr. Jos. N. Ryan, his worthy and popular
                        predecessor.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Dr. Sam'l J. Baird has been appointed Clerk of the Hustings Court of
                        Staunton, vice Mr. Jas. F. Patterson. The services of Mr. Patterson will, of
                        course, be retained, for that Court to do business without having Mr.
                        Patterson to record its proceedings would be like enacting the play of
                        Hamlet with the character of Hamlet omitted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>East</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sears</ln>
                        <fn>Robert D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the appointment of several local Judges. One man was unable to take
                    the oath of loyalty, and as a consequence resigned his position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Making Treason Odious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The treatment by the North of the South since the war has not had the effect
                        to "render treason odious," but to render the conduct of the North odious.
                        To have rendered treason by their acts, says the Petersburg <emph
                            rend="italic">Index</emph>, "that we had revolted against the best, and
                        wisest, the most benignant government on earth, and not by their acts have
                        strengthened our convictions that it is the meanest, basest, most malignant
                        and narrow-minded upon which the sun shines."</p>
                    <p>"Make it so by removing those vile test-oaths which are a snare to the soul
                        and a solicitation to perjury, and which have only made loyalty a drag net
                        for rascality, which passes over the old conscientious Union man and catches
                        those who have no conscience and will swear to anything. Let them apply the
                        moral of the fable of the South and the Wind to their treatment of the
                        South. Let them cease to act the part of the father who sets steel traps and
                        spring guns for the returning prodigal.</p>
                    <p>Never will there be, never ought there to be, a real peace so long as the
                        South is treated as a reprobate -- and never thus can "treason be made
                        odious."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that the treatment of the South by the North makes the latter more
                    odious than the treason of the former.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Outrage Near Chambersburg, PA.--Excitement and Attempted Lynching</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Chambersburg, Pa., March 21, -- On Thursday afternoon last a girl thirteen
                        years old, and two young ladies, all white, and the daughters of farmers
                        living within two miles of this place, were ravished by a negro. On Friday,
                        a negro, nineteen years old, named Norris, a native of Chambersburg, was
                        arrested, and is now in jail, as the perpetrator of these outrages.-- There
                        seems but little doubt of his being the guilty party. The excitement in the
                        community is intense.</p>
                    <p>On Friday night an effort was made to take Norris from the jail with the
                        intention of hanging him. No lest than eight hundred people gathered about
                        the building, but a number of prominent citizens made speeches and induced
                        the mob to disperse. The prison has since been guarded by a <emph
                            rend="italic">posse comitatus</emph> summoned by the sheriff. The young
                        ladies outraged are daughters of three of our most respectable farmers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A freedman is accused of ravishing three women in Chambersburg. A lynch mob
                    nearly broke him out of jail to hang him but were stopped by the insistence of
                    prominent citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reassures readers that the remains of the soldiers buried in the
                    small pox cemetery have not been forgotten. The soldiers died of that disease,
                    and they will be moved to the soldiers' cemetery once it is "thought safe to do
                    so." In the meantime, these graves have also been decorated with flowers on
                    memorial day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Odor</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William A. Harrell and Miss Nancy F. Odor, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 11th at Mossy Creek by the Rev. Thomas E. Carson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Edward B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward B. Dull died suddenly in Covington on March 18th. He was 37 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawrence</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Ellen Lawrence, daughter of Thomas and Sarah J. Lawrence, died near
                    Staunton on March 24th. She was 17 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Miss Almira Wheat, daughter of the Rev. J. C. Wheat, died in Staunton on
                    March 12th. "Bearing the stamp of serenity upon her brow, her generous heart and
                    gentle influence, being ever ready to relieve the oppressed, and comfort the
                    afflicted, causes the announcement of this sad event to keenly cut its way to
                    every heart that knew her."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
