<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.02.23">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/06/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-02-23">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day norm="">23</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.02.23.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.02.23.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Gen. Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President elect has been so reticent, so wisely silent, that the public
                        are left to conjecture as to what line of policy he will adopt, and as to
                        what will be the character of his administration, whether conservative or
                        radical. So far, he has so acted to excite the hopes of the conservatives
                        and the fears of the Radicals. In the language of the Balt. <emph
                            rend="italic">Gazette</emph>, "while the question as to what he may do
                        is an open one, there can be no doubt as to what he can do if he pleases. He
                        can wield the sword of State with the firmness of Andrew Jackson, and
                        faction will cower low before him. If he has the brain and the nerve his
                        admirers have claimed for him, he can stay the usurpations of Congress with
                        a resistless hand and break the cobwebs the meshes in which it has sought to
                        fetter his lawful prerogatives. If he should set himself about the
                        restoration of constitutional law and free government, he would find himself
                        backed by a concourse of the people who applauding shouts would send terror
                        into the body of corrupt revolutionists, who, for purely partisan ends, are
                        ready to sacrifice the interests, welfare, and honor of the country. If he
                        has the head and heart for the work of reconstruction on a fair and honest
                        and patriotic basis, the opportunity is now his to lift his name from the
                        ranks of fortunate or successful soldiers and place it among those of the
                        rulers who live in the world's history as patriots and statesmen who have
                        saved or founded nations, and of whom Washington is the great exemplar. The
                        people, and the law, and the right, all await the advent of the man who
                        shall release them from the thrall of faction, and if General Grant be, as
                        his friends say he is, 'the foremost man of the age,' he can now do that
                        which will forever preclude mankind, from hereafter questioning his
                        greatness or detracting from his glory."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Though General Grant has thus far given little indication of his intentions
                    for the Presidency, the Spectator is hopeful. He has an opportunity to free the
                    country from faction, and the editors hope that he will use it, and thus secure
                    his place in history.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.02.23.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Radical Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On yesterday, Monday, (Court day) a Radical meeting was held in the Town
                        Hall. The greater part of the meeting consisted of negroes. We were not
                        present, but learn from one who was that the following proceedings were had.</p>
                    <p>A. T. Maupin, the Postmaster at Staunton, nominated Maj. Jno. A. Harman as
                        President. The nomination was voted down. Then A. T. Maupin assured the
                        meeting that Maj. Harman was now thoroughly identified with the Radical
                        party. Phil. Roselle (colored) then said that if that was the case he and
                        his colored friends would vote for him. Maupin then renewed the nomination
                        of Maj. Harman, and he was elected President of the meeting.</p>
                    <p>On taking the chair he said that he felt embarrassed -- that he was in a
                        novel position -- but that he could assure the meeting that he cordially
                        endorsed the reconstruction measures of Congress. He alluded to the
                        opposition expressed by his friend, Mr. Rozelle, to his appointment as
                        chairman, and said that he was heartily with them in the political issues of
                        the day. He urged them to go to work to secure the success of their party.</p>
                    <p>The Vice Presidents were then nominated and elected in the following order:</p>
                    <p>1st. Giles Jackson (colored).</p>
                    <p>2nd. Sam'l Landis (white).</p>
                    <p>3rd. Henry R. Shelton (colored).</p>
                    <p>Robert Newman (white) was elected Secretary. He wished to be excused as he
                        had been chewing so much tobacco that morning that, he said, he couldn't
                        write. But he was not excused and acted.</p>
                    <p>The following committee was appointed to nominate delegates to the Radical
                        Convention at Petersburg on the 9th of March:</p>
                    <p>Phil. Rozelle (colored), Henry Rippetoe (white, Henry Davenport (colored),
                        Henry Norris (colored), and Wm. Brown (white.)</p>
                    <p>The committee reported the following and they were elected delegates:</p>
                    <p>Oscar Morries (colored), Jas. Black (colored), and A. T. Maupin (white).</p>
                    <p>The following were elected alternatives:</p>
                    <p>Phil. Rozelle (colored), Wm. Lewis (colored) and Geo. A. Smith (white).</p>
                    <p>On motion of Jacob Bear the same committee was authorized to appoint a county
                        Executive Committee to be composed of two from each Magisterial District. It
                        was stated by a member that it was not expected that the Committee would
                        report to the meeting then in session.</p>
                    <p>After the adjournment, the meeting was addressed by Capt. F. S. Tukey, now of
                        Caroline, formerly in connection with the Freedmen's Bureau in this place.</p>
                    <p>A. T. Maupin also addressed the meeting.</p>
                    <p>Comment is unnecessary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rozelle</ln>
                        <fn>Phil</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>Giles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landis</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>Henry R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rippetoe</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davenport</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>Oscar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tukey</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Radicals met in the Town Hall, to elect their leaders. Maj. Harman was
                    selected as President and the editor lists the names of other officers elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The National Life Insurance Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>R. T. Phillips, Staunton agent for the National Life Insurance Company,
                    writes an open letter informing citizens of the benefits and success of his
                    employer. Since its charter in July, 1868, a large number of policies have been
                    issued, and some of the leading bankers in the country are invested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Robert S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>M. Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Robert S. Hamilton and Miss M. Ella Allen, both of Augusta, were
                    married in the Presbyterian Church on February 18th by the Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNear</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. R. Turk of Augusta and Mrs. E. M. Hull of Highland were married on
                    February 18th by the Rev. William R. McNear.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierce</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James A. Gregory and Miss Fannie J. Pierce, both of Augusta, were married
                    on February 18th at the residence of the bride's parents by the Rev. J. J.
                    Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>John J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCorkle</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruffner</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John J. Dixon and Miss Margaret J. McCorkle, daughter of Samuel McCorkle,
                    were married at the residence of the bride's father on February 11th by the Rev.
                    W. H. Ruffner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Rosa B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minnigerode</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. James C. Dunlap of Middlebrook and Miss Rosa B. Nelson of Richmond were
                    married on February 16th by the Rev. Dr. Charles Minnigerode.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>Alpheus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alpheus Henkel of New Market and Miss Fannie Killian of Augusta were
                    married on February 11th by the Rev. J. Killian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>Alpheus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henkel</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alpheus Bowman of Rockingham and Miss Mollie Killian of Augusta were
                    married on February 11th by the Rev. S. Henkel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John White and Miss Isabella Wade, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 16th by the Rev. J. Killian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rear</ln>
                        <fn>Luther O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strouse</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Luther O. Rear of Kentucky and Miss Jennie R. Coiner of Augusta were
                    married at the residence of Mr. P. Strouse near Middlebrook on February 7th by
                    the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>Lina E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David C. Hanger and Miss Lina E. Rusmisel, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Middlebrook on February 11th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Luther Hailman and Miss Lizzie V. Shuey, both of Augusta, were married on
                    February 14th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong. "Two loving hearts are joined in
                    one/Which can be severed by God alone."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>U. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. U. D. Poe died near Spring Hill, Augusta County, on February 10th. He
                    was 62 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Ann C. Robertson, wife of Col. George Robertson, died near New Hope on
                    February 8th. She was 75 years old. "Having been an earnest disciple of her
                    Divine Master and a devoted and useful member of the Church of God, under that
                    form known as Methodism, for full three score years, she goes softly and
                    hopefully to the rest of the future."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.02.23.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
