<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.05.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/20/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-05-04">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="">4</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.05.04.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.05.04.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>The Conservative Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Knowing the interest which our readers must feel in the proceedings of the
                        Conservative Convention which assembled in Richmond on Wednesday last, we
                        devote a large portion of our space this week to their publication. As this
                        was the only body which could speak authoritatively for the Conservative
                        party of this State its utterance was awaited with deep anxiety. The result
                        of its deliberations, it was felt, would inspire hope or induce despondency.
                        It was necessary that it should recommend a policy which all conservatives
                        could adopt without compromising their principles, as it is absolutely
                        necessary that no divisions should exist in the party. Upon the united
                        action of all the conservatives depends the salvation of our State from ruin
                        and its citizens from woes unnumbered.</p>
                    <p>The object to be accomplished, if possible, by the Convention, was to
                        recommend a line of action which would enable the Conservatives to act
                        together, without any compromise of principle, in their patriotic efforts to
                        save the State from the ruin which would result from the ratification of the
                        unmodified Underwood Constitution. The candidates on the Conservative ticket
                        having resigned, and their resignations having been accepted, the Convention
                        declined to nominate another Conservative ticket, and declined to endorse
                        either of the other tickets, leaving each and every Conservative in the
                        State free of all party obligations to vote for one or the other or neither,
                        and only enjoined upon them the duty, which all should with alacrity
                        perform, of voting against the obnoxious clauses of the Constitution which
                        will be submitted to a separate vote, without recommending them to vote for
                        or against the Constitution thus modified. In party terminology, this
                        "platform" is broad enough to afford standing room for every Conservative in
                        the State, as well as for "any other man" white or colored who does not wish
                        to see ninety of every hundred of the native whites of the State denied
                        eligibility to office. It is a platform upon which all should stand without
                        regard to color or previous political affiliations. The man who will not
                        vote to strike out the obnoxious clauses of the Constitution which will be
                        submitted to a separate vote should be ostracised from society and
                        proscribed in business, for he is a declared enemy of the people among whom
                        he lives, and proclaims it by such a vote as effectually as he would do by
                        brandishing the warrior's sword or the incendiary's torch.</p>
                    <p>The Convention did, in our opinion, the wisest thing it could have done <emph
                            rend="italic">in the circumstances by which it was surrounded</emph>. It
                        did enough and not too much. All lament the circumstances which made it
                        unwise to do more. We should have liked to see the chosen leaders and worthy
                        standard-bearers of the Conservative party remain in the field, and deeply
                        regret the existence of circumstances which made it a patriotic duty for
                        them to resign the positions assigned them. They won honor by the gallant
                        and efficient service they rendered in the canvass they prosecuted with such
                        zeal and vigor, and added a crowning glory to it by the manner in which they
                        resigned their positions in obedience to the dictates of patriotic duty.
                        Such patriotic and self-sacrificing conduct deserves to be rewarded, and the
                        time will arrive when it will be. They merit the award: "Well done, good and
                        faithful servants."</p>
                    <p>We would earnestly invoke the Conservatives of the State to guard sedulously
                        against what we conceive now to be our greatest danger -- listless
                        indifference and a want of a proper appreciation of the fact that it is
                        absolutely necessary that all who can do so should attend the polls on the
                        day of election and vote, and that those who have not registered should do
                        so as soon as the registration books shall be again opened, and be sure to
                        vote.</p>
                    <p>None should fail to vote at the next election. Cast your votes then, if you
                        never vote again. The man who shall fail to vote then, will probably have
                        cause to regret it as long as he shall live, and his children, who will be
                        the suffering victims of his remissness, will curse his memory. Do your duty
                        -- REGISTER AND VOTE.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper praises the recent conservative convention for its work, and
                    discusses some of its accomplishments. Also urges all conservative men to
                    register for the coming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.05.04.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. C. R. Harris will lecture in Staunton by request of the Augusta Fire
                    Company. The topic of his talk is "The Influence of the Fine Arts on the Moral
                    Sensibilities." The proceeds will go towards purchasing equipment for the
                    company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> STAUNTON, April 12th, 1869.<lb/><emph rend="italic">Gen. Jubal A
                        Early.</emph></p>
                    <p>General -- Your many friends in Staunton tender you a cordial welcome to your
                        native State once more.</p>
                    <p>They would be glad to meet you as their guest in their homes which you long
                        defended so faithfully.</p>
                    <p>To that end they trust you will consent to pay a visit to the town at as
                        early a day as your convenience will permit.</p>
                    <p>Respectfully yours,</p>
                    <p>M.G. Harman, John B. Baldwin, Bolivar Christian, Wm. S. McChesney, George E.
                        Price, B.B. Donaghe, Alex. H. H. Stuart, Wm. G. Sterrett, Fred. Scheffer, J.
                        H. Skinner, H. W. Sheffey, Jes. Bumgardner, Jr., John Echols, H. M. Bell,
                        Geo. Baylor, Marshall Hanger, and 49 others.</p>
                    <p>Reply</p>
                    <p>Lexington, Va., April 15th, 1869.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Gentlemen</emph>:--I am truly thankful to you for the
                        cordial welcome and kind invitation contained in your note of the 13th inst.</p>
                    <p>It would afford me the very highest pleasure to visit your town, and avail
                        myself of your hospitality, but circumstances will prevent my doing so for
                        some time.</p>
                    <p>While declining everything savoring of a public demonstration, in accordance
                        with reasons stated in a note to friends in Lynchburg, yet I hope to be able
                        to be at no distant day, to visit you quietly at your homes, and meet you in
                        a social way as old friends and comrades.</p>
                    <p>The recollections which have so much endeared the people of the Shenandoah
                        Valley to me, have not at all faded from my memory; and it has been among
                        the most pleasant of my anticipations to mingle with them again on my
                        return.</p>
                    <p>Very truly and respectfully yours,</p>
                    <p>J. A. Early</p>
                    <p>To Messrs. M. G. Harman, John B. Baldwin, Bolivar Christian, Wm. S. McChesney
                        and others.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>B. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A delegation of Staunton citizens invite Confederate General Jubal Early to
                    Augusta, but he declines despite his attachment to the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Lexington Presbytery met at Shemariah Church in Augusta County on
                    Wednesday. The Rev. Mr. Bell, the Presbytery Evangelist, made a report, as did
                    Rev. Mr. Scott and Rev. Mr. Calhoun, who are now successfully working in the
                    "destitute mountain regions within the bounds of this Presbytery. The meeting
                    licensed Mr. Swoope of Augusta County to preach. Mr. Laird delivered a sermon,
                    and a second collection was taken up for the Domestic Missions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Brooks and Miss Sarah A. Fauber, both of Augusta, were married at
                    Churchville on April 29th by the Rev. J. J. Engle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howser</ln>
                        <fn>David S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golliday</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donald</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whithers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David S. Howser of Augusta and Miss Eliza Jane Golliday of Nelson were
                    married in Buckingham County at the residence of Capt. John Donald on April 15th
                    by the Rev. Mr. Whithers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGilvray</ln>
                        <fn>Althea A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dameron</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Robinson and Miss Althea A. McGilvray, both of Augusta, were married
                    in Greenville on April 15th by the Rev. C. Dameron.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perrow</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Fannia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Charles H. Perrow of Nelson and Miss Fannia A. Mitchell of Augusta were
                    married at the residence of the bride's father, Joseph T. Mitchell, on April
                    29th by the Rev. J. A. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.05.04.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
