<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.06.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/21/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-06-01">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="">1</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.06.01.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.06.01.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Culpable Apathy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are pained to learn that many are so inexcusably apathetic, and seem so
                        indifferent about registering, and about voting in the elections which will
                        take place on the 6th day of July. Unless the masses of the people be
                        aroused from this feeling of indifference we will be utterly and
                        irretrievably ruined. Those who will fail to do their duty in that election
                        will be responsible for the ruin which will be entailed upon the State by
                        their culpable remissness.--Such remissness will be worse than criminal.</p>
                    <p>This class of persons should remember that there are sins of <emph
                            rend="italic">omission</emph> as well as of commission. On the day of
                        that election the voters will have a chance, the only one that will be
                        presented, of rescuing their State from impending ruin.</p>
                    <p>The golden opportunity should not be allowed to escape unimproved--when lost,
                        it will be lost forever. Those who will fail to register and vote will
                        regret it deeply and sorely as long as they may live, and their children
                        will reproach them as the authors of the direful ruin wrought, and the
                        intolerable evils visited upon them and their posterity.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounced all those who seemed indifferent to voting in the upcoming
                    election. Claimed that if they failed to vote, the ruin of the state would be on
                    their shoulders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Who Can Register?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It should be borne in mind that all who did not take an oath to support the
                        Constitution of the United States before the war can register, it matters
                        not what they did during the war, or what they may have done since.</p>
                    <p>No one who is qualified to register should fail to do so as soon as the
                        opportunity shall be presented. The only test required is an oath that you
                        did not before the war take an oath to support the Constitution of the
                        United States and after that, participate in the rebellion. It requires the
                        conjunction of both these facts to disqualify from registering.</p>
                    <p>If you took an oath to support the Constitution of the United States before
                        the war, and did not participate in the rebellion, you can register, and if
                        you did not take such oath before the war, you can register, it matters not
                        what your conduct during the war may have been.</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Register and vote</emph>
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summarized the requirements needed to register to vote, which appeared to
                    be very lenient.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Registration and Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We publish on the first page Gen. Canby's order concerning registration and
                        elections.</p>
                    <p>The revision of the registration lists is to commence on the 14th day of
                        June, and to continue for ten days(exclusive of Sundays.) The Boards will
                        strike from the lists of registered voters the name of any person not
                        entitled to vote, and will add the name of any person who may at that time
                        possess the requisite qualifications to register.</p>
                    <p>Two white and colored persons of each district or ward shall be selected by
                        the Board as challengers of the right of any person to register.</p>
                    <p>The election takes place on the 6th day of July. The polls to close at
                        sunset, unless in the opinion of the commissioners at any voting place the
                        vote cannot be polled by that hour, in which case they shall be kept open
                        until 10 P.M.</p>
                    <p>Two persons from each political party may be selected to act as challengers
                        at the polls, at each voting place, through whom all challenges of the right
                        of any person to vote shall be made.</p>
                    <p>Let it be remembered that Registration is necessary to voting. <sic>This is
                            the loading the gun</sic>; you fire it afterwards if you please, and as
                        you please.</p>
                    <p>The number of election precincts in the towns will be increased, as there is
                        to be one for every four hundred voters. We regret that this will not help
                        us in the country. Great inconvenience was experienced in some instances in
                        the election for the Convention in 1867 in consequence of the great distance
                        which the voters had to ride or walk to get to the voting places.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Described in detail the procedures laid out by General Canby for the
                    qualifications needed to register and vote in the upcoming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>The Votes to be Cast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the coming election each voter will have a number of votes to cast.
                        Besides voting for Governor, Lieut-Governor, Attorney-General, Congressman
                        at large, Congressman for the District, State Senator, and members of the
                        House of Delegates, he will have three votes upon the constitution. The
                        constitution will not be voted upon as a whole, but in parcels.</p>
                    <p>There will be a vote upon Clause <sic>4th</sic>, Section 1, Article III--a
                        vote upon Section 7, Article III--and a vote upon the remaining portion of
                        the constitution.</p>
                    <p>The first--clause <sic>4th</sic>, Section 1, Article III, denies suffrage to
                        a large portion of the white citizens, including all <sic>whoever</sic> held
                        any office, civil or military, Federal or State, and is called, in brief,
                        the disfranchising clause.</p>
                    <p>The second--Section 7, Article III--embraces the iron-clad test-oath which
                        would exclude from the right of being elected to any office ninety out of
                        every hundred white citizens, and is commonly called the test-oath or
                        ineligibility section. <emph rend="italic">Against both, all should
                        vote</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Listed all the offices and sections of the constitution to be voted on in
                    the upcoming election. The editor especially urged voters to reject the
                    test-oath and disenfranchisment clauses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph> says, "the whites
                        largely outnumber the blacks in this State; they possess the power which
                        wealth gives, and they have superior intelligence to enable them to wield it
                        for their own protection. Now, we ask any black man having the least
                        perception, what hope there can be for his race in provoking a contest
                        against such odds? No; the true policy for the black man is to court the
                        friendship of the whites--not that of scalawags and carpet-baggers, like
                        those who now seek to use him, with the view of promoting their own, selfish
                        ends--but of the old slave-owners and property-holders of the country; for,
                        after all, those who once owned the negroes, having grown up with them, are
                        still their best friends.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tried to convince blacks to disavow Republicans and join their old
                    slaveowners in friendship because the latter are the true friends of blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds readers that only persons eligible under the 14th
                    amendment can vote or run for office. The editors warn voters not to cast
                    ballots for ineligible candidates because wasting votes could result in the
                    election of a radical.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. A. H. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following letter from Hon. A.H.H. Stuart addressed to a distinguished
                        gentleman in Albemarle, which we copy from the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Enquirer</emph> and <emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph> of Saturday last,
                        will be read with interest:</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON, May 24th, 1869</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">My Dear Sir</emph>--When I casually met you a few days
                        ago, you requested that I would express to you in writing my views of the
                        course the people of Virginia should pursue in regard to the questions about
                        to be submitted for their decision under the President's proclamation. I now
                        proceed to do so.</p>
                    <p>There certainly was much disappointment felt when it was ascertained that the
                        President had failed to include the "county organization" clauses of the
                        constitution among those which were to be submitted to the people to be
                        voted on separately. It was known that the President had expressed strong
                        opposition to these clauses, as tending to segregate the white and colored
                        population by a geographical line, and to impair the productive power of the
                        State, by separating the labor of the country from the capital of the
                        Commonwealth. Hence a confident expectation was entertained that he would
                        afford to the people an opportunity of striking these objectionable features
                        from the proposed constitution.</p>
                    <p>In the first excitement occasioned by this disappointment, some persons
                        expressed their purpose to try and defeat the whole instrument by voting,
                        first, to strike out the disfranchising clauses and the test-oath, and then,
                        against the instrument thus expurgated.</p>
                    <p>This disposition was not unnatural under the circumstances. Within the four
                        years which have elapsed since the close of the war, the people of Virginia
                        have been subjected to so much disappointment, annoyance and obloquy, that
                        they have become sensitive, and in some degree soured. But, unfortunately,
                        we are in no condition now to take counsel of our wishes. We are not in that
                        happy state, in which we can afford to indulge in the luxury of a little
                        ill-temper. We are bound by inexorable necessity to confront the stern
                        realities of our situation, and to make the best we can of them.</p>
                    <p>After giving to the subject the best consideration, I have satisfied myself
                        that it is the true policy of the people of Virginia to vote to strike out
                        the test-oath and disfranchising clauses, and then to vote <emph
                            rend="italic">for the adoption</emph> of the residue of the
                        constitution. I admit that it is a painful necessity, yet it is not the less
                        a necessity. It is true that we will not get all that we had expected to
                        get, yet I think it is obvious that by so doing we gain a great deal. The
                        constitution, even when expurgated, will be a very objectionable instrument,
                        but it is certainly much better than in its original form, and in my
                        judgment, it is infinitely preferable to constitution at all. We can at
                        least live under it for a time, with the certain assurance, that after a
                        while, we can greatly improve it.</p>
                    <p>It would tax my time and your patience too largely to give all the reasons
                        which have brought my mind to this conclusion. But I will state one or two
                        of the most prominent:</p>
                    <p>It seems to me that in casting their votes under the President's
                        proclamation, the people are called on to decide where the political power
                        of the State is to rest hereafter, and who are to control her destinies in
                        the future. They will have to elect between three competing propositions,
                        neither of which is entirely acceptable, but there is no other open to us.
                        These propositions are:</p>
                    <p>1st. To take the Underwood constitution pure and simple.</p>
                    <p>2d. To vote the whole constitution down.</p>
                    <p>3d. To adopt it with the disfranchisement and test-oaths stricken out.</p>
                    <p>Let us now consider what is the practical bearing and effect of each one of
                        these propositions. Let us see how it will affect the future status of the
                        political power of the Commonwealth.</p>
                    <p>If we allow the Underwood constitution to be adopted with all its
                        disqualifications it is obvious that we voluntarily disfranchise ourselves
                        for a generation to come, and place the political power--the power to
                        control our lives, liberty and property--in the hands of the carpet-baggers
                        and the worst classes of our own people. I presume there are few intelligent
                        and upright men in the State who will favor this proposition, and I
                        therefore pass it by without further commentary.</p>
                    <p>Let us now consider the second. Suppose we vote the whole constitution
                        down--what follows? Some contend that matters would stand as they are.
                        Assuming such to be the fact, I ask is not that bad enough? We would have
                        Wells for our nominal Governor, and all our offices filled by aliens and
                        strangers. We would have justice administered under military supervision and
                        by appointees of a military commandant. But what assurance have we that
                        matters would remain as they are? How do we know whether our situation will
                        not be rendered more intolerable than it now is? By voting down the
                        constitution altogether we in effect recommit the whole political power of
                        the State to a radical Congress. Has the past action of that body been such
                        as to render it desirable that they should again assume unlimited control
                        over our destiny? I must acknowledge I think not. If we virtually decide
                        that we will have nothing to do with shaping our own fortunes, we compel
                        Congress to take upon itself that office.</p>
                    <p>The third proposition is, then, the only one that offers any hope of escape
                        from the terrible evils by which we are threatened. If we strike out the
                        restrictive features and then adopt the residue of the instrument, while we
                        do not gain all we want, we at least place the political power of the State
                        in the hands of the better classes of the people of Virginia. We snatch it
                        from the grasp of the carpet-baggers and their allies, and we withdraw it
                        from the control of a Radical Congress.</p>
                    <p>We will entitle ourselves to a restoration to our rights in the Union, and to
                        the withdrawal of military supervision and control over us.--We can elect
                        officers and enact laws of our own, and within a year or two, after the
                        excitement incident to these political struggles shall have passed away, we
                        can call a new convention and form a new constitution adapted to our
                        existing condition. By striking out the disfranchisements and test oaths
                        almost the whole body of our population will be clothed with the power to
                        vote and be rendered eligible to office. The principle of popular
                        sovereignty will be established on a firm basis, and the voice of our own
                        citizens will be potential in framing our future organic law, and shaping
                        our future policy.</p>
                    <p>I have thus stated, I think fairly, the three propositions, between which the
                        people of Virginia are compelled to choose. If there be any other open to
                        them, I am not aware of it.</p>
                    <p>Ought the people of Virginia <sic>ot</sic> hesitate between them. I think
                        not. I think they ought to expurgate the constitution, and then adopt it.</p>
                    <p>But it is all important that we should spare no pains to secure a good
                        Legislature and a good Governor. The reasons are too obvious to require
                        enumeration. They will readily suggest themselves to every intelligent mind.
                        If we expect good laws we must elect a good Legislature. If we desire and
                        wish an honest execution of the laws we must choose a wise and honest
                        Governor. And while this is, at all times, necessary, it is especially so
                        now. The new Legislature will have to enact all laws necessary to put the
                        new government into operation. The constitution is not self-enforcing, it
                        requires legislation to give effect to it. The new Governor will be clothed
                        with the veto power to check hasty and improvident legislation. Need I say
                        anything to show to the people the necessity of making a wise selection of
                        those who are to wield powers fraught with so much of weal or woe to the
                        State?</p>
                    <p>Very truly yours, &amp;c.</p>
                    <p>ALEX H.H. STUART</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Printed a letter from A.H.H. Stuart, who put forth his reasons for
                    supporting the Underwood Constitution but not the disfranchisement and test-oath
                    clauses. His main points were that Virginians had to choose between Radical
                    rule, continued military rule, or self-rule. He knew many people would be
                    disappointed by this decision, but he felt it was the best scenario Virginia
                    could expect.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.06.01.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Alex B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex B. Cochran has scheduled a series of night-time meetings in which he
                    will discuss the political issues of the day. He deliberately set times so as
                    not to interfere with farm labor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Memorial Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual celebration of the Memorial Association will be held next
                    Saturday. "Persons should bring flowers and garlands with which to decorate the
                    graves of the soldiers who lost their lives whilst engaged in defense of the
                    South." A poem written by Dr. J. L. Brown will be sung by the Musical
                    Association, and one written by Father Ryan will be read.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Staunton Musical Association are rehearsing for a performance of the
                    operatic cantata entitled the "Haymakers" on June 10th. The piece has received
                    praise all across the country. "As it graphically delineates scenes and
                    incidents in the life of a farmer, our country friends especially will be highly
                    interested, and ought to be present." The music ranges from grave and serious to
                    gay and comic, and should be enjoyed by all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Valley Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The association met last week at the Tinkling Spring Presbyterian Church
                    near Fishersville. The Rev. T. D. Bell, president, presided and Prof. Evans
                    directed the singing. 77 members and a large number of spectators attended. A
                    concert was given at the close of the exercises.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>May Queen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Regina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Lena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hurley</ln>
                        <fn>Julia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deneur</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crow</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deneur</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Quinlan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fallon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Irene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>St. Francis Catholic Church crowned a May Queen last Friday. Miss H. Hurley
                    was selected for the honor and was attended by a large court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Musical Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"K." writes to the paper to give an account of the recent meeting of the
                    Valley Musical Association at Tinkling Spring Church. "Its meetings were
                    attended by a large and brilliant assembly of young people from this and the
                    adjoining counties. The exercises were highly interesting and delightful and
                    prove that our people have as fine voices and talent as any other people. With
                    proper cultivation and exercise they could rival the finest schools of Germany."
                    To that end, the society is pushing for construction of a school in Staunton.
                    "The subject of music is justly attracting much attention in this section of
                    country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>Charles B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Ella D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles B. Berry, M. D., and Miss Ella D. Bear were married near
                    Churchville on May 26th by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lucas</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Smiley and Miss Hannah A. Lucas, both of Augusta County, were
                    married on May 20th by the Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Henry Bedinger</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bedinger Michie, son of Henry B. and Virginia B. Michie, died in
                    Staunton on May 24th. He was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.06.01.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
