<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.09.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/09/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-09-28">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">28</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.28.01" exists="no">
            <div type="l">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The Memory of our Deceased Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Whilst we are contemplating upon the passing scenes of life, marking each
                        moment as it flies, and recording upon memory's pages the changes incidental
                        to our animated existence -- may we not forget to pause a moment to reflect
                        upon those illustrious dead who fell in vindication of their native soil.
                        Both the ties of nature, and the bonds of affection, demand that we should
                        cherish with high veneration the memory of our brothers, our relatives, our
                        friends. We do not think it at all probable that those dead ones have been
                        forgotten; for how can we erase from memory the mental images of those brave
                        and noble patriots who chose death rather than submission.</p>
                    <p>Some one may say that this subject is too painful to be recalled to mind, and
                        others perhaps, that it is a matter of little consequence whether the dead
                        are remembered or forgotten; but I would think it much more painful to know
                        that we were to die and be forgotten. -- Let us then in our minds' eye
                        review the battle fields where the heroes who fought for justice are
                        sleeping their last sleep of death. Our dead! where are they? Would you seek
                        their last resting place? Then go to the plains of Manassas and you will
                        find them there sleeping in all the honor and glory of the slain soldier.
                        Visit the battle-fields of Fredericksburg and Chancellorsville, and you will
                        find them there. Go to the banks of the James and call for our dead, and the
                        murmuring waters of that stream as they glide swiftly along, on their way to
                        the sea, will respond to your call, and gently proclaim that our dead are
                        resting there. Survey the fields of a thousand battles, and you will
                        perceive there, where many of our friends and comrades are quietly reposing.</p>
                    <p>Sleep on, brave soldiers, and take your rest where the battle-cry disturbs
                        you not, and the clash of arms is never heard. You have fallen in defence of
                        your homes and firesides, and we humbly trust that high Heaven will reward
                        you for your gallantry, and in memory of the slain may it be inscribed upon
                        the hearts of the living, <emph rend="italic">Dulce et decoran est pro
                            patria mori.</emph></p>
                    <p>Sleep on, brave soldiers, take your rest</p>
                    <p>Where the din of battles cease,</p>
                    <p>And the war trump's sound disturb you not,</p>
                    <p>THERE MAY YOU REST IN PEACE.</p>
                    <p>The winds a tale of you unfold--</p>
                    <p>The stream lets murmur too--</p>
                    <p>The leaflets tremble in the breeze,</p>
                    <p>IN MEMORY OF YOU.</p>
                    <p>We'll not forget to mourn your loss,</p>
                    <p>And speak of you with pride;</p>
                    <p>Brave soldiers of the southern cross,</p>
                    <p>HOW NOBLY YOU HAVE DIED.</p>
                    <p>Sleep on brave soldiers! sleep in peace,</p>
                    <p>As quiet as the dove;</p>
                    <p>Till Heaven's trump shall call you home,</p>
                    <p>TO BETTER WORLDS ABOVE.</p>
                    <p>W. H. T.</p>
                    <p>BEALETON STATION, Va., Sept. 15th, 1869.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"W. H. T." asked Virginians to remember and honor their brave soldiers,
                    even though this may be a painful memory to recall. Closed with a poem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Lynchburg <emph rend="italic">Virginian</emph> expresses the wish that
                        the Legislature will say nothing, and do nothing, at its meeting but ratify
                        the fifteenth amendment. This is our view of the whole duty imposed upon it;
                        and such we believe to be the view of a large majority of the people of
                        Virginia. They want a silent Legislature, for once that will give a single
                        vote and adjourn.</p>
                    <p>The Virginia Military Institute has already present upwards of <emph
                            rend="italic">three hundred cadets</emph>, and will very certainly
                        reach, during the session, three hundred and fifty to four hundred.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Lynchburg Virginian advised the Legislature to simply ratify the
                    fifteenth amendment, and then dissolve. Also reported that three hundred cadets
                    are currently enrolled at the Virginia Military Institute and more may arrive
                    later.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Valley Railroad</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper printed excerpts from the Baltimore Gazette expressing support
                    for a $1,000,000 appropriation to the Valley Railroad. The increased trade from
                    the Valley would benefit Baltimore greatly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: -- On all hands it is acknowledged that the construction of the
                        Valley Rail Road is the greatest enterprise upon which the future of our
                        Valley is based. Without it we languish -- with it, and the advantages we
                        would derive from it in the development of our resources, agricultural,
                        mineral and manufacturing, it would be difficult to estimate the amount of
                        wealth which would fall into the possession of the present owners of the
                        lands of the great Valley. Column after column of your sheet might be
                        exhausted in telling the well understood tale, but at last we know that the
                        construction of the Road is dependent upon the raising of the necessary
                        capital, and that again upon the names and reputation of the men who, as the
                        leaders and conductors of the enterprise, are to disburse it. The writer has
                        nothing to say in disparagement of the gentleman who up to this time has had
                        charge of the fortunes of the Road. He has done his part well and faithfully
                        in arousing attention to the claims of this Road to general and local favor.
                        It is believed that his efforts in that behalf have assured the subscription
                        of the necessary capital, and now the question arises who shall be the
                        leader in the prosecution of the work to its completion -- upon whom shall
                        the meeting of Stockholders, convened for the 12th of October next, devolve
                        this important duty. We have in our own Valley a great and mighty name -- a
                        name famous throughout the civilized world in its connection with science
                        and works of practical utility -- a name which commands the respect of all
                        interested in our great work and which would call forth the necessary
                        contributions of capital -- a citizen of our neighboring county of
                        Rockbridge, which by her liberality and promptitude in voting $400,000 to
                        the stock of the Road has entitled herself to a foremost position in its
                        organization. I nominate for President of the Valley Rail Road Company,
                        Commodore Matthew F. Maury, of Lexington. What says the Press and people of
                        the Valley? AUGUSTA.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous writer reiterated the importance of the proposed Valley
                    Railroad for Augusta county. Called the project the most important enterprise
                    for the future of the Valley and urged the immediate raising of capital for its
                    construction. At the end, he suggested that Commodore Matthew Maury of Lexington
                    serve as President of the Valley Rail Road Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Incendiarism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An old house used as a granary and stable by John Gregory of Staunton was
                    destroyed by fire. He lost 130 bushels of wheat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Alex C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Martha F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kramer</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex C. King of Augusta and Mrs. Martha F. Brown of Albemarle were married
                    at the Staunton residence of George Harlan on September 26th by the Rev. George
                    C. Kramer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Washington Swink died at his residence near Moscow on September 19th. He
                    was 55 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John T. Arnall died of paralysis at his Staunton residence on September
                    22nd. "Mr. Arnall was generally known and highly esteemed by the people of
                    Augusta county whom, for many years, he had served with fidelity and efficiency
                    in important public trusts. As a public officer he was distinguished for
                    promptness, clearness and method in all his transactions, and for a genial and
                    pleasant manner, which gained friends and secured good will. As a citizen, he
                    was the advocate and exemplar of that sound conservatism which recognizes civil
                    liberty as dependent upon social order and the supremacy of the law. In all the
                    social and family relations, as neighbor, friend, father and husband, he lived
                    and died without reproach, leaving to his family the priceless inheritance of a
                    good name."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.09.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
