<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1869/va.au.ss.1869.03.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/06/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1869-03-09">
            <year>1869</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.09.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Inauguration of President Grant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives an account of Grant's inauguration, including excerpts from his
                    inaugural address.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Grant's Policy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Southern man who understands the occult art of extracting blood from a
                        turnip may possess the rare faculty of extracting a few drops of comfort
                        from the inaugural address of President Grant. Those who can discern in that
                        document any encouragement for the people of the oppressed South belong to
                        that class who have</p>
                    <p>"options keen, we ween,</p>
                    <p>To see what is not to be seen."</p>
                    <p>Grant's policy, if he has any, in reference to the South, is as yet an enigma
                        -- it is neither <emph rend="italic">expressed</emph> nor <emph
                            rend="italic">understood</emph>.</p>
                    <p>In plain terms, he expresses his desire to invest disfranchised negroes with
                        the right of suffrage, but says not a word in favor of restoring suffrage to
                        the thousands of white people in the South, who have been unjustly and
                        wrongfully deprived of that right.</p>
                    <p>The mode in which the disfranchised negroes are to be made voters is more
                        objectionable even than the end proposed to be attained, for it removes the
                        foundation stone from the structure of States' Rights. For this mode of
                        accomplishing universal negro suffrage in the several States of the Union he
                        can find no warrant in the Constitution of the United States which he is
                        sworn to preserve, protect and maintain, on the contrary, it is in direct
                        contravention of the views and purposes of the wise framers of that
                        instrument. Nor is he under any party obligation to recommend this mode, for
                        the platform upon which he was elected not only does not express approval,
                        but in plain terms, disapproval, for it declares that the question of
                        suffrage is one for the several loyal States to determine each for itself.
                        This mode violates the principle of the Republican platform, for it allows
                        three-fourths of the Legislatures of the States to determine the question of
                        suffrage in one-fourth of the States, however much they may be opposed. This
                        policy is in contravention both of the constitution and of the Republican
                        platform, and if consummated, will deal the heaviest blow ever inflicted
                        upon States' Rights principles. It will be a seven-league stride towards
                        consolidation.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator is displeased with the inaugural speech of General Grant.
                    Contrary to his campaign platform and the principles of states rights, Grant has
                    spoken in favor of imposing universal black suffrage on the States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that some people in Staunton's African-American community
                    celebrated the inauguration of Grant "by making 'night hideous' with yells, the
                    firing of pop-crackers, sky-rockets, burning tar-barrels, etc."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fox</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George H. Fox and Miss Mary M. Hanger were married on February 25th by the
                    Rev. J. M. Shreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wynn</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heiser</ln>
                        <fn>Susan M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles Wynn and Susan M. Heiser were married on March 1st by the Rev.
                    George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roach</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Day</ln>
                        <fn>Emma J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Roach and Miss Emma J. Day were married on March 4th by the Rev.
                    George B. Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deter</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Julia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Deter and Miss Julia A. Hill were married on February 25th near the
                    Mossy Creek Iron Works by the Rev. John Pinkerton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Runcle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennett</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennett</ln>
                        <fn>Aaron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Liggett</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Runcle, postmaster of McGaheysville, and Miss Ann Eliza Dennett,
                    daughter of Aaron Dennett, were married on February 28th in McGaheysville by the
                    Rev. J. L. Liggett.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1869.03.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
