<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.06.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/23/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/3/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-06-12">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.06.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Manufactories</head>
                <origin>Columbus Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An upcoming opportunity will enable the Confederacy to obtain machinery
                    from Europe. This article calls upon capitalists to take advantage of this
                    opportunity and to help increase the production of cotton, woolens, and paper.
                    The prospect of getting the machinery is risky but is necessary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Latest from the United States</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a letter to Jefferson Davis dated April 23, 1863, Major General D.
                    Hunter states that Davis issued an order in August 1862 to execute anyone arming
                    African Americans and that unless Davis revoked the order, Hunter would execute
                    all Confederate officers and slaveholders in his possession. Further, Hunter
                    states that Davis contends he is leading a fight for liberty but that that
                    liberty (for Southern white people) depends on slavery (of African Americans).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page contains a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, a poem in tribute of General Jackson, war news, advertisements,
                other articles, and an illegible article entitled "An Incident at Recent Battles on
                the Rappahannock."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.06.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Situation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor has war news from reliable sources but the news is not yet
                    certain. Thus, he will wait to report it until he receives something official,
                    rather than dispense information that will generate rumors. He is confident,
                    however, that Southern troops in Mississippi have performed well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The town council convened on Saturday and Tuesday nights and passed a tax
                    bill similar to last year's, rescinded an ordinance calling for the issuing of
                    $30,000 in small notes, and authorized the mayor to buy $8000 of seven percent
                    Confederate bonds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the Rappahannock</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent engagement between General Lee's army and enemy forces saw the
                    Yankees cross the Rappahannock at several fords, only to be driven back across
                    the river by General Stuart. Colonel A. W. Harman was slightly wounded in the
                    neck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Congressional Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A table lists the votes Baldwin and Letcher received for the delegate from
                    the eleventh district, with Baldwin gaining a majority by 971 votes. In Augusta
                    County, Baldwin received 1352 votes; Letcher, 162.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Circuit Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eddy</ln>
                        <fn>Nancey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Circuit Court began session on June 3. So far several persons have been
                    convicted of felony; all but one sentenced to the penitentiary. In the case of
                    Comts. vs. Nancey Eddy, for attempting to burn the county jail, the jury was
                    dismissed after being unable to agree on a verdict. The Grand jury is still in
                    session, having issued more than one hundred presentments, principally for
                    selling liquor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes assorted war news, various advertisements, and a listing of
                market prices from Richmond markets.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
