<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.05.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/23/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/3/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-29">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.05.29.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Funeral of Lieut. Gen. T. J. Jackson</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the funeral of General Jackson and lists the order of escorts for
                    his funeral procession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>William H. Richardson, Adjutant General, wrote Major General F. H. Smith,
                    Superintendent of Virginia Military Institute, May 1, 1863, to announce the
                    death of General Jackson and to convey the governor's directives that he
                    received the highest funeral honors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Headquarters, Va. Mil. Institute</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Major General F. H. Smith issued orders on May 13, 1863 regarding the
                    mourning period for General Jackson and offered a summary of his career and a
                    tribute to him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gen'l Jackson</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Jackson will live in the admiration of the world and the affections of a
                    great republic, long after those whose prospects for fame and distinction seemed
                    fairer, shall have been even forgotten."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This article describes the appointment of General Jackson to the
                    Professor's Chair at the Virginia Military Institute in 1851.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes a reprint of a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, a reprint of a proclamation by Governor Letcher calling for
                state elections, a poem in tribute to General Jackson, a report of expenditures and
                receipts of the post office, a report of a meeting of the Council of the Protestant
                Episcopal Church for the Diocese of Virginia, advertisements, and assorted war
            news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.05.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Correction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor of the Vindicator states that editor R. Mauzy of the Spectator
                    wrote unfair and incorrect information concerning accusations against Colonel
                    Harman in an effort to place the candidate in an unfavorable light. The editor
                    of the Vindicator seeks to correct the wrong information.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Statue to Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The office of the Vindicator will receive donations towards the erection of
                    a bronze statue in the capital in memory of Jackson. A gentleman from Petersburg
                    has already sent one thousand dollars, and the editor hopes that "many in this
                    Valley, which Jackson loved so well and defended so bravely, will come forward
                    and do likewise."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War upon Women and Children</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains a series of letters about federal orders requiring women and
                    children within range of the movements in northwestern Virginia whose "natural
                    protectors" are in the Confederate forces to relocate elsewhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Broke Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>John</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Thursday night, May 21, the following prisoners escaped from the county
                    jail: T. W. Wilkerson of Alabama, charged with stealing a horse and assaulting
                    Samuel Patterson of Augusta County; John Coakley of Rockingham, charged with
                    stealing a horse; John W. Thomas, charged with stealing government cattle in
                    Craig County; Sidney Johnson, who claims to be free and from Alabama; Sam, slave
                    of Captain Antrim, charged with stealing money; Anderson, a runaway belonging to
                    R. Russell of Charlotte County and said to have been raised near Waynesboro;
                    Shadrach, a runaway belonging to J. Bolling of Fauquier; and Charles, slave of
                    John Bickle of Staunton. Steel bars had been ordered for the windows, but one
                    window still had iron bars. Prisoners sawed these bars and escaped through this
                    window. Walls in between cells were open, thereby allowing many prisoners to
                    escape. County court, at its meeting on Monday, ordered stone walls be built
                    between cells.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Monument of General Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of the old Stonewall Brigade are invited to contribute to a
                    monument for the grave of Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Joseph A. Waddell has received a letter regarding the difficulty of
                    getting rosin [used for fuel] from North Carolina and states he has been
                    promised a supply within the next two weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General W. H. Harman resigned as commonwealth attorney for Virginia on last
                    Monday. John N. Hendren, Esq., was appointed to fill the vacancy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The circuit court will convene Monday, June 1, to try several criminals.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Straughan</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Franklin Pennington of Hampshire County, Virginia, married Jennie
                    E. Straughan, of Augusta County, in Staunton on April 19, with Reverend William
                    E. Baker officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>James B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Lucretia S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James B. Bush married Lucretia S. Wright on April 14, with Reverend C.
                    Beard officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John C. Mowry married Mary Susan Coiner on April 21, with Reverend C. Beard
                    officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Willson</ln>
                        <fn>Susan S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan S. Willson, 71, widow of Captain William Willson of Lexington, died
                    in Staunton on May 14 at the residence of D. C. McGuffin. She had been a member
                    of the Presbyterian Church for many years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Funeral Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The funeral of William H. Patterson, member of Stuart's Cavalry, from
                    Staunton, will be at the Baptist Church, Staunton, next Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Public Sale of Negroes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. F. Johnson announces he will sell a young African-American woman and two
                    "likely" boys for cash on June 1, 1863, in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes an address by General J. A. Walker upon his appointment to
                lead the Stonewall Brigade, the proceedings of a meeting of officers and men of the
                Stonewall Brigade on the occasion of Jackson's death, various war news, political
                announcements, a reprint of an exchange notice regarding Confederate officers and
                enlisted men, a proclamation by Governor Letcher regarding the upcoming election, a
                reprint of a list of deserters from the Staunton Artillery, and assorted legal
                notices and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
