<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.06.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/23/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-06-19">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>19</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.06.19.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>"Stonewall" Jackson's Name and Memory</head>
                <origin>London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This tribute to Jackson notes that the victory at Chancellorsville came at
                    the great cost of losing the Confederacy's best general. The article recounts
                    the events at Chancellorsville and Jackson's subsequent death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Speech of Senator Wall of New Jersey--He Declares for an Immediate Cessation
                    of Hostilities</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary>Senator James W. Wall of New Jersey delivered this speech before the
                    Democratic club of Philadelphia on May 9. It reviews the antecedents to the war
                    and credits the Black Republican party with "responsibility of this iniquitous
                    War."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This long excerpt from a longer speech discusses how the war could have
                    been averted and how the Southern states could have left peacefully. In his
                    speech, Wall calls for an immediate end to the fighting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Recent Tremendous Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thirty thousand men gathered in New York City recently to register their
                    opposition to the Lincoln administration. Democratic political leaders were
                    absent, but the rank and file agreed that the administration was a failure and
                    called for an end to the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Depression in Trade</head>
                <origin>Atlantic Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At no time since the war began has the depression in trade been so deep and
                    so widespread. This situation is not necessarily bad, in that the wheat crop is
                    abundant, families are practicing economy and reduction of expenses, and people
                    are simply doing without blockaded goods.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Confederate states have an excess of prisoners captured throughout the
                    Confederacy of about 17,000 noncommissioned officers and privates. The captures
                    of commissioned officers are about equal between the North and South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, a poem, advertisements, and miscellaneous war and political
                news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.06.19.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glorious News from Winchester</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Early's troops, many of whom are from the Valley, recaptured
                    Winchester, taking all the enemy guns and stores and between 6000 and 7000
                    prisoners. A son of Mr. J. Givens Fulton, of Augusta, was a member of the
                    Staunton Artillery and was killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Hospitals</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Surgeon</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merrillat</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Surgeon</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Surgeon</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>After visiting several hospitals in the state and throughout the
                    Confederacy, the editor asserts that the General Hospital in Staunton "is better
                    adapted to the wants of a hospital and that more care is taken to render its
                    patients comfortable than at any other." The board which oversees the hospitals
                    speaks highly of the local one also.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Northern Toadyism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor comments on some peace meetings in the North and sees nothing to
                    encourage him in them, as, in his opinion, they are full of blather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Governor has called out all reserves to meet the call of the President
                    for 8000 militia to serve for six months, beginning August 1, to repel enemy
                    raids. The President wants volunteers for this project, rather than stretching
                    the militia any further. Organizations to repel raiding parties have been
                    forming in neighboring counties already. A meeting will be held in Staunton on
                    next court day to form a similar group.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Life of Gen. Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. Dabney has been selected by Jackson's family to write a biography
                    of the general. The popularity in the Valley of both the general and the
                    biographer ensures a great demand for this work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Soldier</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer is from another state but participated in the recent Valley
                    campaign. Jackson's troops were few in number and were being driven up the
                    Valley by the enemy. The troops left the main road, retreated to Port Republic,
                    and thus left the town of Staunton open and unguarded. The writer notes that the
                    editor of the Spectator took the first opportunity, left his town, office, and
                    property, and relocated to Lewisburg. The soldier criticizes the editor for not
                    staying to protect his and his neighbors' homes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also includes war and political news, an article on the execution of
                Confederate officers as spies in Tennessee, legal notices, and
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
