<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.10.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/30/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/12/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-10-02">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.10.02.01">
            <pageNote>This page contains a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, articles on the war, proceedings from the General Assembly,
                anecdotes, and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.10.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Meeting on Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Generals Wigfall and Smith addressed an unusually large gathering of
                    Augusta citizens at the court house last Monday. These distinguished gentlemen
                    have been in service in the field and in government and offer counsel and wisdom
                    based on their experience. The assembly passed resolutions that the editor hopes
                    will end "extortion and disloyalty in Old Augusta."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Skirmish and Capture of Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two companies of Imboden's Cavalry attacked the enemy at Burnt House, about
                    seven miles from Beverly, and captured thirty-eight horses and thirty-seven
                    Yankees. The prisoners passed through Staunton on their way to Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Public Speaking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Chairman</sf>
                        <pf>Honorable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf>Secretary</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>S. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the large gathering of Augusta citizens on Monday, September 28, a
                    committee was appointed to write resolutions which were unanimously adopted
                    following the speeches by Generals Wigfall and Smith. The Honorable A. H. H.
                    Stuart was appointed chairman, and A. F. Kinney was appointed secretary of the
                    assembly. Thomas J. Michie, Benjamin Crawford, and Matthew Pilson were appointed
                    to a committee to host the speakers. Thomas J. Michie, Major S. L. Lewis, Jacob
                    Baylor, Samuel B. Finley, William P. Tate, J. Marshall McCue, Dr. John
                    McChesney, A. Koiner, and John S. Ellis were appointed to the resolutions
                    committee. N. C. Trout and S. B. Finley offered other motions. The resolutions
                    thank the women of the county for their patriotic service, discourage desertion
                    by soldiers, and encourage citizens both to pay the tithe of produce as tax and
                    to abide by prices set by the government for surplus produce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>How It Works</head>
                <origin>Greensboro Patriot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Exemption Act of Congress includes a provision subjecting to
                    conscription every exempted manufacturer who charges a profit of more than
                    seventy-five percent on production cost. An excerpt from the Greensboro Patriot
                    uses an example of lard oil to demonstrate the difficulty of setting prices by
                    legislation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Attention Ladies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garnett</ln>
                        <fn>T. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>T. N. Garnett of the General Hospital in Staunton appeals for the women of
                    Staunton to make socks for soldiers before the winter. He has money with which
                    to buy yarn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Negro Girl for Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reader has a slave woman to sell. She is 20, tall, stout, healthy, "black
                    as the Ace of Spades, of captivating temper, of fine intelligence," and
                    efficient at house or field work.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news and additional advertisements and
            notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
