<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.04.24">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/3/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-04-24">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.04.24.01">
            <pageNote>This page contains a poem, a reprint of an address by President Davis relating
                to the production of provisions, a reprint of a plan by Secretary of War James A.
                Seddon for implementing Davis's proclamation, a list of dying words of famous
                persons, a report from the Confederate Congress, a reprint of an article noting the
                number of Virginians who had relocated to Rome, Georgia, and miscellaneous war
            news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.04.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Deserter Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burus</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A deserter calling himself Michael Burus was arrested en route to Staunton,
                    sent to Richmond, and shot to death there while trying to escape.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gov. Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gov. Letcher has announced his candidacy for representative from his old
                    district in the next Congress. His service to his constituency, his state, and
                    the Confederacy demonstrates that he would be an able statesman and an efficient
                    representative.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Western Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We fondly look for the day when this portion of our State will be redeemed
                    from abolition rule by the brave hearts and strong arms of Western Virginians.
                    May it come quickly."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor comments on a report from the Wheeling Intelligencer that
                    western Virginians overwhelmingly ratified an amended Constitution, surmising
                    that many fake votes were cast and that many were coerced into voting in favor
                    of the Constitution. The editor is certain that the majority in western Virginia
                    support their old state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor commends the quick response in Augusta County for calling a
                    meeting to implement the President's proclamation and encourages a large
                    turnout.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Barbara Shreckhise, 92, died April 15 at the home of her son, George
                    Shreckhise, near Mt. Sidney.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>$200 Reward!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sam, about 15, well formed, well grown, yellow complexion; Caroline, black,
                    tall, straight, missing her left thumb; and her two children, Mary Adaline,
                    about 7, and Armistead, about 4, ran away from Mr. A. Atkinson's near Mint
                    Spring, last Saturday, and are believed to be heading toward Winchester. James
                    H. Carson will pay $200 for the return of Sam, and Mr. Atkinson will pay the
                    same for the return of the others.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sabbath School Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Sabbath School, connected with the M. E. Church of Staunton, will give
                    an exhibition to benefit the families of soldiers on May 7. Tickets are $1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blouth</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf>Chief Steward</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>By order of the surgeon in charge, J. W. Morgan, Chief Steward, issues a
                    caution that impostors are canvassing the county representing themselves as
                    agents for the purchase of supplies for the General Hospital at Staunton. The
                    authorized agents are Augustus Blouth and Henry K. Bryan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes war news, letters endorsing political candidates, the texts
                of proclamations by Governor Letcher regarding upcoming elections, an announcement
                by Letcher of his candidacy for Congress from the 11th District, a reprint of a list
                of deserters from the Staunton Artillery, assorted announcements, legal notices, and
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
