<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.05.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/21/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/3/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-01">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.05.01.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>M. G. Harman writes to decline the opportunity to run for representative
                    from the 11th Congressional District, stating that he has no political
                    aspirations and seeks only to help his country "safely through her great
                    struggle for Independence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page includes a reprint of a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, a reprint of Governor Letcher's proclamation calling for state
                elections, two letters from William Smith regarding his candidacy for governor,
                correspondence regarding candidates in a neighboring district, a report from the
                Confederate Congress, and assorted other items.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.05.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Yankee troops raided in the Valley as far as Woodstock. They initially
                    overpowered troops led by Major Myers, only to have Myers attack the next day
                    more successfully. Rumors say that three columns of the enemy have crossed the
                    Rappahannock, with one column having 10,000 troops. However, the editor cannot
                    confirm or deny the rumors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editor notes that General J. D. Imboden has consented to become a
                    candidate for Lieutenant Governor. He believes that Imboden is in his element in
                    whatever he does, thus making the editor certain Imboden would do well in that
                    position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Northern and Local News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor has learned that two editors from Cecil and St. Mary's counties
                    in Maryland are in Staunton, having been driven away because of their comments
                    "on the usurpations of the Northern Dictator." The editor notes the irony of the
                    situation--the men were driven from the land where life, liberty, and freedom of
                    speech were guaranteed its citizens. The editors from Maryland initially
                    believed that the North was conducting its war in "the style generally adopted
                    by Christian Nations" but have since seen enough to know that it was acting
                    barbarically. The editor reports several incidents in the Valley that prove the
                    Yankees are savage and uncivilized.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congressional Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Vindicator's editor criticizes the Spectator's editor for denouncing
                    anyone who opposes Baldwin. The Spectator endorsed Col. Baldwin for
                    representative and claimed that any who are against him have axes to grind. The
                    editor of the Vindicator argues that these people have the freedom of choice and
                    do not necessarily have anything against Baldwin. The editor of the Vindicator
                    hopes the campaign will be between two worthy candidates rather than two
                    political parties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Meeting of the Voters of the "Stonewall Brigade"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Voters of the Stonewall Brigade from the 11th Congressional District met to
                    select a candidate to represent them in the next Confederate Congress. Major
                    James W. Newton of the 5th Virginia Infantry served as chairman of the meeting,
                    and Colonel H. J. Williams stated the purpose of the meeting. The men nominated
                    Colonels William H. Harman and John B. Baldwin. Walter Monteiro, Esq., of the
                    5th Virginia Infantry spoke on Harman's behalf. The men selected Harman as their
                    candidate and appointed a committee of Captains Curtis, Gibson, and Trevy to
                    inform Colonel Harman of his nomination and call upon him to be a candidate for
                    Congress from the district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>E. L. Curtis, J. W. Trevy, James W. Gibson</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>E. L. Curtis, J. W. Trevy, and James W. Gibson wrote General William H.
                    Harman on April 20, 1863 to ask him to be a candidate for Congress from the 11th
                    District. They informed Harman that members of their brigade met on April 18 and
                    selected him as their candidate. The soldiers chose him because of his "worth as
                    a statesman and soldier."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. H. Harman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. H. Harman wrote on April 28, 1863 that he has already agreed to be a
                    candidate for the Virginia House of Delegates from Augusta County and thus must
                    decline the opportunity to run for the Confederate Congress from the 11th
                    District. He expressed much gratitude for the endorsement from the men who
                    encouraged him to run.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter of Col. J. B. Baldwin</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jno. B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel John B. Baldwin responded to criticism of him that is intended to
                    diminish his chances for election. He has commanded the 52nd Virginia Regiment
                    for eight months and is confident the members of that brigade will speak on his
                    behalf. He assures readers that he voted to abolish flogging of soldiers and to
                    increase soldiers' pay.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Absalom Koiner</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Absalom Koiner writes that he agrees to be a candidate for a seat in the
                    Virginia House of Delegates, after having been solicited by numerous citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Henry O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jamieson</ln>
                        <fn>Annie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry O. Cease and Annie M. Jamieson, both of Staunton, were married April
                    29 by Rev. D. M. Gilbert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fireman's Ball has been postponed until further notice because of the
                    unavailability of gas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Patterson, 26, died March 26, at the residence of his father
                    near Waynesboro.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Announcements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Honorable</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The list of candidates in the upcoming election includes General William
                    Smith of Fauquier for Governor; Governor John Letcher for congressman from the
                    11th District; Honorable John B. Baldwin for reelection as congressman from the
                    11th District; James H. Carson for reelection to the state Senate from the
                    district composed of Frederick, Clarke, and Warren counties; Major William
                    McLaughlin to represent the state Senate district composed of Rockbridge, Bath,
                    and Highland counties; Hugh W. Sheffey, Esq., for reelection to the House of
                    Delegates; James Walker for reelection to House of Delegates; Howe Y. Peyton,
                    Esq., to represent Augusta County in House of Delegates; Colonel William H.
                    Harman for House of Delegates; Major Absalom Koiner for House of Delegates; and
                    H. K. Gregg for House of Delegates from refugees from Clarke County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also includes war news, letters announcing candidacy or endorsing
                candidates in the upcoming election, a reprint of Governor Letcher's proclamation
                regarding the upcoming election, a reprint of a list of deserters from the Staunton
                Artillery, legal notices, and assorted advertisements and announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
