<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1863/va.au.rv.1863.03.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/02/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/2/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-06">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bold Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Burr reiterated that Mr. Lincoln was a greater traitor than Jeff
                    Davis, and if his abolition policy was permitted to go on, he (Mr. B),
                    maintained that Jefferson Davis was fighting for liberties in the North, as well
                    as those of his fellow citizens in the South."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>C. C. Burr, at a speech at the Philadelphia Democratic Club, asserted that
                    the United States had no rights except state's rights and that the current
                    abolition policy was a disgrace.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Northwestern Virginia</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Pierpont's bogus government is getting into bad odor, and is openly and
                    severely denounced by leading influential men, who have heretofore not
                    co-operated with the South."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a meeting held at the courthouse in Wheeling of persons opposed
                    to establishing a new state and recounts the response to this meeting as
                    published in a pro-new state newspaper, the Intelligencer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>M. G. Harman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>E. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harman expresses thanks to the Waynesboro Soldier's Aid Society for a
                    barrel of socks and shirts for the regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To Our Farmers--Plant Corn</head>
                <origin>R. Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Should our planters, labouring under the belief that a state of peace will
                    ensure before the maturing of the next crop, and that belief turn out to be a
                    failure, plant large crops of cotton, to the exclusion of grain, the most
                    disastrous results will, in our opinion, be felt by our government."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages farmers to plant corn and other foodstuffs in order to feed the
                    armies. The Examiner argues that farmers can show their patriotism by planting
                    food instead of planting cotton for profit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary>The Lynchburg "Virginian" well remarks.</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages farmers to grow corn and other food stuffs and not be lured into
                    growing tobacco.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From the Spectator</head>
                <origin>Spectator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>This letter from "a refugee from Clark County" calls for the election of
                    William L. Goggin of Bedford as governor, Alex. R. Boteler of Jefferson as
                    lieutenant governor, and William H. Harman of Augusta for attorney general.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Seeks to confirm rumors that the 133d regiment of New York Volunteers,
                    under the command of General Banks, has had trouble after the introduction of
                    African-American troops. Officers have resigned or refused to recognize the
                    troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Mississippian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes a man from Mississippi who says that more than one thousand slaves
                    carried away by Northern troops have returned voluntarily to their owners,
                    citing the poor conditions and bad treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The top third of column five is missing. This page also carries excerpts of
                other war news and a report from the state legislature.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1863.03.06">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Impressment of Supplies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor responds to an editorial from the Spectator, which stated that
                    farmers would not grow more than their families needed unless they had some
                    guarantee against or compensation for impressment of their harvest. The editor
                    of the Vindicator asserts that farmers of the Confederacy will continue to raise
                    whatever is necessary for the army out of patriotism, not because of
                    legislation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Conscription in the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Let us then do all that we can to add to the comfort and efficiency of our
                    brave men in arms, and prepare to meet, at every point, these myrmidons of the
                    Tyrannical Dictator, with invincible forces."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial cites new conscription efforts in the North that may raise
                    the number of troops to one million. This number should not intimidate the
                    Southern troops, however, which already "have had to meet great odds in every
                    conflict."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Concerts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The cornet band of the 5th Virginia Infantry performed concerts last
                    Tuesday and Wednesday for large audiences. The proceeds from Tuesday's concert
                    will benefit the soldiers; those from Wednesday will benefit soldiers' wives and
                    children in Staunton. The total amount raised was nearly $600.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Artificial Leg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Hanger of Augusta County lost his leg in the battle of Phillippi but
                    has made an artificial one for himself that enables him to walk without a cane
                    or a noticeable lameness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Houses pillaged, families driven to the winds of winter for shelter and
                    comfort, virtue outraged, and a brutal soldiery permitted, without let or
                    hindrance, to revel and riot in the misery and destitution of as pure virtue and
                    as proud patriotism as ever adorned our race. Whilst these heart-rendering
                    scenes are being enacted, what is being done to stay them?"</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial praises the sacrifices made by the people of the Valley,
                    deplores their current condition, and condemns Brigadier General Jones, the
                    commander of the forces of the Valley, for his poor leadership and contribution
                    to the poor conditions in the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Robbery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burwell</ln>
                        <fn>T. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The store of T. C. Burwell, deceased, was robbed last Saturday night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Barn Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Walter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Walter Davis's barn near Barterbrook burned Tuesday night, along with three
                    horses. Arson is suspected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation by the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Davis calls for a day of "fasting, humiliation and prayer" on
                    Friday, March 27, asking God to continue mercy toward the Confederate cause, to
                    scatter the enemy, and to restore peace and security.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Soldier Drowned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Artidore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Artidore Bear, son of John Bear of Greenville, drowned last Friday
                    attempting to cross the South River at Waynesboro. He was on his way home on
                    furlough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKim</ln>
                        <fn>Randolph H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes Gray</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Agnes Gray Phillips, daughter of Rev. R. H. Phillips of Staunton, married
                    Randolph H. McKim of Baltimore on Thursday, February 26, at Trinity Church, with
                    Rev. Phillips officiating and Rev. Mr. Latane assisting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tisdale</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>Ann S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann S. Powers married John W. Tisdale, both of Augusta County, on February
                    5, with Rev. C. S. M. See officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leech</ln>
                        <fn>George V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brady</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parr</ln>
                        <fn>Martha V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha V. Parr married George M. Brady on February 16, with Rev. George V.
                    Leech officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Paris, 86, died at his home on February 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cherry</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Cherry, 46, died January 24 near Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Birah</ln>
                        <fn>Alice C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Birah</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alice C. Birah, daughter of Judge Birah of Clinton County, Missouri, died
                    of typhoid fever on February 22 at the home of Lewis Bumgardner in Greenville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Susan Alice Landes, 1, infant daughter of J. W. and Annie Landes from near
                    Mt. Sidney, died January 28 of chronic croup.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Top third of column three is missing. This page also contains a report from
                the Confederate Congress, a calendar, and advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
