<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0011"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0011">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Eliza H. Stanton to Margaret Dunlap,
                    January 5, 1858</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county eliza h stanton to margaret dunlap, january 5 1858</title>
        <author>Stanton, Eliza H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sarah Parnes</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A0011</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501786</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Eliza H. Stanton to Margaret Dunlap, January 5, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county eliza h stanton to margaret dunlap, january 5 1858</title>
            <author>Eliza H. Stanton</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Dunlop Family Correspondence, 2nd
                            83:g, 6th 13:A, Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North
                        Carolina</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-01-05">1858-01-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Arts/Leisure</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0011T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Eliza H. Stanton writes Mag Dunlap to discuss news of their friends and how she
                    spent her Christmas.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-01-05">
                            <hi rend="underline">January the 5th 1858</hi>
                        </date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Mag</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have just read your letter and was very glad to <orig reg="hear">here</orig>
                    from you again, yours found me well and quite happy;; I receive your <orig
                        reg="favor">favour</orig> of october the 12th And <orig reg="wrote"
                    >rote</orig> an answer to it a few evenings after;; But on <orig reg="reviewing"
                        >revewing</orig> it I <orig reg="concluded">concluted</orig> not to send you
                    that answer But <orig reg="write">rite</orig> another; <orig reg="deferring"
                        >defering</orig> it from time to time the present evening has <orig
                        reg="arrived">arived</orig> with out it being answered; Not because I did
                    not wish to answer it + from the fact that I did not have time; As another
                    reason was that I did not know what to <unclear>write</unclear> to you,, you
                    still wish to come here to live, I have not heard any thing about Miss Lamb
                    going to leave I rather think that a <orig reg="mistake">misstake</orig>,; As I
                    have not heard any thing about any the <unclear>attendance</unclear> leaving, I
                    for my part do not know how long I may stay; or how soon I may leave, I have no
                    notion of leaving here now, if I should take the notion to leave why I will
                        <orig reg="write">rite</orig> to you and let you know you wish to know what
                    kind of a Christmas I had; May I first tell you it was as dry a Christmas as
                    ever a seen in my life; I have seen no Christmas yet; nor <orig reg="New Year"
                        >newyear</orig> either This night a week <orig reg="ago">a go</orig> I was
                    at a party in town; the party was given by the Firemen of Staunton; They were
                    not many there that I was acquainted with; I enjoyed myself tolerable well
                    considering all things; The <orig reg="amusement">immusement</orig> of the
                    evening was <orig reg="dancing">danceing</orig>; of which in <orig reg="course"
                        >corse</orig> i did not take part in it; there fore did not do anything but
                    look on and say nothing, you <orig reg="write">rite</orig> as though Mag Potmer
                    was going it Strong with <pb n="2"/>
                    <orig reg="someone">some one</orig>, success to her; I wish that I may soon hear
                    the same good news from you; Bob Strawsburg is gone to the West <hi
                        rend="underline">Why</hi> I am not <orig reg="surprised">supprise</orig> to
                        <orig reg="hear">here</orig> that you wish to come here, But my Dear Friend
                    there is no use to cry over spilt milk the best way is to take it easy Tell Mag
                    that she must ask me to her wedding when ever she gets <orig reg="married"
                        >maried</orig> you speak of the singing in West View being very <orig
                        reg="interesting">interresting</orig>, I was glad to here that, We have no
                    sing here now nor have they had any <orig reg="since">scince</orig> I have <orig
                        reg="been">bin</orig> here</p>

                <p>Dear Mag the thoughts crosses my mind of the time we had <orig reg="at"
                    >att</orig> Bethelham They are past and gone; But the joyous moments spent there
                    will never loose their <orig reg="influence">influance</orig> over me; They are
                    days when my mind wanders back in the past; And gains <orig reg="strength"
                        >streanth</orig> there from; oh shall we who name the name of Christ ever
                    grow <orig reg="weary">wery</orig> in well doing I pray you that we may not Dear
                    Mag I must close for the present <orig reg="hoping">hopeing</orig> that I may
                    hear soon from you; So good night Mag pleasant <orig reg="dreams">dreames</orig>
                    throng thy brain Till I shall <orig reg="hear">here</orig> from you again</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Yours in the bonds of Amity</hi>
                    </salute>
                    <signed>Eliza H. Stanton<lb/>Va<lb/></signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">PS <orig reg="Write">Wright</orig> Soon <name
                            type="recipient">To Miss Mag Dunlap<lb/>West View<lb/><hi
                                rend="underline">Va</hi></name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
