<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0304"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0304">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James B. McCutchan to his Cousin, February 23,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james b mccutchan to his cousin, february 23 1863</title>
        <author>McCutchan, James B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0304</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501812</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: James B. McCutchan to his Cousin, February 23, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta james b mccutchan to his cousin, february 23 1863</title>
            <author>James B. McCutchan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Rockbridge Historical Society Collection, Special
       Collections, Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-02-23">1863-02-23</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualites, Family, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0304T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>McCutchan relates the harsh winter conditions in camp and mentions that although there is
     word his cousin, James R. McCutchan might be dead, he still holds hope that he is alive.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-02-23">Feb 23rd 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Winder</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Cousin</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your long looked for and welcome letter a few days ago, I was somewhat surprised
     when I received it. I had come to the conclusion that you did not intend to write any more to
     me, well I will not treat you so bad as you did me, and will write sooner although I am afraid
     it will fail <unclear>in</unclear> interest - we have no news of importance here now times are
     very dull. It is reported that old Joe Hooker has left the Rappahanock, and I suppose it is
     true. I would just as leave he had advanced here as any where <pb n="2"/>else and rather I
     believe. I suppose he has concluded that it would not be healthy on this side of the river.
     Some of the troops have been <orig reg="moving">moveing</orig> away form here, don't know where
     they have gone. I hope we will not have to leave <orig reg="until">untill</orig> the weather
     moderates some, we have had some prety rough weather, it <orig reg="snows">snowes</orig> or
     rains nearly every day. it snowed all day yesterday it is about a foot deep. it is clear today
     and the snow is melting some. we have our wood to carry a long ways now and I tell you it is a
     pretty tough job, but I will be content to carry the wood if they will just leave us here until
     warm weather. when we do leave this camp we will have to carry all that we take along. it will
     be as much as our poor horses can do to take the empty wagons out. I never saw the like of mud
     before. I thought it was bad at <unclear>Romney</unclear> last winter, there was some bottom in
     the mountains but there don't appear to be any here, there is nothing but sand here. I don't
     think I have seen a rock as big as a mans head since we came here except just on the bank of
     the River. well I believe I will stop for the present and do some washing while the sun shines,
     will finish this to night. Well I have done a big days washing, pretty hard job, will now
     finish my letter - <pb n="3"/>I received a letter from home this evening stating that it is
     thought that Ja's R. is dead. I am sorry indeed to hear it and still have some hopes that it is
     not so. <unclear>Of</unclear> that this cruel war was over alas there are many that started out
     that will not return when it is over. I wish I was by your fire with you tonight. I think I
     could interest you more that I can on this poor sheet. I hope the time will soon come when that
      <orig reg="privilege">priveledge</orig> will no longer <orig reg="denied">denyed</orig>. Well
     Cousin I must draw this poor affair to a close. I miss <unclear>save</unclear> (the dear
     creature) a few lines tonight I have not <orig reg="written">wrote</orig> to her for three
     months. Give my love to Cousin Lizzie and all the rest of the folks. Excuse mistakes.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>As ever your true Cousin</salute>
     <signed>Ja's B. McCutchan</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Yates just now told me that Louis D has been up to see you. he must be
      getting <unclear/> he has been to Lexington by this time</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
