<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0305"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0305">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James B. McCutchan to his Cousin, October 29,
     1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james b mccutchan to his cousin, october 29 1862</title>
        <author>McCutchan, James B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A0305</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501813</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: James B. McCutchan to his Cousin, October 29, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta james b mccutchan to his cousin, october 29 1862</title>
            <author>James B. McCutchan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Rockbridge Historical Society Collection, Special
       Collections, Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-10-29">1862-10-29</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Troop Movement,
      Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A0305T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>McCutchan describes a skirmish near Shepherdstown in which his brigade was heavily shelled
     and had to retreat to Bunker Hill. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-10-29">Oct. 29th 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Camp in Clark County - Near Berryville</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Cousin,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I don't remember whether I answered your last letter or not. but don't think I did I <orig
      reg="reckon">recon</orig> you think that I am a very careless kind of <orig reg="fellow"
     >felow</orig>, well I acknowledge that - I am. I will just tell you how it is, I have almost
     quit writing letters and I <orig reg="scarcely">scarsely</orig> know who I do owe letters. I
     have found time to write home and that is about all, we have been <orig reg="moving"
     >moveing</orig> about so much, and are so poorly fixed when we are in camp that one has no
     satisfaction at all in writing. I have made out to write home occasionaly and that is about
     all. We have a pretty nice camp now, and I will try and write some letters. We came to this
     place yesterday, came from Bunker Hill. I am very well satisfied with the change if they will
      <orig reg="let">lett</orig> us stay here. We are camped in a <orig reg="large">larg</orig> and
     beautiful forest, and in a beautiful and wealthy country. Well we have have had a pretty hard
     time of it for the last two or three weeks. It consisted in marching tearing up and burning
     railroad, burning public buildings (in Martinsburg) fighting &amp;c. Our Brigade had a
     pretty sharp little fight on the 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> near Shepherdstown, but the yankees
     were too strong for us, so we had to retreat. not much <unclear>don</unclear> on either side.
     we lost several men <orig reg="killed">kiled</orig> and some wounded none in our company. They
      <orig reg="shelled">sheled</orig> us at a <orig reg="tremendous">tremendus</orig> rate. I
     thought at one time that we would nearly all be cut down but we got orders to retreat in time.
     our dead was left in the field, but were got and buried the next day. We had a terrible time
     that night. It got dark soon after the fight <pb n="2"/> was over and it was not long until it
     commenced raining very hard then it got dark indeed. The 4th and 5 companies of the 5th
     regiment was cut off from the rest of the Brigade and had to retreat on a different road. We
     marched on through the dark, mud and rain, until we got within two miles of Bunkerhill when we
     received orders to march back about 5 miles and throw out pickets. We started back and had
      <orig reg="gone">gon</orig> about two miles when <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Williams,
     (who was in command) found that the men could not stand it much longer, stopped and sent a
     dispatch on to know what to do. Then received orders to camp or go on to Bunker Hill. we had
     then made fires so stayed all night. Started in the morning, stiff, sore and hungry. got to
     camp cooked a days rations and started to Martinsburg that evening, had a big time down there.
     Oh how I wish that I could be with you for a while. I know I could tell you more than I can
     write and I know that it would interest you a great deal more. We will have to be content with
     things as they come, perhaps there is a better time coming for some of us it is to be hoped any
     way. We have no war news now everything is quiet. It seems that we are doomed to stay in camp
     another winter. It is beginning to feel a good deal like winter now. The nights are pretty
     cold, cold enough to have tents, don't know whether we are going to get any or not. Well I must
     stop for the present I hope I will find time to write oftener hereafter. Give my love to all
     inquiring friends, reserve a portion for yourself. Write soon and Direct to Winchester </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>As ever your Affectionate cousin</salute>
     <signed>Ja's B. McCutchan</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">[note added by recipient] Rec'vd Nov 11 1862 Pa brought it from the <del
       hand="h1"/></seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
