<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0312"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A0312">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James R. McCutchan to Rachel Ann
                    McCutchan, May 2, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james r mccutchan to rachel ann mccutchan, may 2 1864</title>
        <author>McCutchan, James R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A0312</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501820</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta : James R. McCutchan to Rachel Ann McCutchan, May 2, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta james r mccutchan to rachel ann mccutchan, may 2 1864</title>
            <author>James R. McCutchan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Rockbridge Historical Society
                            Collection, Special Collections, Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee
                            University, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-02">1864-05-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family,
                        Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A0312T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>James R. McCutchan's poetic letter speaks of his longing for the pleasant spring
                    days of his youth and the company of his friends. He also describes a long march
                    his company had to make to the New River and back. The letter also contains
                    references to the presence of "hard looking' women in camp, and the death of a
                    young woman, possibly his cousin.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-02">May 2nd, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Greenbrier County</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Rate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I will try + write you a few lines this lovely morning. Such beautiful spring
                    weather gives me the <unclear>blues</unclear> it recalls to memory scenes of
                    long ago, to roam over hills, through ravines, governed alone, by the dictates
                    of my own will. Oh the bright sunshine of one's school days. How well do I
                    remember the many happy hours, I have spent on just such mornings as this - when
                    soft, balmy breath of this youth of the year, was calling the little flowers, +
                    the green grass from out the earth again. How I longed for school hour to come
                    in the morning, when I could hasten away, to the sound of familiar voices, + the
                    sight of familiar faces from whom one night seemed long to be separated.</p>

                <p><pb n="2"/>But those days are gone. The kind voices, + bright smiles, that once
                    greeted me. I no longer see or hear. When I was free + happy but now I am living
                    that life which I once looked forward to with pleasure. I see + feel the
                    coldness and selfishness of the world, + in the solitude of my heart I look
                    'round, + in the vast concourse of human beings, I can see not one to whom I can
                    pour out my sorrows or receive the answering sigh of sympathy.</p>

                <p>Evening. I had to stop my writing + go on drill. When I came back, I found about
                    a dozen ladies in camp, they were such hard looking cases, though, that I was
                    afraid to go close to them. I think from the way they crowded around the band
                    when it began to play, that some of them never had been from home before. <pb
                        n="3"/> When we shall leave this camp, I am not able to say, we hear a
                    thousand different rumours about going, but so far they have all turned out to
                    be false.</p>

                <p>It is now reported that the "Doodles" are coming, + it is my opinion, if we don't
                    have to fight this week that <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Jenkins will be
                    here in a few days, + send us for our horses.</p>

                <p>I hope he may soon come, I want to be mounted, + get away from here. We had a
                    right hard march about a week ago, a hundred of us were marched to the Narrows
                    of New river for arms. We made the trip there + back a distance of ninety <abbr
                        expan="miles">mls</abbr> in four days + a half. </p>

                <p>I have <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> letters from three of my
                    <unclear>M</unclear> friends who were in the penitentiary with me they were
                    exchanged some time after I was at City Point at Petersburg they formed a
                        <unclear>co</unclear> calling themselves the <pb n="4"/>1st Missouri <abbr
                        expan="Cavalry">Cav.</abbr> + are now under Imboden's command.</p>

                <p>I <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> a letter from <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to day. I am
                    glad that Sue is better from what I had heard I was fearful she would not
                    recover.</p>

                <p>I never was so <unclear>sh</unclear> as when I read your note telling me that
                    Susie was dead. How little did I think when I left your house, 'twas the last
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> should see her. Oh it seems so <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that little
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> like <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> must die, <unclear>wh</unclear> have
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> done wrong. But we dont <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> what is best <del
                        hand="h1"/> than we are + we can be her again in Heaven.</p>

                <p>You must write to me soon. It is probable I may get home for my horse, though I
                    am not sure that I shall. Give my love to all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
