<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0324"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
 <TEI.2 id="A0324"> 
 <teiHeader type="migrated"> 
  
    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Philip H. Powers to [?], May 4, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county philip h powers to , may 4 1864</title>
        <author>Powers, P. H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Peter Brownfeld</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Peter Brownfeld</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 
  
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 
  
        <idno type="VCDH">A0324</idno> 
  
        <!--
 <availability> 
 <p>Publicly accessible </p> 
 <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
 <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the  
 University of Virginia</p> 
 </availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date> 
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501832</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil  
 War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 
  
      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: P. H. Powers to [?], May 4, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county p h powers to , may 4 1864</title>
            <author>P. H. Powers</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>7 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Photocopy from the collection of  
 Fredericksburg-Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,  
 Fredericksburg, Virginia.</idno> 
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Several lines are cut off from this copy. This is signifed by  
 "...".</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 
  
    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-05-04">1864-05-04</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>Troop Movement, Battle Description</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term> 
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 
  
    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date> 
        <respStmt> 
          <resp/> 
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name> 
        </respStmt> 
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
 </teiHeader> 
  
 <text id="A0324T"> 
 <front id="d2"> 
 <div1 type="summary" id="d3"> 
 <p>Powers describes recent troop movements and despairs of the deaths and  
 casualties around him.</p> 
 </div1> 
 </front> 
  
 <body id="d4"> 
 <div1 type="letter" id="d5"> 
 <head> 
 <name type="recipient">[No name]</name> 
 </head> 
  
 <opener> 
 <dateline> 
 <date value="1864-05-04">Wednesday May 4 1864</date> 
 </dateline> 
 <salute></salute> 
 </opener> 
  
 <p>My letter had hardly reached the office and I was lying down suffering with  
 neuralgia, when I heard the Genl's clear voice say "<hi  
 rend="underline">pack</hi> <hi rend="underline">up.</hi>" I knew what was  
 coming and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as I was got up and went to work.  we moved this  
 afternoon some five <sic>mile</sic> towards Fredericksburg.  And are in camp by  
 the road side.  I am hardly able to march but I hate to be absent at such a time  
 and do not wish to go to the Hospital, so I will struggle on - hoping the  
 neuralgia will leave me tomorrow - I will sleep in a house to night.  The Whole  
 Army is in motion and the great battle will soon begin.  There are <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>  
 notes <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> which I will <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> down as I can and send you for a  
 letter.  Good night - </p><pb n="2"/> 
  
 <p>Thursday-- I have had a bad day. My love-- Such a terrible pain in my eye.   
 We moved about fifteen miles closer down ... battle had commenced on our left  
 with Ewells Corps.  His firing was terrific but <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Stuart told me a  
 while ago that the old wooden leg soldier with his veterans whipped the 4th  
 Yankee Corps badly - Capturing 2000 prisoners and 4 <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> -- our loss  
 heavy.  Genl. Jones (from Charlottesville) and Genl. Stafford killed.  Also poor  
 William Randolph was <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> of the 2nd Va.  The  
 Regt. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to lose its commanding officers.  Randolph was just wounded  
 last week. I saw him &amp; his wife at John Ballords.  They were in fine  
 spirits.  He remarked that he thought bad luck had run with the regt. long  
 enough.  He thought it would<pb n="3"/> change and he escape.  God, not  
 luck, <unclear>disposer</unclear> of our lives.  And he <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> poor fellow  
 - has fallen another martyr to Southern liberty and his young wife, so bright  
 and happy a few days ago, is today a widow and her unborn baby fatherless.  Oh  
 the dreary <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> hearts that this day has made, and the blacker day  
 <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> tomorrow!  I feel sad and <unclear>wretched</unclear>  
 over it all.  My <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> has gotten <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, but my heart grows sick  
 when I think of the awful scenes around me.  Genl. Lee and Genl. Stuart are in  
 fine spirits.  May God give us a victory and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> this cruel war!  This  
 is a dreary <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> country.  Most <unclear>fifty</unclear> <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>  
 sickness for many miles, not a house and not an open field.  Nothing but a  
 wilderness of trees and<pb n="4"/> underbrush and marsh and perfectly flat.   
 We are in a small field by the road side about 2 miles from the city of Battle -  
 And here are Genl. Lee and Genl Stuart's Hqrs -- and an <hi rend="underline">  
 infinity </hi> of wagons and artillery.  But I must try to get a place to  
 sleep.  I am taking Quinine hoping to drive off Neuralgia tomorrow.  Have seen  
 Jim today.  Adieau -</p> 
  
 <p> Friday morning -- What a din. What an uproar! -- the very heavens seem  
 filled with sound.  And in the midst of it all I sit by the road side and write  
 to you my dear Thanking God that you do not hear what I hear, nor see what I see  
 this awful day.  The battle recommenced about sun-rise and as I write seems to  
 be raging<pb n="5"/> with intense fury.  Oh how my heart sickens as I listen  
 and think of the untold misery arising from this bloody day.  Have you ever  
 imagined a battle field and its vicinity, the throng of men hurrying to &amp;  
 fro, the trains of wagons and artillery passing and repassing apparently in  
 inextricable Confusion.  All is bewildering to the spectator.  And yet how  
 strange that one master mind should control all and bring desired results from  
 this Chaos of War.  At intervals there is a perfect Calm, and you might imagine  
 all over, when suddenly the whole heavens reverberate with the clamor of the  
 contending hords -</p> 
  
 <p>Genl. S. has gone off in fine spirits to lead his Cavalry. May God protect  
 him this day is my earnest prayer -<pb n="6"/></p> 
  
 <p>It is now 8 o'clock and the last report from Genl. Lee was that he was  
 driving the enemy back handsomely.  This seems <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> from this sound.  The  
 firing having ceased in the centre - but Ewell is still keeping it up on the  
 left.  Longstreet came up this morning.  I think we will whip them and be able  
 to tell you tonight.  My head is much easier today but I feel weak.  Jim took  
 breakfast with us.  He managed to have something cooked even on the  
 <unclear>verge</unclear> of the battle field at 5 o'clock.  So far as heard from  
 we have been successful in the day's fight - And the Yankees are falling back.   
 The fighting has not been as continuous as I expected this morning.  No  
 artillery hardly can be used - But my impression is that the fight will be  
 renewed tomorrow - in fact<pb n="7"/> is not over for today -- firing is  
 still going on.</p> 
  
 <p>I am sorry to tell you Genl. Longstreet was wounded in the shoulder to day -  
 they say by our own men. His wound is not considered dangerous.  Genl. Jenkins  
 was killed today and Col. J. Thompson Brown was.  A courier is just going off  
 and I send this.  The field of battle is between Chancellorsville and  
 Verdeersville in the Wilderness.  I write again tomorrow.</p> 
  
 <closer> 
 <salute>Ever yours</salute> 
 <signed>P.H. Powers</signed> 
 <seg type="postscript">Excuse my paper 
 </seg> 
 </closer> 
 </div1> 
 </body> 
 </text> 
 </TEI.2> 
  
 