<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0339"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0339">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: George P. Kersh to Adam W. Kersh,
                    January 25, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county george p kersh to adam w kersh, january 25 1862</title>
        <author>Kersh, George P. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0339</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501847</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: George P. Kersh to Adam W. Kersh, January 25, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county george p kersh to adam w kersh, january 25 1862</title>
            <author>George P. Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>The second paragraph of the postscript was unsigned but likely
                                written by Elizabeth J. "Josey" Kersh, the thirteen-year-old
                                daughter of George P. Kersh.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-01-25">1862-01-25 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Family, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals, Women </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0339T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh writes about work and about sickness at home. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Adam W. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-01-25">January 25, 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Mount Crawford, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I again seat myself to inform you that we are all tolerable well my children I
                    fear are about to take the whooping cough they all take coughing spells except
                    Martha Mother, Jane &amp; myself are well and I hope when these lines reach
                    you they may find you well we have a snow here now about four inches deep it
                    fell yesterday 24th. today is pleasant Sunshine R. F. Lisner &amp; Ambrose
                    Moyers are now at home on furlough Bob staid all night with us. today he is
                    making a pair of wooden stirrups in your shop I have not worked in the shop
                    three hours since the middle of July consequently I keep it locked after I came
                    from the mountains I found it necessary to take that precaution your tools are
                    all safe and in the order you left them except a few not very valuable ones
                    which were hooked Whilst we were in service I have a boy now hired by the name
                    of Geo. A. Back son of James sixteen years old he is a great help to me I had
                    expected to have been out there to see you and my friends and acquaintances
                    before this but did not meet with the chance however I will now state that
                    Samuel Plecker and myself will come out there in a few weeks in my one horse
                    wagon and bring you some rations along that we think you stand in need of </p>
                <p> I Received your letter some eight or ten days ago you stated you wished me to
                    tend to that affair between yourself and H Frye I have done so. Mrs. Hary Fry
                    Paid Esq.Fulton $142 independent of the note or bond of John Craun's
                    consequently Harry Fry now owes $42 on his lot Esq. Fulton holds the Bond of
                    John Craun it is now left to you whether I shall take Craun's Bond back or leave
                    it in Fultons hands the other Bond that Fry has taken and paid Click I know
                    nothing about. you and Fry for that I seems that Fry is now quite able to pay
                    for his lot I wonder if he made any of that money by gambling. Esq. Fulton
                    explained the case to me about the lot you are safe I think in every respect In
                    your next letter I want you to State whether this affair was transacted as you
                    wanted it Samuel Whitmore said I must write to you to inform you that he wishes
                    to settle for his yearly Rent if you wish me to tend to it I will do so We are
                    looking for you home now every day on furlough you must come as soon as you can
                    Aunt Easter Landes is still poorly and in feeble health I must now close excuse
                    this hastily written letter </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Brother </salute>
                    <signed>George P Kersh </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. Grandmother says she is just tolerable well you
                        stated in your letter that you would like to have A shirt or two have got
                        you two one is a cotton flannel one we tried in Staunton and in Harrisonburg
                        but could get nothing else but cotton flannel and as soon as we get a chance
                        we will send it to you Papay and Mr. Samuel Plecker talk of coming out in a
                        week or two I want you to get a furlough as soon as you can I would like to
                        see you very well if you need any thing you must write<lb/><lb/> Dear uncle
                        I must tell you that I received your letter and was glad to hear from you
                        Mr. Evers is here now and he says I must tell you he sends you his best
                        respects and wants you to come home and play the fiddle he is still teaching
                        school his school is increasing very much Louisa says I must tell you that
                        she would like to see you Georgianna says she is going to take old roach and
                        come and bring you home tell cousin Jacob <unclear>Craun</unclear> that we
                        are all tolerable well </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
