<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0343"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

  
<TEI.2 id="A0343">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    May 8, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 8 1863</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0343</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501851</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, May 8, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 8 1863</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Photocopy from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia.</p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-05-08">1863-05-08 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Home Front, Troop
                        Movement, Military Strategy </term>
                    <term>52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000-07">July 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0343T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh comments on the news of Stonewall Jackson's wounding.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-05-08">May 8, 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Spotsylvania County, VA</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I take this opportunity to write you a few lines to let you know that I am well
                    and hope these few lines may find you enjoying good health I received your
                    letter dated the 19th of April on the 1st of May I also received the letter you
                    had written before Stating that you had rented the farm and about J Smiths
                    contrariness And had answered it some time ago and was waiting for an answer is
                    the reason I did not write sooner </p>
                <p>Probably it will or has come to hand now as they are a long time on the road some
                    times You sated in your letter that D A Plecker wishes to buy my house and lot
                    in Centerville He had spoke to me about it some time ago and I told him I would
                    not sell and when you see him tell him I dont wish to sell You were speaking of
                    folks wanting to rent my house and lot I will rent it to any good respectful
                    person for one year at 30 dollars </p>
                <p>I will now write some about the fight on the 29th of April the Yankees commenced
                    crossing the river about a half mile below Fredericksburg they drove our Pickets
                    - - - (3 or 4 words torn out) company of the 13th Georgians and killed some few
                    but nothing like the number we killed of theirs We were ordered down there about
                    day light and put in the ditches in line of battle Skirmishers were out and some
                    firing was done and shelling during - day but not many were hurt On the 30th
                    some firing amongst the skirmishers and some shelling done not much damage done
                    may lst everything quiet except a shot occasionally amongst the skirmishers Our
                    regiment went on skirmish the Yankees recrossed the river some shelling done the
                    Yankees left a good many things behind </p>
                <p>We then ordered up the river about ten miles where General Lee was fighting we
                    marched about 8 miles and was ordered back to Fredericksburg to the ditches the
                    Yankees were crossing back again we got back about 12 o'clock in the night May
                    the 3rd Our batteries opened this morning about 7 o'clock and a hot shelling was
                    kept up for about 3 hours and then ceased they poured it into our batteries like
                    thunder but our artillerymen held their position nobly and gave them as good as
                    they sent while this was going on the Yankees were flanking us on the our left
                    Our force was not strong enough to keep them back they took about eight hundred
                    prisoners Alabamians and Mississappians and about eight pieces of artillery they
                    gained our heights above Fredericksburg reinforcements come in then and held
                    them in check we killed a good many of them more then they killed of ours eight
                    of our artillerymen were killed and about 12 wounded they have the advantage of
                    us in the way of artillery their artillery is on the other side of the river
                    most of it and heavy pieces ranging with every road - - - <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>- - we
                    bring our troops in we were ordered back this evening in the rear on our left to
                    reinforce our left where we lay in line of battle all night May 4th the next
                    morning we advanced towards the enemy exposed to Shells which they threw at us
                    in abundance but not many were hurt in our brigade we were held in reserve about
                    5 O'clock the general fight commenced our men charged them and drove them like
                    chaff before the wind during the action one man in our regiment in Company was
                    killed by the name of Alves and one wounded by the of Rosen about sunset we were
                    ordered to the field to reinforce but when we got there the firing had ceased so
                    we were not in the fight at all Our men drove them back about 4 miles next to
                    the river got the heights back we took about one thousand prisoners and killed a
                    great many of them more than they killed of ours. They say we had one division
                    against thirty thousand in this fight they crossed back during the night on the
                    other side May the 5th we were ordered to fall back they threw, shells at us
                    like forty got about a mile and was ordered back that the Yankees were about
                    crossing below Fredericksburg they Yankees kept throwing shells at us one fell
                    in our regiment and killed four men and wounded seven Company A Joseph Curry
                    killed Stoggle Lieutenant Kenny wounded Co K killed Archy and McClong wounded
                    Gilliott lieutenant Lindsay Company G Hen Sipes killed Company C lieutenant
                    Wellar wounded it is another one wounded I cant think of his name </p>
                <p>None in our Company got hurt our regiment did not get to fire gun the whole eight
                    days the Yankees had all went back on the other side of the river when we left
                    and said they did not intend to fire on us now for a while they did not throw
                    any shells at us when we left we arrived in our old camp on the 7th The hardest
                    fight was above us where Lee and Jackson fought them they it was the (hardest)
                    fight thats been fought yet the ground is blue with Yankees they had about nine
                    thousand Yankee prisoners at Guinea station taken in the fight they say Stewart
                    captured four thousand cavalry near the central railroad I will close as you
                    will get the news in the papers better then I can give a I dont know the
                    particulars </p>
                <p>General Earley had command in the Frederiscksburg Fight Extra Billy Smith has
                    command of our brigade </p>
                <p>They say that Jackson was wounded one arm was taken off and two fingers of the
                    other hand excuse this badly written letter as I wrote it in a hurry </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
