<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0351"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A0351">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh,
                    May 12, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 12 1864</title>
        <author>Kersh, Adam Wise </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matthew Kelly </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 8</num> kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0351</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501858</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Adam Wise Kersh to George P. Kersh, May 12, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county adam wise kersh to george p kersh, may 12 1864</title>
            <author>Adam Wise Kersh </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Typescript from the collection of Fredericksburg-
                            Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military Park,
                            Fredericksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-05-12">1864-05-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 52nd Va. Inf. </term>
                    <term>Company: F </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0351T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kersh writes in detail about the casualties and destruction resulting from the
                    battle of the Wilderness.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">George P. Kersh </name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-05-12">May 12, 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Near Fredericksburg, VA </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Brother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Skirmishing all along the lines whipped them on the right May 10th fighting along
                    the lines Yankees charged our breastworks 11 times and were repulsed broke
                    through once but were driven back with great slaughter our loss small They
                    captured our Division Ordnance train to day </p>
                <p>Wednesday the 11th Skirmishing all along the lines </p>
                <p>Thursday the 12th this morning the Yankees made a great charge on our breast
                    works Jones Brigade gave Adam Wiseay and they got through our brigade was on the
                    reserve we charged them and drove them back they got through at several other
                    places but were driven back again with great slaughter by Jones men giving Adam
                    Wiseay others had to giveAdam Wiseay to keep from getting flanked Wounded in our
                    company in this charge David Snell in wrist but not very badly and Sergeant C
                    Walker in the face not serious And myself very slightly on the head with spent
                    ball is all in our company Our loss in officers is greater than privates
                    according Colonel Skinner was badly wounded in the face Captain Airheart was
                    wounded Lieut. Weller wounded Lieut. Fry wounded and two Paxton lieutenants in
                    Rockbridge Company Captain Humphreys wounded Lieut. Coiner killed Our doctor was
                    killed by a shell while we were supporting our lines Doctor Edwinson We have two
                    doctors with our regiment yet Gibson and Ewings </p>
                <p>Nothing but sharpshooting for the last three or four days here we are lying
                    behind our breastworks waiting for the enemy to advance killed wounded and
                    missing in our regiment 78 total 18 commisioned officers 4 killed 10 privates
                    killed dead balance wounded <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                </p>
                <p>Some think that old Grant is crossing back but I dont believe if they are
                    fortifying in our front still As you have got the news of this fight long before
                    this I will close I would have written sooner but did not have a chance I am
                    well and hope these few lines will find you in good health excuse badly written
                    letter as I wrote it in a hurry Samuel Artgenbright wishes as to state that he
                    is well let his friends know if you see them </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours respectfully </salute>
                    <signed>Adam W Kersh </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
