<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0579"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0579">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John H. Cochran to His Mother, April
                    14, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john h cochran to his mother, april 14 1861</title>
        <author>Cochran, John H. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0579</idno>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501876</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John H. Cochran to His Mother, April 14, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john h cochran to his mother, april 14 1861</title>
            <author>John H. Cochran </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Cochran Family Letters, 1860-1861, (MS 92-032),
                            Civil War Collections, Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic
                            Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-04-14">1861-04-14 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Enlistment, National Government, Patriotism, State Government</term>
                    <term>Regiment: Wise Legion </term>
                    <term>Company: A </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0579T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Cochran describes the debate and discord in Richmond over the subject of
                    secession. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-04-14">April 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861 </date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Mother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter was received several days ago. But owing to the mail communications
                    being cut off I did not think it worthwhile to write to you before there was
                    some news to write. All of the rail roads to the north were very much damaged so
                    much so that we had no northern mail for several days. The river rose so high
                    that it formed a connection with the dock and at one time looked like it would
                    flood the lower part of the city entirely. Boats were rowed about in the lowest
                    parts of Main and Cary streets. The river has subsided considerably and is fast
                    resuming its <unclear>
                        <orig reg="wanted">wonted</orig>
                    </unclear> bounds.</p>

                <p>If I go south it will be for the double purpose of taking up arms and of
                    attending to the business connected with my grandfathers estate. But I shall
                    wait in Virginia until all hopes of secession or <hi rend="underline">revolution</hi>
                    <orig reg="are">ar</orig> killed. The feeling is growing here that we will have
                    to disperse this convention drive Letcher out of the eastern part of the state
                    divide the state and declare Eastern Virginia free of the West and of the Black
                    Republican Union. News of the surrender of Fort <orig reg="Sumter"
                    >Sumpter</orig> was received here yesterday after a bombardment of nearly thirty
                    hours (not counting the time that both parties ceased firing during the night.)
                    We fired a salute of one hundred guns in honor of the victory on the square
                    under the very noses of the <hi rend="underline">Traitors</hi> to the state who
                    hold their daily "pow wow" in the capitol. After which we hoisted the flag of
                    the Confederated States upon the capitol where it remained until removed in the
                    darkness of night by the order of Letcher. Bonfires <del hand="h1">burnt</del>
                    <orig reg="blazed">blased</orig> in main <orig reg="street">streat</orig> until
                    12 Oclock at night and the city looked like an<pb n="2"/> immense hive.</p>

                <p>Things <orig reg="are">ar</orig> growing warm here and members do not scruple to
                    say <del hand="h1">th</del> in debate that they will divide from the west rather
                    than remain in this disgraced position which the west has made Virginia assume.</p>

                <p>I can not have the stock <orig reg="transferred">transfered</orig> to my name
                    even with an order you will have to do it in person or send a power of attorney.
                    I think it had better remain as it is until you come down.</p>

                <p>Enclosed I send you a piece taken from the Examiner by <orig reg="the">th</orig>
                    paper in which it appears. </p>

                <p>I hope that you have recovered and that all are well. Give my respects to all and
                    believe me your</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>affectionate son </salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John">J.</abbr> H. Cochran </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. Fort Pickins has been reinforced. I think that after
                        its reduction Davis will march on Washington. <lb/> J.H.C. <lb/> P.S. 12
                        O'clock the river has again commenced to rise </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
