<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0749"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A0749">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Aunt, September 28,
     1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his aunt, september 28 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Sally Henninger </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca.<num type="kilobytes"> 7</num> kilobytes </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va.</pubPlace>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1997">1997</date>
        <idno type="VCDH">A0749</idno>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501886</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Aunt, September 28, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his aunt, september 28 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361, Virginia Military
       Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also available online at
       http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html</p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-09-28">1862-09-28</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Home Front</term>
          <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav.</term>
          <term>Company: C</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="A0749T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Langhorne talks about the demand for books and requests certain clothing that his school
     cannot provide. He also suggests that his father should send Maurice to VMI.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Aunt</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-09-28"><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 28, 1862 </date>
      <name type="place">Virginia Military Institute, </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Aunt </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I have been intending to write to you but have been waiting to hear from home but as today is
     Sunday and in the afternoon and I cannot spend my time more profitably I will try to write to
     you knowing at the same time that I have nothing that will interest you. </p>

    <p>Tell <abbr expan="Brother">Bro</abbr> Jim that I received the books &amp; have sold them
     already &amp; I had bought them from the first class men before they reached here. I wish
     he had sent a dozen <orig reg="copies">coppies</orig> of French Grammar as it would be a great
     recommendation to the boys to get them and I could sell every <orig reg="copy">coppy</orig> for
     two $ apiece. When you write ask him <orig reg="whether">wheather</orig> there were any more
      <orig reg="copies">coppies</orig> there or not and at what they can be bought for. </p>

    <p>Dear Aunt I had intended to write you a tolerable long letter but night came before I thought
     it would <orig reg="it is">tis</orig> now after supper and the <orig reg="study">studdy</orig>
     drum will soon beat and as I want some things from home I will just change the subject
     &amp; write for what I want. Tell Pa my gray jacket, <abbr expan="to">2</abbr> order me a
     pair of shoes as I have drilled so much since I have been here that they are nearly worn out
     and General Smith says that it is impossible for him to furnish shoes and the reason I write
     for my jacket is that there is at least 100 boys to get <orig reg="their">there</orig> uniforms
     before me and my coat will not be <orig reg="decent">deacent</orig> to wear to church and if
     any one is not dressed <orig reg="decently">deacently</orig> at church roll call they get 5
     demerits for it and send my old over coat as it is pretty cold here at 5 oclock in the morning
     and standing guard at night.</p>

    <p>You will please tell Ma to send them as soon as possible. Tell Papa if he has not succeeded
     in getting Maurice to some good school to send him here as they have a class here that he is
     perfectly qualified to join and any one is obliged to study some here to get along at all.
     There are some boys here as small as John but they are older than I am. There is scarcely a boy
     in school that is not older than I. I would let you know how I stand in my class if I could see
     the section marcher I would let you know how I stand in my class. I will let you know next
     time.</p>

    <p>Dear Aunt the study drum has beat and I must close. Give my love to all at Edgehill and <orig
      reg="Cousins">Cousine</orig> Fannies &amp; <unclear>Hues</unclear>. I have been thinking
     of you all day. The Misses Baxters send <orig reg="their">there</orig> love. <orig
      reg="Goodbye">Good by</orig>. Kiss Ma for me </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain <orig reg="your">you</orig> attached nephew </salute>
     <signed>Kent </signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
