<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0757"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A0757">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Parents,
                    January 2, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his parents, january 2 1863</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0757</idno>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501894</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Parents, January 2, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his parents, january 2 1863</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-02">1863-01-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Arts/Leisure, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0757T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne writes about examinations and about meeting girls at tea. He also asks
                    about family who have been sick and reports that the school would like to hire
                    three of Uncle Archer's servants. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Parents</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-02">January the 2nd 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Virginia <abbr expan="Military">Mil</abbr> Institute </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Own dear parents </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I commenced writing to you yesterday &amp; wrote upon unruled paper and it
                    was written so indistinctly that I was afraid you could not read it and I
                    determined to write it over. I cannot express my thanks in writing for the nice
                    box you sent me also for the 10$ you sent me for Xmas gift.</p>

                <p>The examination commences today. I think I will get through very well if I do not
                    get confused, but as I was never examined in public before. I feel <orig
                        reg="almost">allmost</orig> certain that I will get through on Geography
                    &amp; French. If they examine me by asking me questions I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> think I will get through but if he gives me examples I think I
                    will get through on Math. I am determined to commence this year by doing my duty
                    as well as I can in <orig reg="everything">every thing</orig>.</p>

                <p>We only had one day Christmas and I was very glad of it. I thought of home so
                    that I did not enjoy my self Xmas day. I was thinking all day about the deaths
                    of poor Henry &amp; Elsy and about the sickness at home since I left. Things
                    will be so much altered when I get home so I cannot enjoy myself at all. There
                    is no enjoyment to be seen now no how.</p>

                <p>Lexington has done more for the soldiers than any place I know for the size of
                    it. They gave nearly 5 hundred carpet blankets to them besides giving 3
                    theatrical performances &amp; the cadets gave a kind of negro show for their
                    benefit. The show given by the cadets cleared 3 hundred dollars. The ladies made
                    about 600 hundred dollars in all of their performances.</p>

                <p>I was invited to the Misses Baxters Monday night to tea and was introduced to 4
                    young ladies. I was never as much confused in my life as I was when they entered
                    the room. I had been in the house nearly an hour when they came in and I was not
                    expecting them <orig reg="at all">atall</orig> as I had been there so long. We
                    had a splendid supper, had muffins, chipped ham, biscuit, tea &amp; <hi
                        rend="underline">coffee</hi>, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. I did not enjoy myself much
                    as they were all perfect strangers to me. </p>

                <p>Tell Uncle Archer if he has not hired out all of the servants yet that General
                    Smith would like to get 3 of them for waiters in the hall and will give $175 for
                    them and you <orig reg="clothe">cloth</orig> them. They would not be exposed
                        <orig reg="at all">atall</orig> as all they have to do is to wait in the
                    Hall. Write to me soon and let me know how Maurice and <unclear>Tru</unclear>
                    are getting. I was so glad to hear that Maurice is entirely out of danger. When
                    he was so sick and I did not hear from home for so long and I tried to get a
                    furlough and couldn't get one I thought I would desert several times. I hope he
                    is well enough to walk about now. Tell him I will answer his letter next. Give
                    my best love to Aunt Sarah and thank her for the nice ham she sent me. Tell her
                    that I answered her letter as soon as I received it and have not heard a word
                    from her since. Tell Molly I think she might write to me some time. When you
                    write again send me some stamps as we cannot get any here.</p>

                <p>I have just been examined on Geography and got through <orig reg="without">with
                        out</orig> a blunder. Write and let me know whether the two lame horses will
                    ever be any account &amp; how Nanny is looking. I would like to take the
                    Lynchburg Virginian this year as I never hear any news here at all. Tis nearly
                    time for dress parade and I want to put this in the <orig reg="mail">male</orig>
                    tonight. Give my love to Miss Laura when you see her. <orig reg="Good Bye">Good
                        by</orig></p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your attached son, </salute>
                    <signed>Kent. </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I cannot write often and you must not wait for me to
                        write. Tell Sister she must write twice to my once. Kent. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
