<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A0756"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A0756">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Mother,
                    December 20, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his mother, december 20 1862</title>
        <author>Langhorne, Jacob Kent </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va.</pubPlace>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997</date>
                <idno type="VCDH">A0756</idno>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501893</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jacob Kent Langhorne to His Mother, December 20, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jacob kent langhorne to his mother, december 20 1862</title>
            <author>Jacob Kent Langhorne </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source Copy Consulted: Jacob Kent Langhorne Papers, Manuscript #361,
                            Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia. Also
                            available online at http://www.vmi.edu/~archtml/ms361.html </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-12-20">1862-12-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Va. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="A0756T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Langhorne asks about his sick brother Maurice. He also mentions the death of a
                    cadet and requests money for Christmas events and white gloves. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mother</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-12-20">December the 20th, 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Virginia Military Institute </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Own Dear Mother </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I received your letter a day or two since and have been very uneasy about Maurice
                    ever since as you said you had to give him food or nourishment every hour. I
                    went to <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Smith and carried him a copy of Papa's
                    letter to him and tried to get a furlough but he would not let me have one. I
                    never wanted to come home so much in my life as now. I will certainly know how
                    to appreciate the comforts &amp; pleasures at home when I get there. You
                    could send me a box by Bonsacks but you must not do it you have <orig reg="too"
                        >two</orig> much trouble now to think of me or boxes either. My roommates
                    will get boxes and they will share with me.</p>

                <p>We <orig reg="lost">los</orig> another one of our most promising fellow cadets
                    yes, the very flower of them all, young Preston son of <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col</abbr> P. professor of the Institute. He was the most perfect young
                    Christian I ever saw. He had just been lingering for the last 7 weeks <orig
                        reg="almost">all most</orig> all the time out of his head. He was more
                    generally beloved by all that knew him than <orig reg="anyone">any on</orig> I
                    ever saw. </p>

                <p>I have not gotten my Shoes yet on account of the River being frozen up. I wrote
                    to sister whilst she was in Lynchburg to give Uncle Daniel some money to get me
                    a pair of skates. I hope she got the letter before she left. I want you to send
                    me some money by Christmas as there will be several Tableaux and a gymnasium
                    performance for the benefit of the soldiers and I would like to go to them.
                    There has been one <orig reg="already">all ready</orig> and the boys are up town
                    at another to night. I have not been to either because I had no money and do not
                    want to be disappointed again. </p>

                <p>Ma when they all get well at home I want you to send me a couple a pair of white
                    gloves as we are not allowed to wear any but white ones and I cannot keep one
                    pair clean and tis so cold to hold a cold <orig reg="steel">still</orig> gun in
                    your hand at night. I wrote a note in one of aunt Sarahs letters to you to get
                    me some linsey to line my overcoat with as we can get nothing but cotton cloth.
                    I have gotten my jacket &amp; pants which are very comfortable.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all at Edgehill &amp; cousin Hues. I have not time to write
                    more now as it is nearly time for Tattoo and as I am orderly I have to go for a
                    bucket of water for morning. Ma I never knew how much I loved you all until now
                    I have been <orig reg="separated">seperated</orig> from you. Some one of you
                    must write me every week, you would if you knew how much pleasure it affords me
                    to receive one from any of you. Tell Brother Jim I think he might write to me
                    oftener than he does. I was looking over the letters I received since I have
                    been here and every one has written oftener than he. </p>

                <p>Kiss May &amp; Mary for me, tell Maurice I will answer his letter as soon as
                    I can. <orig reg="Please">Pleas</orig> send me some stamps as I have to borrow
                    one to send this. Love to all white and black.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute><unclear>
                            <orig reg="Good">Good</orig>
                        </unclear> night your <orig reg="devoted">dovoted</orig> son </salute>
                    <signed>
                        <abbr expan="Jacob Kent Langhorne">J. Kent L.</abbr>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I hope all are better &amp; your mind is not so much
                        troubled. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
