<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1118"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1118">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: L. [Letitia?] R. Smiley to Smiley's
                    sister (Mary?), March 7, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county l letitia r smiley to smileys sister mary , march 7 1867</title>
        <author>Smiley, L. [Letitia?] R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1118</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501921</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: L. [Letitia?] R. Smiley to Smiley's sister (Mary?),
                            March 7, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county l letitia r smiley to smileys sister mary , march 7 1867</title>
            <author>L. [Letitia?] R. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers, Accession
                            #1807, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-03-07">1867-03-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1118T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter, Smiley provides updates--and makes inquiries--about her friends
                    and family. She writes that she has been doing well in school.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-03-07">March 7<hi rend="super">
                                <hi rend="underline">th</hi></hi>, 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">A. T. Seminary<lb/> Staunton V<hi rend="super"><hi rend="underline">a</hi></hi></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear sister</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been waiting for you to write to me about long enough, but it does seem
                    like you ain't a going to do it Well in the first place I am very well &amp;
                    will tell you how well your old sister did in examination yesterday. she passed
                    third best. I think I was doing very well when I got 90, considering the hard
                    examination. &amp; only 5 of us passed. There were 4 examinations on hands
                    yesterday. &amp; the girls all <hi rend="underline">dis</hi>tinguished
                    themselves out of pretty near the whole school only 10 passed. Luce got 76 on
                    her <abbr expan="Geometry">Geom.</abbr> we have two more books to study yet
                    before the final examination &amp; then all will stand together. Did you
                    ever in all your days see such weather not a single ray of sunshine for a week.
                    Mary <orig reg="Smith's">Smiths</orig> party comes off tomorrow night. I believe
                    there are about 200 people to be there. The roads are so bad. the girls are
                    afraid she cannot send for them I believe there are twelve going from here.
                    &amp; if she <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> send for them it will be a great
                    disappointment to some of them. Grandma has been sick for about a month. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> think she is getting any better. M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> Waddell has been here for about two weeks. she went home Monday &amp;
                    Kattie went too, she had been sleeping in our room for a while. Has Bettie
                        <unclear>Echard</unclear> got home from her trip yet. I reckon she would
                    have a fine time &amp; in the end will go to Albermarle to live. Heard Bil
                    Anderson &amp; <unclear>Kip</unclear> Gullin were to be married at last:
                    reckon Becca would get to that wedding. has she been down<pb n="2"/> to see you
                    yet? Give my love to her and tell her our old roomate Margaret Ann Louise hasn't
                    written to us yet; but that we heard she was flying around generally with the
                    boys. &amp; wonder if <hi rend="underline">she</hi> is doing the same. We
                    had a stranger on the table <orig reg="today">to-day</orig>. all the way to
                    three turkeys, were <hi rend="underline">powerful</hi> glad to see them. Lucy
                    &amp; Mary are going <del hand="h1">t</del>home the last of March if the
                    roads are not too bad, I expect Annie Fulton will go with them if she does, she
                    will go down to see you. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> care about going home
                    quite <add hand="h1" place="inline">so</add> soon, but will leave it to you all,
                        <del hand="h1">jus</del> I am about as near out of clothes as people
                    generally get. when you send my clothes please send me some yarn to knit: I
                    think it is <add hand="h1" place="inline">in</add> that trunk <orig
                        reg="upstairs">up stairs</orig>. You see I want to have something to work at
                    on Saturday night when I go into the parlor to hear <abbr expan="Doctor">D<hi
                            rend="super">r</hi>.</abbr> Brown read. They didn't make much at their
                    concerts, <add hand="h1" place="inline">here</add> it was raining so that no one
                    could come. A quartette went from here over to Charlottesville the same week to
                    assist in a concert there. I believe they made about $500 clear there. I had
                    thought I would get a letter this morning; but it seems I was doomed to
                    disappointment. The girls have all gone to Mary <orig reg="Smith's"
                    >Smiths</orig> at last I think Miss B ought to give us a holiday. Now if you
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> write to me soon, you had better. My love to
                    all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate sister</salute>
                    <signed>L. R Smiley</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Lucy got a letter from Mag this morning, she is suffering
                        with a <unclear>felon</unclear> her finger.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
