<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A1700"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A1700">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Jubal Anderson Early to Edmund
                    Jennings Lee II, September 26, 1872</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county jubal anderson early to edmund jennings lee ii, september 26 1872</title>
        <author>Lee, Edmund Jennings, II</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A1700</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501970</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Jubal Anderson Early to Edmund Jennings Lee II,
                            September 26, 1872</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county jubal anderson early to edmund jennings lee ii, september 26 1872</title>
            <author>Jubal Anderson Early</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jubal A. Early to Edmund Jennings
                            Lee II, September 26, 1872, Edmund Jennings Lee II Papers, Duke
                            University Library, Durham, North Carolina.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1872-09-26">1872-09-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                    <term>Home Front</term>
                    <term>State Government</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2006-02-19">February 19, 2006</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofed against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A1700T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Jubal A. Early writes to Edmund Jennings Lee II about the burning of Montgomery
                    Blair's house during Confederate incursions into Maryland and Pennsylvania.
                    Early acknowledges responsibility for burning places like Chambersburg, PA, but
                    denies that he had anything to do with the burning of Blair's house.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1872-09-26">Sep 26th 1872</date>
                        <name type="place">Lynchburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the 24th with the enclosures has been received. I made no speech at
                    Williamsport on the occasion referred to in the extract from the "Age" -- I had
                    sent to Hagerstown and had several prominent Republicans
                    <unclear>arrested</unclear> as <unclear>hostages</unclear> for some persons
                    arrested by Hunter near <unclear>Hedgeville</unclear>. With them came several
                    persons to intercede with me for the release of the arrested parties on
                        <unclear>parol</unclear>, and among those who came to intercede with me were
                        M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Hamilton, now senator from Maryland, M<hi
                        rend="super">r</hi> Romaine, and Judge <unclear>Thompson Warren</unclear>.--
                    I had a good deal of conversation with the parties, but had no idea of making a
                    speech, and did not suppose any one would so regard my remarks.-- If
                        <unclear>you</unclear> heard that any publication was made in regard to what
                    I said it has escaped my memory.-- I certainly said nothing to authorize the
                    idea that I had ordered or sanctioned the burning of Montgomery Blair's House.-
                    It is very possible that I may have said that the burning of his house stood on
                    a different <unclear>footing</unclear> from the plundering of his father's
                    house. But if so, it was not intended to <pb n="2"/>convey the idea that I had
                    ordered the burning, but was much intended as an excuse for the act by my men if
                    any of them committed it.- If I had thought proper to burn the house myself, I
                    would have had abundant justification for it in the fact that Mr. Davis' house
                    in Mississippi had been burned by the Yankee troops, the Institute at Lexington
                    had been burned, and many private houses of citizens of Virginia had been burned
                    by Hunter, as I had seen in the line of his march.</p>

                <p>The reasons why I did not burn Blair's house were 1st because, in my
                        <unclear>then</unclear> position, I did not wish to do any act which might
                    seem to give <unclear>authority</unclear> for any liscence on the part of my
                    troops, and thus relax the reins of discipline; and 2nd, because it was then
                    well known that the Blairs were opposed to some of the harsh measures
                        <unclear>pursued</unclear> by their party, and for that reason were in very
                    bad <unclear>odom</unclear> with the Radical portion-- In fact, it was not long
                    before Montgomery Blair was compelled to retire from the Cabinet-- I did not
                    think it would be true <unclear>piling</unclear> to retaliate on him, and in
                    fact I supposed such retaliation would have <pb n="3"/>gratified the extreme
                    Radicals.-- But as he was then a member of the cabinet, I had no doubt of my
                    right to retaliate on him if I thought <unclear>proper</unclear>.-- A gentleman
                    now living in the Valley, who followed my force, but was not in the service,
                    came to me and asked permission to burn the house, but I refused it
                        <unclear>puncuptarily</unclear>. The house was a new one just finished as I
                        <unclear>understand</unclear>, and I believe was not furnished at all.--</p>

                <p>I did put a guard on it, and the fire was <unclear>discovered</unclear> and
                    pointed out to me, as we were moving back, by one of my staff-officers who now
                    resides at Staunton, and knows that I did not intend to burn the house. I have
                    abundant testimony to show what were my purposes, if I thought proper to produce
                    it; but really I do not care whether M<hi rend="super">r</hi>. Montgomery Blair
                    believes my statement or not-- My <unclear>card</unclear> in regard to the
                    matter was not published to propitiate him, or to clear myself of a charge of
                    vandalism, but simply to vindicate the truth of history--</p>

                <p>Nor do I care care whether the present editor of the "Mail" thinks my
                        <unclear>card</unclear> consistent with the statement published in the
                    "Age"-- If his sympathy for the Southern cause had taken <pb n="4"/>the shape of
                    service under my command, instead of much very unfruitful sympathy as we were
                    accustomed to meet within Maryland, he would have learned that I never shirked
                    any responsibility for any act of mine-- I have assumed the responsibility of
                    the burning of Chambersburg, and also of <abbr expan="Thaddeus">Thad.</abbr>
                    Stevens' iron-works-- Though I am informed Stevens always believed that
                    Barksdale of Mississippi burned his works-- I also approved the burning of
                    Governor Bradford's house by one of my subordinates, though I did not know of it
                    until the act was consummated-- Subsequently, if I had had an opportunity I
                    would have done much more burning in the enemy's country.--</p>

                <p>If I had burned Blair's house, I would have been entirely justified in doing so,
                    and would have assumed the responsibility at once. I did not do it for the
                    reasons before stated, and I have never known to this day whether the burning
                    was done by my men or some person in the neighborhood hostile to the Blairs-- It
                    is very possible that some of my men did it-- If so they abundant provocation in
                    the sight of their own houses or the houses of their friends that had been
                    consigned to the flames of the enemy in the line of their march into Maryland.
                    If you think proper, you can show this letter to the editor of the "Mail," and
                    he can show it to Judge Blair if he thinks proper.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your servt <unclear>Truly</unclear></salute>
                    <signed>Lt. Early</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient">E.J. Lee Jr. Esquire</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
