<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2002"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2002">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E.C. Gallaher, May 23,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, may 23 1861</title>
        <author>Gallaher, William B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2002</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501975</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>This letter was transcribed from another transcribed copy. William B. Gallaher's mother's
      name was taken from the census. The text of the letter mentions that William B. Gallaher would
      write to "Hugh" on the back of the page, but the transcriber did not include the letter (or
      Gallaher did not write to Hugh).</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William B. Gallaher to E. C. Gallaher, May 23, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william b gallaher to e c gallaher, may 23 1861</title>
            <author>William B. Gallaher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William B. Gallaher Letters, Waynesboro Public
       Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Waynesboro Public Library Collection, Waynesboro, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-05-23">1861-05-23</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Family, Medicine/Hospitals, Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2002T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>William B. Gallaher describes an accident in camp, mentions a visit to his grandfather's
     home, and requests a box of provisions.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">E. C. Gallaher</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-05-23">May 23, 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Harpers Ferry</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Ma</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I am writing this letter in the Hospital. The house belonging to the states occupied by Ball
     Superintendent who has left. It is a beautiful place. I and John Lipscomb are staying here with
     Elliott Fishburne. He was shot in Martinsburg the day before yesterday by the accidental
     discharge of a pistol in one of the boys hands. It was one of the old revolvers or it would
     have killed him. He was sitting at a table when one of the boys came up &amp; was snapping
     the pistol in 2 feet of his face &amp; it went off. The ball entered his left cheek knocked
     out tow of his teeth &amp; fractured his jawbone &amp; struck his tongue. They dont
     know where the ball is. I think he swallowed it. At the time I was sitting on a bed in 10 feet
     of him and was the 1st to get there. I washed his face &amp; by that time the Doctor came.
     He was taken to the Ferry on the train. He can walk very well. I do not consider the wound
     mortal. I &amp; John will take good care of him. Capt Patrick has written to this folks
     &amp; I suppose he will hear of it before you get this. I am very sorry the accident
     happened but perhaps it was all for the best. I am getting on very well &amp; am satisfied.
     We have a good house to sleep in &amp; are getting along as well as could be expected. I
     wrote to Pa about our trip through Shepherdstown to Martinsburg on last Sunday &amp;
     stopped at Grandpa's got my dinner saw all the folks. They are well &amp; were very glad to
     see me. They all look as well as ever to me. Grandpa got his horse &amp; rode to
     Martinsburg with me &amp; got his supper at Mr. Rawlings. They say you must come down this
     summer to see them &amp; bring Ginny. I went to see Mrs Rawlings family. They are all well.
     Mr R brought us 4 large rolls nice baker to use in quarters. I saw him before I left. He sends
     his respect to you &amp; Pa. Ma please send me a large box of provisions. You can send it
     down the Valley. We get plenty to eat but I notice a good many of the boys getting boxes from
     home with hams butter apples &amp; some of the nicest apple butter I ever ate. They all
     share with me. I should like to return the favor. I think I shall fatten up some &amp; heal
     this summer. Tell Sallie I got hers &amp; little brother Hughs letters and that I will
     write to them today or sometime. I went down &amp; took dinner with Ed Waddell today. He is
     looking very well but has a right sore foot. There is 15000 soldiers here. At night I can look
     out of my window &amp; can see the camp fires all over the hills. There is about 250 tents
     besides the houses are all very near full of soldiers. There is 3500 Mississippi troops here
     about 2000 Alabamers 600 Kentuckians. They have 40 or 50 cannon here &amp; more are coming
     today. They have a large 32 pounder station above the Powder Magazine which commands the
     Railroad. It will shoot 5 miles. You know where it is. I saw John Hill &amp; Claire Evans.
     They are both well. Tell Mr. Evans George is not here. Tell Pa John Lipscomb sent him a gun by
     James Patrick &amp; some cartridges by William M Bush. I forgot to tell you that the 1st
     night I got here we were ordered under arms at two oclock but by the time we were ready we got
     orders to go to bed. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think there will be any fighting here.
     When we were in Martinsburg I took some dispatches down to Col Allen's Camp who is encamped in
     the woods 13 1/2 miles of the Potomac River. The next morning I went down to the River to wash
     my face &amp; I could see Williamsport very plain. There is a lot of Maryland soldiers come
     on &amp; joined our Army. How are you all getting on. How is Clinton pleased with clerking.
     I will write Hugh a letter on the other side. Write soon give my love to all. I was vaccinated
     the other day &amp; it has begun to make my arm sore. I will go to Shepherdstown as soon as
     I can &amp; stay a day. If you send me anything direct it care of Capt Patrick Valley
     Rangers. How are you getting on with your garden. Ma send me some ham pickles biscuit pies
     &amp; you know what to send. I will stop as I have written you a very long letter. Tell Pa
     the cartridges must be torn off at the end &amp; the paper taken off the ball it will fit
     loose but will spread when shot from the gun. Give my love to all. Write soon. Tell Charles I
     will write to him in a few days. I am taking good care of myself. Kiss Hugh Ginny &amp;
     Betty for me.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>W B Gallaher</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
