<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2016"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2016">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Casper Branner to Father, January 10, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county casper branner to father, january 10 1861</title>
        <author>Branner, Casper</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2016</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501987</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Casper Branner to Father, January 10, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county casper branner to father, january 10 1861</title>
            <author>Casper Branner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Casper Branner Letters, Accession #11162, Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-01-10">1861-01-10</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>State Government, Enlistment</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2016T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Branner tells his father about the formation of military companies in nearby Harrisonburg and
     comments on the growing secessionist sentiment in Virginia.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Father</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-01-10">Thursday Evening Jany. 10/61</date>
      <name type="place">Mossy Creek Academy, Augusta County Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Father,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Having some leisure moments I thought I would write you a short letter. The boys have all
      <orig reg="arrived">arived</orig> here at last except one. I came all the way on Saturday. I
     stopped in Harrisonburg and tried to get my self a pair of boots but did not <orig
      reg="succeed">succeede</orig>. I was at all the shops in town and could not find a pair of
     boots to fit me. I came on to Bridgewater and met with no better success. I had my measure
     taken <orig reg="there">their</orig> for a pair <pb n="2"/> stick down <unclear>Kip</unclear>
     boots, and I expect to get them tomorrow morning by the mail. he charges me five dollars and a
      <orig reg="half">halfe</orig>. I asked the price of the same boots in Harrisonburg and they
     said they could not make them for less than 7 dollars. Beaver and the boys from down the valley
     came Wednesday. I found but very few here when I got here and had a lonesome time. But <orig
      reg="everything">every thing</orig> is started on right now. I payed Mr. White my book bill
     this evening and took his receipt. It was quite a military day in Harrisonburg Saturday, there
     were two <orig reg="companies">companeys</orig>
     <orig reg="parading">parrading</orig> the Horse company and the Rifle Company they made quite a
     show, and I thought went through the <orig reg="maneuvers">manouvers</orig> very well. The
     horse company was receiving their <pb n="3"/> arms. Beaver tells me that the arms for the New
     Market Cavalry is on the way. They are to be sabres and two of Colts Navy revolvers. I think it
     is time that they should arm the volunteer companies of the State. As in all probability they
     will be called out in the spring. Secession is on the increase here, I have heard men say in
     the last few days that they were strong secessionist, who before Christmas were quiet
     submissionist. I think the time has come when submission can no longer be withstood, and we
     should claim our rights, if not in the Union we must - out of it. The North will hear to no
     compromise, and the South will not submit to an unconstitutional party. Write soon. My love to
     all.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your Son,</salute>
     <signed>C.C. Branner</signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><pb n="4"/>P.S. Friday Morning. My Boots came this morning <orig
       reg="they">the</orig> do very well. I tell you they are stomppers, soles about half an inch
      thick. <hi rend="underline">C.C.B.</hi></seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
