<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2524"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2524">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April
     2, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 2 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2524</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502013</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, April 2, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, april 2 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Library of
       Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-04-02">1862-04-02</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Military Strategy, Military Authority, Battle Description,
      Death/Casualties, Prisons/Prisoners, Women, Arts/Leisure, Camp Life, National Government</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2524T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes skirmishes with Federal forces. He also discusses his new position in the
     army and gives brief details about the battle of Kernstown.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-04-02">April 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Rev. Mr. Rude's, Two Miles up the Valley from Mt. Jackson</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Wife --</salute>
    </opener>

    <p> We have changed quarters today and are nearer to you than before -- Yesterday the Yankees
     advanced this way and Ashby and his Cavalry contended with them all day, but they advanced some
     twelve miles through Woodstock and on to Edenburg, where they were stopped by the burning of
     the bridges over Stony Creek and meeting some force which the General sent forward -- I was up
     along the creek the day before and made a sketch of it, and recommended to the General to make
     a stand there, and today he sent a Brigade and some guns there and there was considerable
     skirmishing during the day, in which we had the advantage, and when they came across we drove
     them howling back with several killed The Gen. has ordered a force back tomorrow and I suppose
     a fight may take place We have been favored by Providence today the Gen. Says. The shells of
     the enemy howl dreadfully -- I never heard such unearthly noises -- the shells are very long --
     some 12 or 15 inches. Quite a number of them burst near the Gen. and his staff yesterday but
     not one of our men was injured -- A little boy just behind Ashby had his horse shot today by
     the enemy firing at Ashby -- I hope he may be preserved -- he is a noble man -- I went down
     last night to tell him about the roads &amp;c. We sent our baggage to the rear yesterday
     and it did not get back until very late, so we slept on the ground. I slept finely was tired
     enough to enjoy it. This morning we started at day break to the front 5 miles, where the fight
     was to be and the enemy held in check. We spent half of the day there, that is the Gen.
     &amp; staff, and then I went out to see a back road and the Gen. moved his <abbr
      expan="Head">Hd.</abbr> Quarters back of Mt. Jackson to a line of hills above there a fine
     position to hold and the next one above Stony <pb n="2"/> Creek. </p>
    <p> I am now attached to the <abbr expan="Engineer">Eng.</abbr> corps and posted at or near head
     quarters, and have a much pleasanter position than in the Adjutancy of a <abbr expan="Regiment"
      >Regt.</abbr> or any other post in the Army, the Chief of the Corps, Lieut Boswell, is a very
     fine fellow, and I meet many of my old friends of Valley Mt.</p>
    <p> There are 614 of our men killed, wounded &amp; prisoners at the Battle of Kernstown, the
     loss of the enemy was about 1000. Henry Robertson was taken prisoner. The news of the battle is
     more fully related in the papers than I can give you, for we only hear odd ends of news and no
     very connected statement. I have not read more than one or two papers since I came here. In
     fact have not seen more than one or two, have read some Northern papers. I hope Nelly has fully
     recovered and that you are all getting along --. I am enjoying good health, am getting better
     of my cold, sleeping on the ground seems to agree with me.</p>
    <p> If you have an opportunity you may do up and send me the life of Marlborough, send it by
     some one that is coming down here, if you happen to know of any. I got Mr. Ruffner's Barometer
     today and he lent me a compass -- he is very kind indeed --</p>
    <p> I have got a mess chest and a box for my papers &amp;c and have a table and chairs, and
     also some dishes. I got some butter today at 30 <abbr expan="cents">cts</abbr> a lb. -- not
     very good. I just ate the last of my home biscuits. I wish I had a half <abbr expan="basket">
      <unclear>bask.</unclear>
     </abbr> of them, and some butter from home. The militia will be drafted in tomorrow. The Gen.
     has just ordered 4 companies of riflemen and several pieces of cannon up to Rockingham to storm
     the camp of the Militia that refuse to come to duty -- so <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> be
     alarmed if you hear the noise of a battle near at hand, for no harm will come but to the
     recreant. They are near McGaheysville. There will be an example made of some of those that fail
     to come. Give my love to all the friends God bless and keep you -- Kiss the darlings for Pa --</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
