<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2542"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2542">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June
     15, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 15 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2542</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502031</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, June 15, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, june 15 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-06-15">1862-06-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Troop Movement, Military Strategy, Battle Description, Medicine/Hospitals, Home
      Front, Women, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2542T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates news of skirmishes with Federal forces and Confederate successes against
     Generals Shields and Fremont. He also describes the harsh treatment of civilians by Fremont's
     "Dutch" troops.</p>
   </div1>


  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="figure" id="d5">
    <p>"The Union supreme at all points." [accompanied by image of a compass]</p>
   </div1>
   <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-06-15">Sunday June 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Near Mt. Meridian, Augusta Co Va, </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>(captured <abbr expan="Federal">Fed.</abbr> paper) </p>
    <p> Your letter of a few days ago came duly to hand, and was very welcome, though I had heard
     from you by some of the neighbors, and sent you word by Mr. Helms that I was still in <del
      hand="h1"/> after the battles of the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> and 9<hi rend="super">th</hi>,
     I was too tired to write, or well as too busy, after the battle, making a sketch of the country
     around our position for the use of the different officers who did not know the country. I have
     been hoping that Nelson might be able to get away and come down here, but the road is so bad
     that it would be to the great discomfort of any one that should attempt to come. I did not get
     to eat any of the nice victuals you prepared for me, for the General sent me ahead when we left
     Mt. Solon and I was not at my wagon again until we got to Winchester and so everything had
     spoiled, much to my regret, but while fighting &amp; marching are going on we do not often
     see our wagons until quite late at night, I wish I had the things now, but I am doing very well
     as I am among my friends here and have been invited out several times, I hope I may get home
     soon but I cannot well ask to go for several are away that have not been <pb n="2"/> off
     before. If we go to Mt. Crawford I will send from there what I have for you, unless I got a
     chance from here; I shall not send until I am sure it will go safely, I would like some
     provisions from home, some <hi rend="underline">substantials</hi>, crackers and butter, but
     little of anything else, and I may be able to send for that. We are being heavily reinforced
     and I suppose will soon be on the march again after the enemy. God blesses our arms, our men
     all fight like heroes, and success has heretofore attended all our efforts -- We whipped
     Fremont on the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi>, and part of our army slept nearer to Harrisonburg
     that night than he did, we inflicted a great deal of damage on him, drove his regiments with
     great slaughter from the field and then came on the next day, and unmolested crossed the river
     and whipped Shields completely, captured all his artillery and pursued him 10 miles <pb n="3"/>
     capturing several hundred of his men and scattering his whole army to the four winds, while
     Fremont drew up on the opposite side of the river and witnessed Shields defeat, only throwing
     over a few shot and shell after the whole affair had ended and we were sending our ambulances
     to bring Shields' own dead &amp; wounded from the field, and Fremont was near enough to see
     what we were doing, and he actually threw shell at the building in which the wounded of both
     armies lay, with a hospital flag flying from it -- the brute. Shield's men fought well for
     their officers made them believe that we would kill every man that we captured -- They said
     many of them would give themselves up if they knew we would treat them kindly. Many of them
     regretted that Ashby was killed -- for he <hi rend="underline">was</hi> killed on Friday -- in
     a skirmish after a sort of battle in which he had displayed great valor -- he is a great loss
     to us, <pb n="4"/> we miss him every day, but hope that Providence may raise up some men to
     supply his place -- and be the right hand of Jackson. The men of Fremont are Dutch -- of the
     very worst sort, they have plundered the country wherever they have been, they stripped the
     houses at Cross Keys completely, taking all the drapes of the ladies, breaking up the dishes
     &amp;c &amp;c They wrapped up their dead in the blankets, carpets, quilts &amp;c
     that they had taken from the houses -- they were very brutal to the women in language, and
     stole everything they could get hold of. they came up "spoiling for a fight and a good many of
     them spoiled after the fight" as Gen. Ewell says. I will write more about the battles, or tell
     you more when I see you. We had sacrament today in camp, it was a solemn scene, and Dr. Dabney
     prefaced it by some excellent remarks --. Our men are enjoying the rest, they are now getting,
     very much, and will soon be ready for another march. I did not send the illustrated papers, as
     I said, but I <hi rend="underline">will</hi> send them the first chance. Write often and may
     God bless you all. Love to all </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
