<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2562"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A2562">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 12, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 12 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2562</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502051</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 12, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 12 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-12">1862-11-12</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Women, Arts/Leisure</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2562T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes his travels as he maps the countryside, and tells of the people and
     places he sees.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-12">Nov -- 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Strasburg Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Deary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have not written to you for a little more than a week -- "I've been roaming" as a poet
     would say, and so have not had time to write, or rather have not had a chance to send -- I went
     to <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> the 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> of Oct. and Gen.
      <abbr expan="Jackson">J.</abbr> told me I had better look after my commission and that he
     wanted me to see Gen. Lee and get authority from him for him to employ me still, as he desired
     to retain me &amp; Gen. Lee was now in command of the Army and he alone could order such
      <orig reg="disbursements">disbursebments</orig> -- so I settled up to the 1<hi rend="super"
     >st</hi> of Nov. and set out for Culpeper to see Gen. Lee -- though in no hurry, for I knew
     Gen. Lee too well to have any fears about my place -- I took my time and mapped the roads as I
     went, stopped over Sunday at my friend Buck's, in Front Royal, and then last Tuesday went
     across the Ridge at Chester's Gap -- the finest one I have ever passed through -- a gentle rise
     &amp; fine farms up <hi rend="underline">to</hi> and on the top -- When I got to the base
     of the Ridge word came that the Yankees were advancing along the base, so I took a route to
     Culpeper that was at a more dignified distance and went by the way of Sperryville <pb n="2"/>
     spent Tuesday night in Washington, the county seat of Rappahannock Co -- and Wednesday went on
     to Culpeper <abbr expan="Court  
 House">C.H.</abbr> I called at Nelson's store to ask for
     Grinnan, thinking that I would spend the night with him, and was there informed that he was in
     prison - - I asked no more questions, but went on to Gen. Lee's <abbr expan="Head  
 Quarters"
      >Hd. Qrs.</abbr>, about a mile from town and spent the night with his Engineer got my
     application from Gen. Jackson approved the next morning and then started back by way of the
     memorable battle field of Cedar Run, and recalled the scenes of the bloody day we spent there
     as I passed along. I went on towards Madison <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> - and stayed
     Thursday night at Mr. Smoot's, the father-in-law of Jacob Plecker -- and you remember how it
     snowed Friday -- I kept myself by the fireside, glad to be in the rickety quarters of a
     humorous old widower, for he kept a good fire and one of his married daughters had come home
     for a few days and made the eating very good, so I thanked a kind Providence that had so well
     provided for me, while so <pb n="3"/> many were exposed to the pitiless storm -- But it is
     almost incredible to believe when I tell you that soldiers, many of the barefooted, passed by
     that day from 8 miles off, going a mile or so beyond after liquor at 12 dollars a gallon -- to
     what straits will not men go for the vile stuff -- they said that apple brandy sold that day in
     camp at 48 dollars a gallon -- Saturday I came on through Madison <abbr expan="Court House"
      >C.H.</abbr> -- quite a nice place, on the top of a ridge. One of the prettiest sights I have
     ever seen is constantly presented in this part of Va -- in the clumps and groves of pines, so
     perfectly regular in outline and so rich and dark a color -- presenting such a contrast,
     especially at this time to the other woods -- I reached Criglersville Saturday night and got
     quarters for Sunday at Mr. Strickler's, a nice place, and so I escaped a cold day's ride again,
     for Sunday was quite raw -- I read and chatted -- they had a tutress, Miss Turner from
     Richmond, who was educated in <abbr expan="Massachusetts">Mass</abbr>. She was quite chatty --
     has been teaching a long time -- <pb n="4"/> I read most of Headly's Life of Josephine -- a
     very good book and very well written -- she was a <hi rend="underline">real</hi> woman -- but
     how badly treated -- since she gave her whole thoughts to her husband -- Monday was a fine day,
     and I had a nice ride across the Blue Ridge, by the crookedest road I have ever seen -- 19
     miles across -- but the road is a fine one -- I stopped for the night at the foot of the Mt.
     Tuesday I came on to New Market -- found Mr. Dedrick on the Mt. with some of Potter's goods --
     he was going to Luray but turned back -- Said Potter was not well and Bell was very sick with
     Pneumonia, the Dr. came twice a day to see her and charged $5 a visit -- they are off on the
      <unclear>Keezletown</unclear> road -- they had to leave New Market I suppose. The old man was
     glad to see me, and I got a good dinner through him -- I came to Mt. Jackson last night, and on
     here tonight -- I want to go on to Winchester tomorrow to our <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd.
      Qrs.</abbr> -- A part of our army is here, and a part in Clarke Co. and a part near Winchester
     -- the Yanks have left the Valley it is said --</p>
    <p> Longstreet was at Culpeper when I left there -- Stuart has been fighting the enemy almost
      <orig reg="daily">dailey</orig> -- I hope to soon come home -- Keep my coat and pants until I
     come or send -- Excuse this lingo my love &amp; kisses for the family -- I bought 2 doz
     ladies stockings &amp; 3 <abbr expan="handkerchiefs">hdkfs</abbr> -- God bless you all --
     Good bye </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss --</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
