<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2561"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2561">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 2, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 2 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2561</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502050</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 2, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 2 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-02">1862-11-02</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Home Front, Troop Movement, Women, Family, National Government</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2561T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes troop movements in the Valley, and discusses the northern political races
     and their implications for peace.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-02">Nov. 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Front Royal Va</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Wife</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I wrote to you just one week ago today, from New Market, but you will wish to hear from me
     again by this time &amp; though I am on the wing so that I cannot hear from you as often as
     I desire I will not therefore deprive you of the pleasure you will derive at home from hearing
     from me. I went from New Market, after the rain of Sunday, into the upper end of the Fort
     Valley &amp; went down to Burner's Springs and then across into the Luray Valley and down
     to Front Royal -- meeting there with my old friend of 1847, Mr. Marcus Buck &amp; spent a
     very pleasant night at his house, well up on the side of the Blue Ridge, a place that he bought
     when Ralph &amp; I were here then &amp; which he has <orig reg="built">builded</orig>
     &amp; planted until he has made it a delightful place -- orchards, vineyards &amp;c
     &amp; has a large and interesting family grown up around him, two sons Lieutenants in the
     army &amp;c -- I found when I got to Front Royal that the army <pb n="2"/> was in motion,
     found part of it on the way to the Ridge &amp; all bustle on every side, the people excited
     with fear that the Valley was to be evacuated &amp; they turned over to the tender mercy of
     the invaders &amp;c &amp;c. I went, Friday, to our <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd.
     Qrs.</abbr>, not far from Berryville, Clarke Co -- and spent the night there, found that the
     enemy had moved away from Sharpsburg and down the river &amp; was crossing into Loudon Co
     -- and that our forces were so disposed as to meet them if they should advance and offer
     battle. There may be another great battle in a short time if the Yankees persist in coming on
     along the base of the Ridge towards Culpeper <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> &amp;
     Gordonsville -- and by God's good blessing they will get one of the very worst threshings they
     ever got if they do come on. There are all sorts of rumors about an armistice of 90 days
     &amp;c &amp;c but no one can trace them to any source entitled to credit -- and we all
     think the intervention story is about played out. I only wish there was some prospect of peace,
     some ray of hope on which to base a calculation <pb n="3"/> but I see none yet. I am going
     across the Blue Ridge tomorrow, to what point I do not exactly know, as yet, but will write to
     you before long -- I may be able to bring myself around by home again -- I shall do so if in my
     power &amp; so get my overcoat &amp; boots, as I sent word to Nelson not to send them
     to me until he heard from me. Have my pants made by Mrs. Fisher and ready -- If you can find a
     suppy of butter, buy it, and I may be able to find some on my round up through Rockingham. I
     have read the New York Tribune of the 30<hi rend="super">th</hi> ult. it is full of Black <abbr
      expan="Republican">Rep.</abbr> speeches &amp;c -- preparing for the election of next
     Tuesday -- there are strange combinations -- D. S. Dickinson and Horace Greeley speak from the
     same stump &amp; for the same purpose, while Washington Hunt and Jon Van Buren go side by
     side. The Tribune says flatly that it thinks Seymour and Van Buren are antiwar men -- and that
     they pretend to be for the war only to get votes and so get into power and that when once in,
     they will make <pb n="4"/> peace with the Rebels -- If the Democrats carry New York there are
     many that think there will be no more fighting, but that we will go into winter quarters and
     negotiations will be carried on during the winter for peace. I am not sanguine enough to think
     so, but yet place some hope in the division of the U.S. Congress so that there will be two
     sides to the question and then <orig reg="there">the</orig> will become a peace party as well
     as a war party. Some of the Democrats speak plainly of a change of men at Washington from the
     President down -- and Old Abe does not arrest them &amp; so the power of free speech is
     again abroad and there is some hope yet that the love of freedom, inherent in Anglo Saxon men,
     will make itself heard &amp; free itself from the bondage of its own rulers and then let us
     alone to choose our own way of life -- But I am talking politics and not writing a family
     letter -- which I <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> do again --. So kiss the babies for me -- tell
     them to be good girls -- Nelly read the Bible be like the good women it tells about, and little
     Anna listen &amp; do good thing too -- pray for peace &amp; may God keep you all under
     his holy wing Write to me -- for I may get it Good bye </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
