<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2571"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2571">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     December 21, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 21 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2571</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502060</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, December 21, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, december 21 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-12-21">1862-12-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority, Home Front, Desertion/Leave</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2571T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes briefly about the position of Federal forces, the possibility of securing a
     leave, and his health.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-12-21">Sunday Morning, Dec. 21<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Moss Neck --</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My <abbr expan="Dear">Dr.</abbr> Sara:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have a chance to send you a line this morning, and so will gladly avail myself of it, for I
     know your thoughts are running hither, in spite of anything else that may be transpiring
     &amp; mine are morning and evening going to my pleasant home by the pond side &amp;
     wishing I were there to bask in the sunshine of those I love -- but it is otherwise ordered,
     and so I will not complain, but only for the thousandth time wish the evil days were over and
     our land was enjoying its days of rest: come they must, come they will, before long, the hand
     of a merciful Providence is guiding us, by ways we know not of, to the long-wished-for day of
     freedom -- all things cheer us -- the Vandal host that came with pollution &amp; desolation
     has been driven back with a loss four fold greater than our own &amp; now skulks between
     the deep inlets of the Potomac &amp; Rapahannock in constant alarm lest deep rivers may not
     keep back the "vast Rebel Army" We thank God for this fourth deliverance, "by a stretched out
     arm" from, from the swarm that would settle down upon our vitals &amp; consume them if they
     could -- <pb n="2"/> The enemy is still opposite to us, but removed from the river, and nothing
     of interest is transpiring -- I am very busy making a map of this county, which I hope to
     finish in two or three days, and then I want to ask the General to let me come home for a week
     to attend the fixing of your comfort for the coming year -- I think he will grant it, but
     cannot tell -- Boswell has applied for leave of absence to go to Alabama for a month -- and he
     has gone to Gen. Lee now to have it approved -- I hope he may get it. I reckon my letter about
     my box did not get home in time to have it get back to Staunton -- I have not heard anything
     from you about it, and so take it for granted that it did not reach in time. I am doing very
     well though, on bread &amp; coffee -- now &amp; then a little potato soup -- think my
     health is as good as ever it was -- though I am working very closely, hoping to get a respite
     for a few days that I may come to my own sweet nest for a few days of this rapidly passing
     winter. If you have not sent my eatables &amp;c, let them rest until I write again. I have
     not been able to get any washing done since I left home -- </p>
    <p> Yesterday 14 persons, in good circumstances, but refugees from destruction, from
     Fredericksburg &amp; Port Royal, staying in an old house near here, sent to be a morsel of
     food -- they had not a single thing to eat -- <pb n="3"/></p>
    <p> Harris goes this moment -- so good bye and God bless you </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Do write</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
