<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2573"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2573">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, January
     2, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, january 2 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2573</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502062</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Date originally written 1862, but corrected to 1863</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, January 2, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, january 2 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-01-02">1863-01-02</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Slavery, Camp Life, Military Authority, Women, Home Front,
      Prisons/Prisoners</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2573T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes of his failure to secure a slave servant, camp life, and miscellaneous
     instructions for his wife.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-01-02">Friday Jan. 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Moss Neck</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Sara:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I use the first opportunity that offers to write to you of my welfare &amp; whereabouts
     -- I was about in Staunton on Monday, trying to find a servant to come to the army, but it was
     of no avail, there are so many to go to Richmond &amp; so many that want substitutes, to
     send to Richmond, for their servants that they want to have stay at home. I took dinner at Dr.
     Young's and spent the night there, got my camp stove &amp; <hi rend="underline">all</hi>
     fixed, "that was a great deal done" you will say. I got up before day Tuesday morning and went
     over to the Depot -- found Maj. Harman there to see me off -- The cars were very full -- and
     such crowding before we got to "The Junction" -- the servants of course had it almost to
     themselves, so many going &amp; coming -- as this was the hiring day -- I never saw so many
     slaves along the R.R -- We did not make the connection at the Junction -- and I spent the night
     there with the Commissary -- &amp; some 400 soldiers were there too -- The next day I got
     on the train and could only get part of my baggage on, the crowd was so great, so I went on to
     Guinea's with the part and then came back and got the other part, spending the night of
     Wednesday at The Junction also -- but I finally got all things to Guinea's -- found my horse
     there &amp; the wagon <pb n="2"/> and came on to <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd.
     Qrs.</abbr>, all safe, everything in fine order, Boswell delighted with his clothes &amp;c
     and we had a nice supper -- and he had fixed up a bed of cedar twigs &amp; we had every
     thing in order -- he was much obliged for the sausages -- This morning we had a nice breakfast,
     eggs, and Brown, Garber, Allen, &amp; Judge Lee breakfasted with us --. We are still at the
     same place, the Gen. has gone into a room, himself, all the rest are in tents as before. The
     Gen. is much pleased with his fine horse that the people of Augusta sent him. We are all much
     elated at the news today from The West -- hope it may all end well -- it will help on the
     coming of peace -- God speed the coming of that much to be desired day --</p>
    <p> I enclose three buttons, to finish out the number for my vest -- have them put at the bottom
     -- get Mrs. Lickliter to make it &amp; have the back of my old vest put in it -- Have
     Boswell's vest made by mine, she can suit, and get cloth &amp;c from Lindsay to make it,
     and send me the bill of the cloth you get and the making -- Boswell wants round holes one side
     (his buttons have rings to them) and button holes in the other -- the same number of buttons as
     mine --. I hope Allen has come to you -- I could not find him Monday -- write to me very soon
     my love -- I heard from Grinnan -- he was taken prisoner by the Yankees &amp; was at Fort
     McHenry -- Kiss the children for Pa -- I shall take your apples to the Gen. tomorrow -- Good
     bye &amp; God bless you </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
