<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2576"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2576">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Elisabeth E. Reddy to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March
     29, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county elisabeth e reddy to sara a hotchkiss, march 29 1870</title>
        <author>Reddy, Elisabeth E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2576</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502065</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Elisabeth E. Reddy to Sara A. Hotchkiss, March 29, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county elisabeth e reddy to sara a hotchkiss, march 29 1870</title>
            <author>Elisabeth E. Reddy</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1870-03-29">1870-03-29</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties, Family, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2576T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Elisabeth Reddy writes to her sister, Sara Hotchkiss, relating family news, including
     children's education, a change in residence, family photographs, and health.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1870-03-29">March 29, 1870</date>
      <name type="place">Casenovia</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Sister Sara</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It is a long, too long, neglected duty I now undertake. I am not well, scarcely able to be
     up, still I fear long to delay.</p>
    <p> Your letter came to hand just as I was preparing to return to our home in Casenovia. We only
     took a few things to Utica for the winter, shutting up our house.</p>
    <p> Libbie commences school again this week. We have fears as to her being able to continue long
     in school. Our conference is to hold its session the middle of April. Until after <pb n="2"/>
     which we shall be held in suspense as to our future destiny.</p>
    <p> I am very sorry to learn of your poor health. Ought you not to seek some "remedial cure"?
     Our Jamie is at Clifton Springs Water Cure. A Clerk and Student. Make your preparations when
     you come north to go there for a few weeks. I think it is about thirty miles this side of
     Rochester. Libbie was there several weeks and greatly benefitted. <hi rend="underline">I</hi>
     was only there a few days, still it did me good.</p>
    <p> My effort at moving back, and getting chilled, lifting too much &amp;c has brought me
     down again. I cannot <hi rend="underline">now</hi> see when I could fix upon a time to meet you
     at <pb n="3"/>
     <unclear>Mother's</unclear>. I think you better make your arrangements without reference to me,
     but let me know, and if it is among the possibilities, I will meet you.</p>
    <p> Did Mr Reddy ever send you the "Olive <unclear>jar</unclear>
     <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>" He promised me he would, and afterward said he did not know whether he had or
     not. I sometimes tell him if <hi rend="underline">forgetfulness</hi> is a means of grace to
     help him to heaven, he will surely get there.</p>
    <p> I send you several photographs. They are none as good as I wish, and <hi rend="underline"
      >mine</hi> is too bad to be seen. It was taken by request of the Chittenango people just as we
     were to take stage for depot after working two <hi rend="underline">nights</hi> in packing,
     because <pb n="4"/> because of so many interuptions <unclear>days</unclear> I fear I shall
     never have any better taken. <hi rend="underline">hide</hi> it as soon as you look at it. I
     never yet had a <hi rend="underline">good</hi> picture.</p>
    <p> Shall we not expect those of yourself <orig reg="and">an</orig> family? When you write we'll
     look for them.</p>
    <p> I am quite tired, as you will see by my writing</p>
    <p> I do not know where brother Isaac is. I have heard that he had started south from Illinois.
     Hope to hear something sometime. We are terribly scattered and thinned out as a family. But I
     trust we shall <hi rend="underline">all</hi> meet in a world where no sorrow or separation
     comes. Mr Reddy did not come with us, and will not come until on his way to the conference to
     be held at Syracuse April 13. Much love to yourself and family </p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>Elisabeth E. Reddy</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
