<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2584"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2584">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     November 12, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, november 12 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2584</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502073</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, November 12, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, november 12 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original available is a typed copy of the letter.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-12">1862-11-12</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Prisons/Prisoners, Agriculture</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2584T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes his trip to the Cedar Run battlefield, current skirmishes and prisoners
     taken, and the state of the surrounding countryside.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-12">Wednesday <abbr expan="Morning">Morn.</abbr> Nov., 12., 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Strasburg, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother;-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have only a few moments to write this morning before starting on to Winchester, where our
     Head Quarters are, but I know you will expect something from me, so you shall have it. I have
     been over the ridge to Culpeper <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> to see Gen. Lee, and had
     to come back by the way of New Market, a long circuit, but necessary for safety, as the enemy
     was along the base of the Ridge and rapidly advancing, though I hear that they have fallen back
     now. I was on the battlefield of Cedar Run, a portion of our army was encamped there. The
     evidences of the hotly contested field are plain to be seen. I enquired for Grinnan at
     Culpeper, and it was said he was in prison; for what or where I did not learn. I suppose he has
     been taken by a conscript officer, as he has not been on duty since he got well. Our army, that
     is Gen. Jackson's corps, is still in the lower end of the Valley, and I hope we may stay here,
     as the best check we can have on any advance of the enemy. We are skirmishing occasionally near
     the Blue Ridge, and we have taken a good many prisoners. 120 went up to Staunton a few days
     ago, and there are some 150 here today. It is said the enemy has been destroying everything
     before it, turning up the cornfodder in the fields, where they advanced in Loudon and Fauquier
     Co's. I do not know how true it is. I hope to come up soon. I must rest my horse. I wrote to
     you to keep my coat and boots until I sent or came. I hope you have got them, especially the
     boots. The crop of corn is fearfully short where I have been, and not much wheat sown, but I
     hope there will be enough. Buy some potatoes if you can. This is charming weather. I hope you
     have been able to seed a good deal. Put in all you can. My love to all the family. Write to me. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
