<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2583"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2583">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     September 28, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, september 28 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2583</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502072</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Only original available is a typed copy.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, September 28, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, september 28 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-09-28">1862-09-28</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, Military Authority, Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Slavery,
      African Americans, Women, Family, Patriotism, Enlistment, Agriculture, Home Front, National
      Government, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2583T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his brother on various topics, including recent battles and troop
     movements, his daughters' education, the lack of army provisions, northern opinions of the war,
     and the growth of the Confederate Army.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-09-28">Sunday. Sept. 28th., 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Bunkers Hill, 12 miles below Winchester</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother;</salute>
    </opener>

    <p> I got a letter from you while I was in Frederick City; the first one for a long time then
     that I <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> from home; since then, as before, we have been
     going, going, and I have not found time to write, though I have often thought of it. I wrote to
     you, I think, soon after the Manassa fight, then we crossed into Maryland and took a turn and
     came back to Martinsburg and then went to <orig reg="Harper's">Harpers</orig> Ferry and
     captured it, with the large stores etc. there, an account of which you have seen, then we came
     back up the river and fought the hotly contested battle of Sharpsburg in which no decided
     advantage remained with either side, though we gained the day on each wing, but Gen. McClaws
     failed to attack, as ordered, in the centre, and so no results came from our advantage, though
     we held the field of battle all the next day and buried our dead and collected our wounded, and
     then retired unmolested across the river during the night of the 18th. The next night a large
     force of the enemy came across and routed our picket on the bank and took 4 pieces of
     artillery, but Gen. Jackson went down in the morning and sent them howling back, killing some
     500 of them; since then all has been quiet. We moved our camp to near Martinsburg, and have
     been there until yesterday when we moved up here to find a better camp, foraging, etc. This
     country is almost destitute of every kind of forage or subsistence, for it has been full of
     armies for a long time. It is quite dry here too, though the people have been sending some. I
     could not buy anything in Maryland for the want of Maryland money, as we did not oblige them to
     take Confederate money, leaving every one to their own choice. I bought 20 yards of fulled
     cloth in Charlestown, some of which I intend for the servants, but will have to have some
     clothes for myself off it. When <pb n="2"/> we are near a town, on a march, our wagons are not
     with us, and there is no way of carrying anything but on your horse, and when on duty that is
     impossible, so I have not been able to get many things that I would have desired to purchase
     for you and Harriet. You asked my advice about sending Elmore to Mr. Stover. I think you had
     better send him; it will be much better than to have him lose so much time. I also think it
     will be well for you to employ Allie and keep the girls going, have them pursue a regular
     system of studies though, not merely music and painting, but common things, Reading, Writing,
     Arithmetic, etc., and it would be better for them to have 4 or 5 other scholars with them: it
     affords a stimulus that is wanting where there is only a family. They cannot too thoroughly
     learn the common branches; they are the basis of an education, and unless completely mastered
     all things besides will be comparatively worthless. See that Allie has all that she wants, of
     everything that can be had. If I find needed articles I will buy them, but I do not expect to
     find anything unless we go North again, and I do not see any chance for that at this time. It
     was a great thing, a glorious achievement, to free our state from the enemy and drive him
     beyond the Potomac. Defence is our true policy much as we might desire some other, and as long
     as we can hold our foe in check, and strike him hard blows when the opportunity offers, so long
     we are doing well and our cause is prospering, we gain by delay and the enemy loses. Our army
     is filling up from conscripts and men returning from hospitals, etc., and it is thought we
     number more now than we did before the recent battles. We must reorganize, though, for many of
     our regiments have lost all their officers, and some regiments are reduced to mere companies.
     The Yankee papers <pb n="3"/> say that one regiment of ours opposed two of theirs and three
     batteries and they could not move it. The 1st <orig reg="Louisiana">Louisana</orig>
     <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg.</abbr> had 10 color bearers shot, and had 144 bullet holes through
     the flag and flag staff.</p>
    <p> I have written to Staunton for a pair of boots,-to have them made. I cannot find a pair high
     enough in the instep. I could have bought a pair very reasonably in <abbr expan="Maryland"
     >Md.</abbr> if they had been high enough at the pinching point; as it is I am almost
     barefooted. I hope you will have grain enough for us and vegetables. I want to eat any quantity
     of vegetables if I should be fortunate enough to get home during the winter. I see no signs of
     peace as yet, and still think as I did at first, that only a change of administration will
     bring a change of policy in the North.</p>
    <p> I saw any number of N.Y. men at Harper's Ferry, men of the better class. They had
     volunteered because they did not wish to be drafted, and New York had furnished her part of the
     600,000. The privates all wanted to go home and stay there and were willing to let us alone,
     but the officers thought we ought to submit to the <hi rend="underline">old flag</hi>, and had
     no right to set up for ourselves, and all such nonsense.</p>
    <p> I hope I may get to come home before long. I am not very well just now; have a touch of
      <orig reg="diarrhea">diarrhoea</orig> and headache, but hope I may get over it soon. I am
     keeping quiet now.</p>
    <p> My best love to all. I have some nice paper, envelopes, etc., for Allie and the girls if I
     can ever get a chance to send them to them. Write often, and I will try and do better, if we do
     not have so much racing to do. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> Brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I wrote a few words to Father by Col. Seguin of Auburn.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
