<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2585"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2585">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     December 4, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, december 4 1862</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2585</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502074</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, December 4, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, december 4 1862</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-12-04">1862-12-04</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Home Front, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2585T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates his travels to eastern Virginia, and gives his brother instructions for
     food and other provisions at home. </p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Mr. Nelson H. Hotchkiss <lb/>Churchville, Va. <lb/>Care of <abbr expan="Quarter  
      Master"
      >Q.M.</abbr>
     <lb/>Staunton, Va.
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-12-04">Thursday, December 4th., 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Guiney's Depot, Richmond &amp; Fredericksburg <abbr expan="Railroad"
       >R.R.</abbr>, 10 miles from Fredericksburg, Va</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother;-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p> I got here this P.M. and though I am very tired I will drop you a single line to let you
     know that I got here safely, though the ride stirred up the bile awfully, and I was yellow
     enough with the Jaundice, but a good drink of cider last night cured it and I am better today.
     I pursued the army about 100 miles, in four days, and at last found it here in the lowlands,
     flatlands, swamplands, pinelands, sandlands, enless woodlands of eastern Virginia where, as I
     supposed, the Gen. wants me to make a map for him, for no one can get along here without some
     guide. Ask any one the direction to a place and he will tell you two or three ways, any one of
     which is twice as far as it ought to be. We are four miles from Gen. Lee's headquarters, but
     about 15 by the roads. I asked a man today the distance to a place, he said, "they used to call
     it 10 miles, but they "supervised" the roads a few days ago and found it only 8 miles, so I
     went on and concluded that they had better "Supervise" the roads again. The Yankee gun boats
     are at Port Royal, 15 miles below Fredericksburg on the Rappahannock river, and they cannot get
     up any higher and they have to get across the river before they can throw a shell on this side,
     and if they come up higher we can pick the men off the decks with sharpshooters. - No stir to
     report, everything is quiet and we are ready for them every way, I should think.</p>
    <p> I think you had better let me have one of the large hogs as you said you had no choice, on
     account of lard.- Have Mr. Wooster pack it down, or you see to it. - I wish you would get some
     oak plank, thin, and have me a box made about two feet long and 12 or 15 inches deep and wide,
     with a good lock - not padlock, and hinges that do not show, with holes <pb n="2"/> bored in
     the side 1/4 if an inch to let in air, and a pair of rope handles so I can have sent me a few
     substantial eatings from home, and keep them when I get them. - Fix it up pretty soon. - No
     living here unless you provide for yourself. I provided for a few things to go in before I left
     home. I wish you could find me 3-gallon stone jars, straight sides.- Write to me soon. Tell
     Allie to send her list to me - Love to all. I hope you may all be prospered in these times of
     trouble. Brother, I am fearful I may not get home to stay. Remember the fence and wood hovel,
     please, and lots of wood. Good-bye, love to all, </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
