<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2588"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="A2588">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, May
     20, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, may 20 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2588</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502077</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, May 20, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, may 20 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-05-20">1863-05-20</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Military Authority, Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Troop Movement, Military
      Strategy, Slavery, African Americans, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2588T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss gives his brother a description of recent military action: a series of battles that
     saw both his tent-mate killed and General Jackson wounded.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-05-20">May 20th 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2 <abbr
       expan="Northern Virginia">N.V.</abbr> Corps <abbr expan="Army of Northern  
        Virginia"
        >A.N.V.A.</abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother:-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have been too amiss in writing to you and replying to your last letter but I was very much
     engaged, as you may well suppose, during the many days of fighting that we have had and if
     possible I have been more busily employed since, having received orders the very day the fight
     ended to make a map of the battlefield, involving a necessity for a survey of the Wilderness,
     in which we fought, and my toes have been well blistered and my face well sunburned by the heat
     and exercise of last week. I got back to our quarters yesterday and avail myself of this
     evening to do a duty to you so long delayed. I supposed from your letter that you would very
     soon go over to the Valley and so my letter would not reach you at Howardsville and you would
     hear of my safety as soon as you got to Churchville. Though spared myself it seems lonely and
     desolate here; my tent mate and well beloved friend, Capt. Boswell was instantly killed and our
     revered and adored Commander is gone too. His aids have left also and only two or three of the
     "Old Staff" are here and though we all know and like and admire General A.P. Hill, who commands
     our Corps, still it is not as of old. The singular but good and great man that directed
     everything and stamped a peculiar character upon it is no longer at his post and everything
     wears an altered and lonely look, but such is earth and such are earthly things.</p>
    <p> We had a terrible battle or series of battles. We first occupied the same place that we did
     at the first battle; the enemy crossing over a large force there, but General Lee knew that was
     only a blind and as soon as the body of them crossed the river above and was coming down to our
     flank we left a protecting force in front and <pb n="2"/> went up to meet them, fought them
     until they had concentrated; then General Jackson moved some 9 miles around to the rear of them
     and fell on them unawares and routed and threw them into confusion and drove them some two
     miles when night came on, and in the confusion General Jackson was wounded; our men thrown into
     confusion by the breastwork of the enemy and the trees they had felled and there the fight was
     stayed for the night. General A.P. Hill being disabled by a bruise from a shell General Stuart
     came and took command and got the forces in order during the night and in the morning by ten
     o'clock had taken the heights which the enemy had occupied with his heavy force and fortified,
     defending it with 70 pieces of artillery. Our men behaved gallantly, never giving away in
     confusion, but when forced to fall back on account of the thick woods which prevented the
     advance of the line and gave advantages to the enemy they did it slowly and sullenly and at
     once reformed and pressed forward, driving the enemy at last from their stronghold and
     compelling them to go back with a heavy loss which would have been much greater if the country
     had been opened but the dense masses of pines and the broken character of the country made it a
     difficult matter to follow them with an organized force, and only such a one is safe when an
     enemy has such numbers.</p>
    <p> I am still at the same headquarters. General A.P. Hill is in Command of this Corps and I may
     stay here; I suppose I shall.</p>
    <p> There is one of the small stoves at Dr. Wilson's which you can get and then you will have
     the one in your dining room and if you want another I will try and fix for one for you before
     you need it. If you want the cup-<pb n="3"/>board don't deprive yourself of it. It was only in
     expectation that you would sell it that I spoke of it. I will find you a boy if I can. Sara has
     concluded that she cannot stand your woman after her performances in regard to Allie, so you
     had better hire her out at an advance which you can to some one that can manage her. I will
     find you a boy if I can but am kept very busy here by business. Write to me soon and I will not
     postpone so long. My love to all, </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
