<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2593"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2593">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     October 3, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, october 3 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2593</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502082</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, October 3, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, october 3 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-10-03">1864-10-03</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement, Family, Enlistment, Home Front,
      Agriculture, Women, Death/Casualties, Church/Religious Activity</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2593T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss describes to his brother news about recent skirmishes and the damage done by
     Federal troops in the Valley. He also relates news of people back home.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-10-03">Oct. 3rd. 1864.</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr>
       <abbr expan="Valley District"> V.D.</abbr> Mt. Sidney, Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It has been a long, long time since I heard from you, and I lately learned that you had not
     heard from me, though I have written often. I hope this may reach you <orig reg="though"
     >tho'</orig>. We have had all sorts of fortune lately. Have been badly handled in two fights,
     but not half as badly as the Yankees as our own papers assert. At Winchester we had whipped the
     Yankee infantry when their cavalry charged ours on the left and broke them and got in the rear
     of our infantry and compelled them to fall back, and they took a good many prisoners, but we
     retired in good order and saved all our trains; the same thing happened at Fisher's Hill, only
     the enemy got thirteen pieces of artillery. They only took some 500 prisoners from us. Since
     then we have successfully resisted them, holding them back at New Market and driving off their
     cavalry from New Hope and Waynesboro. The Yankees are now near Harrisonburg, but I hope they
     will not <hi rend="underline">be there</hi> long. They did but little damage in Augusta county;
     burned a few barns and mills in the lower end of the county, but in Rockingham they have done a
     vast amount of damage, burning mills, barns, wheat and hay stacks, and robbing houses. The
     cavalry, some of it, was from Broome county. I got hold of a copy of the Broome Co. Republican;
     see that David and Albert Hotchkiss had joined the cavalry. Giles had gotten the quota
     diminished by 100 for the county. Rev. Mr. Gilbert is in Binghamton, and I see that his
     daughter has lately been married to Mr. Bruce. I will send you the paper, though torn, as soon
     as I have sent it home. I only heard of them. Will look out for the prisoners now and get the
     news. The Yankees did not go to Churchville this time at all, those that <pb n="2"/> retreated
     from Waynesboro went by Spring Hill and Mossy Creek, but in so much haste that they did no
     damage. They burned Mohler's barn at the cave, and J.C. Roler's at Mt. Sidney. The loss of
     grain to us is very great, but I hope there is still enough left. The corn crop is a tolerable
     one, and they only use enough of that to feed their horses. The only damage done the <abbr
      expan="Railroad">R.R.</abbr> was to burn the bridges over South river at Waynesboro and over
     Christian's creek. They robbed Mr. Garber's store in Staunton of $5,000 worth of goods. There
     is a tale in circulation that Gen. Early was drunk at Winchester and also at Fisher's Hill.
     There is not one word of truth in it. A baser slander was never circulated. It is true Gen.
     Early is a drinker of spirits, is too fond of it, but I have never seen him under the influence
     of liquor since we started on this campaign. He is sober enough to know his duty and attend to
     it at all times, and it is much to be regretted that such stories should be circulated. My
     usual luck attends me in regard to horses. A few days ago I had 4, now I have only 2, one
     killed and one died, I got one for the killed one and now one has been stolen. I had a fine
     colt that I wished to send you to keep, but it was killed in the fight at Weyer's Cave.</p>
    <p> Miss Allie cannot stand it at home, and she desires to come back to Virginia. The fogs make
     her sick, and the people torment her, call her traitor, etc., and she is very anxious to get
     back. She had not heard from any of our people as she had spent most of the time at home and
     had not been well. I succeeded in getting a supply of flour with much difficulty. So many had
     sold all to the government before I got a chance to look out and a good many had sold on
     speculation, but I got a barrel here and one there, and so made up what I wanted. Henry
      <unclear>Sliey</unclear> stays <pb n="3"/> at the old place and manages it for the heirs, the
     old lady being dead. <abbr expan="Samuel">Sam.</abbr> Cochran died a few days ago, from fever,
     at home. Robert is a detailed farmer, also H. Seig and Frank Sterrett. Young Hite died from the
     effects of a wound. We have been resting today, after a hard march yesterday through the rain,
     and we have enjoyed the sunshine. I went and heard Mr. Bowman preach. Mr. Hildebrand has been
     getting along badly at Churchville. They do not support him. He says no one of the Methodists
     has done anything for him since he came there. Mr. Greeding has joined the Presbyterian Church
     and been made an Elder. They are all well at home. Got a good deal frightened about the
     Yankees. What are you doing and all the family? I should be delighted to see you all, but see
     no chance now. I have only been three days at home since March. My love to all. Write me soon
     to <abbr expan="Head  
 Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> Valley District, care of Gen. Early. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff.</abbr> Brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed.</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
