<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2590"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A2590">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss,
     August 21, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, august 21 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A2590</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502079</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>The only original is a typed copy.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Nelson H. Hotchkiss, August 21, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to nelson h hotchkiss, august 21 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-08-21">1863-08-21</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Death/Casualties, Family, Church/Religious Activity, Military Authority, Camp Life, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A2590T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his brother after hearing of the latter's severe illness. He also
     discusses the army's recent fast day, and the state of the army's provisions.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Nelson H. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-08-21">Aug. 21st, 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2 Corps Orange <abbr
       expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr> Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Brother:-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>With mingled feelings of pleasure and pain I received some two days ago your letter of July
     25th. Of pleasure at hearing from you that you were still in the land of the living, though not
     well; of pain that you thought that I had neglected you and had written something in my letter
     that grieved you, some unspoken but hinted at complaint of your doings, none of which things I
     had intended and it made me know at once that you are sick and all things wear a sombre hue
     with you. I have written several times, as often as I could find time in the constant marches
     of our army and yet now when quiet I find myself more busy than before, but I wrote to you a
     few days ago and the letter is with you before this and I do hope you are all better before
     now. I want to come and see you with my own eyes; handle your hearty welcome with my own hands,
     and know for my own satisfaction of the brother love I bear to you and yours and how you are
     really and truly getting along; how the world is using you and see if I can do anything for you
     and may be cheer you up some from my constant expectation of good and disposition to draw good
     out of everything, but enough of this. You know that I feel towards as a brother in all things
     and wish to say and do as a brother and so shall not give heed to any clouds that may for a
     time come over the sunshine.</p>
    <p> We have had an excellent fast day observance throughout the army; had an admirable sermon by
     Mr. Lacy at our headquarters on the hilltop on a beautiful lawn. A congregation of some 1500,
     including Generals Lee, Rodes, Johnson, etc. <pb n="2"/> The text was from 2nd Kings 6th 16ths.
     He administered rebuke where necessary, spared none from the highest to the lowest and drew a
     fine argument to show that God is certainly on our side because the conduct of our army and
     people is, in the main right, while the conduct of our enemy is such that a just and <orig
      reg="righteous">righeous</orig> God could not approve. He called upon each one for himself to
     become good for himself, rectify his own errors and so the whole people become good, and then
     we may ask for God's blessing as his own people. I can but think that good will come to us from
     this day; good everyway, and from this day we may date the renewal of success.</p>
    <p> Our men are being nicely clothed and shod and will soon present a nice appearance; a
     uniformed army. The Commissariat of our army is in fine condition too and today the soldiers
     had roasting ears issued to them, a barrel to the hundred men, and that much is to be issued
     daily while the roasting ears season lasts. There is enough to eat. The bugbear of starvation
     has fled; the enemy has cruelly said that they would starve us and Heaven answered them with
     blessing our land with abundance. We fasted until a 6 P.M. dinner. We had roasting ears,
     tomatoes, potatoes, good light rolls, and <orig reg="beefsteak">beafstake</orig>, a good enough
     dinner for any one and so fare the soldiers now while we are resting, and it is well it is so
     for the times of privation always come when marching and fighting begin, as begin it must,
     although there are no signs now of any movements and a profound quiet reigns everywhere, the
     enemy having retired further away.</p>
    <p> I hope you succeeded in getting in something to eat and do not have to buy at the horrid
     prices now prevailing. <pb n="3"/> A change must come before long in some way, no one knows
     how, but it is sure to come.</p>
    <p> I am glad you advised Miss Allie as you did, but I might have known that you would have
     given her good advice. I agree with you entirely in your views about what she had better do. I
     have asked her to come to my house and stay and she is welcome to if she will and will be
     welcomed there if she will only think so. </p>
    <p> I hope to hear from you in a few days and then will be able to tell if I can come and see
     you all and I shall come if we stay here.</p>
    <p> I fear the change of <orig reg="weather">water</orig> has had a bad effect on you all but
     hope you are getting used to it. Remember me very kindly to the family, Harriet and Lora and
     Sarah, the grownup family and Elmer and Ollie and Neddy and Styles He the little mischief, has
     no doubt forgotten me.</p>
    <p> I wrote to Father a few lines while in <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> My kind regards
     to Dr. Young. I should like to see him playing farmer. Be of good cheer. Write to me soon. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your affectionate brother,</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
