<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2919"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2919">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 15,
                    1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 15 1864</title>
        <author>Ott, Ginnie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2919</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502104</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Ginnie Ott to Enos Ott, December 15, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county ginnie ott to enos ott, december 15 1864</title>
            <author>Ginnie Ott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Enos Ott Papers, Private
                            Collection of Gail Ott</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-15">1864-12-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Desertion/Leave, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2919T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this letter to her husband, Ginnie informs Enos of Henry's continued stay at
                    home, the impending marriage between Mr. Steele and Miss Annie McNutt, and the
                    status of her attempts to have Enos's hat and boots made.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Mr Enos Ott<lb/>Camp Lee<lb/>Richmond<lb/>Virginia<lb/>Care of Rev Henry
                    Brown
                    <name type="recipient">Mr Enos Ott</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-15">Dec 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Home</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Husband</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received your letters of the 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> &amp; 8<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> yesterday and was glad to hear that you were well and
                    doing well and hope these few lines may find you enjoying the same great
                    blessing I have been very well since you left except for the last few days I
                    have not felt very well I was not well last night and this morning but feel
                    better now. I think it is caused from eating liver pudding for supper last
                    night. the rest are all well. Henry is still at home &amp; busy as he can be
                    threshing he has not bailed any of his hay yet but expects to get at it as soon
                    as he can get the hoops ready, he sent to the mountain to get some hoops made
                    but was disappointed he only got the poles and will have them to shave himself,
                    he has written to the army to get his detail extended but has not heard from it
                    yet. Alex was down the valley last week took down a load of apples he said he
                    never saw as many apples at one place in his life they were just rotting. he
                    said he did not see a man down there that he knew they had all gone to Richmond.
                    Becca was over last night and said Mr Newton would make your hat soon but he had
                    promised some others before you spoke and would have to make theirs first. I
                    expect to go over to Pas next week and I will try and get him to make it as soon
                    as possible, your boots are made but Mag thinks they are too small. I made you
                    another pair of gloves and if you do not get home we will send you some things
                        <pb n="2"/>but I hope you will get home soon I hope you will know soon what
                    you will have to depend upon, though I think if you do not get home there is a
                    poor chance for others getting off. We have not got the cloth home from Staunton
                    yet but Mr Spencer is going down Thursday and will bring it for us. I think if
                    we dont soon get it we will not get our cloaks made before Christmas. Mag wrote
                    to you for a pattern but I dont think I will wait for a pattern as I heard they
                    are the same there that they are here. There has been very bad weather here for
                    the last week snow ever since last Friday and the appearance is very good for
                    more. Charlotte says if you want to see her single once more you had better
                    hurry home for if you dont come soon she cannot wait. Davie B sung over at the
                    school house last Saturday night and is going to sing tomorrow night. Mag and
                    Hannah are at a sewing today at Mr Thomas Harris helping the girls to make their
                    cloaks I was invited too but was not able to go I did not expect to go if I had
                    been well. I have just finished reading a statement of the treatment of <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> L. M. Lewis when a prisoner in the north and it
                    is the most outrageous things I ever read I wish you could see it. I commenced
                    this letter Thursday and found I could not send it to the office and it is now
                    Saturday. I believe I have no news except that Mr Steele &amp; Miss Annie
                        M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Nutt are to be married next Thursday. old <abbr
                        expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Henry was here this
                    morning put a black scarf on Henry <unclear>arm</unclear>. Davie Black sings at
                        <orig reg="Newport">newport</orig> today and Mag is going over to the office
                    &amp; to the singing she is going to start, so I must close hoping you will
                    get home soon</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your affectionate Wife</salute>
                    <signed>Ginnie</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><pb n="1"/>PS I expect to go over to Pas the last of next
                        week and if you dont get home before then direct to Greenville. Ginnie</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
