<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2947"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2947">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    October 15, 1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, october 15 1865</title>
        <author>Spillma, Robert B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2947</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502117</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, October 15, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, october 15 1865</title>
            <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-10-15">1865-10-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term/>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2947T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert writes to Kate of his devoted friendship to her, his desire to maintain
                    regular correspondence and his plans never to marry until he can properly
                    support a wife.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-10-15">Oct 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Fredericksburg Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sister Kate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your very kind long looked for &amp; ever welcome letter of the 11<hi
                        rend="super">th</hi> just reached me safely about 8 <orig reg="o'clock"
                        >oclock</orig> last night. I was truly delighted to hear from you. I felt
                    exceedingly anxious about you when I wrote to you in September I was by no means
                    sure that my letter would ever reach you. <orig reg="Consequently"
                    >consequently</orig> I <orig reg="labored">laboured</orig> under many fears
                    &amp; doubts as to whether I should ever hear from <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">you</add> again or not &amp; to be deprived of a
                    correspondence with so dear a friend as I claim you to be would be truly hard to
                    bear with. Ah! my dear Kate I am sure you can form no idea how much I missed the
                    pleasures of your dear sweet letters during our long silence. I was truly
                    deprived of a pleasure beyond the comprehension of many but now that our
                    correspondence has commenced again I feel perfectly delightful I hope that
                    nothing may happen to <pb n="2"/>prevent a regular correspondence as long as we
                    continue to be such devoted friends. I am satisfied that marriage on my part
                    will never make me forget my dear sweet sister Kate as for my dear little friend
                    Lou she is well aware that you &amp; I are devoted friends &amp;
                    correspondents &amp; I know her well enough to be perfectly satisfied that
                    one of her kind &amp; gentle nature will, or does highly appreciate your
                    true &amp; unselfish friendship for sure, but as for marrying, indeed my
                    friend that is something that I certainly <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> expect
                    to do soon my present situation will not admit of any thing of the sort. <orig
                        reg="Were">were</orig> I to get married now I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    think that I would be doing any lady justice in consequece of my embarrassed
                    situation in life. I <add hand="h1" place="inline">am</add> fully determined
                    never to marry any one until I feel capable of placeing the object of my
                    affections in a <orig reg="parallel">paralel</orig> condition to her present one
                    or better it if possible. Therefore I fear it will be a <hi rend="underline"
                        >long long</hi> time before I can realize any thing of the kind. Well enough
                    on that subject <pb n="3"/>I am truly glad to hear that your dear brother
                    &amp; friend Willis are safe at home after the great fall of our poor old
                    Confederacy. <orig reg="It">it</orig> is truly a great blessing that they were
                    spared to return to their homes &amp; loved ones. I assure you that I have
                    really enoyed peace &amp; quietude since the close of the war not
                    withstanding that it did not end in accordance with my desire &amp; at first
                    I was truly thunderstruck, but when I considered that the grief of one could not
                    possibly do any good I concluded I would try to enjoy peace &amp; the sweets
                    of home once more &amp; try to thank God that it was no worse &amp; that
                    a few of us were spared to tell the tale. You see from the steading of my letter
                    that I have left old <orig reg="Westmoreland">westmoreland</orig> for a season
                    &amp; am at this time staying at this place where I expect to be for several
                    weeks. <orig reg="Will">will</orig> try to keep you posted as to when I shall
                    remove from here so that your letters may always be properly directed so they
                    may reach me safely. <orig reg="You">you</orig> must write to me as often as you
                    can your letters are such a great comfort &amp; satisfaction to me. <pb
                        n="4"/>You must remember me kindly to your Pa &amp; Ma &amp; sisters
                    &amp; all enquiring friends if there be any, but of course I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> expect there are any from the fact that I have no
                    acquaintances in that section of the County. With much love for your dear self
                    believe dear Kate to be as ever</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your ever affectionate &amp; truly devoted brother</salute>
                    <signed>Robert</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">write soon &amp; direct to Fredericksburg Va
                            <lb/><abbr expan="yours">yrs</abbr> R. <lb/>Oct 23<hi rend="super"
                        >d</hi> This letter was written the 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> but not
                        mailed until til <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. <orig reg="No">no</orig>
                        changes have taken place I am well &amp; truly hope this may reach you
                        &amp; find you the same <lb/>my love to all, <lb/><abbr expan="yours"
                            >yrs</abbr> fondly Robt</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
