<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2945"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2945">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    January 12, 1865</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, january 12 1865</title>
        <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2945</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502115</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Robert B. Spillman to Amanda C. Armentrout, January 12, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta robert b spillman to amanda c armentrout, january 12 1865</title>
            <author>Spillman, Robert B.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-01-12">1865-01-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Medicine/Hospitals, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2945T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Robert discusses his pleasure in his acquaintance with Kate, remarking on how
                    close they have become since they first met. He then writes poetically of his
                    surroundings at Chimborazo Hospital in Richmond.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>August Co. Va</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-01-12">Jan 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1865</date>
                        <name type="place">Office <abbr expan="Chimborazo">Chimbo</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Hospital">Hosp</abbr> Richmond</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sister Kate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Again I have the pleasure of responding to your Ever dear &amp; affectionate
                    letter that reached me to day the perusal of which was done with no little
                    degree of pleasure. I can not find words to express my self on the present
                    occasion could I but wield the pen of a novelist, I might passibly be able to
                    give some faint idea of my high appreciation of your dear letters and the pure
                    unselfish friendship you have to long &amp; so repeatedly expressed for me
                    how often in my silent musings does my mind wander back to the days when I had
                    no knowledge of you, before I was <orig reg="honored">honoured</orig> with your
                    acquaintance &amp; your friendship. <orig reg="How">how</orig> different
                    were the lonely hours spent then, no fond anticipation lay before me of a day
                    that would bring with its natural charms a messenger from a <hi rend="underline"
                        >dear dear</hi> friend in the distance, a letter from you dear Kate. How sad
                    &amp; still how pleasing are the many changes since first we met, both
                    combined are truly almost incomprehensible. think, for a moment, but a little
                    more than a year ago we were as those who had never lived to each other but time
                    with its <pb n="2"/>many changes find us now as it were bonded &amp; <orig
                        reg="bosom">bossom</orig> friends. <orig reg="How">how</orig> pleasing it is
                    to me to think that I have the esteem &amp; confidence of a friend so pure,
                    so noble, as your self. Tis truly an honour not merited by me I can scarecely
                    realize that one so insignificant as my self should enjoy such pleasures as are
                    realized from such a pleasing correspondence. Well dear Kate, you had need <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">not</add> expect a long or interesting letter this
                    time as my mind is restive it seems that it <orig reg="can't">cant</orig>
                    possibly be concentrated or centered upon any one particular subject. Not
                    withstanding the present moment is a time when I should feel or rather be able
                    to produce some sentimental language for now it is about Eleven <orig
                        reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> at night. No sound breaks the stillness of the
                    night save the constant roar of the rapid waters of the James River as it rushes
                    madly over the rocky falls wending its way along the winding current towards its
                    mother ocean. Other than that, all is quiet. The blazing stars shine brilliantly
                    high up in their orbit while the gentle moon sheds its silvery light over all
                    nature. Still I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> feel sentimental since I <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> find words to express my self <orig reg="tonight">to
                        night</orig>. I hope you will excuse my brevity &amp; I'll promise to do
                    better <orig reg="next">nex</orig> time, but that is a promise that <pb n="3"/>I
                    aught not to make, as I'll be most sure to break it for <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">I</add> am not endowed with the mental faculties which
                    enables one to write a communicative or interesting letter. <orig reg="Still"
                        >still</orig> I am fond of writing, if I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig>
                    interest or give information. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> exactly agree with
                    my dear little friend Lou. She seems <add hand="h1" place="inline">to</add>
                    think that letters should not be written unless it bears important news, or
                    something cheering or animating but it is not so with me. I like to speak at a
                    distance with my dear friend through the silent medium of the pen tis truly a
                    pleasure that I would not be deprived for the world. I could not <orig
                        reg="dispense">dispence</orig> with such a pleasure while I am blessed with
                    the power of writing I must profit by it. Well dear Kate the old Bacon Clock has
                    just told by its lonesome ring the approach of midnight hour, so I must close.
                    My love to all with a full portion for your self.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Write soon to your fond &amp; affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>Robert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
