<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2965"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2965">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    October 11, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, october 11 1863</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2965</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502135</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, October 11, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, october 11 1863</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-11">1863-10-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Troop Movement, Death/Casualties, Family,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2965T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate about her cousin's illness in the army, his ailing toe,
                    the nearness of the Yankees, and the preacher who talks to the men often.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate A. Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate A. Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-11">October 11th 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">On Pickett</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dearest Kate</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> your kind &amp; interesting letter
                    this morning and being on a <orig reg="reserved">resurved</orig> post I hasten
                    to reply My health is very good &amp; hope this may find you enjoying the
                    same. <orig reg="Every">Evry</orig> thing is quiet along the lines our foes are
                    quietly watching us from the north side of the Rapidan <orig reg="every"
                    >evry</orig> thing would betoken a friendly appearance if our Officers would
                    allow us to <orig reg="traffic">trafick</orig> with the Yankees, a great many of
                    our boys bought <orig reg="tobacco">topacco</orig> for the purpose of trading
                    for coffee; with all the yankee notions that might be brought forward for the
                    exchange of the great southern weed <pb n="2"/>your cousin Jimmie V has been
                    complaining for some time he looks badly I came across him the other day in the
                    woods lying down when I first came upon him I felt like kneeling down beside him
                    &amp; raising him in my arms I <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> for about a
                    minute &amp; looked at him &amp; then called him by name I asked him how
                    he felt. <orig reg="He">he</orig> said about as usual was just <orig
                        reg="sunning">suning</orig> him self a little you need not be in the least
                    uneasy <orig reg="about">abut</orig> Jake no doubt he will write to say as he is
                    left in camp well Kate Jake made me blush the other day by asking <orig
                        reg="where">whare</orig> I was he was looking at me at the same time. Abe
                    answering told him I was writing to his sis. Jake then said he suspicioned that
                    then all the boys commenced laughing you may well <orig reg="know">now</orig> it
                    was very hard to keep from blushing all the boys tease me a <orig reg="great"
                        >grate</orig> deal more since I come back than <orig reg="they">thay</orig>
                    ever did before but I never mind them. I often tell them <pb n="3"/>you said you
                    had a <orig reg="great">grate</orig> deal of company since my return I am glad
                    for I know you can always enjoy your self when in gay company I suppose you have
                    been <orig reg="wondering">wandering</orig>
                    <orig reg="where">whare</orig> I got my red ink. Our post is near a patch of
                    Poakroads <orig reg="berries">perries</orig> of which Brother John made the ink
                    that I am now using I hope it may last longer than the marks of a lead pencil. I
                    told John that Hettie sent her love to him he blushed and replied that he would
                        <orig reg="have to">hafto</orig> return the compliment <orig reg="There"
                        >Thare</orig> is none but <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; myself in this post.
                        <orig reg="We">we</orig> have a gay time John says he will not believe that
                    H sent her respects to him unless I will let him read the letter he says he
                        <orig reg="knows">nows</orig> that Hettie is <orig reg="too">to</orig>
                    backward to send her love to any one and says the blame must rest on you I
                    obliged him a great deal about the blush on his cheek telling him that it was a
                    hidden disease. <pb n="4"/>I was in hopes that Charles was at home by this time
                    I hope while he is an exile that he may be tamed I have never heard from sister
                    since I returned to camp I am very <orig reg="anxious">ancious</orig> to hear
                    from her I will write again to be sure that she may hear from me. oh Kate I have
                    no news &amp; how am I to <orig reg="interest">interrest</orig> you you said
                    you had paid Kate a visit &amp; that you ware rather <orig reg="fearful"
                        >fearfull</orig> that Tom will not come; I hope he will for if he <orig
                        reg="disappoints">disapoints</orig> her She <orig reg="will">wil</orig> take
                    it very hard if she should be so fortunate as to get married I hope you may be
                        <orig reg="there">thare</orig> &amp; enjoy yourselves to the <orig
                        reg="greatest">gratest</orig> advantage I think Mr Lee <orig reg="will"
                    >wil</orig> hardly let me <orig reg="off">of</orig> this time as I had such a
                    long stay this summer. My toe is getting so that I can stand the
                    <unclear>truss</unclear> very well The boys are mostly in fine spirits Jake is
                    not very <orig reg="well">wil</orig> this morning but I think its nothing more
                    than a slight bilious attack &amp; will be well in a day or <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">two</add>
                    <pb n="5"/>they just remind me of my duty to write to your cous; John B to get
                    that ring finished &amp; return it to you Miss Kate Shields <orig reg="will"
                        >wil</orig> probably think that her ring is gone We have prayer meeting one
                    night and preaching the next I believe the <orig reg="boys">boy</orig> generally
                    like our new chaplain the Rev. Mr. See. I think he is a good man &amp; a
                    noble Preacher hope his efforts may be crowned with success <pb n="6"/>your
                    cous, He sends his respects to you oh yes Jim Campbell told me to tell you that
                    he was going to strut in that <orig reg="Confederate">confederate</orig>
                    <orig reg="uniform">unaform</orig> that he is going to get of him I must bring
                    this to a close by asking an interest in your prayers write soon as I am always
                        <orig reg="anxious">ancious</orig> to hear from you I remain yours truly as
                    ever.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Good bye dear Kate at present</salute>
                    <signed>W</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Excuse my ink as it blots badly</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
