<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2971"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2971">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    March 24, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, march 24 1864</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2971</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502141</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, March 24, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, march 24 1864</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-24">1864-03-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2971T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate of a snowball Battle with Rhodes' division, troop
                    movements, preaching in camp, and his love for her.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss Kate Armentrout<lb/>Greeville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-24">Mar 24th 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Stonewall Brigade</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> your letter on the 21st was truly glad to
                    hear from you I had almost given up all hope of ever hearing from you again, but
                    it seemed that I was <orig reg="blessed">blest</orig> at the eleventh hour by
                    receiving a long &amp; affectionate letter, Peace seemed a stranger to my
                    mind I went to preaching regular &amp; often found my mind wandering on
                    things that <orig reg="didn't">didnt</orig> interest my soul. Salvation tonight
                    I am on <orig reg="guard">gard</orig> and as I can not sleep I have concluded to
                    spend my <orig reg="lonely">lonly</orig> hours in writing to my best of friends.
                    My health is very good, I have no reason to complain of any thing. I am only <pb
                        n="2"/>in all things to say Lord thy will be done not mine. Thare is no news
                    astir in camp that would <orig reg="interest">interrest</orig>. <orig
                        reg="Every">Evry</orig> thing is quiet along the Rapidan. Our Brigade has to
                    go on Picket Monday morning I hope we may have a <orig reg="pleasant"
                    >plesant</orig> time We had quite a heavy snow storm <orig reg="here"
                    >hear</orig> last <orig reg="Tuesday">tuesday</orig> &amp; <orig
                        reg="Tuesday">tueasday</orig> night It was from ten to twelve inches deep
                    the boys had a gay time snow balling; our Brigade bantered <orig reg="Rhodes'"
                        >Roades</orig>
                    <orig reg="division">devision</orig>
                    <orig reg="they">thay</orig> come out and drove us back to our quarters we had
                    no General to command us in the first Battle they had two. Walker seeing us
                    drove back came out &amp; rallied the old brigade and drove our <orig
                        reg="opponents">opponants</orig> to <orig reg="their">thare</orig> quarters
                    capturing one of <orig reg="their">thare</orig> Gen I suppose <orig reg="there"
                        >thare</orig> was two thousand engaged on either side. <orig reg="There"
                        >Thare</orig> was none killed on either side but <pb n="3"/>a great many
                    bloodly n<del hand="h1">o</del>oses. Dear Kate wish I was by your side <orig
                        reg="tonight">to night</orig> I am sure I could talk much easier than write
                    I do not feel my self capable of answering your letter but look over my many
                    short comings &amp; I will try Dear Kate you spoke of kneeling at my feet to
                    implore mercy I pray thee never kneel to no man, but rather to thy creator in
                        <orig reg="whom">hoom</orig> is our only help, he can change the hearts of
                    those that hate us; to love &amp; <orig reg="respect">repect</orig> us; Dear
                    Kate can you imagine my <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig> when I came to the
                    words "Willie I love thee; &amp; my love has been <orig reg="tried"
                    >tryed</orig>; ah methinks I can hear those words <orig reg="coming"
                    >comming</orig> up from thy noble but storm tossed heart; and they make me feel
                    like a strong man. Then again Oh God is it not <orig reg="sinful"
                    >sinfull</orig>, you entreat me to forget, who, my first, my only, and I hope my
                    last lover. Dear Kate is this not <orig reg="cruel">crual</orig>; one that loves
                    me one that I love, to advise me to forsake her, what have I done to bring this
                        <orig reg="judgment">judgement</orig> upon me have I com<pb n="4"/>mitted
                    some foul deed that will leave a stain up on my character or am I not good <orig
                        reg="enough">enoughf</orig> for thee I can not bring my self for a moment to
                    think that you would advise me thus on account of my need of worldly goods; oh I
                    know you know to well on this last, that God is the giver of all such gifts you
                    said you cared not for your own <orig reg="happiness">hapiness</orig> but that
                    you would be <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig> in seeing your friends <orig
                        reg="happy">hapy</orig> Dear Kate let me pray <orig reg="thee">the</orig>
                    never <orig reg="speak">speake</orig> thus again I for one of thy loving hands
                    will never <orig reg="cease">seace</orig> striving <orig reg="until"
                    >untill</orig> it may please the almighty to <orig reg="place">plase</orig> me
                    in a condition to make you <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig> Then &amp; not till
                    then shall I be <orig reg="perfectly">berfectly</orig>
                    <orig reg="happy">hapy</orig>, then if you refuse me I can live my days as I am;
                    when I learn to quit using tobacco I will do it for your sake you asked me
                    whether I went to see your cous, Lizzie I did not I wanted to see her but could
                    not I was in trouble I had left a face that I loved with out seeing it &amp;
                    no other face seemed familiar. Dear Kate let us forget the past &amp; try
                    &amp; live as two loving friends for awhile; then if it may please our
                    master may I hope we may be drawn closer friends</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                    <seg type="postscript">You will please excuse all mistakes &amp; if you find
                        any thing in this <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to your feelings I pray they forgive me.
                        I have written to night with a heart that seems to me nothing but love but
                        its pure &amp; forgiven nature you will please write soon as I am all in
                        hopes that the day may soon roll round when I may again have the pleasure of
                        beholding your face &amp; having the permission of once more <orig
                            reg="touching">tuching</orig> your ruby lips I would have <orig
                            reg="the">the</orig> never to forget me in your prayers that I may <orig
                            reg="prove">proove</orig> a <orig reg="valiant">valient</orig> soldier
                        to my country and to my God I must close. Please have no complaint in this
                        letter my love to all <orig reg="enquiring">enquireing</orig> friends if
                            <orig reg="there">thare</orig> be any Now may the blessing of a great
                        &amp; good God be with you friend your well wisher.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
