<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A2977"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A2977">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout,
                    January 19, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 19 1863</title>
        <author>Brand, William F.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Mary Elizabeth McCaskill</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Elizabeth Ladner</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A2977</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502147</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: William F. Brand to Amanda C. Armentrout, January 19, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta william f brand to amanda c armentrout, january 19 1863</title>
            <author>William F. Brand</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William F. Brand Papers</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-19">1863-01-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Economy, Troop Movement, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A2977T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>William writes to Kate of the army serving oysters but having no butter to eat
                    them with, and of other news from his camp, including news on the Yankees and
                    troop movements.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Miss A. C. Armentrout<lb/>Greenville<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Virginia
                    <name type="recipient">Miss A. C. Armentrout</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-19">January 19th 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Winder, Caroline Co. Va</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have seated my self for the purpose of writing you a few lines to inform you of
                    our <orig reg="whereabouts">wharabouts</orig> my health is very good &amp;
                    hope <orig reg="these">theese</orig>
                    <orig reg="few">fiew</orig> lines may find you enjoying the blessings of health
                    and <orig reg="happiness">happines</orig> I have been waiting in <orig
                        reg="suspense">suspence</orig> for some time for a letter from you I have
                    come to the conclusion that my letter never came to hand I wrote soon after I
                    came down, you can well <orig reg="imagine">inmagin</orig> how <orig
                        reg="lonesome">lonsome</orig> I have been in looking for a <orig reg="few"
                        >fiew</orig> lines from you I will now send out the second arrow hoping it
                    may <pb n="2"/>find <orig reg="it's">its</orig> destination Jake told me
                    yesterday <orig reg="evening">eavning</orig> that you had never <orig
                        reg="heard">hurd</orig> from me since my return to camp I had in writing
                    yesterday <orig reg="but">put</orig> I thought I would wait and send this by Mr
                    Carson as the other failed by mail I have no news of importance to write We
                        <orig reg="were">ware</orig> on pickett last week had a very easy tour of
                    it, I could not see any yankees across the river I think the <orig reg="greater"
                        >grater</orig> portion of <orig reg="their">thare</orig> army has <orig
                        reg="gone">gon</orig> South &amp; some twenty or thirty thousand of our
                    army has <orig reg="gone">gon</orig> to meet them we have orders to keep one
                    days rations in our haversacks <orig reg="until">untill</orig> further orders
                    Some thinks we are going to South <orig reg="Carolina">Carlina</orig> I <orig
                        reg="haven't">havent</orig> but one objection to going It <orig reg="would"
                        >wuld</orig> be so seldom <pb n="3"/>that we could hear from home I would
                    like to See the country &amp; then we would be on the <orig reg="coast">cost</orig>
                    <orig reg="where">whare</orig> we could get plenty of oysters we <orig
                        reg="have to">hafto</orig> pay six dollars a gallon for them here &amp;
                    no butter then to eat with them, well I got a letter the other day from the
                    mill; I tell you that it had Sams name in more than one line I had to <orig
                        reg="laugh">laughf</orig> at several of her conclusions of the hearafter we
                    have a large Co. now for duty some sixty odd, the largest in the brigade we have
                    got our tents at last the boys are busy building <orig reg="chimneys"
                    >chimmies</orig> to them, I hope we may camp <orig reg="here">hear</orig> all
                    winter We have plenty of wood and tolerable good water, and are enjoying all the
                    sweets of camp life, and you know they are <orig reg="few">fiew</orig> at best
                        <pb n="4"/>I hardly know what to write to <orig reg="interest"
                    >interrest</orig> you I hope you have <orig reg="received">recieved</orig> my
                    other letter before this time I wish I was <orig reg="where">whare</orig> I
                        <orig reg="wouldn't">wouldnt</orig> have to write for it is a <orig
                        reg="great">grate</orig> deal more pleasure to me to talk to you than to
                    write I have often been near you in my dreams since I last seen you, but alas
                    what are dreams they vanish in a moment from our sight &amp; are <orig
                        reg="gone">gon</orig> forever I hope the time may soon come when I may
                    fondly encircle thee in my arms &amp; call thee mine oh Kate forget <orig
                        reg="thee">the</orig> I never can &amp; would not be forgot for the gold
                    of opher, I hope your path may be <orig reg="strewn">strune</orig> with flowers
                    and if I can not make you happy some other may I ask an interest in your prayers
                    excuse this <orig reg="uninteresting">uninterresting</orig> letter I will try
                    and do better next time let no one see this my respects to all &amp; my love
                    to you</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>from your true friend</salute>
                    <signed>W.F.B.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
