<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4038"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4038">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, May 31,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, may 31 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4038</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502237</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, May 31, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, may 31 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-05-31">1863-05-31</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Women, Military Strategy, Military Authority, Family,
      Desertion/Leave, Home Front, Slavery, African Americans</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4038T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss writes to his wife, describing personnel changes in the Army after the Battle of
     Chancellorsville. Hotchkiss does not anticipate being able to go home soon, but comments on
     affairs at home.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-05-31">May 31<hi rend="super">
        <hi rend="underline">st</hi>
      </hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="super">
       <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
      </hi> Corps.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Darling Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received, a few days ago, your letter stating that you had just received my second letter
     since the battle, only relieving you of suspense after a long time -- too long, for such
     suspense weighs heavily, &amp; pressed out the life blood too -- but I hope you will not
     indulge in painful apprehensions or gloomy fore bodings, trusting that Providence will continue
     to be, as He has so far been, merciful to spare &amp; save in all the dangers that surround
     us -- You have received my last letter, in which I enclosed some money &amp; in which told
     you what I had been engaged in -- I have nearly completed my map of the Battles, to Gen. <orig
      reg="Lee's">Lees</orig> satisfaction -- I expect to remain where I am -- as Gen. Ewell has
     arrived and taken command -- he was married two or three days ago to a widow Brown of <abbr
      expan="Tennessee">Tenn.</abbr> who nursed him while sick, being a cousin of his, her kind
     attentions endearing her very much to him, no doubt,<pb n="2"/>The Army has been divided into
     three Corps, Longsheet still has the 1<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">st</hi>
     </hi>, (ours) Gen. Ewell's will be the 2<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
     </hi> &amp; Gen. AP Hill is made Lt. Gen. and takes command of the 3<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">rd</hi>
     </hi>, all well officered, and we have our wishes gratified here in having Gen. Ewell to
     command the old army of Gen. Jackson -- as much of the ardor as could possibly be <hi
      rend="underline">transferred</hi> to any man has been transferred by this Corps to Gen. Ewell,
     much of the "old Army of the Valley" turned out to meet him when he came and seems to be
     enthused by his presence -- an omen of good, I take it, for the success of his management of
     them; he is compelled to use his crutches still, though he has a a cork leg &amp; will
     probably soon be able to use it alone -- I hope so -- I do not suppose we will remain here
     long, as the symptoms of a move are quite strong, we may go any day &amp; we may stay here
     indefinitely -- I am sorry you was so disappointed in regard to my coming home -- I should have
     been along with Gen. <abbr expan="Jackson's">J's</abbr> remains but I was 20 miles off, on the
     battlefield surveying it, under orders,<pb n="3"/>when he died and did not know of his death
     until after he was sent away -- I was at the post of duty, where <hi rend="underline">he</hi>
     wished every one to be. I do not know when I may come home -- I see no chance now &amp; may
     not find one for months to come, but, My Dear, you may be sure I shall come whenever I can
     consistent with duty, for I long to see you and my dear little ones, how you all must miss me,
     for if in the bustle and excitement of camp life my thoughts constantly go back to my home
     &amp; its beloved trio, ho much more must your thoughts, undistrubed by the calm &amp;
     quiet of the country, wander away to my unstable abiding places -- O! that the days of peace
     would soon come that I might again return to the routine of a quiet life -- that is all my
     ambition craves. I saw Thornton Stout &amp; Capt. McRoberts today, both just from home -- I
     send this by Capt. <abbr expan="McRoberts">M</abbr> -- he says Nelson moved last Monday -- and
     I gathered from them some news from the county. My butter gave out today, but I do not see how
     I can get any from home -- Capt. Elhart is now in Staunton &amp; would bring some to me if
     he had it there -page four- and so would Capt. Garber, but I do not know how long they will be
     there &amp; so, cannot give you any definite directions -- how would it do to send the jar
     to Dr. Young and have him keep it in his cellar until he got a chance to send it by Capt.
     Elhart, Capt. Garber or some one else -- you be the judge of that, but do not by any means send
     away what you must want for your own use, unliess you can buy what you want -- I hope your
     chicken business has done well this spring. I send you sixty dollars in this, and I sent you
     forty the other day &amp; will send from time to time so will have enough -- I want to send
     some &amp; pay up the half <orig reg="year's">years</orig> hire of William in July before
     long. Mr. Lacy preached us a splendid sermon today on the parable of the supper &amp; we
     had a large and attentive audience -- Gen. Lee, Gens Ewell, Hill, Pendleton &amp; a crowd
     of lesser lights -- I think Gen. Lee is one of the noblest men I ever saw -- he is a man ever
     way -- My love for you all -- I know my little girls must be growing rapidly, every way I
     trust, in size, goodness, learning, working, and all the like -- this is a busy world &amp;
     all must do what they can -- Write often and to the <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr>
     of 2<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
     </hi> Corps <abbr expan="Army of Northern 
 Virginia">A. N. Va.</abbr> and it will find me -- .
     Good bye &amp; God bless you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your loving husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
