<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4052"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4052">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     September 6, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, september 6 1863</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4052</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502251</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, September 6, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, september 6 1863</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-09-06">1863-09-06</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Home Front, Military Authority, National Government, African Americans, Slavery,
      Church/Religious Activity, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4052T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss conveys various pieces of news to his wife: the possibility of leave, affairs at
     home, and preaching in camp.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-09-06">Sunday Night -- Sept. 6<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr> 2<hi rend="underline">
       <hi rend="super">nd</hi>
      </hi> Corps -- Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C.H.</abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Loved One:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have a chance to send a letter to Staunton tomorrow &amp; I cannot miss the occasion to
     give you a salutation -- (would I could seal it with a dear sweet kiss) and let you know of my
     welfare I added to my last that I had received yours telling me of Nelson's being over
     &amp; yesterday I heard from him -- and he told me what he had done &amp;c and that he
     saw Mr. Evans about straw &amp;c &amp;c and that all things were satisfactory for you
     -- but I expect to come home to fix you up for winter -- I am coming for 10 days, the Gen. says
     I may if we do not have to move or any thing in three or four days, we shall know tomorrow I
     reckon, when Gen. Lee is expected back from Richmond, where he has been, in constant
     consultation with the President, for a week past -- he is said to be in fine humor, and that
      <orig reg="augers">augurs</orig> well for the way things are going on -- I want to come home
     with my horse &amp; William, by way of Nelson's, two horses, so I can look after <orig
      reg="mother's">mothers</orig> &amp; be prepared for any changes of position of the army --
     and we can take some good rides too I hope -- but I will not build any castles -- war is an
     inexorable tyrant &amp; delights to overturn the cup of happiness just as it is about to be
     quaffed -- but<pb n="2"/> we will hope and pray that these days may be shortened -- and that
     taught by the stern necessities of the times how much we are essential to the enjoyment of each
     other,we may be allowed to spend many years of usefulness in the quiet of a happy home -- We
     are the arbiters of our own conditions more than is usually supposed -- and I am more and more
     convinced, by the experience of every day, that we are happy or miserable &amp; that we
     make those around us happy or miserable at our own will or pleasure -- but no more philosophy.
     Dr. Dabney is here on a visit, collecting information for his life of Jackson -- &amp; I am
     going tomorrow, with him &amp; Gen Early, to the battlefield of Cedar Run -- I think he
     will make a good life of Gen. <abbr expan="Jackson">J.</abbr> and still leave room for another
     work -- he <orig reg="preached">preaced</orig> at Orange <abbr expan="Court 
 House"
     >C.H.</abbr> today, I went to hear him -- he preached a capital sermon on Faith -- he enquired
     particularly after <abbr expan="Brother">Bro.</abbr> Walker &amp; spoke of his great regard
     for him &amp; his modest worth. There are many chaplains coming to the army, many men are
     coming for several months &amp; there is a blessed work going on - - Mr. Lacy preaches
     every day. If you need any money call on <abbr expan="Harvey">H.</abbr> Bear, or Dr. Hamilton
     -- it is so uncertain in a letter -- I have it ready for you, but hope to bring it myself -- if
     I do not come I will send it -- Nelson says Harriet has given up her <unclear>ideas</unclear>
     about going to the North &amp; he is happy again -- how true the Apostle that a married man
     only cares for his wife -- Excuse my brevity - write soon my love -- Kiss the darling children
     remember me to Allen &amp; May God bless you all -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>
      <hi rend="underline">Your devoted husband</hi>
     </salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
