<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4073"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4073">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, May 1,
     1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, may 1 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4073</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502268</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, May 1, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, may 1 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-05-01">1864-05-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Desertion/Leave, Military Authority, Troop Movement, Military Strategy, Patriotism,
      Church/Religious Activity, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4073T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss relates to his wife some movements of the Union army, and the possibility of a
     large battle in the near future.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-05-01">May 1<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">st</hi>
      </hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Head Quarters 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> Corps <abbr
       expan="Army of Northern Virginia">A. N. Va.</abbr>
      </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Dear Wife:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>What is the matter? I have been two weeks here &amp; have written to you three times
     &amp; not one word have I heard from you -- and I have imagined that all sorts of things
     have happened. My coming away without being able to come home again, did not make you sick, did
     it? But I will hope that there has nothing happened; that you have written to me in your prompt
     &amp; loving way &amp; that the cruel mails have been making sport of me &amp; that
     I shall hear from you by tomorrow -- Be sure &amp; write to me often, if only a few words
     at a time -- that I may not fail to know of your welfare. May Heaven be kind to you all -- you
     are in the hands of the Father of Mercies &amp; He only, at any time, has power to safely
     guard. I have been very hard at work, trying to get things out of the way before anything
     happens -- Today we heard that Burnsides had mired at the Rappahannock &amp; is now making
     a junction with Meade -- the time of many of the Yankee troops expires in a few days &amp;
     the moving towards the front today indicates that Grant intends to make use of them while he
     can &amp; play anew the role of <pb n="2"/>Hooker of one year ago this very day --
     Everything indicates that in less than 48 hours we may have the bloodiest battle of the war
     fought on this very ground &amp; the fresh green shores of the Rapidan be stained by the
     life blood of thousands -- It sad to think of -- the soul in calm reflection recoils from the
     contemplation of the ghastly spectacle - Man cannot become hardened to the horrors of war -- O
     that the blessed days when war shall be no more "would come upon the earth! But we have
     accepted the issue of "liberty or death." there is now no retiring from the contest -- we are
     to fight it out &amp; leave the issue in the hands of the Dispiser of all events -- All
     feel confident of success -- the events of the year have all been favourable to us &amp;
     are happy auguries of the event of this great struggle that must again baptize the soil of "Old
     Virginia" in blood--.</p>
    <p> We are calmly waiting the coming conflict -- hoping &amp; praying it may be the last. I
     went up to Orange <abbr expan="Court House">C. H.</abbr> to church today -- the houses of
     worship were full there were also services at our <abbr expan="Head Quarters">Hd. Qrs.</abbr>
     Gen. Lee &amp; many of the high officers of the army were there, the preacher was high
     church -- going through the flexions &amp; genuflexions. I enclose you Ten Dollars, in new
     issue, for fear you may want some &amp; I will send you more very soon. It looks very
     spring like today, but was quite cold yesterday -- We get along very well with the rations --
     only they ate all the meat up one day before the time &amp; had to without one day -- Be
     sure now, my Dear, to write -- let me know of any troubles your dear little soul may have
     &amp; of any thing I can do for you. My regards to our kind neighbors. Kisses for <hi
      rend="underline">you</hi> and Anna &amp; Nelly &amp; heavenly blessings be with you -- </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your loving husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Tom Doyle came to see me yesterday &amp; sends his regards &amp;
      I saw Bob Fisher also. Capt Bell took up a box of my things to Staunton today they are at Maj.
      Bell's</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
