<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A4104"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A4104">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss,
     November 8, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 8 1864</title>
        <author>Hotchkiss, Jedediah</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Lara Diefenderfer</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Rider</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A4104</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502299</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Jedediah Hotchkiss to Sara A. Hotchkiss, November 8, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county jedediah hotchkiss to sara a hotchkiss, november 8 1864</title>
            <author>Jedediah Hotchkiss</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Jedediah Hotchkiss Collection, Reel 4, Manuscripts
       Division, Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-11-08">1864-11-08</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Troop Movement, National Government, Patriotism, Military Authority, Church/Religious
      Activity, African Americans, Slavery, Women, Family</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A4104T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Hotchkiss informs his wife that the army is on the move again. He relates news of Northern
     opinion, election, and Southern sympathizers.</p>

   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Sara A. Hotchkiss</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-11-08">Wednesday Nov. 8<hi rend="underline">
        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
      </hi> 1864</date>
      <name type="place"><abbr expan="Head Quarters Valley District">Hd. Qrs. V. D.</abbr> New Market
       Va.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dearest One:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We are off agian tomorrow, I suppose, for "down the Valley" again, as it is reported that the
     Yankees have left Cedar Creek &amp; we must go to see where they have gone &amp; keep
     watch of them that they do not slip off to Richmond &amp; so bring an undue force against
      <hi rend="underline">Mas.</hi> Robert" -- We are all in a good humor at the idea, poor
     creatures that we are, we soon get tired of the quiet &amp; monotony of "camp life"
     &amp; long for the "storm &amp; bustle &amp; hurricane of war" Heaven grant that we
     may meet with no disaster &amp; that we may not have to fight another battle this fall
     &amp; sadden many a hearthstone with the <hi rend="underline">inevitable</hi> news. I was
     talking with Mr. Lacy today &amp; he says he can but think as I do, that in the good
     Providence of God this year will end this long &amp; cruel war -- I do not see that any
     good can come to us from <pb n="2"/>this Yankee election &amp; yet I long to know how it
     has gone -- to know if the majority of the people have approved the course of "Old Abe" for the
     last four years &amp; desire a continuance of the same -- I do not think there will be a
      <hi rend="underline">real</hi> election, so many have been sent from the army &amp; from
     government employ to use the influence, patronage &amp; means of corruption at their
     disposal that they will carry the election by <hi rend="underline">fraud</hi>, if no other way
     -- One of the Consuls of the "Hessian States" from New York has been here for a few days -- he
     left there three weeks ago -- he says there are many Southern sympathizers there, but they are
     so closely watched that they do not dare to express their sentiments -- he also says that the
     frauds practiced on foreigners to entrap them into service are almost beyond belief. I send you
     the paper today containing the President's Message -- he broaches some "new doctrines" -- the
     country is much divided in regard to the proper employement of the slaves -- I think the
     soldiers are opposed to arming them -- they want them used <pb n="3"/>as wagoners &amp;c
     but are unwilling to see arms put into their hands -- the President handles the subject
     cautiously as though treading on uncertain ground. I wrote you that I was very busy, am really
     tired I have been working so closely, &amp; am glad to ride again &amp; have field duty
     -- then it has turned warmer today &amp; the air is inviting -- I suppose we shall now have
     "Indian Summer" I have not heard from Mr. Euritt so I suppose he got off as he desired, else he
     would have let me know as he agreed. Our men have been much improved by the course of
     discipline they have undergone &amp; are in better "trim" than at any previous time <hi
      rend="underline">during</hi> the campaign, I hope much from them. Gen. Early has issued orders
     in regard to the keeping of the Sabbath, getting liquor &amp;c which have had a fine
     effect; the men have been kept in camp &amp; drilled most of the time, then so many have
     come back from hospitals &amp;c and filled up our depleted ranks -- &amp; so I might go
     on -- "hopeful as usual" you will say. <pb n="4"/>I hope William has been of <hi
      rend="underline">some</hi> use to you, though of not much -- for I fear he was out of the way
     -- during my absence he got hold of liquor and got a taste of the accursed stuff &amp; has
     used every effort to obtain it since -- I shall take him in hand after he returns -- I gave him
     money to pay his way up &amp; back, but I fear he spent it -- yet I can stop him &amp;
     will do so -- I shall try now to get some of the the things you want -- hope William will come
     tomorrow &amp; bring letter -- I have had a pair of shoes made for myself by one of the
     Engineer Company -- I got some 7 <abbr expan="yards">yds.</abbr> of linsey from Cumberland --
     that is, it is on the way -- I want my cape lining completed &amp; you may have the balance
     -- I may let you have it all --</p>
    <p> I hope Nelly and Anne <orig reg="ate">ar</orig> making good progress in their studies
     &amp; are good &amp; dutiful children -- fearing God &amp; obeying their Mother. I
     must write to Nelly -- I shall expect her to be able to make me a loaf of bread when I next
     come home -- when I shall be in her debt somehow -- &amp; Anne shall not be forgotten if
     she shows progress according to her years -- Also remember me to Mary -- I hope she does well
     -- Write soon -- Goodbye &amp; God bless you </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Your <abbr expan="affectionate">aff</abbr> husband</salute>
     <signed>Jed. Hotchkiss</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I enclose you Twenty Dollars --</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
