<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A5062"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A5062">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to Charles and
                    Mary McGuffin, May 12, 1866</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to charles and mary mcguffin, may 12 1866</title>
        <author>Roadcap, Martha L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A5062</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502346</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Martha L. Roadcap to Charles and Mary McGuffin, May
                            12, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county martha l roadcap to charles and mary mcguffin, may 12 1866</title>
            <author>Martha L. Roadcap</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: McGuffin Family Papers, Accession
                            #6732, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-05-12">1866-05-12</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Home Front, Family, Death/Casualties,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2002-11">November 2002</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A5062T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Martha Roadcap's letter is primarily addressed to her daughter-in-law, Mary
                    McGuffin. She writes that she will be coming to visit them in Augusta County
                    before too long, but wishes that Mary and Charles would come to visit her as
                    well. The rest of her letter is filled with news about family and friends.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-05-12">May 12/66</date>
                        <name type="place">Near Goshen</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Son &amp; Daughter</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>As I have not heard from you for so long I thought that I would drop you a few
                    lines to let you know that we are well &amp; hope this will find you well
                    also. I have looked for you till I have given you out I suppose you will not be
                    out this spring at all I had heard the death of Mother Doak I was truly sorry to
                    hear of her death but was not surprised at all as she was so old &amp;
                    frail. how long was she sick did she die suddenly &amp; was she resigned to
                    go. hope you &amp; Charles were with her in her last hours how I would like
                    to have <pb n="2"/> seen her before she died still thought I would have gotten
                    over to have seen her before she died. hope she is at rest &amp; now with
                    those loved ones that have gone long before her. How is Aunt Polly did she take
                    her death hard &amp; suppose her mind will be a great deal worse that ever I
                    have not news to write you Mary I hope you &amp; Charles will come over
                    &amp; see us soon I think he might bring you over &amp; leave you with
                    me a while two or three weeks anyhow Maggie Clayton &amp; myself are coming
                    to see you next month I suppose about the middle or the last of the month you
                    may look for us. she is going on a trip to <pb n="3"/> Greenbrier &amp; as
                    soon as she returns we will come. How does Charlies wheat look that he labored
                    so hard last fall I hope &amp; pray that he may reap something after his
                    hard labor give my love to the family, Allie sends her love to you &amp;
                    Charlie, also Abram &amp; the children, give my kindest regards to Charlie
                    &amp; ask him to write to me I hope to hear from you <hi rend="underline"
                        >very</hi> soon. I have company here today a nephew &amp; niece of
                    Abram's they have been lately married. Mary we are about to lose all of our good
                    neighbors, M<hi rend="super">rs</hi> Campbell is going to Mississippi next fall,
                        M<hi rend="super">rs</hi> McLaughlin has gone some five or six miles <pb
                        n="4"/> from us to Mt Agnes to live hope you will get to see M<hi
                        rend="super">rs</hi> Campbell before she <hi rend="underline">leaves</hi> I
                    have been quite busy this spring have just got done making soap &amp; dying
                    my Black wool a very pretty black I have now got it to pick I wish you were here
                    to help me. I have an old black woman living with me but she is very little help
                    to me I have nearly all the work to do, my paper is nearly give out &amp; I
                    will have to stop. <hi rend="underline">Jimmie</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Furr</hi> has been with us for two months Abram hired him
                    for a short time. hoping to hear from you soon &amp; close</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain your Mother affectionately</salute>
                    <signed>M L Roadcap</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
