<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6008"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6008">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, March 8,
     1862 </title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, march 8 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6008</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502371</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, March the 8th/62 </title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, march the 8th 62</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-03-08">1862-03-08</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front,</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6008T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick writes about family news and camp life. He also complains about the high cost of
     clothing in camp.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-03-08">March the 8th/62 </date>
      <name type="place">Camp Alleghany</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take my pen in hand this morning to write you a few lines to make up what I have wrote on
     the other piece, as I was in a hurry for I thought I would send it and wait until the next time
     and then I did not send it, as I would have time to write more.</p>
    <p>I am well at this time and I hope when these few lines comes to hand they may find you all in
     good health. I received a letter from Father yesterday and I was very glad to hear from them
     and to hear that they was well. He said in his letter that he was out to see you the day
     before, and he said that you and Willie was well and all the rest of your pap's folks was well.
     He said when he started from there that little Willie cried and hollered after him. He said
     that he left with a sad heart to think that the little boy would cry after him and to think
     that I was out here and did not know whether we would ever meet on earth any more or not, and
     he said that he had to shed tears when he was writing to think about it. Dear Lissa you don't
     know how it hurt my feelings to read it.</p>
    <p>Dear dear Lissa we have some very good times here although we have to run out in the ditches
     sometimes when the pickets makes a false alarm. I tell you that we get up and toddle to the
     ditches and there we have to stand out there and all most freeze, but we take it all in fun. We
     hear so much news here that we don't know what to believe and so I don't listen at anything
     that I hear.</p>
    <p>I must stop writing as I am getting tired. Father sent me the pattern of our sweet little
     boys hand. I was glad to see it. It has growed very much since I seen it. Dear Lissa I tell you
     that we have to pay high for every thing that we buy. I bought two checks shirts and I had to
     pay for the two four dollars and a half. I think that it is right hard that we can't get a
     shirt with out paying $2.25cts for it. I have some money here, if you want some let me know. I
     don't like to send in a letter, but if you need it I will try send it in a letter. It is very
     pleasant here today. Give my love to all of my inquiring friends if there be any. May god bless
     you and save you through Christ. From you husband. I hope that I will see you on earth again.
     God bye Dear wife, for this time</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
