<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6016"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6016">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, [no
     date]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, no date</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6016</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502379</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, [no date]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, no date</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Pages one and two of the original letter are missing, and the letter begins on page
       three.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-06">ca. 1863-06 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Battle Description, Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Family,
      Prison/Prisoners, Race Relations, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6016T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick describes the action near Winchester and the taking of prisoners, including African
     Americans. He continues to eat well and reports on recent desertions.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    

    <p>...them thunder. There the Yankees broke for Winchester before we got there. It was nine
     miles from where we was to Middletown. We went 3 miles below town that night and we stayed
     there about 3 hours and then we started for WInchester. Some of our forces was on ahead and
     they came in on the Yankees about daylight and in a few minutes after we got there. Our men
     made a charge on them and they broke and run and we run them 5 miles and we got a great many
     prisoners. The cavalry men has been bringing them back in big squads all day today.</p>
    <p>They brought a yankee past and his wife was with him and she was a <unclear>back</unclear>
     one at that. Dr. Lewis asked him if that was his wife. he said yessir and
     <unclear>the</unclear> had took a good many negroes and we got a good many of them back. We
     have taken a great many horses and wagons and other things. We got 3 trains of cars at Front
     Royal and 500 sacks of coffee and a great deal of salt and other things. They burnt up nearly
     one square of Winchester. We expect to follow them on.</p>
    <p>I have more news but I have no time and no paper with me, but I have plenty in my knapsack.
     It is in Harrisonburg. I seen John and <unclear>Harry</unclear> Friday morning. They are both
     well. I seen Uncle Jacob Dedrick in Bridgewater. He said he seen Jake that morning driving a
     wagon and I heard of him being at FrontRoyal but I have not seen him yet.</p>
    <p>Give my love to all and accept a great portion for yourself. So nothing more but remain your
     affectionate husband until death. May god bless you all. Write soon. H. H. Dedrick to wife. I
     sent you a letter some time ago and I have got no answer from it.</p>
    <p>Dear Lissa I just have eaten a hearty dinner. Me and Ben White had the pleasure of eating
     dinner by ourselves as all the rest of our mess has run off but four. J and James Lewis and
     Joseph Liggett has gone out to get their dinner. I received your kind letter while I was at
     dinner and I was truly glad to hear from you and to hear that you all was well.</p>
    <p>Dear Lissa <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> be very glad to see you at his time. I have a good deal of news
     to tell you which is too tedious to write. You will please excuse my bad writing as I have no
     chance to write. Fare you well my dear.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
