<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6014"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6014">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June 9,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june 9 1863</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6014</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502377</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June 9, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june 9 1863</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Toward the end of letter Dedrick switched from pen to pencil and the text is illegible
        except for a few sentences at the end.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-06-09">1863-06-09</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Family, Military Authority, Military
      Strategy, Prison/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6014T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick describes troop movements and skirmishes near Culpeper, Virginia. He also complains
     of soreness from the march and talks about his courtmartial.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-06-09">June the 9 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp near Culpeper Courthouse</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I thank god that I have been permitted to see a few more lines from under your hand. I
     received your most kind letter this morning. It was dated on the 2nd of this month. I was truly
     glad to hear from you and to hear that you was well and to hear that all the rest of the folks
     was well. I am well and doing as well as could be expected. I do hope when these few lines
     comes to hand they may find you and little Willie in good health.</p>
    <p>We have been permitted to stay here today. We got here yesterday about twelve oclock and
     drawed three days rations and was to be ready to start this morning by day light, and then we
     got orders to stay here today and cook another days rations. I don't know where we will go.</p>
    <p>We left the old camp last Thursday night at twelve oclock. We have not been marching very
     hard but it went very hard with some of us. My feet got very sore and my legs has been very
     sore for some time, but they have got better. I have heard cannon all day long. It commenced
     about sun rise and was very heavy. It is down the river between this and Fredericksburg
     somewhere, but I don't know where.</p>
    <p>The same night that we left our old camp the yankees crossed the river at the same place that
     they crossed before, but General Hill was there with his Corps. The Yankees shelled his troops
     friday, Saturday and Sunday, but General Hill laid still to draw them out, but they smelt the
     Rat and would not come out. General Hill has been reinforced with five thousand new troops.
     They have never been in a fight, but if they stay there I think they will get into it and that
     before long. We expect to go into it at any time. I would not be surprised if we don't be in
     Maryland before ten days. Some thinks that we will go over in the valley. We are on the road
     that leads to New Market. It leads from Culpeper to Sperryville and then to New Market, but I
     can't tell you where we will go.</p>
    <p>I have more news but I have not time to write. I sent you a letter at the same time that I
     sent Fathers. I mailed them both at the same time. I saw Jacob Ded. several days ago, he was
     well and send his compliments to you all.</p>
    <p>They have courtmartialed me at last, but they had right smart trouble before they got it
     done. But I have not heard my sentence yet. They wanted to make me drill and to<del rend="none" hand="h1"/></p>
    <p>Dear Lissa I want you to forget to tell me who told you that I had said that you didn't care
     anything about me. Dear Lissa I have some good news to tell you when I write again. May god
     bless you. H. H. Dedrick.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>H.H. Dedrick</salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
