<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6019"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6019">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary E.A. Dedrick to Henry H. Dedrick, February
     1, 1862 </title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary e a dedrick to henry h dedrick, february 1 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Mary E.A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6019</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502382</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary E.A. Dedrick to Henry H. Dedrick, February 1, 1862 </title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary e a dedrick to henry h dedrick, february 1 1862</title>
            <author>Mary E.A. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>This letter likely was written in Sherando, Virginia.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-02-01">1862-02-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Family, Home Front, Death/Casualties,
      Desertion/Leave, Mililtary Authority</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6019T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Mary discusses the disposition of their rye crop and the difficulty getting food. She also
     refers to their son's first birthday, which will occur in nine days.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Henry H. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-02-01">February 1, 1862 </date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Henry</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your dear letter Wednesday and was very glad to hear you was well. I would have
     received it sooner I suppose but the mail was delayed. We are all well. Your Father was here
     last Sabbath and they were all well. They say that Mag <unclear>mon</unclear> and Dave <del
      hand="h1"/> is married. Franklin Manly is dead, he had the sore throat and little Tis Manly is
     about of. Times is hard here and if this war continues I don't know what poor people is to do.</p>
    <p>You wanted me to give you some satisfaction about your rye. I had to give rye for threshing
     and I paid James Lewis and pap and I lent Dr. Drummand a bushel and a half and Pap got his
     share out of it and sold Hester a half of bushel for coffee, and I have a little left and I
     have got a little to thresh. You wanted me to take care of it and I do assure you that I will
     take care of everything that I have got.</p>
    <p>You wanted to know if I had any corn. I have got some and I have to feed my hogs every night
     and morning a little for they are <unclear>there is</unclear> not a bit of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>.
     Dear Henry you wanted to know if I got anything from Mr. Ellis. He gives me 25 and 30 lbs. of
     flour a month, 1 lb of coffee, 2 lbs of sugar and no meat. He give me a little last fall but
     none since, and it don't do me, and I had to use what little buckwheat I had and have to use my
     corn and I can't get to go after it always, and if I want a horse I have to pay 25 cts for it
     and if I want a little wagon I have to pay 50 cts. for it and everything is so high. You don't
     know what hard times I have here about wood. Your Father did haul me a little and Aunt Becky
     got some hauled and when that is done I don't know what I will do. Pap sold his horse, when he
     had his I could get it any time.</p>
    <p>Aunt Becky says Willie can eat as much corn bread and buttermilk as the next one. He can
     whistle pretty good. Uncle Jonathan says watch and pray lest you be led into temptation for he
     says your wife is here and you are there. Dear Henry I am glad that you are not give up trying
     to get to heaven. In this world we have tribulation. But in Christ we have consolation. I hope
     we will meet around the throne one day or other. Dear Henry strive for heaven. From your
     sincere wife, M. A.E. Dedrick</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed/>
     <seg type="postscript">P.S. I was glad when I heard Long was going to try to get you married
      men a furlough but I don't believe Genl. Johnson will give you any. Nine days from today your
      baby will be a year old. Amanda Ma and pa sends their compliments to you and Hiram and Wm.
       <unclear>S. H. O.</unclear></seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
