<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6015"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6015">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June 14,
     1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june 14 1863</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Henry H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6015</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502378</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Henry H. Dedrick to Mary E. A. Dedrick, June 14, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county henry h dedrick to mary e a dedrick, june 14 1863</title>
            <author>Henry H. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-06-14">1863-06-14</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Home Front, Military Authority, Military Strategy,
      Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6015T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Dedrick describes the action near Winchester in which many prisoners were taken. He also
     instructs his wife on a matter relating to coonskins.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary E.A. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-06-14">June the 14 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Near Winchester, five miles below</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Wife-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take the opportunity this evening to drop you a few lines to let you know how I am and
     where I am. I am five miles below Winchester.</p>
    <p>My dear wife I tell you that we have had a hard time since we left our old camp. We arrived
     at Winchester last Saturday and we found some yankees there and we took a general review on
     Saturday and Sunday our skirmishes and the yankees was fighting all day long. The Yankees
     shelled us all day on Sunday.</p>
    <p>About half past eleven oclock our division, that is Gen. Early's division, took back about
     two miles on the left hand side of the turnpike and then we turned to our right and marched
     down below Winchester opposite of the Yankees fortifications, and then we laid there until six
     oclock and then we opened fourteen pieces of artillery on them in their fortifications. And I
     tell you the yankees had to get out of that place. Pretty soon the La. brigade charged on them
     and run them out of their fortifications and then our brigade charged for about a mile to hold
     the ditches.</p>
    <p>We took fourteen pieces of artillery from them at that place and that night the yankees got
     up and scadaddled out of that place and took for Martinsburg. But old General Edward Johnson he
     went down and got before them and as they come along he pitched in to them and took nearly all
     of them prisoner. I think that we have taken nearly all that was at Winchester. It is reported
     that we have got old Gen. Milroy. If we have got him it is a fine thing for he has treated some
     of our people very bad. I think we have got about four thousand of them. Our loss is not very
     heavy. We only lost one man out of our Regiment. We have take all of their artillery that they
     had here but I have not heard how many pieces they had.</p>
    <p>I saw Jacob today. He is well. We will stay here until tomorrow. I don't know where we will
     go. I did not finish telling you about the yankees. We took everything that they had. I saw a
     long train of wagons just below Winchester where they left. I have more news but I have not
     time to write. Dear Lissa I am well at present and I hope when these few lines come to hand
     they may find you enjoying the same blessing of god aresting upon you.</p>
    <p>Wheat looks very well down here. Corn is short. Lissa I understand that John Coyner claims
     them coonskins at fathers. I want you to tell father that I want him to take them to the
     tanyard and get them tanned and you send the one that is in the spring house. I want you to
     take the fur off of them and get somebody to get a hat made out of it. Give my love to Julie
     and tell her I have no chance to write to her. Tell her Hiram is well and I received her letter
     when I got yours and one from Martha Balsley. Give her my love and tell her I have no chance to
     write. Give my love to all inquiring friends. I have more news but no paper. I will close for
     this time. Write soon. May god bless you all. I remain your affectionate husband until death.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>H.H. Dedrick</salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
