<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6020"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6020">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary E. A. Dedrick to Henry H. Dedrick, April
     15, 1862 </title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary e a dedrick to henry h dedrick, april 15 1862</title>
        <author>Dedrick, Mary E.A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Diane B. Jacob, Virginia Military Institute</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6020</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1999">1999</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502383</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary E. A. Dedrick to Henry H. Dedrick, April 15, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary e a dedrick to henry h dedrick, april 15 1862</title>
            <author>Mary E.A. Dedrick</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>1 page</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Henry H. Dedrick Papers, Manuscript #0332, Virginia
       Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia Military Institute Archives, Lexington, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-04-15">1862-04-15</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Family, Home
      Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Tagging checked; final corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6020T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Mary talks about his son's illness and recovery, the high costs of livestock, and family
     news. She expresses concern about the soldiers' well-being in the cold.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Henry H. Dedrick</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-04-15">April the 15th 1862 </date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear husband</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I'll attempt to write to you once more to inform you of our health. I am well, only a pain in
     my back and side. Willie has been very sick with the Cholera Morbus. It weakened him down
     considerably, but he is now as mischievous as ever. I have had the same complaint that Willie
     had, but I have gotten over it.</p>
    <p>It is a cloudy disagreeable day today. It has been raining here today but it has quit. I tell
     you Dear Henry my thoughts were fixed on you all them cold snowy days last week. I don't know
     how you poor fellows can stand it. I know you all have a hard time out there in them cold
     cotton hats. I expect they will be many of you sick that haven't been.</p>
    <p>Tears came twinkling from my eyes when I came to where you said that you came out on a hill
     and seen the Laurel Spring hollow and saying to yourself how soon could I get home if I was
     there. But I hope if it is gods will that you will be nearer home than that hollow before long.
     Dear Henry no one knows how bad I want to see you. No one knows how bad it is to be from each
     other, only those that have tried it. But one thing I do sincerely hope that you may never
     volunteer again for no one one knows how bad I want you to be in peace at home again.</p>
    <p>I got a letter from Jack's wife and she wasn't very well. She expects to be confined soon.
     Jackson and Harry are in the army. William is at home on a sick furlough, he is getting better.
     I suppose Shenandoah has got a right nice little town on it chiefly of white houses. Tell me in
     your next letter how many regiments there are out there besides Baldwin's. I received the
     fifteen dollwars you sent by Meyers. He came up to Lewises. Amanda has the mumps but she is
     better (little Cate had them too). She sends her best and kindest respects to you and cousin
     William Diddle and to the rest of her friends out there and tell them their kindness were
     welcome received.</p>
    <p>I was sorry to hear that you was so cold when you was writing and that you all was so cold. I
     hope if it is for the best that it will soon be pretty clear warm weather.Who did you send your
      <unclear>coat</unclear> and letters by. I haven't got them yet. I don't know whether
      <unclear>Mary</unclear> has got hers yet or not. I seen her yesterday but I forgot to ask her.
     Tell Uncle Will that she and the children were all well. Mother and pap are well. pap tried to
     get us two calves over at old Gray's sale but they were too unreasonably high and he didn't get
     them.</p>
    <p>Tears came in mother's eyes as I read her your letter. Pray a great deal dear Henry and never
     forget god who is <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> who has give you health, that you have been spared so long.
     "Pray without ceasing."</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your wife M.E.D.</salute>
     <signed/>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
