<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6064"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

  
 <!ENTITY Smiley33 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503191" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley33b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503192" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6064">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to William Smiley, October 17,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to william smiley, october 17 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Thomas M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6064</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503190</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to William Smiley, October 17, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to william smiley, october 17 1861</title>
            <author>Thomas M. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-10-17">1861-10-17</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Mititary Strategy, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6064T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses regiment's movement to Centerville to counter union troops movements toward Fairfax
     Court House.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">William Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley33" pid="uva-lib:503191"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-10-17">Oct 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Camp near <orig reg="Centerville">Centervill</orig></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Father</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I will this evening endeavor to write you a few lines to let you know that I am well and hope
     when these few lines reach you they may find you enjoying the same blessing. I would have
     written by M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Beard but we were ordered off on picket so sudden that I
     could not do so We went on picket last thursday and got back on the next tuesday evening about
     sundown eat our suppers and was preparing for a good nights rest when orders came to strike our
     tents and prepare for a march no one knew where we got ready and started at three Oclock on
     wednesday morning and soon found ourselves in <orig reg="Centerville">Centervill</orig> and
     pitching our tents I was then detailed on guard duty and was obliged to lose two nights sleep
     so that I think you must excuse my bad writing I would not have written now but there is some
     excitement in camp <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig> so that I thought I had better <orig
      reg="write">wright</orig> when I have a chance We do not expect to stay long at this camp<pb
       n="2" entity="Smiley33b"/>
      it is reported that the enemy are advancing and that they are as
     far as Fairfax <abbr expan="Courthouse">C.H.</abbr> but I do not think that it is correct they
     have advanced a little I know but not so far the object of our falling back is to get a good
     place to attack them we have a very commanding position here and I think we can give them <del
      hand="h1">Hail</del> Hail <orig reg="Columbia">Collumbia</orig> if they do not come too soon.
     There is some talk of our brigade going to Winchester or at any rate some of the most
     influential citizens of the <orig reg="valley">vally</orig> have petitioned that we may be sent
     there as there is a body of the enemy under the command of General Banks prowling about Harpers
     Ferry Martinsburg and the upper potomac <orig reg="generally">generaly</orig>. I saw Andy
     Whipple <orig reg="today">to day</orig> he happened to pass our company and I recognized him he
     said he knew me the moment he saw me he made a narrow escape being taken prisoner by the
     yankees he had six balls fired at him and only at the distance of 30 yards a lieutenant was
     taken prisoner at the same time they had left their picket posts and gone a short distance for
     chestnuts when they were surprised by the enemy and taken I received the things you all sent
     safe except the <orig reg="tomatoes">tomattoes</orig> which were a little mashed the comfort is
     the very thing we need here but it is a little unhandy carrying about I suppose I need not
     write any more as M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Beard can give you the particulars of how we live
     and get along</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>so nothing more at present but remain your affectionate son</salute>
     <signed>T M. Smiley</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
