<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6063"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley32 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503188" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley32b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503189" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6063">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, July 27,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, july 27 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6063</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503187</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, July 27, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, july 27 1861</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Battle of Manassas</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-07-27">1861-07-27</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Family, Military Authority, Miitary Strategy,
      Prisons/Prisoners </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6063T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses details regarding the battle of Manassas.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1"  entity="Smiley32" pid="uva-lib:503188"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-07-27">July 27<hi rend="super">th</hi> /61</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Received your letter yesterday &amp; now hasten to answer it &amp; give you the
     desired information as far as I know myself. The loss of the South in Sundays battle is
     reported to have been 500 killed &amp; 800 wounded whilst the North admit a loss of 5,000
     but it is estimated at 10,000 by the south. All their cannon was taken except two pieces 67 in
     all amongst them the <orig reg="Sherman">Shermon</orig> battery which is said to be the most
     famous battery in the United States Besides there is no estimate to be made of the amount of
     small arms taken a great many besides those belonging to the slain. they just loosed their belt
     and cast away their arms knapsack haversack &amp; all in their retreat. Old Scott's
     carriage is said to have been taken all his plans &amp; dispatches &amp; his epauletts.
     They had not the least expectation of a defeat &amp; their plan was after taking that place
     to feast one day and then to go on and take Richmond. We have got back enough of provisions men
     amp;c now to pay for what was taken from us in Western <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. The
     prisoners were let <orig reg="off">of</orig> on parole &amp; have gone home but I think it
     was scarcely <orig reg="worthwhile">worth while</orig> going home. Pa hailed a man the other
     day and gave him his dinner that was in the fight at Laurel Hill and was taken prisoner The
     company were from Halifax <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr> and going home on parole. He said they
     were kindly treated by <orig reg="McClellan">McCleland</orig>. He appeared to be very near give
     out. Pa having come from Beards and wanting to write some has left very little for me to tell
     Sib Strain brought home a Charly Bell, on Wednesday he had his arm &amp; shoulder shot
      <orig reg="off">of</orig> though he did not die until after he started with him. Strain
     started back yesterday he was not in the battle he could not find his company &amp; was
     only a spectator to the bloody work. <orig reg="Johnston's">Johnsons</orig> men it is said
     fought <orig reg="until">till</orig> 11 oclock and were about being flanked &amp; his men
     being exhausted were about to give way when <orig reg="Beauregard">Beuregard</orig> came to his
     assistance &amp; afterward Davis when they charged for them. They could not stand the cold
     steel and ran. It is reported that we came very near getting Seward as for Scott it is not
     known what became of him The militia are still at Staunton some of them have been at home
     several times though. It is raining today &amp; pa &amp; ma have
     
      <pb n="2" entity="Smiley32b" pid="uva-lib:503189"/>
      gone to Uncle Jim's They wanted to see Arehart before he starts He expects to start
     tomorrow I reckon he is afraid to stay longer also George Clemmer and his father they expected
     to go to the Junction but Uncle J intended telling them of what you wrote so I dont know what
     they will do. You are very silent about your spell of sickness You must be afraid to tell how
     bad you were for we heard from Bil Arehart that you were very bad. Pa wants to know why you
     dont tell more particularly about it, you put almost <orig reg="too">to</orig> good a face on
     the <orig reg="measles">measels</orig> quite a light disorder I suppose you think. We started a
     letter Tuesday to Winchester I reckon you can get it there if you want it there was a good deal
     of it for Tish &amp; me both wrote</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Nothing more but remain your affectionate sister</salute>
     <signed>Mary A Smiley</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Thomas M. Smiley my Dear Son<lb/> I have just been to <abbr
       expan="William">W<hi rend="super">m</hi>
      </abbr> Beards hearing a letter from Samuel written on tuesday after the Battle at the
      Junction he Says there is not a man of the Southern <orig reg="Guards">Gards</orig> killed or
      wounded but Captain Williams who was Slightly wounded with a Splinter threw <orig
       reg="against">agaist</orig> him by a cannon ball Striking a fence or Some timber and Struck
      him <orig reg="across">a cross</orig> the face but so Slightly that he is Still able to be
      with his Company Johnsons Army Suffered very much especially the Virginia <orig reg="Regiment"
       >Regment</orig> Baxter Ott is killed and Several others from Augusta &amp; Rockbridge all
      of <orig reg="whom">whome</orig> I do not remember I have heard from President Davis <orig
       reg="dispatch">Dispach</orig> both to Congress &amp; his wife Stating the number killed
      &amp; wounded South 500 killed 800 wounded and the North a great many <orig
       reg="prisoners">prisners</orig> the killed not known but they piled on top of one another in
      front and were Strewed over the ground <unclear>thick</unclear> for ten miles we took it is
      Said <orig reg="sixty-seven">Sixty Seven</orig> cannon with the great Sherman Battery and
      thousands of Small arms of <orig reg="every">evry</orig>
      <orig reg="description">discrption</orig> and provisions <orig reg="enough">anough</orig> to
      last the whole Southern army for Sometime and camp <orig reg="instruments">instriments</orig>
      of all kinds but I have taken up so much of the paper I will close by remaining your Father
       <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig> Wm Smiley </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
