<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6062"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley31 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503185" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley31b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503186" NDATA uvaHighRes> 

 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6062">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, July 23,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, july 23 1861</title>
        <author>Smiley, Mary A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6062</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503184</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Mentions Joe E. Johnston and Manassas.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>


      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary A. Smiley to Thomas M. Smiley, July 23, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary a smiley to thomas m smiley, july 23 1861</title>
            <author>Mary A. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-07-23">1861-07-23</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Desertion/Leave, Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals,
      Military Authority, Military Strategy </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6062T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Discusses mobilization of militias and volunteers, exemptions, skirmishes, and Manassas.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Thomas M. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1" entity="Smiley31" pid="uva-lib:503185"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-07-23">July 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi> 1861</date>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We have received both letters that you have written since you were sick the first came the
     same day that John Beard started the other the day after <unclear>Steele</unclear> got home We
     were not expecting a letter not getting any with Steele who said he had advised you not to
     write &amp; were sorry that you did write if you were not able for the task though before I
     did not think. but that you could write too when others in the hospital were writing. I suppose
     though that you must have been right bad from what you say. We are all well at present feel
     quite pert after the cold rain we had yesterday I hope it was not as cold down the <orig
      reg="valley">vally</orig> as it was here I would be rather uncomfortable without fire Tell
     John Beard that he did not take all the rain away with him this time &amp; that he must
     have left all the cold behind him. I believe that Bill Steele has a mind to fill the offer of 2
     Lieutenant in your company provided he can get a higher office in the militia This anyway is
     the <orig reg="opinion">oppinion</orig> of some and it looks something like it. He got to
     Staunton Wednesday came home Thursday night &amp; started back the next Morning for
     Winchester but was at church Sunday. I heard of his saying he had the offer of an office in the
     militia. I suppose if he can get one higher in the militia than that in your company he will
     take it if not he will have that to fall back on I dont know whether he has gone this week or
     not but if not I think it would be a pretty good plan not to let him have that chance &amp;
     if he cant get suited here make him go as a private I think people here in the valley are
     mighty stuck up anyway, unlike the people further south they <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> come
     down a peg if it can possibly be helped Nearly all of any pretentious <unclear>stall at least
      great</unclear> &amp; you know there are a good many of that are ripping around to get an
     office. The militia have not gone from Staunton yet and do not know when they will indeed I
     believe it is sort of doubtful whether they will if they can get volunteers There is few if any
     that is volunteering of the Newport<pb n="2" entity="Smiley31b" pid="uva-lib:503186"/>
      company. They would rather go in the militia if they have to go as
     they are only taken for six months whilst the volunteers are taken for the time the war lasts.
     A great many have gotten off the millers have been exempted &amp; a good many that claim to
     be invalids &amp; some others There are some half dozen or so of McNutts company home among
     others Jim Strain who has won for himself a great name, that is a <hi rend="underline">great
      coward</hi> it is said it will not be good for him if he goes back I believe <abbr
      expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Curry &amp; some of his men are expected back shortly were
     made to take the oath &amp; will be sent home there was some 12 of his men taken among them
     Julius Hamilton His father says <abbr expan="Julius">J</abbr> is smart enough for <orig
      reg="anything">any thing</orig> but the yankees were <orig reg="too">to</orig> smart for him
     that time. Bob &amp; Bil Stuart are said to be two of the bravest men out there &amp;
     some of the <orig reg="Phinegar">Pingah</orig> set are said to have gained more honor that day
     than they ever did before in their lives. The wagons that started last have got back they were
     in Beverly time of the fight but all escaped, the ones that started the day before did not have
     as good luck I believe they are getting back with their horses but their wagons were taken. I
     think Scott ought to have his life taken for not taking part in that fight or giving those that
     were <orig reg="ammunition">amunition</orig> when his men wanted to go on &amp; help He
     must be as great a coward as Jim Strain who would not let that company know about it <orig
      reg="until">till</orig> it was too late. Report has good news for the South from the fight at
     Manassas Junction on last week Old Scott is reported to have said that he was never whipped,
     before, in his life We have heard nothing yet from the fight on Sunday it is supposed that it
     was at the Junction If your company was in Johnson's command that went to that place give us
     full particulars. As I have not seen what Tish has written you must excuse me if it is like
     hers. If your eyes still continue to be sore &amp; hurts you to write you had better not
     write but can send word with others that are writing to the neighborhood. Give my best respects
     to <del hand="h1">the company</del> my acquaintances &amp; receive my love to yourself</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your sister</salute>
     <signed>Mary A Smiley</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
