<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6072"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;

<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">

 
 <!ENTITY Smiley59 SYSTEM "uva-lib:503219" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley59b SYSTEM "uva-lib:503220" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley59c SYSTEM "uva-lib:503221" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley59d SYSTEM "uva-lib:503222" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY Smiley59e SYSTEM "uva-lib:503223" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 
 ]>  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6072">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to Mary A. Smiley, May 9,
     [1863]</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to mary a smiley, may 9 1863</title>
        <author>Smiley, Thomas M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Alice McShane</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6072</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:503218</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Thomas M. Smiley to Mary A. Smiley, May 9, [1863]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county thomas m smiley to mary a smiley, may 9 1863</title>
            <author>Thomas M. Smiley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Smiley Family Papers Accession #1807 Special
       Collections Department, University of Viriginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>Punctuation added to letter at later date by family member or archivist. Additional
        information regarding General Stonewall Jackson's fatal wound also written on letter.
        Original letter includes mention of Stonewall Jackson and A. P. Hill.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-05-09">1863-05-09</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Death/Casualties, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Troop
      Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6072T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Describes battle of Chancellorsville in which he participated in and was slightly wounded.
     Mentions Stonewall Jackson's loss of arm.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <pb entity="Smiley59e" pid="uva-lib:503223"/>Miss Mary A. Smiley<lb/> Moffetts Creek<lb/> Augusta <abbr
      expan="County">Co</abbr><lb/>
     <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
     <name type="recipient">Mary A. Smiley</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     
      <pb n="1"  entity="Smiley59" pid="uva-lib:503219"/>
     
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-05-09">May 9<hi rend="super">th</hi></date>
      <name type="place">Camp near Hamiltons Crossing </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>You have no doubt heard of the battle of Chancellorsville before this and you may feel uneasy
     about me I will now try to quiet that uneasiness by writing a few lines to you for the purpose
     of letting you know that I am safe with no broken bones. but I made a very narrow escape
     indeed. There was a shell exploded a few yards from me one of the pieces of which struck in the
     ground by my side throwing the dirt and gravels over me my eyes were blackened and bruised up
     and my right hand was struck bruising and swelling it so that I could not do duty for a couple
     of days but I am thankful that I was permitted to escape from any worse wound. I am now in the
     company but my hand is still right sore. The last letter I wrote I stated that <orig
      reg="everything">every thing</orig> was quiet so far as I was able to judge but the next
     morning the cannon began to roar near <orig reg="Fredericksburg">Fredericsburg</orig> we were
     ordered out and got to the old <orig reg="battleground">battle ground</orig> that evening. we
     lay<pb n="2" entity="Smiley59b" pid="uva-lib:503220"/>
      at the same place on Thursday and on Friday we started and marched
     to within a couple of mile of <abbr expan="Chancellorsville">Chancellors</abbr>. There was a
      <orig reg="pretty">prety</orig> heavy skirmish that evening but we were not engaged. on
     Saturday our division and <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> A P Hills division started around
     the enemys right and came out above them at the junction of the Culpeper &amp; Orange
     &amp; Fredericksburg turnpike roads. Hills division and the third brigade of our division
     were sent on in front and attacked the enemy driving them out of their position and
     entrenchments which were well chosen &amp; strengthened considerably Saturday night was
     spent in maneuvering and occasional skirmishing in one of these skirmishes General Jackson lost
     his arm which we all feel to be a sore bereavement to us Sunday morning found us fronting the
     enemy they being sheltered by <orig reg="breastworks">breast works</orig> which they had thrown
     up during the night nothing daunted however we charged them they breaking and running like
     frightened sheep we charged them thus out of two <orig reg="different">diferent</orig> works
     the last one being a very strong work it was here that we lost the most men as our
     reinforcements did not come up in time they planted a battery and graped us driving us back<pb
      n="3" entity="Smiley59c"/>
      a short distance but our support coming up at this time we drove
     them from every part of the field and all that kept their defeat from becoming an utter <orig
      reg="rout">route</orig> was the difficulty of getting through the thick growth of bushes
     between that and the river. On Sunday night both armies formed another line of battle and
     commenced fortifying. Monday &amp; Tuesday was spent in working on <orig reg="breastworks"
      >breast works</orig>. &amp; Wednesday we received the joyful news that the enemy had
     crossed the river. We then started for camp with light hearts, yet, still <orig reg="grieving"
      >greiving</orig> for the loss of many brave &amp; good men Among them I will mention the
     name of our General. Paxton from Lexington. in our brigade the loss was over six hundred about
     fifty of these were killed dead others will die of their wounds. In our company <abbr
      expan="Sergeant">Sergt</abbr> J B. McCutchan was wounded in the head <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
      >Lieut</abbr> Carson in wrist Corporal Cochran in ankle <orig reg="severely">severly</orig>
     James T Beard in foot <abbr expan="Robert">Robt</abbr> Wiseman in hand M Smith in hand J Runkle
     in leg Joseph Black and Sam Hite and several others slightly the list will be in the newspapers
     of Staunton soon as it was sent this morning Cyrus Strong was wounded severely it is<pb n="4" entity="Smiley59d" pid="uva-lib:503222"/>
      thought doubtful by some whether he will get over it or not Hugh
     Beard was wounded and Jim Reece is wounded again. <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr> Charles
     Calhoun had his leg taken off, and many others are wounded but I will not name them We captured
     about ten thousand prisoners took a good many <orig reg="pieces">peices</orig> of cannon
     fifteen thousand stand of small arms and many other things such as knapsacks
     <unclear>Gum</unclear> cloths, <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig>. they also left five
     hospitals in our possession containing near a thousand patients the most of them very badly
     wounded. but I will close for this time by asking you to write soon. Excuse all mistakes as
     this was hastily written. Give my love and best respects to all <orig reg="enquiring"
     >enquiring</orig> friends and relations and receive a due share yourself </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>from your affectionate Brother</salute>
     <signed>Thomas M Smiley</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">P.S When you write let me know whether you have got the blanket I left
      in staunton or not and anything else of interest. I suppose that the same directions will
      answer for letters sent to us now, we are nearer hamiltons crossing than Guinea but I do not
      know that there is a post office at Hamiltons<lb/> Write Soon<lb/> Thomas M Smiley</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
