<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6121"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6121">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Lizzie Fackler to Mary, November 18, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county lizzie fackler to mary, november 18 1862</title>
        <author>Fackler, Lizzie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6121</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502393</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Lizzie Fackler to Mary, November 18, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county lizzie fackler to mary, november 18 1862</title>
            <author>Lizzie Fackler</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Fackler Family Letters, Accession #4199, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-11-18">1862-11-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Women, Home Front, Military Authority, Troop Movement</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6121T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Fackler writes about fear of Yankee invasion in Staunton.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-11-18"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 18th/62</date>
      <name type="place">Staunton</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I have at last seated myself to write you that long promised letter, you must remember when
     you were in S-- that I had a very bad habit of putting off things that should be done, from one
     day to another, and although I have tried to break myself of it, I have not entirely succeeded,
     and particularly does my fault show itself in letter writing, though I love both to receive and
     to answer letters from my friends. However, if you will again correspond with me I will try to
     follow your rule of anwering a letter as soon as it is received. Let me congratulate you upon
     being rid of the Yankees though I am late in the day doing it, better late than never", an old
     proverb says. Mrs. <orig reg="Ide">Tde.</orig> brought me both letters she received from you,
     and from your account you must have been very much annoyed by their presence. We have been
     several times alarmed, for fear the Yankees would get us, but they have not succeeded yet, and
     I trust Jackson will never give us up to them. They have been as near at eighteen miles in
     several diretions. At one time we had a regular panic, and almost everybody left Staunton, but
     after playing "refugee" about a week, they returned and were laughed at a great deal about it.
     We have not had school at the Institute since the war began. Mr. Wheat has had a boy's school
     and Mr. Phillips has been manager of a clothing Factory established for the benefit of the
     soldiers. Mrs. Forrest has the best school in town now, and I walk there, about a mile, every
     morning to take French lessons. Mr. Ide teaches music there. Mrs. Ide spent a day with us not
     long ago and she said she had either first written to you or was going to do it very soon. It
     does seem so strange that you have never seen either of her children. They have grown and
     improved so much lately. Ella is very pretty and little Nettie Bell is as sprightly as she can
     be. Bee Taylor is still in Staunton and was over to see me this morning. She would send her
     love if she knew I was writing. I have not been well for some time. I had a slight attack of
     typhoid fever this summer and have not gotten entirely over it yet. As a necessary consequence
     I have lost all my beautiful suit of hair, which of course distresses me very much. How is your
     cousin Sue? And what has become of your Sister Jennie? I do not know when I took such a fancy
     to <orig reg="anybody">any body</orig> from a description as I did to her. We have been having
     a very pleasant time lately, as the Fauquim Artillery have been stationed here for the last
     three weeks but much to our sorrow they were ordered away yesterday and of course had to go. As
     Staunton is the central depot for the troops, and persons going to and coming from the army
     have to pass through, we necessarily got acquainted with a good many gentlemen, so not
     withstanding the war we have enjoyed ourselves very much. I heard of a very narrow escape a
     cousin of mine had when the <orig reg="laboratory">labratory</orig> at Jackson, Mississippi,
     blew up. He is one of the officers in charge of it and only happened to be out of the building
     at the time, because he was sick. I am so thankful he was not hurt. He is one of my favorite
     cousins. You may have heard me speak of him, Steve Kinney, he was at West Point when you were
     here. Mr. Ide was here this morning and says he sent you a daguerreotype of Ella, the other
     day. Do you ever expect to come back to Staunton? By the by, I met Mr. John Bledsoe on the
     street a day or two ago, with his arm in a sling, I do not know whether he was wounded or not.
     Jakey Points is still in Staunton, has never been in the Army since the first battle of
     ----------. We had a wedding the other day and who do you think was married? Kittie Woodward. I
     suppose you remember her. She lived at the Lunatic Asylum. I have written you quite a long
     letter and you must answer it very soon. Ma joins me in love. Bee went to the country today
     with Grandpa and Rob has going to an uncle's to stay until Christmas, otherwise they would send
     some message. Do write soon. </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Yours truly</salute>
     <signed>Lizzie</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
