<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6152"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6152">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mollie Houser to James Houser, April 5, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mollie houser to james houser, april 5 1864</title>
        <author>Houser, Mollie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Julie Beagle</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6152</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502422</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mollie Houser to James Houser, April 5, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mollie houser to james houser, april 5 1864</title>
            <author>Mollie M Houser</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John F. Houser Papers, Special Collections
       Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-04-05">1864-04-05</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Patriotism, Women, Home Front</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6152T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter Mollie Houser expresses her concern for soldiers in the field and her wish
     that the war may soon end.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-04-05">April the 5 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Augusta County <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Cousin Jimmy</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I seat myself this morning to Express my gratitude unto you in answering your kind letter of
     the 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> finding me in good health with the rest of the family &amp;
     hoping when those few lines comes to hand they may find you enjoying that condition of health
     which renders the human most happy in this life Cousin you must <orig reg="excuse">excus</orig>
     me for not writing sooner I would have written but I had started a letter to you a few days
     before I received your last &amp; I thought I would wait for an answer from that but <orig
      reg="perhaps">perhapse</orig> you <orig reg="did not">didnot</orig> get it as you requested me
     to direct to NC I will do so as I have nothing of importance to write at present <orig
      reg="I'm">Im</orig> sorry I <orig reg="haven't">havent</orig> something good to write to you
     this time but I <orig reg="can't">Cant</orig> interest you by writing as long as the war lasts
      <orig reg="perhaps">perphapse</orig> it may take a notion &amp; stop of a sudden sometime
      <orig reg="A great">Agreat</orig> many persons think it will this spring but I <orig
      reg="believe">beleave</orig> the old Prophets are all dead &amp; the <orig reg="young"
      >yong</orig> ones <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
     <orig reg="know">no</orig>
     <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> about it or it would have stopped long ago well Jimmy
      <orig reg="we've">weve</orig> had some very disagreeable weather for sometime on the soldiers
     but they <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
     <orig reg="seem">seam</orig> to mind it as much as I do for them I received <orig
      reg="a letter">aletter</orig> from one <orig reg="a few">afew</orig> days ago &amp; he
     stated that his fingers had gotten so frosted when he was on guard he Could hardly write poor
     fellow if I had him here I would Certainly Cure them for him like <unclear>Kit</unclear> did
     yours if you remember <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> about it well Cousin <orig
      reg="I'm">Im</orig> sorry to tell you that Brother William has gone back to camp again I hate
     to <orig reg="see">se</orig> a soldier start as bad now most as I did at first but they <orig
      reg="can't">Cant</orig> help it I have to shed tears but it does no good well Cousin I hope we
     may have fine Crops this year &amp; plenty of fruit &amp; the war may Close that the
     Men May get home again &amp; we will<pb n="2"/> Certainly have some fine spread boilings as
     the old <orig reg="Pennsylvanians">Pensylvanians</orig> Call it I want you If the war ever ends
     to bring your Sister &amp; some of your Connections to see us &amp; tell Cousin AM to
     Come tell him he <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think <orig reg="worthwhile">worth while</orig>
     to write to me but he does to <unclear>Kit</unclear> &amp; she ain't as much kin to him as
     I am for my name is houser &amp; hers is hanger &amp; if he <orig reg="don't"
     >dont</orig> think so tell him <orig reg="I've">Ive</orig> heard old people say that I favor
     them more than all the rest by the name &amp; I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> think I will
     ever take the letter H from my name If it <orig reg="ain't">aint</orig> Houser it will be
     something like it well Cousin Jimmy it would have afforded me great <orig reg="pleasure"
      >pleisure</orig> to see you &amp; your Cousin AM before you left Virginia but I hope to
     see you both some future day if we never meet on this earth we will hope to meet in heaven
      <unclear>weel</unclear> in the god of battle trust &amp; die for old Virginia I must soon
     bring my uninteresting letter to a Close for the want of something to write receive my love
     &amp; warmest affections</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain your Cousin</salute>
     <signed>Mollie M Houser</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">PS Please write soon give my love to all tell your Cousins to write to
      me &amp; the next time you write tell me what has become of your brother William as you
      wrote to me once about his being in bad health give my most pious regards to Cousin Monroe
      &amp; my love to all the rest of your Connections &amp; receive a due portion
      yourself<lb/> from your most affectionate Cousin MMH<lb/> Greenville
       Augusta<lb/>County<lb/><abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr><lb/> when you direct my letters to
      Mollie M Houser they will be <orig reg="alright">all rite</orig> I always get mine without
      fail they always <orig reg="know">no</orig> who to send them to or they <orig reg="might"
      >mite</orig> hear something like fuss </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
