<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6241"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6241">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    November 26, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 26 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6241</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502482</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, November 26, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 26 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, November 26, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-11-26">1868-11-26</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6241T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert writes Evans and discusses the arrival of her father, apologizes for
                    teasing David, affirms her love for him, and urges him to visit soon.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-11-26">Nov. 26, /'68</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I know you did not expect a letter from me by the train yesterday as you know I
                    could not send it to the Depot in time to be mailed. Your dear &amp; welcome
                    letter of Tuesday came safely. I was so glad to hear from you my love that you
                    were well. You can imagine how delightful was our surprise last evening when the
                    passenger train <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> just above the house &amp;
                    papa <orig reg="stepped">steped</orig> from the car I was looking out the window
                    when the cars <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> &amp; wondered <pb n="2"/>
                    who was coming here but I knew pa as soon as I saw him leave the car. Mr. John
                    Ferror was here when pa arrived &amp; eat supper with us. papa was so
                    anxious to see us all at home that he did not stop in Staunton. I am so glad he
                    is with us again. has many interesting things to tell us of his long stay in New
                    York City. he says Mountain Palace looks strange to him. Ma &amp; Hamie had
                    not been at home but a little time before pa came. I wish you were here too my
                    love then I should be very happy. I am so glad you are coming Saturday if you
                    live. I want to see <pb n="3"/> you so much. You must forgive &amp; forget
                    all my teasing last Sabbath I have been so sorry about it. I will do so no more.
                    I love you too devotedly to wound your feelings in even a jest I would not for
                    the whole world do or say <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> to pain you my
                    love.</p>

                <p>It is one of the greatest desires of my heart to always please you in all things,
                    &amp; in every way you wish me, it makes me very happy to please you who I
                    love more dearly <orig reg="than">then</orig> all on Earth for you are more to
                    me <orig reg="than">then</orig> all the wide world one to whom I have given my
                    heart &amp; all its true &amp; unchanging devotion of thought &amp;
                    affection. <pb n="4"/> No one on Earth can take them from you my love you have
                    my affection secure in your keeping &amp; have since I first loved you. I
                    have loved you only with a faithful &amp; devoted love with no change in my
                    heart only to love you more &amp; more every day of my life, &amp; to
                    make you happy is the great desire I live for. I am happy my love in loving you
                    as I do with all my heart &amp; soul. I do love you with a devotion which
                    nothing but death can ever take away from you No woman has ever loved more truly
                    &amp; entirely <orig reg="than">then</orig> I love you. Come Saturday if you
                    live I want to see you more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I can tell. I love to
                    have you here with me. I am perfectly contented then. All send love. pa sends
                    his love to you. <hi rend="underline">he likes you</hi>. I love you with all my
                    heart &amp; soul &amp; ever shall while I live. Come Saturday May God
                    bless &amp; let you come to the one who loves you best I send a loving kiss
                    to you my only love.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Lovingly</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
