<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6242"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A6242">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    December 1, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 1 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A6242</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502483</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, December 1, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 1 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, December 1, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-12-01">1868-12-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A6242T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert responds to Evans and discusses family news, the fire in Staunton, her
                    disappointment on the postponement of his visit, and Evans's opinion on her
                    fashion choices.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-12-01">December 1st</date>
                        <name type="place">Buffalo, Va,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have your welcome &amp; dear letter of <orig reg="today">to day</orig>. I
                    was thankful to hear of your safe arrival home. how much I did miss you my love
                    &amp; I wished with all My heart that you could have <orig reg="stayed"
                        >staid</orig> longer with me but while you were riding home I was here
                    thinking of you &amp; loving you. I was disappointed to read in your dear
                    letter that you cannot come Saturday but I know you would <pb n="2"/> enjoy
                        <orig reg="yourself">your self</orig> much more to be here when we can be
                    with each other &amp; not so much company to divide our time with. I know I
                    should, my thoughts will be with you my love. I shall miss you sadly it will be
                    the first Sabbath for me to spend at Mountain Palace without your dear society I
                    shall not know what to do with myself without you my love it will seem lonely
                    here in my new home next Sabbath not to see you, but I must wait &amp; if we
                    both live you will come next week the time will be very long to me in passing
                    away. I will love you &amp; think of you every hour &amp; wish I was
                    with you who I love so devotedly. Hamie was <pb n="3"/> delighted when I told
                    him that you had commanded pay from Mr. Stanley for the loss of his whip. he
                    said "you were the business gentleman to please him." I was very sorry to hear
                    of Mr Johnson's &amp; Hoge's loss by fire but glad it did not extend further
                    &amp; others made to suffer. fire is a dangerous element one cannot be too
                    careful with it. My dear papa has been trying to improve the <hi
                        rend="underline">beauty</hi> of Mountain Palace since his return. I do not
                    know what you will say about it when you come Have you seen my discarded King
                    Louis the fifteenth just to think that I should discard a King for your sake. I
                    love you more <pb n="4"/>
                    <orig reg="than">then</orig> all the crowned heads in the world or their
                    fashions I will not wear <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> you do not
                    admire. I love you &amp; love to look well in your dear eyes if I please you
                    I do not care what others think or say of me I wish always to be just as you
                    want me to be to you in dress as well as in disposition. I love to please you
                    &amp; I want you always to give <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> if I wear what you see is not becoming I thank you for it
                    because I know that your taste is fine &amp; artistic &amp; I love you
                    the more for being so. I wish I could see you my love &amp; how I wish you
                    were coming Saturday I long to be with you more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I
                    can tell. I love you with all the deep devotion of my heart &amp; soul,
                    &amp; ever shall while I live You are more to me then all on Earth, one
                    look, one word from you is dearer to me <orig reg="than">then</orig> the praise
                    of all others living. I will write to you it is a sweet pleasure my love to
                    answer your dear letters. All send love. Write soon to me I love you with all my
                    heart &amp; soul. God bless you my love &amp; grant that you may soon
                    come to one who loves &amp; thinks only of you I send you a loving kiss.
                    Goodby my only love. Write soon</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Lovingly</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
