<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6509"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6509">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, May 18,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, may 18 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6509</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502521</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, May 18, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, may 18 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-05-18">1861-05-18</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Arts/Leisure, Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Slavery, State Government, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-01-25">January 25, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6509T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher uses the laws of logic to excuse his break with etiquette by sending "Miss
     Mary" a friendly letter without first securing her permission. He recounts the last days of his
     trip away from his home in Loudoun County and comments on Virginia's mobilization for war. He
     reveals that his community plans to organize a home guard for which he has been offered the
     captaincy and for which he wishes he could obtain one of her father's pistols.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Miss Mary <abbr expan="Anna">A.</abbr> Sibert<lb/> Mt. Solon<lb/>Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr><lb/><abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-05-18">May 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> 61</date>
      <name type="place">Maplegrove</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>It is with the utmost diffidence that I commence a letter to you so soon after forming your
     acquaintance without first hving asked your permission. But Chum is in Page and I have no
     correspondent in Augusta to give me news from you; emboldened therefore by having heard you
     say; first; that when you received a letter from a friend you always answered it, and secondly
     that you considered me one of your friends, which two propositions combined in the form of a
     sylogism necessitate the conclusion that you would answer my letter. I have concluded to write,
     and trust to this very indirect promise. I think the conclusion which I have drawn is clearly
     demonstrable by any rules of logic from Aristotle to Whateley and hope you will not violate
     even this indirect promise.</p>

    <p>I think I heard you say some time ago that you agreed with me in thinking the <pb n="2"/>
     prevalent prejudice against ladies and gentlemen corresponding with each other, both
     unreasonable and injurious; and that it was the part of wisdom to disregard it. I hope
     therefore that although I am asking a great favour of you you will not consider it too great a
     one to devote an hour occasionally to writing a letter to me. I own it is hardly fair, for you
     will have usually have long boring letters to read without either correction or order in the
     arrangement, while I cannot fail to be very much improved as well as interested by
     corresponding with one who has gained so young, a <orig reg="literary">litterary</orig>
     reputation.</p>

    <p>I had the pleasure of meeting you cousins in <orig reg="Luray">Leuray</orig> and spent an
     hour or two very pleasantly in their company. In Rappahannock I called on a gentleman whom I
     had met only once before with the intention of staying all night but he insisted so on my
     remaining longer that I found it impossible to escape for nearly three days. H. B. He had a
     very pleasant daughter. I stopped then a day in <pb n="3"/> Warrenton and saw two of my lady
     friends from Washington, both very strong southerners, and several gentlemen in the army from
     Alexandria with whom I was acquainted. Of course the time passed pleasantly and I was sorry
     that as my visit had already been protracted two weeks beyond my first calculation, duty bade
     me hurry on. I arrived at home on Wednesday about noon much to the joy of Pa &amp; Ma and
     myself too in fact, for I had been away so long that I was beginning to wish for the quiet
     pleasures of home once more.</p>

    <p>Day before yesterday I went to Leesburg to get me a copy of Gilhams tactics but could not
     find one in the place and heard a gentleman say that he bought a week ago the last copy in
     Richmond so I sent by a friend of mine who is smuggling military stores from Baltimore for the
     south. I hope the abolitionists will not catch him and I will have my Gilham by next Thursday
      <pb n="4"/> previous to that time I shall prosecute as fast as possible the study of Hardee
     which I shall commence to-day.</p>

    <p>I believe Virginia has now nearly as men in the field as she needs but we are talking here of
     organising a company to act at present as a home guard and to be called out when our services
     are needed. I have had the offer since my return of the captaincy of the militia but have not
     yet accepted. I think I shall write to <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Letcher this morning
     to know whether he will arm such a company, at once, as I mentioned above and if so commence
     enrolling at once. Has Mr. Sibert gotten any of his pistols made yet? I want one very much. I
     can neither beg, buy, borrow, nor steal a colt's revolver now.</p>

    <p>I have several letters of several week's standing to answer this morning. I hope you will
     therefore excuse this hurried letter and write very soon a long one in return; to your true
     friend</p>

    <closer>
     <salute/>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Direct to J. C. L. Hatcher Turcellville Loudon <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
      <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr><lb/><lb/>P. S. Please excuse the middle star on the envelop;
      but it was made with too dull a knife to make the shape and outline very accurate C.</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
