<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6508"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6508">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Samuel B. Coyner to Mary Anna Sibert, January
     20, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county samuel b coyner to mary anna sibert, january 20 1861</title>
        <author>Coyner, Samuel B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6508</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502520</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Samuel B. Coyner to Mary Anna Sibert, January 20, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county samuel b coyner to mary anna sibert, january 20 1861</title>
            <author>Samuel B. Coyner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-01-20">1861-01-20</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Desertion/Leave, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-01-25">January 25, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6508T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Samuel B. Coyner wrote from camp in Hedgesville, (West) Virginia, to one of the "Mt Solon
     girls," Miss M. A. Sibert. He excuses the tardiness of his letter by describing his injuries
     sustained in a sleigh ride gone awry. He also asserts the sobriety of his conduct since
     entering his company and mentions several joint acquaintances.</p>
   </div1>

  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <hi rend="underline">Address Martinsburg!</hi>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-01-20">Jan. 20, 1861-</date>
      <name type="place">Hedgesville, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Miss <abbr expan="Mary Anna">M. A.</abbr> Sibert, <lb/>My dear friend,--</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>On account of a lame hand, got in a <hi rend="underline">frolic</hi>, I have not written to
     you as soon as I intended. I should have written to you on my last arrival at this place; but
     on last Friday night (this is Monday) I became very glusome and determined to have a sleigh
     ride. One of the boys said if I got a sleigh, he would furnish the horse and we would have a
     ride. Slipping around in one of the alleys, I "pressed" the desired article and hitching in
      <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the horse, we started off, for Martinsburg distance 7 <pb n="2"/> miles; we
     went within sight of the town, but the pickets would not let us <orig reg="through"
     >thro</orig>, as it was after the proscribed hour, being about 12 o'clock. We then turned back
     and came in fine style till within 3 miles of camp, when the horse took fright and started. I
     tried to stop him by running him into the fence-course, but that made matters worse, or <hi
      rend="underline">better</hi> I scarce know which, for the vehicle upset, threw us all out,
     myself upon my face, nearly breaking my nose and spraining my thumb, and by my trying to hold
     him, dragged me several paces bruising and blackening my eye in an ugly manner. He got away you
     may guess after all and dashed into town at a wild <pb n="3"/> rate. There was still another
     sleigh and I with the two belonging to that got into it &amp; drove off, but had not gone
     more than 50 paces before that horse started also. We got free however, without any additional
     injuries, and sleigh and horse dashed on. We now had to walk along a road which not an hour
     before we had passed so merrily with jingling of bells and shouting of glad voices. And so
     ended the chapter, with the exception of the repairing of the sleighs. - And I had forgot to
     say that in our party were three sleighs, one broke down &amp; two were run away with, and
     none came into town whole. Four sleighs were smashed up that night. I know you will think that
     we were on a spree. If you dont <unclear>Mag</unclear> will. But I <hi rend="underline"
     >was</hi> not. <pb n="4"/> I was just as sober then as I am in writing this letter. Indeed so
     sober has been my conduct since I have been in the company, that the boys say they would not
     believe it if they saw "Samuel B.," as they call him, <hi rend="underline">drunk</hi>. And I am
     not <unclear>boasting</unclear> in the least. -- But I am taking up all my letter in the
     description of my <orig reg="sleigh ride">sleighride</orig>. I have no news however, of
     importance. We are back again in the glorious little town of Hedgesville after a most terrible
     scout. Indeed, we had a rougher time than we have ever had. Two soldiers of one of the Georgia
      Reg<hi rend="super">s</hi>- like to have <orig reg="froze">frouzed</orig> to death &amp;
     two young <orig reg="men">me</orig> who were visiting their acquaintances really did freeze. We
     expect to quarter here for the Winter &amp; most of the boys are well pleased, there being
     plenty of pretty and dear girls here. Give my love to all the family &amp; all the Mt Solon
     girls &amp; <unclear>Maggie</unclear> &amp; the <unclear>Dr.</unclear> &amp; little
     May.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>&amp; believe me your eternal friend,</salute>
     <signed>
      <hi rend="underline"><abbr expan="Samuel">S.</abbr> B. Coyner</hi>
     </signed>
     <seg type="postscript">I suppose you have heard of John since the battle of
      <unclear>Beth</unclear>. I saw him &amp; all my acquaintances they looked hearty. They are
      in Romney now I think-- Tell Ella Ill write to her soon</seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
