<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A6516"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="A6516">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, August 14,
     1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, august 14 1861</title>
        <author>Hatcher, Clinton</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A6516</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502527</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Clinton Hatcher to Mary Anna Sibert, August 14, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county clinton hatcher to mary anna sibert, august 14 1861</title>
            <author>Clinton Hatcher</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>8 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Evans-Sibert Family Papers, 1849-1900, Accession
       27770, Personal Papers Collection, Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond,
      Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-08-14">1861-08-14</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Enlistment, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-01-31">January 31, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Andre Fleche</name>
        </respStmt>

        <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A6516T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Clinton Hatcher comments on some of the regiments from other states, mentions mutual
     acquaintances, and criticizes Yankee "cowards" for delaying his plans to see Mary Sibert
    again.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     Miss Mary A. Sibert<lb/>Mount Solon<lb/>Augusta County<lb/>Va.
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-08-14"><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 14<hi rend="super">th</hi> 61</date>
      <name type="place">Camp Berkeley</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Miss Mary:</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I received your <hi rend="underline">very</hi> welcome and interesting letter day before
     yesterday, but I am sure you will excuse this delay for I assure you it was entirely
     unavoidable. I went to Leesburg on Sunday expecting our regiment to follow the next morning but
     on account of the rains they were unable to cross the creek. My paper and <orig reg="envelopes"
      >envelops</orig> were all in my knapsack and there were none at all in town for sale. But a
     few hours ago I again returned to camp and your letter has been the first thing to claim my
     attention after my arrival. I am really <hi rend="underline">very</hi> much obliged to you for
     writing me such long kind letters; it is such a relief to the monotony of camp life to receive
     letters from one who writes so well, <pb n="2"/> and is so kind a friend as to waste her time
     in raising the drooping spirits of a soldier.</p>

    <p>I think from your letter that you must have misunderstood my allusions to the battle. I was
     in the fight of Sunday the 21<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">st</hi>
     </hi> ult. and it was that of which I spoke. I had not heard that the Augusta troops were in
     the battle. I thought that <hi rend="underline">all</hi> of Gen. Johnson's force arrived too
     late for the fight. We have all of Gen. Evans Brigade here now consisting of three Mississippi
     Regiments besides our Virginia one. I expect more force will be sent up here before long and we
     will be ordered to cross the river and march on to Washington. I hope to dine there at
     Gautier's soon. Won't you come down? I expected to have made a desperate effort to see you once
     more about this time if it had not been for the war, but it has broken into all of my
     calculations. <pb n="3"/></p>

    <p>I have been a little unwell for several days, indeed for about a week. Since I have been
     staying at the Hotel in Leesburg some fellow has stolen my pistol. I wish I could only find the
     man who has it.</p>

    <p>I met a Mississippian the other morning in the regiment who had given out on the march, and
     as he got in the carriage with me to ride I recognized him to be one of Judge Ferry's sons whom
     I had met at Georgetown college. One of the old Columbian students is also in our brigade from
     Mississippi. It is so pleasant to meet old acquaintances in that way out in the army.</p>

    <p>I am very sorry that Chum did not conclude to come on and join our company, my cousin and I
     have just had a private tent made for ourselves and would be very happy to share it with him.
      <pb n="4"/></p>

    <p>I have no very intimate friend in this regiment and would like so much to have Sam's company.
     But I suppose he is doing more good for his country by manufacturing bombs and if so, I ought
     not to wish to take him away from that employment. I have not heard from him for a long <hi
      rend="underline">long</hi> time although I wrote him four pages of foolscap about the time I
     last wrote to you.</p>

    <p>I do wish with all my heart I could have been with you in your ride, besides being fond of
     horseback riding, I am sure it would have been impossible for me not to have enjoyed myself
     exceedingly in <hi rend="underline">your</hi> comapny. Indeed, I want to see you <hi
      rend="underline">very</hi> much. I shall be tempted never to spare a Yankee for interfering so
     much with my <pb n="5"/>plans and arrangments for this summer.</p>

    <p>I think my photograph on the "Noble Six" is very good. I would give much to look at one of
     yours now as good. There is not a single ambrotypist in Loudon now, is not that dreadful? Are
     there any in Augusta? I have never had a very good ambrotype taken to leave at home even and
     now if I should get killed it would be unfortunate. I am still compelled to write with a lead
     pencil and rather a <orig reg="dim">dimm</orig> one too but I hope you will excuse it without
     any apology especially as I am endeavoring to write you a long letter. On account of the
     irregularity of the Virginia mails it is impossible for me to write to you and receive <pb
      n="6"/> your letters as often as I would wish to, so the only resource is to write long
     letters every time.</p>

    <p>Our company are out on Battalion drill now but I do not feel well enough to be with them; and
     I prefer writing to you to being out with the numerous ladies who have come here from the
     adjacent county to look at the dress parade.</p>

    <p>The <orig reg="Mississippians">Missipians</orig> have just come out for Battalion drill,
     their Col. is on horseback, something quite unusual with us. Our Cols. of the infantry always
     appear on foot. I suppose their Col. is like Napoleon, the present Emperor, who appears much
     better on horseback than on foot on account of his long body and short limbs.</p>

    <p>The men have just been drawing comparisons between the line of <pb n="7"/> battle marching of
     our regiment and the 13<hi rend="super">
      <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
     </hi> Mississippian. Our regiment really beats them awfully. In fact we have been drilling over
     rocks and hills so long that now our men are getting to be quite soldierlike.</p>

    <p>I expect now that the officers see how well we drill we will be pushed into battle as soon as
     possible, at least I hope so. I would like to be in one bayonette charge. I can then <hi
      rend="underline">know</hi> whether I kill a Yankee or not. I think I should feel better after
     I knew that my bayonette had been the means of ridding the earth of one of the cowards.</p>

    <p>If you see Sam Forrer soon please tell him to write me a long letter. I received a <hi
      rend="underline">short</hi> note from him about a month ago which is the only time I have <pb
      n="8"/> heard from him for nearly two months.</p>

    <p>I heard yesterday that our forces had crossed into Md at Mathias Point and Aquia Creek and
     were advancing on Washington; if so I expect we will advance soon in this direction. I hope we
     will have M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Donald's Legion with us. I have <hi rend="underline"
     >great</hi> faith in their efficiency and wished very much that they had been on hand the day
     of the battle to follow the Yankees into Washington. They are daring fellows. Please excuse my
     hurried and disconnected letter and write me another of your long, interesting ones very soon.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>I remain as ever, your <hi rend="underline">truest</hi>
      <hi rend="underline">and</hi>
      <hi rend="underline">most</hi>
      <hi rend="underline">unchanging</hi> friend,</salute>
     <signed>Clinton</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
