<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7128"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7128"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, December 12, 1868</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, december 12 1868</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.163 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7128</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500244</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, December 12, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, december 12 1868</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, December 12, 1868, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1868-12-12">1868-12-12</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Race Relations, Women</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7128T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Concerned about the future success of the AMA schools in Staunton, Scott argues that he was forced to insist upon employing white teachers over black teachers against the wishes of many "influential colored people in the community."  He comments on the arrival of "Miss Daveson" and expresses his apprehension about her teaching abilities.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev E P Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va.</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1868-12-12">12 Saturday Morn./68</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>My dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>The invoice of books has arrived and I expect that the books will come to day.  Mrs Daveson (or some such name which I have hardly learned came last night.--I am glad of help indeed but she raised my apprehensions as to her adaptedness to the work, by making the remark that "It was a long time since she has studied" and now "must go at it and prepare herself" and also by saying that she "had never taught"  I hope however that these are only the expressions of <hi rend="underline">modesty</hi> and not much to be relied upon.  There are so many petty schools here among the colored people that this must be made <hi rend="underline">superior</hi> to be successful--Nor will it do to let a teacher teach the "<hi rend="underline">Alphabet</hi>" class.</p>
	<p>Some of the more advanced ones will often call on her, and soon find out if she is not capable.</p>
	<p>When will the people of the north learn that it is an <hi rend="underline">undeniable fact</hi> that these people are sunken so low that nothing but the <hi rend="underline">best</hi> means will elevate them.  If it should appear that from lack of education or want of practice this most excellent<pb n="2"/> lady is not qualified to teach <hi rend="underline">any who may call upon her</hi>., the circumstances are such that it will ruin this school.  for some of the ignorant yet influential colored people here very much desired me to hire a colored teacher.</p>
	<p>They said that they were poor and wanted the pay and said that small scholars could be taught as well by those of their own color--and if they find out any deficiency--they will so blame me for insisting on a white teacher as to almost destroy my influence and give encouragement to all these petty schools about town, which will spring up in opposition, to mine like mushrooms.  And when my influence is gone here--this school is gone; for others have already abandoned it.  Therefore in order to save the school I should have to part with the teacher, and explain the matter afterward to the people--as a <hi rend="underline">mistake</hi>, or even your Association would lose popularity and even effect.</p>
	<p>Such is the certain result here of any inability on the part of a teacher</p>
	<p>I hope it may be avoided.</p>
	<p>I just pen these thoughts as they occur</p>

<closer>
<salute>Very Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 
<seg type="postscript">I saw one school at Beaufort winter before last rendered so dissatisfied and useless by an incompetent<pb n="3"/> teacher that I am afraid of such results, and here it would be worse than there.</seg> 
<name type="place">N. Y.</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>