<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7158"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A7158"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, April 29, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, april 29 1869</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 5.975 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7158</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500274</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, April 29, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, april 29 1869</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>2 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, April 29, 1869, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1869-04-29">1869-04-29</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Economy, Women, Race Relations</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7158T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott writes to E. P. Smith to make arrangements for summer school, asking if there is a "teacher farther South who would be willing to stop on her way home and remain all summer here!  There is a room large enough for one teacher without renting."  Scott also mentions the possibility of receiving the "Bureau's" assistance in constructing a new schoolhouse in Staunton.</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev E P Smith</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1869-04-29">Apr 29<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1869</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>Yours of the 27<hi rend="super">th</hi> is rec'd.  Altho' both of the teachers are fully aware of the necessity or at least the great utility of a teacher remaining all summer--yet in consequence of their having so hard a time during the winter they feel to much worn to attempt this additional labor.  I think if one could stay;--as to the expense to the A. M. A.--the proposition in your letter could be met--namely that the cost including salary would not be greater than that of going North and returning.  I am exceedingly sorry that something cant be done.  Isn't there some teacher farther South who would be willing to stop on her way home and remain all summer here!  There is a room large enough for one teacher without renting.</p>
	<p>As to the communication from Richmond which I presume refers to the erection of School House here by the Bureau; (yet the terse note enclosed does not say) if there are any preliminary requirements on the part of Govt to be demanded of the colored people before making an appropriation, you will please inform me that I may ascertain whether the people are willing to do their part.  I think they<pb n="2"/> require that the freedmen shall furnish the ground, but dont know,  But I am quite sure the freedmen will not be willing a house shall go up on their ground unless we can controll it entirely, at least for a term of years.  Shall I go on and ascertain what the people will do?</p>
	<p>Mr Brackett has given me <hi rend="underline">indications</hi> that <hi rend="underline">he</hi> intends to try and erect a building here,--and if the AMA intend to build,--would it not be well to communicate with Mr Brackett so as not to conflict with any arrangement of his.  But I may have misunderstood the import of your <hi rend="underline">very brief</hi> communication.</p>
	<p>I rather think we shall keep the schools in operation till the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi> of June, if it please you--as there is not much prospect of a summer school</p>
	<p>Does the Bureau give Transportation this year?  If so, I don't know but I should like mine from Wilmington N. C. instead of Staunton--will write--but I want to see Bro Beals</p>


<closer>
<salute>Very Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 
<seg type="postscript">P. S. I am afraid if we put up a building we shall have to buy the ground</seg> 
<name type="place">New York</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>