<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7164"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A7164"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, May 14, 1869</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, may 14 1869</title>
        <author>Scott, John</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 6.389 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7164</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500280</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Scott to E. P. Smith, May 14, 1869</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john scott to e p smith, may 14 1869</title>
            <author>John Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Scott to E. P. Smith, May 14, 1869, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1869-05-14">1869-05-14</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Women, Economy, Race Relations</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7164T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Scott asks Smith whether it would be best to retain Sarah H. Davison in the field, and he wonders whether he should remain in Staunton in the coming months to "superintend" the construction of a new schoolhouse.</p> 
</div1> 
<div1 type="figure" id="d4">
<p>American Missionary Association letterhead</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d5">
<div1 type="letter" id="d6">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Rev E. P. Smith</name> 
<name type="place"></name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1869-05-14">May 14<hi rend="super">th</hi>, 1869</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>I wish to bring up two questions in regard to business which seem so nearly balanced in my own mind that I dont know how to settle them--at least would like your council.</p>
	<p>First I had thought the question in regard to the expediency of either of the ladies <hi rend="underline">remaining</hi>,--settled, but some things have lately <del hand="h1">takes</del> appeared that cause the doubt.  In the first place I had concluded that Miss Davison would better not remain from the fact of her inexperience, as well as her unfortunate deficiency in education--thinking she might have trouble if left alone.--but while it is merely possible that such would be the case, yet since the advances classes have all gone out to work and will not be likely to return in the summer <hi rend="underline">I do not think</hi> she would have any difficulty.</p>
	<p>Beside this she has shown unusual tact for a beginner in managing a school.  I scarcely ever found better progress in a primary school than<pb n="2"/> her scholars have made, and confess I am agreeably surprised.  She has also taken great pains to improve herself and has persistently used every opportunity to do it.</p>
	<p>These tracts--together with her love of the work--her clear <hi rend="underline">moral judgement</hi> as well as her missionary spirit;--and, her excellent knowledge of all kinds of needle work make her too valuable a laborer to lose from this work.  2<hi rend="super">nd</hi>  I think it would be rather better for the school for her to remain</p>
	<p>3<hi rend="super">rd</hi>--Col Manly has been up from Richmond and says he is ready to help with Govt funds--to build a school house</p>
	<p>Many of the people are ready--they have the ground--but I dont believe they can raise the money till after harvest  If there was anyone to come and lead them in September they would do it.</p>
	<p>These are the considerations in favor of her remaining</p>
	<p>On the other hand she <hi rend="underline">might</hi> have trouble from advanced scholars--Again she would need a vacation in the Fall of at least 4 or 6<pb n="3"/> weeks, at any rate, 3 She rather desires to return north when we do--partly for rest--and partly to better fit herself for next winter. (tho'with other teachers she could do well now)</p>
	<p>The importance of holding this place from the influence of these ignorant colored teachers is my excuse for asking your council in a matter which perhaps it is my business to decide.</p>
	<p>Do you think it best under any circumstances if I can raise the money for me to remain a month to superintend the erection of this building. I merely ask this question as Col Manly promises aid, and the funds my be exhausted by Fall--I don't really want to stay</p>
	<p>Please write by return mail</p>


<closer>
<salute>Respectfully</salute> 
<signed>John Scott</signed> 
<seg type="postscript">Mission Home, Staunton Va</seg> 
<name type="place">53 John St NY</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>