<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7180"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 



<TEI.2 id="A7180"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Annie A. Dunn to E. P. Smith, March 7, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county annie a dunn to e p smith, march 7 1867</title>
        <author>Dunn, Annie A.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 7.085 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7180</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500296</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Annie A. Dunn to E. P. Smith, March 7, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county annie a dunn to e p smith, march 7 1867</title>
            <author>Annie A. Dunn</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>3 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Annie A. Dunn to E. P. Smith, March 7, 1867, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1867-03-07">1867-03-07</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education, Women, Christianity/Religious Activity</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7180T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>In response to AMA administrators' request to relocate to Goldsboro, Dunn argues that she cannot teach in another community as she is "a Widow, and twelve hundred miles from home, the only relatives I have in the south are here, and I cannot make it appear to my mind that it is my duty to leave them to go into another State among entire strangers and still farther from home."  Apparently, the AMA sought to remove Dunn from her position in Staunton because she had "given testimony concerning other Teachers" to "an Officer authorized to take it."
</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">Edw. P. Smith Esq.</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va.</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1867-03-07">March 7<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1867</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>Yours of the 5<hi rend="super">th</hi> is received, and would have been answered <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> this, if I had not considered it a matter that required some time for consideration, as to what it was my duty to do under the circumstances.  This point I have weighed long and well, trying hard to divest my mind of all prejudice in the case, and only consider what was my duty, as a professed Christian missionary, to do under the circumstances.  And painful as it is to me there is but one conclusion that I can arrive at which is that I cannot go to Goldsboro.</p>
	<p>I am a Widow, and twelve hundred miles from home, the only relatives I have in the south are here, and I cannot make it appear to my mind that it is my duty to leave them to go into another State among entire strangers and still farther from home, and especially is this true when I consider that the only reason urged for this change is because I have when called upon for my testimony concerning other Teachers, <hi rend="underline">and by an Officer</hi> authorized to take it, that I simply told the truth, and only answered such questions as were put to me leaving out much that I might have said and volunteering nothing, and I am prepared<pb n="2"/> to prove all that I said, and much more if need be.  But I have no desire to say any more upon this subject farther than this.  It has been urged as a reason for my being ordered away that there was a disturbance among the Teachers and that four were united against one and that it was easier to change one, than four, all of which I am aware is true.  I am also well aware that the money that is being expended in this great work, all comes from charitable contributions, and do not blame the Association for feeling as though it must be expended to the very best advantage, and consequently for coming to the conclusion that it was easier to transfer one Teacher than four.  Nevertheless it does seem to me that the question of justice should have <hi rend="underline">something</hi> to do with this case, and that I should not be removed without a fair investigation of the whole affair or at least that I should only have been suspended from teaching, until the whole truth could be made known.  but it seems you have decided differently and there is no alternative left but for me to submit.  In conclusion permit me to add, that this is my third year in the work, and this is the first time I have ever been complained of to my knowledge.  I have always endeavored to do my duty, and do it faithfully and in looking over the last three years I cannot call to my mind any act of mine (committed knowingly) which I regret.  <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> I am human and may have committed errors of the head, but I think none of the heart.</p><pb n="3"/>  
<p>And now after saying this much, I can only add, that I am in your hands, and whatever decision you may make of my case, I shall try to feel that the Lord orders all things for the best, and in his hands I am willing to leave this result.  with the best wishes for this great work in which you are engaged, and in which I have been deeply interested for the last three years.</p>


<closer>
<salute>I am Respectfully Yours</salute> 
<signed>Mrs Annie A. Dunn</signed> 

<name type="place">53 John St. N. Y.</name> 
</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>