<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7185"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>  


<TEI.2 id="A7185">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William L. Coan to Samuel Hunt,
                    November 4, 1865</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william l coan to samuel hunt, november 4 1865</title>
        <author>Coan, William L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Bart Elmore</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Bart Elmore</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. 14.204 kilobytes </extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7185</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500301</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William L. Coan to Samuel Hunt, November 4, 1865</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william l coan to samuel hunt, november 4 1865</title>
            <author>William L. Coan</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William L. Coan to Samuel Hunt,
                            November 4, 1865, American Missionary Association Archives Collection,
                            Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia,
                        Charlottesville</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1865-11-04">1865-11-04</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Education, Race Relations, Women, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7185T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Coan begins his letter with a discussion of his recent journeys to Woodstock, New
                    Market, and Harrisonburg, arguing that a mission team should be sent to
                    Harrisonburg, a community where he claims "<hi rend="underline">Rebellion</hi>"
                    is "deeply seated." He notes that there "are Lutheran Churches scattered all
                    along this Valley," and argues that a representative from that denomination
                    might be best fit to begin work in Harrisonburg. Excited about the prospect of
                    new schools in Staunton and surrounding communities, Coan exclaims, "I have seen
                    no place where <hi rend="underline">Educational</hi> influences are more needed
                    and demanded than in this <hi rend="underline">Valley</hi>. We owe it to the <hi
                        rend="underline">Rebels</hi> that we throw in the Northern "Yankee"
                    Christian Element here." Though hopeful that Northern aid might quash the social
                    injustice associated with "Rebel" rule in the Valley, Coan criticizes the
                    "Bureau" and "Mr Beecher" for "doing much to encourage these Rebels in their
                    course" and for "doing much which tends to discourage the real Unionists at the
                    South." In one passage of the letter, he refers to the Shenandoah Valley as the
                    "Valley of Humiliation" and a "sink-hole of Iniquity." </p>
            </div1>
            
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Rev. S Hunt</name>
                    <name type="place">Staunton Va</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1865-11-04">Nov 4<hi rend="super">th</hi>/65</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>My last to you was from Woodstock since which I have been at New Market and also
                    Harrisonburg. The latter is quite a flourishing place and an important one in
                    several respects and a school should be established there soon as practicable.
                        <hi rend="underline">Rebellion</hi> was deeply seated there and instead of
                    getting <hi rend="underline">better</hi> like total depravity seems to wax <hi
                        rend="underline">worse</hi> and <hi rend="underline">worse</hi>. They do not
                    boldly <hi rend="underline">threaten</hi> the lives of those who may undertake
                    to teach a school for colored children but, the more mild and <hi
                        rend="underline">nominally</hi> Union who are presumed to speak advisedly
                    say that "a teacher" could not live a week" and in answer to my inquiry "do you
                    mean to affirm that a teacher would be assassinated?" answer "certainly as he
                    undertakes it" Now I do not believe any thing of the kind. The very fact that
                    they back this would lead me to doubt it. But they <hi rend="underline"
                    >feel</hi> all <hi rend="underline">over</hi>. I had a meeting of the colored
                    people who are enthusiastic about the school and will with the aid the Bureau
                    and Supt. of that vicinity provide a school room. It would be well if a man and
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> could be sent there immediately. Military protection will
                    be provided when needed.<pb n="2"/> I hope your Lutheran friends will be
                    disposed to occupy that and adjoining fields unless <hi rend="underline"
                    >you</hi> have other suitable help ready. There are Lutheran Churches scattered
                    all along this Valley, and should Harrisonburg be occupied by such a
                    representative, schools could be located in smaller places in the same vicinity
                    (although of course at some distance) under his direction which I understood
                    from Mr Whipple was desired.</p>
                <p>There is more work to be done and a demand for many more workers in this (the
                        6<hi rend="super">th</hi>) District than I supposed, and probably 40 to 50
                    teachers will be required if the field is properly cultivated. I have seen no
                    place where <hi rend="underline">Educational</hi> influences are more needed and
                    demanded than is this <hi rend="underline">Valley</hi>. We owe it to the <hi
                        rend="underline">Rebels</hi> that we throw in the Northern "Yankee"
                    Christian Element here.</p>
                <p>They are miserable <hi rend="underline">Rebels</hi> and I wish most heartily that
                    Mr Beecher was obliged to spend a few weeks here and inform himself from this
                    stand point instead of President Johnsons Blue or Green Room, as to the real
                    spirit of Rebels, their constant cruel and outrageous treatment of the blacks<pb
                        n="3"/> their determination to make their condition as uncomfortable as
                    possible their deadly opposition to their being educated, the hatred and malice
                    with which they are constantly being <unclear>pursued</unclear> by <hi
                        rend="underline">all</hi>, professing Christians and ministers, seeming to
                    vie with each other to <hi rend="underline">outdo</hi> in their <hi
                        rend="underline">wickedness</hi>. </p>
                <p>Mr Beecher and others at the North are now doing, the Bureau and all friends of
                    the Freed people "much harm" (God forgive them) They are doing much to <hi
                        rend="underline">encourage</hi> these Rebels in their course. They are also
                    doing much which tends to <hi rend="underline">discourage</hi> the real <hi
                        rend="underline">Unionists</hi> at the South. Poor Fellows <hi
                        rend="underline">they</hi> have also suffered <hi rend="underline">much</hi>
                    and still <hi rend="underline">dare not</hi> speak out their <hi
                        rend="underline">Union</hi> sympathies.</p>
                <p>You know little how such a <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as Mr Beecher is working <hi
                        rend="underline">mischief</hi> to the cause of true <hi rend="underline"
                        >loyalty</hi> in both white and black.</p>
                <p>My heart is too full for utterance and I can only <hi rend="underline">with
                    all</hi> Loyal persons express my surprise at such an unexplainable
                    forgetfulness of and <hi rend="underline">ignoring</hi> of the rights the
                    condition of loyal men and women where present and prospective condition appeals
                    to us all as <hi rend="underline">never before</hi> for <hi rend="underline"
                        >sympathy</hi> aid and protection. God <hi rend="underline">will</hi> bring
                    us into judgment for <hi rend="underline">such</hi> a <hi rend="underline"
                        >course</hi>.</p>
                <pb n="4"/>
                <p>I find the school here doing as well as could be expected under the embarrassing
                    circumstances which attend it. Mr Tukey has done all that any one could have
                    done and the same is true of the Ladies Mrs Dunn and Miss McClean.</p>
                <p>They may be obliged to give up their present school rooms, if so I trust as good
                    or possibly better accommodations may be secured. The school is <hi
                        rend="underline">needed</hi> (if only to <hi rend="underline">educate
                    Rebels</hi>) and is a "<hi rend="underline">fixture</hi>" It needs however a
                    reinforcement of teachers. (3) Three teachers should be sent here soon as
                    practicable (one man if you can afford it if not three Ladies) One of the Ladies
                    now here will of necessity be required to superintend house keeping but will aid
                    in the schools so far as practicable. You are aware I suppose that one of the
                    Ladies may at no far distant date sustain a much more intimate relation to Mr
                    Tukey all of which will seem to be but perfecting arrangements for making this a
                    pleasant and successful enterprise in the "Valley of Humiliation" this very
                    "sink-hole of Iniquity made so by these "infernal Rebels" while God and Native
                    have done everything to make it a Paradise--almost.</p>
                <pb n="5"/>
                <p>Bro Hunt, dont think me ungenerous or uncharitable. My feelings are those of <hi
                        rend="underline">all</hi> northern men in or out of the Army who see how and
                    toward what we are drifting as a Nation. My hearts wish is that I had the
                    ability of a Webster of Choate for in that case I would not remain <hi
                        rend="underline">South</hi> but go to the <hi rend="underline">North</hi>
                    and cry out against the influence of those who are unconsciously I trust,
                    endorsing a <hi rend="underline">policy</hi> which is so apparently <hi
                        rend="underline">unjust</hi>. Pardon me if you feel that I am writing too
                    much on the subject. You would not blame me if you understood the <hi
                        rend="underline">tithe</hi> of the evil already resulted to the Cause you
                    and I have at heart. I feel that if those of us on the ground--the battle
                        field--<hi rend="underline">do not</hi> cry out--the "very <hi
                        rend="underline">stones</hi>" <hi rend="underline">will</hi>.</p>
                <p>I ought to know from you at once how much you desire to do in the Valley (I
                    suppose I am to interest myself in the <hi rend="underline">work</hi>, but not
                    alone for the A. M. A. still I can with propriety at least consult with you as
                    to your wishes. The Baptist Association I predict <hi rend="underline">will
                    not</hi> do much this way as the colored people are mostly Methodist,
                    Presbyterian <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Why should no <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and your <del
                        hand="h1"/> supply the demand <hi rend="underline">mainly</hi> in the
                    Valley?</p>
                <pb n="6"/>
                <p>I shall report in person to Col Brown in a few days and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and be
                    prepared to aid where and in such a manner as instructed. To fulfill
                    arrangements made between the Col and Bro Alvord I suppose "I must needs go" to
                    Washington again soon.</p>
                <p><hi rend="underline">Much</hi> should be done every where for the Bank and I
                    would suggest whether you and the Bank could not arrange some plan for combining
                    representatives, + sharing expense, as a <hi rend="underline">permanent
                        arrangement</hi>.</p>
                <p>Mr Tukey has spoken to me about leaving some definite understanding in reference
                    to teachers board etc. which seems proper. He is willing to adopt any feasible
                    plan, suggests that with five teachers your assuming house rent cost of fuel
                    etc. the house can be so managed that board will not exceed (20) twenty dollars
                    per month and probably will be <hi rend="underline">less</hi>. My advice would
                    be that you let Mr Tukey manage it for you, giving him such authority as shall
                    be necessary to his acting efficiently or if you choose to instruct me in the
                    matter I will arrange with him for you. He is disposed to <hi rend="underline"
                        >liberality</hi> toward you and desires to facilitate.<pb n="7"/> It is
                    quite important however that you authorize action <hi rend="underline"
                        >immediately</hi> or the house now occupied may not be held which seems very
                    desirable.</p>
                <p>In sending teachers please oblige Mr Tukey and also the ladies here by sending if
                    you can do so Miss Josephine E. Strong (2 <unclear>Rowe</unclear> Place Boston)
                    who was formerly at Portsmouth and afterwards at Hampton. They <hi
                        rend="underline">desire</hi> this if you are willing to favor it. Teachers
                    for this vicinity should come by Steamer to Richmond then by R. R.. The Ladies
                    now here came via Washington owing to peculiar circumstances, but Mr Tukey
                    wishes me to say that they will pay all extra expenses incurred over the cheaper
                    route.</p>
                <p>I find there are no <hi rend="underline">books</hi> here or other facilities for
                    the school rooms which is very embarrassing and I enclose a Memo. for books etc.
                    for them which should be sent <hi rend="underline">without delay</hi> by the
                    best route, probably by Steamer to Richmond, then by V. C. R. R.</p>
                <p>This letter is long enough and yet I have not said half I should like to.</p>


                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>W. L. Coan</signed>
                    
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
