<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7210"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 


<TEI.2 id="A7210"> 
<teiHeader type="migrated"> 

    <fileDesc> 
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: F. S. Tukey to W. E. Whiting, July 1, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county f s tukey to w e whiting, july 1 1866</title>
        <author>Tukey F. S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt> 
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp> 
          <name>Bart Elmore</name> 
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt> 

      <extent>ca. 5.849 kilobytes </extent> 
      <publicationStmt> 
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher> 
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace> 

        <idno type="VCDH">A7210</idno> 

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p> 
<p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
--> 
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500326</idno>
      </publicationStmt> 
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt> 
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt> 

      <sourceDesc> 
        <biblFull> 
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: F. S. Tukey to W. E. Whiting, July 1, 1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county f s tukey to w e whiting, july 1 1866</title>
            <author>F. S. Tukey</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt> 
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt> 
          <extent>2 pages</extent> 
          <publicationStmt> 
            <publisher/> 
            <pubPlace/> 
            <date value=""/> 
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: F. S. Tukey to W. E. Whiting, July 1, 1866, American Missionary Association Archives Collection, Microfilm 72, Alderman Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville</idno>
          </publicationStmt> 
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt> 
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt> 
        </biblFull> 
      </sourceDesc> 
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Alderman Library, University of Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc> 

    <profileDesc> 
      <creation>
        <date value="1866-07-01">1866-07-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage> 
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass> 
        <keywords> 
          <term>African Americans, Education</term> 
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords> 
      </textClass> 
    </profileDesc> 

    <revisionDesc> 
      <change> 
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt> 
        <item/> 
      </change> 
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc> 
  </teiHeader> 

<text id="A7210T">
<front id="d2">
<div1 type="summary" id="d3">
<p>Tukey reflects on the AMA's efforts to establish schools for freedmen in Staunton and concludes that "firm and prudent management has overcome much . . . prejudice and forced even Rebs to respect us."</p> 
</div1> 

</front> 

<body id="d4">
<div1 type="letter" id="d5">
<head>
<name type="recipient">W. E. Whiting Esq.</name> 
<name type="place">Staunton Va</name> 
</head>

<opener>
<dateline>
    <date value="1866-07-01">July 1 1866</date> 
</dateline> 
<salute>Dear Sir</salute> 
</opener> 

<p>Enclosed please find a Bill of expenses for the Board of Teachers for the month of June 1866 which I believe settles all claims for the year.</p>
	<p>Mrs Tukey's expenses are made up <unclear>exclusively</unclear> of fare between Baltimore and New York for which you sent the Teachers free tickets.</p>
	<p>I passed through N. Y. about three weeks ago, and resigned to have called at the Rooms but I had the misfortune of having my Pocket Picked while passing through <unclear>Baltimore</unclear> and lost the whole of my last two years savings and only had money enough left by me to pay my expenses through to Boston without laying over in N. Y. which I should have been obliged to do had I called at the Rooms.  It was a severe blow for me but I am reconciled to it  True I did not lose very large amounts but when a poor man is robbed of nearly all he has got in the world he feels it very sensibly--be it ever so small.</p><pb n="2"/>
	<p><unclear>yet conclusion</unclear> I wish to say one word about our Schools--and what has been <unclear>accomplished</unclear> at this point during the last year.  When we came here one year ago we found Colored people without Church or School <unclear>house</unclear>, and the popular prejudice so strong against the Bureau and the Teachers, that for a long time the doors were all closed against us, and we could not get a place for an <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> House for the Teachers.  But firm and prudent management has overcome much of this prejudice and forced even Rebs to respect us, and we wind up our Schools here with a Church for the people to worship in, and a School House to educate their Children <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> and it <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>we could hire any House that might be for rent about us soon. <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>. any citizen here.</p>
<p>The Colored people here have made great progress in Learning <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>. True it may have cost a little more than <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> some other points--but if so it is to be attributed to the fact that there was no Govt Buildings here which <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> could get into, and it being the first year everything had to be bought or hired, but it is money well invested that I think will pay a high rate of interest and entitle all which have been engaged in this great work to a higher Seat in the Heavenly Kingdom and in conclusion Mrs Tukey and myself desire to thank you and the rest of the Com. For your uniform kindness and courtesy to us.</p>


<closer>
<salute></salute> 
<signed>F. S. Tukey</signed> 

</closer> 
</div1> 
</body> 
</text> 
</TEI.2>