<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7536"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7536">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    November 14, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 14 1867</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7536</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502578</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, November 14, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, november 14 1867</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, November 14, 1867, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-11-14">1867-11-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-29">December 29, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7536T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert complains that she is lonely, expresses her passionate love for Evans, and
                    asks where they will spend the Christmas holidays.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-11-14">November 14, 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Solon</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. D.H. Evans</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your dear &amp; welcome letter of Tuesday came safely. Its contents gave me
                    much relief as I was very anxious to hear how you all reached town after your
                    packed ride. I thought so much of you &amp; Ma crowded as you were in that
                    small buggy I thank God for your safe arrival home. I did wish you could have
                        <orig reg="stayed">staid</orig> with me longer It is hard for me to give you
                    up, knowing as I do that I cannot see you again for two long, &amp; lonely
                    weeks. I am left in this isolated place to count the days before you can bring
                    your dear self back to me, but I must not complain it cannot now be helped. One
                    wiser <orig reg="than">then</orig> us, is the ruler of our destinies. I have
                    placed mine in His keeping, &amp; I feel sure that God will bless our love
                    for each other in this life. My greatest pleasure is to know <hi
                        rend="underline">you</hi> love me with all your fresh, &amp; truthful
                    heart. to feel that I have the entire devotion of one I love is indeed happiness
                    not many in this weary life journey are so blessed. how many fond hearts love in
                    vain. I pity such unfortunate beings<pb n="2"/>with sincere sympathy. I know how
                    sweet it is to have your love, because I love you, &amp; I can feel for
                    those who love without hope. I am not <orig reg="referring">refering</orig> to
                    my friend <hi rend="underline">M</hi>r. E<hi rend="underline">stel</hi>l indeed
                    I was not thinking of him at all, for I do not <hi rend="underline">belie</hi>ve
                    his heart will break, or suffer much over my refusal he has lived too long in
                    this world for painful feelings of heart ache to trouble him. I have not met him
                    since that Eventful Evening. I suppose he has left the county. You do not know
                    how lonely we are now without either Mother, or father. we miss dear Ma so much,
                    the days seem doubly long since she is gone In Ma's letter by Tuesday, she wrote
                    that "you had been up to see them," &amp; that "she thought you were one of
                    the best men in the world" &amp; "that she would not give you for all the
                    young gentlemen in Staunton" how complimentary to you! I like for her to speak
                    in that way of you. it pleases me because I love you, &amp; I know you are
                    all she thinks, &amp; much more <orig reg="than">then</orig> that to me. I
                    understand you best of all, &amp; how to love &amp; appreciate you,
                    which I do with sincere, &amp; unchanging devotion. I wish you were here
                        <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>. Oh I do want to see you so much, so
                    much. I am lonely without you. I feel <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig> a
                    longing, &amp; yearning desire to have you with me. I want you to kiss me to
                    take my hands in your strong, &amp; loving clasp. Then I should feel happy,
                    &amp; safe. It seems that I must<pb n="3"/>quit writing, get up, &amp;
                    go right to you, &amp; ask you for just one word, one evidence of your love
                    for me I would then be satisfied. I know it is useless for me to wish you here
                        <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>, it cannot be, but I can't help it try
                    as I will. My heart &amp; head grow tired of waiting, then they get
                    impatient, &amp; cry out for you to come, &amp; give me rest, &amp;
                    happiness. Oh! I love you more &amp; more each hour of my life. I wish you
                    could see my heart &amp; read there all I feel for you. then you would be
                    convinced of my sincere, &amp; unchanging affection. I wish I only could see
                    you. Have you forgotten that Rennie invited you, &amp; myself to spend our
                    Christmas with her in her husband's home at Bridgewater? I have not forgotten
                    the invitation, &amp; if you are willing &amp; we all live, I think we
                    should go, but I leave it for you to decide. if you would rather have me in
                    Staunton, why I would rather be there with you <orig reg="than">then</orig>
                    <orig reg="anywhere">any where</orig> in this world. so I can be near you I do
                    not care when it is, if the loneliest spot on Earth, &amp; never see any one
                    but you all the days of life. I would ask for no other society but yours, for no
                    one to see, &amp; to love but you, for then I would be happy, &amp;
                    contented I am writing the truth to you as I hope for Heaven. I am very selfish
                    in this way those I love are my all in this world. I do not care for others. I
                    don't want to be with<pb n="4"/>any but my loved ones. I don't want, or wish for
                    the society of any but those who are near &amp; dear to me it is all I want
                    or ask for just to be with those I love best. I know this is selfishness. I
                    can't help it I have always been so, &amp; Ever shall be while I live. You
                    must not blame me I can't help it any more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I could
                    help loving you with all the deep intensity of my nature, &amp; I know I
                    can't help loving you so, &amp; I would not if I could for I <hi
                        rend="underline">love</hi> to love <hi rend="underline">you</hi> If I could
                    only see your dear dear face <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig> &amp; tell
                    you all my love for you I would be so truly happy, &amp; satisfied. I must
                    wait patiently until God lets you come. Then I will tell you. I wish Saturday a
                    week was here. it is so long to me another long lonely week before you can come.
                    I am so glad to know you are happy &amp; cheerful when with me, for I am as
                    happy as I can be with you near me. I ask or wish for no one else but your dear
                    self to be with me. come soon. I long to see you again My heart &amp;
                    thoughts are Ever with you. I will now send you a Goodnight kiss &amp; write
                    to my dear Ma Write to me by Tuesday's mail, &amp; say you love me only
                    Rennie &amp; Ada send love. I send love, &amp; many kisses Write soon.
                    May God bless you for you are so dear to me. Goodnight. Love me. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours devotedly</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
