<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7541"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7541">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    December 5, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 5 1867</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7541</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502583</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, December 5, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, december 5 1867</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, December 5, 1867, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-12-05">1867-12-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-30">December 30, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7541T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert describes the grief which she still feels over the death of her brother
                    and reports on preparations for the upcoming wedding of her sister.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-12-05">December 5 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt Solon</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Mr. D.H. Evans</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your dear &amp; welcome letter of the 3 came <orig reg="duly">duely</orig> to
                    one who was looking anxiously for it. I was so thankful to hear that you were
                    well. God is merciful to us in all things. I wish you were here <orig
                        reg="tonight">to night</orig> Oh the time does seem so long since I saw you
                    last, &amp; I must wait until next Tuesday before you can come again Well if
                    God only lets you come Then I shall be both happy &amp; thankful, but the
                    time will be long &amp; slow in passing I shall be very busy until then.
                    Cousin David don't like to hear of us all leaving Bridgewater Wednesday night
                    but he must submit for it cannot be helped I hope we shall all have a pleasant
                    &amp; happy time <abbr expan="though">tho'</abbr> to us it will be mingled
                    with sadness for thoughts of one who will not be with us to see his sister given
                    to him she loves best on Earth. My darling lost brother will not be with us then
                    &amp; Oh how deeply &amp; sorrowfully I shall miss<pb n="2"/>his dear
                    handsome face bright with happiness as in the days of his sunny childhood when
                    he completed the joys of home. I have been thinking so much of John &amp;
                    longing for his presence that my heart, soul, &amp; mind are all sad dulled
                    to such a degree that nothing seems to cheer them. The aching void his early
                    &amp; cruel death has made in my heart is never soothed, or filled only when
                    I am with you then I feel entirely happy &amp; that I do not want <orig
                        reg="anything">any thing</orig>, or <orig reg="anyone">any one</orig> in the
                    world but you. before I loved you the void in heart &amp; soul had never
                    been filled or made happy, &amp; contented this is the only &amp; sure
                    fact that I never truly loved any but you. if I still longed for the love
                    &amp; to love another I would then know that I did not love you but I am
                    satisfied, happy cheerful &amp; thankful to love you &amp; to know you
                    love me is the greatest joy of my life. I ask for no other <orig reg="than"
                    >then</orig> to be near you always, &amp; for you to be a true <hi
                        rend="underline">christian</hi>. if these blessings were<pb n="3"/>mine I
                    would indeed feel that God in His divine love had filled my cup of Earthly bliss
                    My life &amp; the lives of those most dear to me should be the burden of my
                    daily prayers that they might be spent in serving God. God knows how truly how
                    faithfully, &amp; devotedly I love you I believe it is His holy will that we
                    should love each other. Do not think any more of what Magnus said about my
                    letter I did not mind it. I knew he was only teasing me. You have a right to do
                    as you please with my letters for they are yours, &amp; I know no one ever
                    reads them but <orig reg="yourself">your self</orig>. They are written to you
                    &amp; for you only. If Magnus had read it I would not have cared, or been
                    angry with you. We have been very busy all week finishing <orig
                        reg="preparations">preperations</orig> for Rennie's Wedding have scarcely
                    time to think I take time to love, &amp; think of you. if I did not know you
                    would be here I should not be so zealous &amp; sure of being happy. You will
                    find quite a crowd Ma has invited near 50 persons<pb n="4"/>I would have
                    prefered only a chosen few of valued friends. Ma is generous &amp; wants all
                    to come Mr Estell called again yesterday evening, sent word before he came that
                    he was coming to see <hi rend="underline">Lula</hi> tell Ella this she will
                    laugh. I did not see the gentleman, being busy all the time he <orig
                        reg="annoys">annoyes</orig> me so much that I never care to see him any
                    time, busy or not.</p>

                <p>Rennie is just as happy as she can be until she is the wedded wife of her dear
                    David My Earnest prayer is that they may be truly happy in their married life.
                    it will be sad to see her leave our home circle to return no more, but then she
                    will we all know be far happier with the one she loves best it is natural that
                    she should. May God bless Them is a sister's prayer.</p>

                <p>Yes indeed I like the arrangement you, &amp; Magnus have made about the style
                    you come in from Staunton. I hope the weather will be fine. I long so much for
                    you to come for it is such a dreary while since I saw your dear dear face. Oh I
                    do love you with all my heart &amp; mind I hope we shall soon see each other
                    &amp; then I can tell you more <orig reg="than">then</orig> my pen could
                    write-- &amp; it is a mean pen too, <abbr expan="although">altho'</abbr> a
                    new one A few more days then I shall see you who I love so fondly, &amp;
                    more <orig reg="than">then</orig> all the world. May God bless you, &amp;
                    grant that you may come Tuesday. Goodnight. I send <hi rend="underline"
                    >love</hi> &amp; a kiss to you. Ma, Rennie, Ada, &amp; all send love
                    Take care of your dear self. <hi rend="underline">I</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">lov</hi>e <hi rend="underline">you</hi>. Goodnight</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
