<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7546"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7546">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    January 24, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, january 24 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7546</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502588</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, January 24, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, january 24 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, January 24, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-01-24">1868-01-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-12-30">December 30, 2004.</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; changes made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7546T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert reports on her recent travels and expounds on the joys of domestic
                life.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-01-24">Jan 24, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt Solon Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Had <abbr expan="General">Gen'l</abbr> Imboden's dispatch come one day sooner I
                    should have sent this answer to your dear letter of Tuesday by papa <orig
                        reg="today">to day</orig>. but we were so hurried getting him ready that I
                    did not have time to write you Even a line. I did wish that I could have gone
                    with him I am so glad you are coming Saturday it seems like months since you
                    were here last &amp; I do want to see you so much. Brother David Sibert was
                    up yesterday Eat dinner with us, asked about you. said Rennie was well,
                    &amp; happy, &amp; that they missed us very much &amp; we should
                    come to see them soon Ada is going down to stay a few weeks in my place. if she
                    lives she will go the last of this, or the first of next week. Pa &amp; I
                    spent the day Monday at Mr. Ferror's. it was very difficult for me to get away
                    from them all they insisted upon my staying a few weeks Mrs. Cosby was there
                    from Richmond. M<del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Dunlap also. They left the next day for their
                    homes. Regina &amp; Billie were left lonely in<del rend="none" hand="h1"/> I promised to
                    go down next week if I live &amp; s<del rend="none" hand="h1"/><pb n="2"/>a week with
                    them. but as Ada is going to Bridgewater I may not get to go. Samie said "it was
                    very strange that I could stay in Staunton 6, &amp; 7 months, &amp;
                    could not stay a few weeks with them." Pa &amp; I had a very nice visit they
                    are so kind, &amp; attentive. Mrs. Dunlap told pa whilst Samie was filling
                    pa's pockets full of apples that Samie had an interest in his Steel pa laughed.
                    they seem so glad to hear of pa's success. We are lonely now since papa is gone.
                    I wish you were here then I should be happy &amp; satisfied. I do miss you
                    coming of Evenings it seems that I cannot let the day go by without seeing your
                    dear, &amp; welcome face. I miss you more then you could possibly miss me. I
                    do not think that you don't miss me any I know you do or you would not say you
                    did but I just feel like I miss, &amp; need your society more then you do
                    mine it is woman's nature the world over to want to be with those they love all
                    the time. we are selfish in that respect I know I am. It pleases me to have you
                    say you love home pleasures for they are indeed The sweetest of all Earthly joys
                    not many are thankful enough for such happiness &amp; would rather be any
                    where else<pb n="3"/><orig reg="than">then</orig> at home. I know you would be
                    both thankful &amp; happy &amp; prefer your fireside &amp; the
                    society of an intelligent, &amp; loving wife <del hand="h1">wife</del> to
                    all other enjoyments. you would not spend your Evenings any where but at home,
                    reading while your wife sewed &amp; if tired listening while she read to
                    you, with your <hi rend="underline">eyes</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">shut</hi> you would forget all the busy outside world,
                    thanking God for the great blessing he had given you. Hamie came in asked me if
                    I was writing to you I told him yes, sends his love to you &amp; wants to
                    know "if you ever miss him." I can scarcely <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to come I want to
                    see you Oh so much, for I love to be with you more <orig reg="than">then</orig>
                    all others in the world I love you only, truly, &amp; devotedly as I never
                    loved mortal being in my life, &amp; my greatest, &amp; sweetest
                    pleasure is to be with you. Come then Saturday my pen &amp; heart say come.
                    I hope God will let you come, &amp; give you a warm &amp; pleasant
                    Evening for I do want to see your dear face more <orig reg="than">then</orig> I
                    can write in words. I think of you all the day long &amp; wish I could see
                    you. Come Saturday if you live &amp; you will meet a glad heart &amp;
                    happy face a b<hi rend="underline">ri</hi>ght f<hi rend="underline">ir</hi>e
                        &amp;<pb n="4"/>warm supper all for you. tell Magnus to come with you. I
                    wish the day was here I am impatient for you to come I have many things to tell
                    you as usual. I will not talk all but will let you say something now &amp;
                    then if you promise not to talk too much like you always do when we are
                    together.</p>

                <p>Ma &amp; all send love. I send love &amp; a warm loving <hi
                        rend="underline">kis</hi>s to you I love you with all my heart, nature,
                    &amp; thoughts. God bless you &amp; send you Saturday to gladden the
                    heart of one who thinks only of you. Goodnight Love me. Come Saturday.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Excuse this writing I've written in haste</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
