<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7557"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7557">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans,
                    April 2, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, april 2 1868</title>
        <author>Sibert, Mary Anna</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Witmer</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7557</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502599</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Mary Anna Sibert to David H. Evans, April 2, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county mary anna sibert to david h evans, april 2 1868</title>
            <author>Mary Anna Sibert</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mary Anna Sibert to David H.
                            Evans, April 2, 1868, Evans-Sibert Family Papers, Accession 27770,
                            Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Virginia State Library and Archives, Richmond, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-04-02">1868-04-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7557T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sibert expresses her relief that Evans is not angry, but notes the "short and
                    cold" tone of his recent letters. She expresses her disappointment at his
                    failure to visit last weekend, and asks him what is troubling their
                    relationship. She goes on to give him family news and reaffirm her love for
                him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>Mr. David H. Evans<lb/>Staunton<lb/>Virginia<lb/>
                    Had this letter written when Magnus came. Will send it by him. Hope you can come
                        Saturday<lb/><hi rend="underline">Mollie</hi>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-04-02">April 2, 1868</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt Solon Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear David</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I hope this will reach you <orig reg="tomorrow">to morrow</orig> &amp; save
                    me the anxiety of mind which occured last week. Your dear letter of Tuesday gave
                    me so much relief to hear you were not angry with me.</p>

                <p>I felt like a new being after reading it. I very willingly Excused its shortness
                    as I know you had but little time to write an answer but it seems to me that
                    your last three letters have all been short, &amp; <hi rend="underline"
                    >cold</hi>. I am not mistaken in this. there is something between our happiness.
                    what is it? I know of nothing that I have done. if I have it was an Error of the
                    head, &amp; not of the heart. Do you Ever see any change in my letters to
                    you? are they not always long, &amp; affectionate? there again I am ready to
                    forgive for I know that I have more time to write &amp; when I am writing I
                    am not so often interrupted as you are by persons. I will think &amp; say no
                    more about it, my love I know you can't help it &amp; in return I now ask
                    you to forgive me for complaining. Your letters are Ever<pb n="2"/>dear
                    &amp; welcome, &amp; if they are brief I must be satisfied for they are
                    from the one I love best. I did wish for you this morning Jennie Douglass
                    &amp; I took a long walk before breakfast, &amp; wanted you so much to
                    be with me. then I should have been very happy &amp; enjoyed the lovely
                    Spring morning, the pure &amp; refreshing air, &amp; songs of birds so
                    much more with you who I love <orig reg="than">then</orig> with all others.
                    Jennie asked about you she said she loved to see us with each other for she knew
                    that we were then very happy. I told her yes I was happy always with you. Ma
                    just came in with a letter from dear pa &amp; one from Ada which came a few
                    moments ago by the Harrisonburg mail. pa was in Washington City when he wrote.
                    left the same day for Baltimore. had gone to Washington to close up his business
                    at the Patent Office Gen'l. Imboden, Gen'l. Barton, Mr. Gordon &amp; Mr.
                    Brady were with him there. Ada is having a nice time she wants to stay during
                    the Summer in Orange she &amp; cousin Fronie have a trip to Washington City
                    in view before she returns <pb n="3"/>home. she writes that she has one of the
                    handsomest beaus we ever saw. This is just like Ada. I did not Expect to hear
                    any thing else then that she had a nice, &amp; handsome beau. I thank God
                    for His goodness in taking care of my noble &amp; beloved papa, &amp;
                    May God let him come home to us again for we are very lonely without his dear,
                    &amp; joyous society. he may come the last of next week if he does not go to
                    New York. I will send his letter, &amp; Magnus will read it to you. I do
                    hope you will come Saturday if you live, for I do want to see you so badly. I
                    can say now that it has been long since I saw your dear face. come. <hi
                        rend="underline">I am</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">at</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">home</hi>. I did not know whether I should be angry with
                    you or not for not coming because you thought I was absent. if I had been going
                    away I should have written to you before I went, &amp; if I had been called
                    unexpectedly from home you should have known it. I wrote to you how greatly I
                    was disappointed by you not coming I have not gotten over it yet nor will I
                    until you really come. last Sabbath was a long sad day to me without you <pb
                        n="4"/> If I had been a bird I should have winged my way to Staunton,
                    &amp; saw you &amp; then I would have only let you touch the tip end of
                    one of my wings for treating me so badly, &amp; after seeing that you
                    &amp; Ella's family were well I would fly home, but not until I told you
                    that I loved you &amp; how sadly you had disappointed me. then I would kiss
                    my hand at you, &amp; fly away, or perhaps I would have kissed your own dear
                    hand if you would let me get that near you. I love you with the same unchanging
                    devotion of heart. I cannot write, or tell the depth, &amp; fervency of my
                    love for you. All the world cannot take it from you. Come Saturday if you live I
                    am so anxious to see you again I will be so glad &amp; thankful to have you
                    with me. I will love you &amp; do all I can for your happiness &amp;
                    comfort. Do come. Hamie left Jim in B. I thought I could have the pleasure of
                    sending for you &amp; Magnus but was disappointed there again. I have so
                    much to tell you. This is a long letter for your two short pages. I love you,
                    &amp; love to write to you I will have a warm supper ready for you &amp;
                    a bright fire <hi rend="underline">if</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">it</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">is</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">col</hi>d to warm &amp; cheer you up, &amp; my
                    heart full of love &amp; thankfulness all for you. Ma &amp; all send
                    love to you I send a loving kiss, &amp; all the love of my heart &amp;
                    nature. I must write to dear Ella come to the one who loves you best of all
                    others May God bless you &amp; let you come. Goodby until we meet Saturday.
                    I love you only now &amp; ever <hi rend="underline">come</hi></p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours</salute>
                    <signed>Mollie Sibert</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
