<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7604"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7604">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, September 2, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, september 2 1863</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7604</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502605</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, September 2, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, september 2 1863</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, September 2, 1863, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-02">1863-09-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Camp Life, Family, Home Front,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, Slavery, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7604T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes his wife to report on his efforts to purchase a house or
                    property in Staunton. He gives her instructions on preparing to move the family
                    to Staunton, including items to pack and tasks to accomplish on the farm. He
                    lists prices of many goods in town. He also discusses the possible purchase of a
                    lucrative hotel now being used as a hospital.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-02"><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 2/63</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I avail myself of another opportunity to write you I am still stationed here in
                    this place <del hand="h1">&amp;</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">as</add> commandant of the post I am very
                    comfortably fixed here but <orig reg="can't">
                        <hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">cant</hi>
                        </hi>
                    </orig> say that I like the place. <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> James S
                    Brown is here with me here &amp; I <del hand="h1">s</del>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; myself keep house we have Louise, Henry &amp;
                    Jenny keeping house for us and do quite well &amp; if you &amp; the
                    children were only here I would be fixed I am trying daily to get a house even
                    in the country but <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">t</hi></orig> as yet
                    get one The one we have is one the Doctor had &amp; is quite small &amp;
                    could not be gotten for us</p>

                <p>I hope to succeed in getting a house soon. I heard of a house in <abbr
                        expan="Waynesboro">Waynsboro</abbr> 12 miles off &amp; rode there on
                    Sunday but it had been sold to Smith &amp; <unclear>Dallinger</unclear>. I
                    rode out 7 miles yesterday to see a property but could not get it. I have joined
                    a gentleman here in the purchase of a large Hotel property here at thirty
                    thousand Dollars $30,000<hi rend="super">00</hi> Said to be one of the finest
                    stands in the Valley it is a large building &amp; is at the Rail Road all
                    say it is quite cheap It is now occupied as Hospital at a rent of $3600<hi
                        rend="super">00</hi>
                    <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> year &amp; <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be got
                    now. If it was furnished &amp; conducted now as Hotel would make I think
                        $100,000<hi rend="super">00</hi>
                    <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> year Hotels here charge $8 <abbr expan="per"
                    >pr</abbr> day &amp; but little to eat There is no chance now to get a
                    portion of it to occupy. You pave the way to move out when I can get a place See
                    if you will be allowed to bring out all your things &amp; Then put up all
                    the fruit you can if you have to get <unclear>packin-</unclear> to put it in<pb
                        n="2"/> &amp; make full preperations with everything needed for a long
                    time so that if can move out that you will be prepared Get your self &amp;
                        <orig reg="children">childred</orig> plenty of clothing &amp; material
                    &amp; get several pairs of shoes each some too large &amp; get Freddy
                    plenty shoes &amp; boots get some of M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Snyders
                    &amp; some at James Hills or elsewhere so that persons will not know your
                    preparations. if you get some coarse goods &amp; shoes for the blacks make
                    these arrangements &amp; perhaps by this time the Valley will be open
                    &amp; there will be no difficulty in getting out &amp; if should not get
                    out of course the preparation would not be amiss have the hogs fattened as I
                    directed &amp; if <add hand="h1" place="inline">you</add> should come out
                    have Henry S. to Kill &amp; put up plenty of Pork for us this fall Save all
                    your bacon &amp; lard Bacon here 150c beef $1. butter 175 a $2. lard 150 a
                        $2<hi rend="super">00</hi> Boots $40 to $60 Shoes $20 to $40<hi rend="super"
                        >00</hi> they are not scarce but every person seems to be
                    <unclear>--ing</unclear> Make every arrangement necessary to come out &amp;
                    live on what you bring except bread meat &amp; butter &amp;c-- Teams
                    would have to be gotten there to come say to woodstock &amp; there reload an
                    other teams Billy &amp; James <unclear>Chennowith</unclear> &amp;
                    Kneadler I think would come &amp; John with carriage with you Moses might
                    have wheel fix<hi rend="super">ed</hi> on our carriage perhaps he would come out
                    there with you. Thomas or Staub must furnish <add hand="h1" place="inline">you
                        with</add> funds funds I have learned that H Thomas was sent off &amp;
                    imprisoned but <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">t</hi></orig> learn if
                    correct if so I feel concerned about the mill property</p>

                <p>Try &amp; write me &amp; let me know how things are and if you <pb n="3"
                    />will be allowed to move out, if come, bring Jane or Mary C. along <del
                        hand="h1"/> M<hi rend="super">rs</hi> Schoppert is living here in
                        <unclear>--ns</unclear> &amp; well she is exceedingly anxious for you to
                    come here, and if can get a house to suit will try &amp; all get together it
                    would be best to bring say 2 cows &amp; it will be necessary to put some
                    careful person in our house also the house Moody lives in I suppose he will not
                    keep house longer Aug &amp; Peggy would move in the home property. If I can
                    I will get a house already furnished in that event our furniture need not be
                        <orig reg="brought">brough</orig> except bedding if this can be done you
                    could buy a team &amp; get your uncle James G.'s large wagon he said he
                    would sell it to me when I was there. In fact One team, One carriage &amp;
                    horses might all be <orig reg="bought">bough</orig> as there would be nothing
                    lost in such a purchase as they could be sold here readily at an advance on cost
                    I <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">t</hi></orig> find a farm here yet for
                    sale</p>

                <p>In short arrange all your matters &amp; have them in train to move out here
                    so that when it suits all will be ready to move out with plenty of every thing
                    you <unclear>need</unclear> but <orig reg="don't">don<hi rend="super"
                    >t</hi></orig> move without communicating to me first Unless you mistreated
                    &amp; have a very unpleasant time there in that event pull up stakes
                    &amp; move on out &amp; notify me as soon as can I wrote several letters
                    to you lately &amp; no reply try &amp; give me word Send a letter to
                    John or some one for me You need not sign your <unclear>name</unclear> for fear
                    it might be intercepted I will know who it is from O Some one can certainly send
                    me a letter<pb n="4"/> say how the mill is, how the children get along how you
                    are all provided for whether interfered with in any way or not I don<hi
                        rend="super">t</hi> ask any information as to the troops &amp;c remember
                    me kindly to the children tell them to be obedient &amp; good also to all
                    enquiring friend say how you get along for help God bless you all</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed>John Nadenbousch</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
