<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7608"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7608">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, September 22, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, september 22 1863</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7608</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502609</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, September 22, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, september 22 1863</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, September 22, 1863, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-22">1863-09-22</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7608T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes to his wife to report that he has rented a house and inquires
                    about preparation for moving the family to Staunton. He expresses the desire to
                    get out of the service, and laments how much domestic life the war has caused
                    him to miss. He sends messages to his children, especially his son Freddy who
                    has reportedly been "running about" and acquiring "bad habits."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-22"><abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> 22<hi
                                rend="super">nd</hi> 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I avail myself of a few moments to write you. I am still here and well, and doing
                    as well as can be expected I have rented a house in the country some few miles
                    in case you can get to move out, but think it best not to come without your
                    household effects, as such here would be hard to get, and could not live without
                    them. <del hand="h1">and</del> the rent will not be much &amp; I had better
                    pay the rent than to miss having a place in case should need it. I wrote you
                    several times to try &amp; see if you could be allowed to move your things
                    out here &amp; if could get teams to move say to Woodstock &amp; I would
                    meet you there with teams to bring you on up &amp;c. have you learned this
                    if so why not send me word what the result is if you Can<hi rend="super">t</hi>
                    write get some one else to write me, Henry, Moses John or Jimmy C. or someone I
                    am anxious to know what to count on If you will not be allowed to bring your
                    things, unless Molested or interfered with or uncomfortable or unpleasantly
                    situated there, I rather think best to remain there for the present but if not
                    Comfortable &amp; pleasant there Move to the country or Come on up here
                        with<pb n="2"/> what you will be allowed to bring. I still think I will be
                    able to get out of the service soon and can be with you <orig reg="altogether"
                        >alltogether</orig> but how soon I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> say. this
                    is uncertain. I have made every effort I can now with propriety, and must hold
                    still for at least a short time, before making another effort. I assure you I am
                    quite anxious to be with you continually. it seems that this war has cut me out
                    of 2 <hi rend="super">1/2</hi> years of my life. My daily thoughts are about you
                    and the children but I learned that you were getting along well &amp; not
                    interfered with but I have not received a letter from you detailing all the
                    little ups &amp; downs &amp; private domestic matters that I feel<del
                        hand="h1">ed</del> concerned about but I hope you are all getting along in
                    every sense of the word well. I had some intimation that Freddy was running
                    about without any constraint &amp; getting in bad habits. do try and prevent
                    this. try &amp; keep him about home or at school &amp; do keep him from
                    being knocked about &amp; getting into bad habits &amp; read to him the
                    following &amp; the other children also. Freddy I learn that you are running
                    about &amp; getting into bad habits. Now do prevent this do you stay about
                    home keep out of bad company do not run with those bad boys. such conduct leads
                    boys to ruin. attend school try &amp; learn all you can &amp; make a
                    smart man of yourself. look after the wants of your Ma - &amp; sisters do
                    all you can to make them comfortable<pb n="3"/> &amp; happy. remember they
                    have no help now there but you. try &amp; conduct yourself like a little man
                    do what is right to all &amp; keep away from the evil ones be kind to all
                    And then every one will like &amp; praise you. Now do this &amp; see
                    after all you can for the family You attend to things as I usually did &amp;
                    dont run about the streets with the bad boys take good care of your little
                    sisters &amp; treat them kindly. I hope to be home soon &amp; will be
                    glad to hear that you conduct &amp; <orig reg="behavior">behavour</orig> has
                    been good <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> you write me a letter you ought to write letters by this time
                    tell me of the Cow the dog the fruit hogs &amp; wood &amp;c&amp;c-</p>

                <p>Hester try &amp; let me know how you are being provide for wood &amp;c
                    &amp;c. - And what prospect for winter meat &amp;c <orig reg="Can't"
                        >Cant</orig> Mary write or Miss Jane might if you cant &amp; send to
                    Winchester to Harrison Bowers or M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Arnold</p>

                <p>I have nothing new to write you I would like to have a pair of soft shoes- say
                    Congress Gators <abbr expan="number">No.</abbr> 7, such as I used to have Shoe
                    the family well Get Moses to send you 1 <add hand="h1" place="inline">or 2</add>
                    calf skin <del hand="h1">or</del> 1 side <unclear>hip</unclear> &amp; 1 side
                    sole leather and keep it in the house if you should move so to bring it along
                    try &amp; get me word that I will know what to rely upon if you <orig
                        reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> come then I will stop thinking about it little girls do you be
                    kind to each other be obedient<pb n="4"/> to your Ma &amp; be good girls
                    Make Freddy be a good boy give My love to Mary A- <unclear>--y</unclear>
                    &amp; lucy- also cousin <unclear>Lute</unclear> &amp; Aunt Peggy</p>

                <p>Tell Cousin Mary the Confederacy is all right yet</p>

                <p>No More but remain</p>



                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John Quincy Adams">JQA</abbr> Nadenbousch</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
