<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7610"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7610">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Frederick Nadenbousch, October 27, 1863</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to frederick nadenbousch, october 27 1863</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7610</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502611</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Frederick
                            Nadenbousch, October 27, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to frederick nadenbousch, october 27 1863</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Frederick Nadenbousch, October 27, 1863, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-10-27">1863-10-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Agriculture, Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7610T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes to his son Frederick and praises him for going to school. He
                    says he has heard of his "wild and unruly behavior," however, and lectures him
                    on the importance of being a good boy. He gives him instructions for the care of
                    animals on the farm and procuring boots for the family. Nadenbousch also
                    describes life in Staunton, discusses his purchase of a hotel there, talks of
                    his desire to leave the army and see his family, and writes about friends and
                    relatives.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Frederick</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-10-27"><abbr expan="October">Oct</abbr> 27/63</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear boy</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I concluded to write you a short letter &amp; I hope you can read it I hear
                    that you are all well and getting along quite <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >well</add> of which I am quite glad I learned also that <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">you</add> were going to School at a School kept in our
                    Schoolroom I hope you are learning fast and are a good boy I have been told that
                    you were quite wild and somewhat unruly.</p>

                <p>Now my boy this will not do. I want you to learn fast and grow up to be a smart
                    &amp; good man and the only way for you to do <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >it</add> is to apply yourself to your studies. be attentive to school and
                    obedient to your teacher. <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> run about the streets at
                    anytime with bad boys. keep out of all bad company keep close about home and
                    take care of your Ma - and little sisters You must remember that you are the
                    only man person left there to care for them, and to look after things, and you
                    should behave right and act like a little man (now listen at what I have said
                    &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> let me have to scold or correct you when
                    I come home for your bad conduct<pb n="2"/> two doctors, captain Brown and
                    myself are now keeping <orig reg="bachelors">batchlers</orig> hall here. we have
                    a fine time of it, we have <orig reg="two">too</orig> violins the doctors play
                    at night but otherwise it is quite lonesome I would like very much to have you
                    all here with me. a friend &amp; me have bought a large Hotel here. we are
                    going to carry it on, as soon as we can get it started it is close to the <orig
                        reg="railroad">Rail Road</orig> I learn that your cow has a fine calf, and I
                    suppose you have plenty of nice Milk now take good care of the cow, have plenty
                    of feed gotten for her, get M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Staub to sell you some bran
                    &amp; shorts for to make slop for her Louise, Henry, &amp; Jerry are
                    here with me they are well Louise is almost crazy to see you all I seen Jack and
                    his family not long ago they are all well Henry is grown to be a smart boy
                    &amp; John is as fat as a <orig reg="possum">possom</orig> they live at a
                    good place 25 miles from here</p>

                <p>Major Robinson died yesterday morning 26<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
                    </hi> just of <orig reg="Pneumonia">Phneumonia</orig> he was sick some time tell
                    his family M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Jacob Thomas &amp; Miss Jennie Robinson
                    went to Richmond this morning to his funeral He will be buried there to be
                    removed hereafter. I regret &amp; mourn his loss, but we must all die sooner
                    or later and should so<pb n="3"/> live that <del hand="h1">me</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">we</add> may die happy. I still have the large <hi
                        rend="underline">Sorral horse</hi>, Uncle Johns <hi rend="underline">bay</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">Selah</hi> &amp; an other bay here I dont ride much
                    now. I am mostly in the house and have a comfortable place but would like to get
                    out of service entirely that I could go where I please &amp; when I please
                    and think I will leave entirely before a great while I have nothing of much
                    interest to write you now I would like to hear much more from home than I <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">do</add> I am always glad to hear from you all and
                    get the particulars as to how you get along</p>

                <p>Get Ma to have you 2 pair good boots made and get the other children several pair
                    each have them all large and lay them away for an other time get plenty of good
                    &amp; nice clothing have Some made up all of you get plenty of things if can
                    try and live comfortable have plenty of coal &amp; wood put away to last all
                    winter have the wood cut &amp; put in cellar lay in some apples &amp;c</p>

                <p>Give my love to the family &amp; kiss miss Jane tell her their friends here
                    are all well her sister is nearly crazy to see her she says.</p>

                <p>They talk of moving to Richmond sometime soon remember me kindly to all friends
                    give my love to Aunt Peggy &amp; cousin Lute &amp; the little girls
                        and<pb n="4"/> also to Aunt Bettsy &amp; Uncle <hi rend="underline"
                    >Jim</hi> And tell Cousin Mary I got her letter &amp; was glad to hear from
                    her and am much indebted to her for her kindness in my behalf I answered her
                    letter I hope she received it.</p>

                <p>tell her to look out for the widower.</p>

                <p>I hope soon to get home and see you all. I want to see you worse this time than I
                    ever did during the war</p>

                <p>Now <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> you write me a little letter &amp; tell me how you all are
                    and are getting along. get Ma- or Miss Jane to show you how</p>

                <p>Send Grand Ma and <add hand="h1" place="inline">all</add> the folks word that I
                    am well Give my respects to M<hi rend="super">r</hi> Staub &amp; all others
                    No more but</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>remain your affection father</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John Quincy Adams">J Q A</abbr> Nadenbousch</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Tell them all to write me put nothing in about the troops
                        or the army</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
