<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7613"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7613">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Mr. Nobody to Hester J. Nadenbousch,
                    January 2, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county mr nobody to hester j nadenbousch, january 2 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7613</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502614</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, January 2, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, january 2 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Mr. Nobody to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, January 2, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters, Eleanor S.
                            Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond,
                        Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-02">1864-01-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7613T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes as "Mr. Nobody" to his wife. He gives her instructions to
                    follow if she decides to move the family to Staunton, including a list of items
                    he needs. He describes the hotel he has purchased and his plans for opening. He
                    complains that she does not write often enough, and expresses the desire to
                    leave the service.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-02"><orig reg="January">Jan</orig> 2<hi rend="super">
                                <hi rend="underline">nd</hi>
                            </hi> 1864</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>I have another <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> and will write you but
                    I write so often that I scarcely know what to write you now but will write
                    something every chance I have</p>

                <p>I am quite well; &amp; we have not gotten the Hotel started yet but are
                    fixing up rapidly. we have all the servants &amp; hand<hi rend="super"
                    >s</hi> hired &amp; suppose they will all be on Monday, we will open about
                        10<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
                    </hi> or 12<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
                    </hi> of the month. I received the 2 papers sent me by some one of your town
                    &amp; seen the <orig reg="President's">Presidents</orig> Proclamations
                    marked &amp;c &amp;c. I regret to learn the children have the whooping
                    cough &amp; hope they will soon be well. you might get out now if they were
                    well. I have written to you so much about coming out that I hardly know what to
                    say more</p>

                <p>But let your understanding be this If you think it adviseable to move out,
                    &amp; can make the arrangements to suit come on at any time you can. that is
                    to come right &amp; comfortable and at any time you can before you move send
                    out anything you can that we may want here. James Thomas might take some things
                    to his house anything you may have bought &amp; want out get him to call
                    &amp; see you</p>

                <p>We want some cups &amp; saucers yet &amp; cream jugs - white stone ware.
                    I think we have most every thing else to start with. we will still want some
                    sheets, <orig reg="pillow">pillar</orig> slips comforts &amp; <orig
                        reg="towels">Towls</orig> and a few small spoons. I think we have enough of
                    large spoons. in fact we can use anything in the way of house fixtures and
                    anything you may have send<pb n="2"/> on, we can use it. We want Axes, butcher
                    knives &amp; some knives &amp; forks but can start with what we have of
                    them</p>

                <p>We will want any quantity of groceries &amp; spices we can get, Candle Moles
                    &amp; Wicks, every thing here is scarce We have plenty furniture &amp;
                        <orig reg="mattresses">Mattrasses</orig> plates &amp;c but as to other
                    fixtures you can judge what we will need. we will do with as few as can but if
                    have a surplus can dispose of them to advantage here</p>

                <p>So at anytime you can get important articles in this way you get them. Collect
                    all the money you can. I wrote you where to get fund<hi rend="super">s</hi>,
                    which get when needed See Moses as I wrote him and you he can assist you</p>

                <p>I forgot to give you an idea of our house it is quite a large building built of
                    brick of an L form 5 stories high has some 75 rooms &amp; the finest dining
                    room I know of close to the <orig reg="railroad">rail Road</orig> but have but 3
                    trains a day here fine large stabling &amp; out buildings every person is
                    wanting the house open. I do wish you <add hand="h1" place="inline">&amp;
                        the children</add> were here with me it would be so much pleasanter than
                    this way I think I could sell out now at $75000<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> seventy five thousand making 150,000<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> fixtures &amp; all</p>

                <p>If you <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> get out <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                    >soon</add> I will try &amp; work along until you can come. you have never
                    wrote me as to how you were whether <orig reg="alright">allright</orig> or not
                    why <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> you write me about our private matters I am so
                    anxious to hear from you and write so often &amp; you never write me <orig
                        reg="at">al</orig> all Sometimes I think you want to take these friend<hi
                        rend="super">s</hi> advice to you last<pb n="3"/> summer to save the
                    property <unclear>Deoxxxx</unclear> but I hope you will not be that cruel (but
                    enough of this write me soon and say how you are &amp;c &amp;c &amp;
                    how the little ones all are &amp; all about our private matters &amp;c
                    &amp;c-</p>

                <p>I want to get 2 lace stockings for my leg &amp; will enclose a measure of the
                    size &amp;c now who is the best person to get them for me Mary Kelley could
                    get them but would prefer getting some person else. Could not C M Shaffer be got
                    to get them you see him &amp; get him to get them for me They are knit out
                    of silk <unclear>gum</unclear> thread covered with silk &amp; knit close
                    like a stocking and to come up <add hand="h1" place="inline">well</add> to the
                    thigh I <orig reg="want">wan</orig> two so I can have a change I did get two in
                    Richmond but the gum was so old that it broke &amp; one is now almost worn
                    out And if could get two good ones they would last at least one year &amp;
                    be a great comfort to me See Henry he no doubt could get them readily &amp;
                    will do it</p>

                <p>I learn the mill is taken possession of I do not know whether at a rent or not
                    but <orig reg="can't">can<hi rend="super">t</hi></orig> you in some way get a
                    rent for it: get Henry to do the best he can in the premises</p>

                <p>John I suppose is scared to death again he seems to be uneasy about the land
                    &amp; what I owe him. I think he would like to have a deed trust on it which
                    might save the property some &amp;c You think over the matter and write me
                    what is best to do and in the meantime say to John he need not fear about what I
                    may owe him he will not lose it I<pb n="4"/> think I have plenty here to pay him
                    if all else is lost but will be glad to secure him if can do it right tell him I
                    will write him &amp; see what can be done in the matter</p>

                <p>Kiss the children for me and remember me kindly to all friend<hi rend="super"
                    >s</hi></p>

                <p>By the way remember me to M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> Baker &amp; tell her I would be glad to see her</p>

                <p>My love to miss Jane if you come out bring her along Schoppert &amp; family
                    are well</p>

                <p>Tell Miss Jane to write to me if you <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> &amp; to
                    write if you do</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>As ever yours</salute>
                    <signed>M<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">r</hi>
                        </hi> Nobody</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I enclose a pattern of the size of lace stocking before
                        it is put on leg: a shade smaller or larger will make no difference <add
                            hand="h1" place="inline">rather smaller than larger</add>. they are
                        gumalastic &amp; will stretch Let them be about the general size of this
                        pattern length &amp;c- if not so long no matter. I want two, 2, of same
                        size in fact would not object to having 4. I find my other leg is getting
                        somewhat the same way but quite slight yet This makes me feel like quitting
                        service entirely &amp; coming home &amp; try to take care of myself
                        Get Henry, Moses, or C M Shaffer to get them, or Mary H could get them but
                        prefer a man getting them Shaffer would be the best person if think it
                        prudent to ask him do so Or W<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">m</hi>
                        </hi> Riddle could get Dorsey to get them you know how all act toward my
                        interest you can tell best who to select They will cost I suppose about $15
                        to $20 apiece. If you have not the money to spare ask Moses to loan it to me
                        I am quite tired of this life &amp; sometimes almost
                        determin<unclear>d</unclear> to quit pointedly &amp; work my way
                        homeward. I am not fit to be in service &amp; if would not be asked to
                        take an oath I might quit &amp; come home Most anytime What do you think
                        of it (say)</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
