<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A7637"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A7637">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                    Hester J. Nadenbousch, November 11, 1864</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, november 11 1864</title>
        <author>Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andre Fleche</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A7637</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502638</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to Hester J.
                            Nadenbousch, November 11, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john quincy adams nadenbousch to hester j nadenbousch, november 11 1864</title>
            <author>John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John Quincy Adams Nadenbousch to
                            Hester J. Nadenbousch, November 11, 1864, J.Q.A. Nadenbousch Letters,
                            Eleanor S. Brockenbrough Library, The Museum of the Confederacy,
                            Richmond, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-11-11">1864-11-11</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-06">June, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A7637T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Nadenbousch writes his wife to say that he and Freddy are doing well but lonely,
                    and hopes the family can soon be together. He discusses business in Staunton,
                    including prices of various supplies. He praises his wife for the job she has
                    done managing things at home, including tasks to which she was unaccustomed. He
                    comments on Lincoln's reelection and hopes it may bring peace soon. He sends
                    instructions to his wife on preparing for winter, and dealing with individuals
                    with whom he has outstanding business.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-11-11"><abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 11/64</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>As there may be an <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> for to get a letter
                    to you &amp; I may not have a chance to get home or may not know when the
                    way is open in time I write in the event that I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    get home at the same time, but hope the way may be open long enough for me to
                    get home this fall</p>

                <p>Freddy &amp; I have both been well, we are living here quite comfortable but
                    quite lonely, though it is very different from being entirely alone as formerly.
                    Freddy goes to school and is doing well he writes to little Mary &amp; I
                    suppose he gives his news. I do wish you were all here, you would have to suffer
                    some privation of your present luxuries but upon the whole might be as pleasant
                    I hope that <add hand="h1" place="inline">it</add> will not be long until we can
                    be together constantly. I have hoped to hear from you for some time but I
                    suppose the lines are held so strict that letters can not pass. but you must
                    write me by every <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> you have &amp;
                    let me know how you are getting along &amp;c &amp;c. I can hardly think
                    of having to spend this winter without you, but I fear we cannot better
                    ourselves now. If the way is open long enough for me to go I will be sure to be
                    down if able to travel &amp;c I have been trying to sell out here, and can
                    sell for a large price but to exchange the money for such as can be used there I
                    would get so little that<pb n="2"/> it would not justify the sale. I am still
                    watching for <orig reg="opportunities">oppertunities</orig> &amp; when <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">one</add> offers that will pay well I will quit
                    this business immediately</p>

                <p>We are doing a considerable business here now our receipts are from 1000$ to
                        $2000<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi>
                    <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> day, but the expenses are equally heavy Flour
                        $200<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">00</hi>
                    </hi> to $280 <abbr expan="per">pr</abbr> Barrel Beef $2 <abbr expan="per"
                    >pr</abbr> pound but we get plenty of supplies</p>

                <p>As to our business there, you have managed so long &amp; done so nobly that I
                    need not interfere, but just let you continue to manage as you think best I only
                    regret that I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be with you &amp; relieve you
                    from all these troubles which you were unaccustomed <orig reg="to">too</orig> as
                    when I was at home I tried to relieve you of all outdoors management. I hope you
                    have fully recovered your health. I fear you give yourself trouble about
                    business matters which sometimes unnerves you &amp; makes <orig
                        reg="nervous">nearvous</orig> &amp; delicate try &amp; take all
                    matters <orig reg="smooth">smoothe</orig> &amp; easy do what you can
                    &amp; let the rest pass by. I suppose Mary B. is still with you &amp;
                    not doubt she is great help to you If she is now with you &amp; suits you,
                    try &amp; keep her, remember me kindly to her. I suppose the little girls
                    are now going to school. <orig reg="don't">don<hi rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">t</hi>
                        </hi></orig> let them be <orig reg="too much">toomuch</orig> confined allow
                    them as much recreation as you can</p>

                <p>The election is over &amp; I suppose Lincoln is again President for four
                    years what result will be from the new election we know not but I hope a
                        speedy<pb n="3"/> peace will soon be brought about Lay in full winter
                    supplies &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> stint yourself in anything
                    there is to be had. I have a lot of money for you such as you can use there,
                    which I hope to get to you soon I will continue to get all I can of that kind of
                        fund<hi rend="super">s</hi> that you may have plenty under all circumstances
                    As to the furniture of M<hi rend="super">
                        <hi rend="underline">rs</hi>
                    </hi> It is but just and right to keep her things under the contract. They were
                    not worth More than that amount of such money at the time we got them. but in
                    view of her being a very poor &amp; needy persons &amp; I think well
                    disposed, I would let her have her things <hi rend="underline">Just make her a
                        present of them</hi> it will be little or nothing to us and perhaps will be
                    best in the end</p>

                <p>As to Wolff say to him that I owe him no money in any way The things I bought of
                    Hamilton I paid him &amp; H for &amp; I have nothing to do with him in
                    the matter and say farther to him that if he interferes with you in any way
                    whatever in the matter he will regret it as I am not always from home. I have
                    saved him from one <hi rend="underline">ducking &amp; tar &amp;
                        feathering since the commencement of this war &amp; this is the thanks
                        for it</hi> you may let him read this paragraph for himself.</p>

                <p>I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> think of any matters now of particular interest
                    to write you. take good care of all &amp; may god ever bless &amp;
                    protect you</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>good night</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="John Quincy Adams">J Q A</abbr> Nadenbousch</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
