<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8013"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8013">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: N. Sargent to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, October 24, 1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county n sargent to alexander h h stuart, october 24 1859</title>
        <author>Sargent, N</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8013</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502665</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: N. Sargent to Alexander H. H. Stuart, October 24,
                            1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county n sargent to alexander h h stuart, october 24 1859</title>
            <author>N. Sargent</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: N. Sargent to Alexander H. H.
                            Stuart, 24 October 1859, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 4,
                            Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-10-24">1859-10-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8013T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Sargent discusses ex-Whig hopes to nominate a candidate for the 1860 presidential
                    election in hopes of influencing the Republican's selection of a canidate in the
                    race. Sargent also discusses the political effects of Brown's raid at Harper's
                    Ferry, and asks for Stuart's opinions on the matters.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-10-24">Oct. 24, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Washington</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Gov. Hunt was here on Thursday. I spent the evening with him as did several Old
                    Whigs--Hoags, Tayloe, Wallach &amp; others. Of course the political aspect
                    of the country did not escape observation, and all concurred in the opinion that
                    the conservative opposition ought to raise its standard &amp; stand by it.</p>
                <p>To the question, What ought now to be done? I replied that the conservative party
                    ought, in my judgment, to call an early National Convention, nominate candidates
                    for whom moderate Republicans can vote, men in whom all true national
                    conservative men have confidence, &amp; then let the Republicans take what
                    course they may think proper. Such a nomination would, I
                    <unclear>thot</unclear>, secure the election of the ticket, &amp; the
                    eventual union of all, save the ultra<pb n="2"/>ists of the Opposition, North
                    &amp; South. But how shall that Convention be called, &amp; by whom? Was
                    the next inquiry. My reply was, "by the Opposition State Convention, to be held
                    at Richmond, Va. on the 14th Dec.</p>
                <p>The opinion seemed to be concurred in that by some such course we should take
                    possession of the track and by presenting an unexceptionable ticket compel the
                    Republican party to adopt it.</p>
                <p>The outbreak at Harper's Ferry must exert no small influence upon political
                    movements. It is a <unclear>chuk</unclear> upon the Republicans, &amp; must
                    make them more <del hand="h1">ready to</del> pliable, yielding and
                    conciliatory;--less audacious, confident &amp; exacting. In this state of
                    things it seems to me that boldness, decision &amp; prompt action on our
                    part, is the dictate of sound policy. Timidity &amp; hesitation always
                    invite aggression and encourage assumption.</p>
                <pb n="3"/>
                <p>I should be glad to have your views on this subject.</p>
                <p>In regard to candidates; I have no personal preferences, except one, &amp;
                    that I will not name to you. Among a number of good men, we must be governed by
                    policy in the selection of candidates. The Blairs, it is well for us to bear in
                    mind, are for Mr. Bates; and so is Mr. Colfax of <abbr expan="Indiana"
                    >Ind.</abbr> &amp; many of the prominent Republicans of the West. That being
                    the case, would they not exert a strong influence, should he be placed in
                    nomination as I have indicated, in inducing the party of which they are leaders,
                    to adopt our ticket? especially if some Republican, say Foot or Fessenden, were
                    placed on the ticket?</p>
                <p>What I rather fear is, that your convention, excited by the late scenes &amp;
                    outrages, will adopt some resolution, or give expression to some sentiment not
                    calculated to "turn away wrath," but to invite by "touching the raw" of the
                    North. I hope, however, you will be able to prevent this.</p>
                <pb n="4"/>
                <p>Mr. Hodge told me he had addressed a letter to you at Richmond, &amp; was
                    desirous to hear from you in reply.</p>
                <p>It seems to be generally <unclear>concluded</unclear> that the Harpers Ferry
                    transactions have laid Seward on the shelf, as well as Chase, Banks &amp;
                    all others belonging to the "irrepressible conflict" section of the <abbr
                        expan="Republican">R.</abbr> party.</p>
                <p>I have had <hi rend="underline">congestive</hi> chills &amp; fever which came
                    near ending my <orig reg="career">carreer</orig>.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With true regard<lb/>Your friend &amp; <orig reg="obedient">obat</orig>
                        <orig reg="Servant">Servt</orig></salute>
                    <signed>N. Sargent</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">When do you deliver your Agricultural address? <name
                            type="recipient">Hon A. H. H. Stuart</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
