<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8011"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8011">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H. Stuart, August 1,
     1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county l luckett to alexander h h stuart, august 1 1859</title>
        <author>Luckett, L.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name/>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">A8011</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502663</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H. Stuart, August 1, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county l luckett to alexander h h stuart, august 1 1859</title>
            <author>L. Luckett</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: L. Luckett to Alexander H. H. Stuart, 1 August
       1859, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the Related Stuart and Baldwin Families,
       1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia
       Library, Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1859-08-01">1859-08-01</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>National Government</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="A8011T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Luckett describes in detail Tennessee and Alabama, noting the political excitment in
    them.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1859-08-01">August 1st. 1859</date>
      <name type="place">Memphis,</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>We left Richmond on Monday morning the 25th, and reached the Springs the same day.
     Unfortunately, we found the weather as much too cold here, as on the other extreme at old
      <unclear>Poial</unclear>. Blanket coats and fires would have have been very comfortable of
     mornings. There were about 350 visitors here, and a greater proportion of them Ladies in
     appearance, than at the Bay.</p>
    <p>This is a very beautiful place, well laid off and very comfortable houses--a good table and
     attentive servants for a watering place. The water I can't say much for, in a medicinal
      <unclear>pooly</unclear> view, it is pretty much as you find in Staunton &amp; in all the
     region of lime Stone--with a pinch of brimstone in it. The Sulphur is hardly discernable to the
     taste and I do <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> think very in efficient, as a curative means--and I suppose
     with the exception of the old White, Bedford, the Berkeley, the <unclear>Sruit</unclear>
     &amp; Bath, there are none of any efficacy, apart from the mountain air. After a few days
     as pleasantly spent as could be<pb n="2"/> expected for those anxious to get home, we took our
     departure on Friday morning morning before day break, the sincerest ordeal the girls had yet
      <unclear>passed</unclear>
     <orig reg="through">thr'o</orig>, and reached this place Sunday night at 10 <abbr
      expan="o'clock">O'C</abbr>. We slept the first night in Knoxville, the second in Huntsville.</p>
    <p>The country we saw <orig reg="through">thr'o</orig> Wythe (Wyth they all call it) &amp;
     Washington <orig reg="though">tho</orig> rough, is a better farming region than I had
     supposed--I saw no houses with trees around them, too cold for that I suppose--but the short
     horses and fine mules took my fancy.</p>
    <p>On leaving Knoxville, I got Parson Brownlow's Paper which kept me laughing for an hour, I
     wish I <abbr expan="could">cd.</abbr> have mailed one to you, to see how fast &amp; furious
     they are conducting their elections here--the way the Parson wields his battle axe, would do
     credit to Richard the Lion Hearted--Bowie Knives, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp;
      cowhides--<del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, coward in every column &amp; paragraph. I don't understand how
     his cloth protects his hide. For such an apparently out of the way &amp; rough country,
     there was one thing as touched me very much, that almost every woman that came on the cars
      along<pb n="3"/> this road, had more or less the air, dress, &amp; breeding of a Lady, and
     to take every one that joined us from the Springs to the Suburbs of Memphis, and they would be
     far superior to the same number at Old Point or the Mount S. Springs--The men that got on were
     all the rough &amp; hearty yeomanry of the rough country, not an exception visible to my
     eye, only as we approached the Alabama line, where the Election was drawing nigh, they became
     more <hi rend="underline">
      <unclear>Semiadlish</unclear>
     </hi>, particularly about the depots, and now I saw how fortunate that we did not put off our
     trip till Election day, as I would have had no wish to be in the cars with the Girls on that
     day. Judging from the conversations, I would suppose the Whigs were in the ascendancy. The
     country from the Mountain East of Huntsville, to the west, beyond Tuscumbia, must once have
     been a Paradise--say forty years ago, when the soil was fresh &amp; would bring a bale of
     Cotton to the acre, this and Tuscaloosa were the regions, the forms of which, captured my fancy
     when a boy &amp; gave me the first impulse southward--and this was the region that broke so
     many Virginians &amp; Kentuckians, about the <hi rend="underline">first</hi> flush
     times--the second<pb n="4"/> was in Missippi &amp; Louisiana. This is a valley surrounded
     by high mountains, to the East, South &amp; North, and the Lookout Mountains to the West,
     and with its original fertility, would equal the valley of the Blue Ridge or
     <unclear>Tennessee</unclear> or the <unclear>McLark</unclear>. Beautiful fields, gently
     undulating, well watered by two small rivers running <orig reg="through">thro</orig> it,
     &amp; many small branches, one froms a spring, that would run a couple of miles--but,
     pretty well worn out now--<unclear>scd</unclear> gullies all <orig reg="through">thr'o</orig>
     it, and cotton so small, that it would break any <hi rend="underline">niggers</hi> back to pick
     it, from six inches to one foot high &amp; corn in proportion.</p>
    <p>From the Montgomery to Mobile, they have a dry <unclear>stream</unclear> in which the corn is
     dead in places, by the drought. East Tennessee has had rains--west &amp; part of Alabama
     the crop of corn is burnt up--some fields, there is hardly a shoot on the stalks, <orig
      reg="though">tho</orig> of good size, had no rain for weeks--and much of it too far gone to be
     benefited now. All parties here are confident, that Douglas will be the Charleston
     Nominee--only <orig reg="though">th'o</orig>, to save the Party &amp; the Spoils. That they
     will try some trick I have no doubt.</p>
    <p>I don't think the girls have eaten one dollars worth of meat or anything else at Hotels,
     since they left Staunton, but for fruits, cakes, candies &amp; other trash, all day
     &amp; part of the night, I don't think any two other animals living, could be found to
     equal them. I found a letter from home--all well, only one rain since I left, no <del hand="h1"
     /> or <unclear>boll worms</unclear>, nor shedding of forms, and crop fine--<unclear>we</unclear>
     <unclear>leave</unclear> this <unclear>morning</unclear> on the <hi rend="underline"
     >Capitol</hi>.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Remember us <unclear>affly</unclear> &amp; kindly to all yr. family and believe us
      most sincerely &amp; truly yrs.</salute>
     <signed>L Luckett</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
