<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8010"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="A8010">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William Kinney to Alexander H. H.
                    Stuart, October 24, 1857</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william kinney to alexander h h stuart, october 24 1857</title>
        <author>Kinney, William</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8010</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502662</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William Kinney to Alexander H. H. Stuart, October 24,
                            1857</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william kinney to alexander h h stuart, october 24 1857</title>
            <author>William Kinney</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Wm. Kinney to Alexander H. H.
                            Stuart, 24 October 1857, Papers of Alexander H. H. Stuart and the
                            Related Stuart and Baldwin Families, 1776-1878, Accession #228-a, Box 3,
                            Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1857-10-24">1857-10-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>State Government, National Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8010T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kinney reports Virginia state senate race results and asks Stuart to write a few
                    essays for publication on "the subject of the Tariff."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1857-10-24">24 Oct. 57</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Stuart</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Our senate race came off yesterday and excited but little interest here or in the
                    county, so little, that we have heard the result but from one <orig
                        reg="percent">precenct</orig> (<orig reg="though">th'o</orig> it is now,
                    12:06, am)<lb/>The vote at <abbr expan="Court">Ct</abbr> House was as
                    follows<lb/> Sheffey for senate.. 199 Mt. Sidney....44<lb/> Baylor " ".. 141..."
                    23<lb/> Peyton 162......35<lb/> Imboden 141.....14<lb/> Walker 130.....69<lb/>
                    Harris 118......14<lb/> Abney 127......24<lb/> Report says Peyton was ahead at
                    Waynesboro @ 4 O'Clock, the impression seems to be that Sheffey, Peyton
                    &amp; Walker are elected, <orig reg="though">th'o</orig> I think it by no
                    means certain, you see Baylor <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Sheffey at <abbr expan="Court"
                    >Ct</abbr> House close, the reason was, that Sheffey could not command the
                    entire Whig vote. This is a severe blow upon Ichabod <unclear>alapod</unclear>
                    Imboden if any two tolerably popular Whigs had run against him, he would have
                    been distanced--he is very distasteful to the leading Whigs of the County, and
                    the Charlottesville Convention did a very silly thing in making him the Whig
                    elector for this Senatorial District, I fear he is not able to cope with
                        Skinner<pb n="2"/> And Summers ought to be here before elections to heal the
                    distractions or devisions in the Whig ranks and make up for Imbodens
                    deficiencies--he is now stumping it little <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. Banks was here
                    yesterday and says his prospects there are very encouraging--He named several
                    conspicuous Democrats in that region that would support him in preference to <hi
                        rend="underline">little</hi> Iam--Summers has promised us he would try and
                    be here &amp; address this People before the election. Hozd's friends in
                    South West are a good deal chafed <unclear>I suspect</unclear> at Iam's beating
                    him in the convention here.</p>
                <p>My main object however in writing you now is, to suggest the propriety of some
                    articles being prepared at Washington by yourself or some one who understands
                    the subject appealing to the young Farmers &amp; Mechanics on the subject of
                    the Tariff, which indeed is now the most important issue between the parties,
                    putting the Whigs in contrast with the pauper laborer of Europe, I think a few
                    well written plain essays on that subject would have a powerful effect. The
                    Democrats here are making strong appeal; to the new voters, and nothing it seems
                    to me is doing to counter act their efforts. I am so harrassed with family cases
                    and anxieties, that really my mind is in such a condition that I am almost unfit
                    for business<pb n="3"/> and that I shall be very much occupied all next month
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Circuit Court. I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to find <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    Jno Davis <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> he made in Senate of U S States contrasting the
                    pauper laborers of Europe with the free white laborer of U S States with a view
                    of publishing some extracts from it, but could not find it.</p>
                <p>We have delightful weather now. I saw your little daughters day before yesterday
                    &amp; Mrs Baldwin passed my office about an hour since, so I presume all are
                    well.</p>
                <p>Excuse my hasty scrawl and let me hear from you as <orig reg="often">of't</orig>
                    as you can &amp; believe me to be</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With all respect &amp; esteem<lb/>Truly <orig reg="your">yr</orig>
                        friend</salute>
                    <signed>Wm Kinney</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">P.S. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Chapman say to him <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> write to him as soon as
                        Mr Craig, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> from Nelson, which he is <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> to do
                        by <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. My respects Mrs S. by <del rend="none" hand="h1"/></seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
