<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8021"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8021">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: M. D. Clayton to Aunt, May 8, 1840</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county m d clayton to aunt, may 8 1840</title>
        <author>Clayton, M. D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8021</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502672</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: M. D. Clayton to Aunt, May 8, 1840</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county m d clayton to aunt, may 8 1840</title>
            <author>M D Clayton</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Private Collection</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1840-05-08">1840-05-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, National Government, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8021T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Ten-year-old Nelly Clayton writes her Aunt and relates how she and her family are
                    doing, discusses the upcoming 1840 presidential election (declaring herself to
                    be a Whig), and alludes to a possible religious "Camp meeting in Sept."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1840-05-08">May 8th 1840</date>
                        <name type="place">Cherry Grove</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Aunt</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Cousin Hetty Ann and myself received <unclear>uneller</unclear> letter a few days
                    ago and we was very much pleased to hear from you all. Aunt I have nothing of
                    importance to communicate only that we are tolerable well at this time I have a
                    very bad cold and <orig reg="sore">soar</orig> throat <orig reg="there"
                    >thay</orig> is a great many persons complaining of colds at this time. Uncle
                    Tho's Claytons family are all well except Cousin Hetty Ann she has been very
                    sick all this week with the <orig reg="sore">soar</orig> throat her throat is
                    very much swelled indeed she is in bed most of her time. Uncle <abbr
                        expan="William">Wm</abbr> Claytons family are all well except Aunt Polly and
                    she is not much better but she bares all of her sickness with great patience.
                    Tell cousin Samuel Black that his father Mother Brothers and sisters are all
                    well, and Cousin Ralph Black is doing very well and Uncle <abbr expan="William"
                        >Wm</abbr> Black also is doing well Cousin Ralph Black is living on fathers
                    Plantation that he bought a few years ago he has one child you may tell cousin
                    Samuel and <unclear>que</unclear> of the finest little wives he ever saw she is
                    very industrious and <orig reg="they">thay</orig> have planty of <orig
                        reg="everything">evry thing</orig> about them for to be keeping house no
                    longer then <orig reg="they">thay</orig> have. Tell Aunt that for James and his
                    wife I say nothing about <orig reg="their">there</orig> industry thay have 2
                    Children and is living on uncle <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> Claytons land
                    Uncle <abbr expan="William">Wm</abbr> Black has bought land of his own and his
                    father and Mother lives on his land close to him give my love to cousin Samuel
                    and family if you please.</p>
                <p>Aunt I hope I shall have the felicity of seeing you yet I am in great hopes that
                    you and Uncle and my Dear little Cousin will pay us all a visit this fall oh
                    Aunt I would be delighted if I could only see you all I often talk of paying you
                    a visit but I fear my talk is is all in vain I often tell father and Mother that
                    if I ever get Maried I will go to Missouri <pb n="2"/> Aunt tell uncle that all
                    the Gentlemen talk here now is about <orig reg="Harrison">Harrisson</orig> and
                    Van <orig reg="Buren">Buran</orig> tell him that I am a Whig and I am very
                    anxious to know what he is I hope he is a Whig for I do not like Van <orig
                        reg="Buren">Buran</orig> the Gentleman laugh very much at the Ladies here
                        <orig reg="they">thay</orig> all say if <orig reg="they">thay</orig> had to
                    vote <orig reg="they">thay</orig> would all vote for <orig reg="Harrison"
                        >Harrisson</orig> all the Claytons here is for <orig reg="Harrison"
                        >Harrisson</orig> and I almost imagine that uncle Ralph is for <orig
                        reg="Harrison">Harrisson</orig>. . . Tell Uncle that I say he must bring you
                    to see us soon for nothing in the World could afford us more pleasure than to
                    see you all.</p>
                <p>We had a very hard winter or at least the <orig reg="biggest">bigest</orig> part
                    of it we have a fine Spring the small grain looks very well indeed. I fear we
                    will not have much fruit if <orig reg="they">thay</orig> is many more long
                    frosts to come but them that provides all things knows best whats to come so his
                    will be done on earth as is in Heaven for he knows better what we all need <orig
                        reg="than">then</orig> we are all to ask or by any <orig reg="manner"
                    >meaner</orig> worthy to <orig reg="receive">recieve</orig>. We have 2 fine
                    Preachers here Mr. Blam is our Presbyterian Preacher and Mr Styne is our
                    Methodist Preacher and it is to be hoped that thay will do a great deal of good
                    in both churches this year <orig reg="They">Thay</orig> talk of having a Camp
                        <orig reg="meeting">meting</orig> in Sept. if nothing happens.......</p>
                <p>Dear Aunt the family all join with myself in love to you all write to me as soon
                    as <orig reg="you">your</orig>
                    <orig reg="receive">recive</orig> this letter my love to Mr <orig reg="William"
                        >Wm</orig>
                    <unclear>Mccutee</unclear> and family I have nothing more only my prayer is that
                    the Lord may be with you all for ever more.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>farewell</salute>
                    <signed>M D Clayton</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
