<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A8047"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A8047">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: B. Estill to John McCue, January 20,
                    1859</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county b estill to john mccue, january 20 1859</title>
        <author>Estill, B.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A8047</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502698</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: B. Estill to John McCue, January 20, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county b estill to john mccue, january 20 1859</title>
            <author>B. Estill</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: B. Estill to John McCue, 20
                            January 1859, Papers of the McCue Family, 1777-1920, Accession #4406,
                            Box 3, Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library,
                            Charlottesville, Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-01-20">1859-01-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Economy, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A8047T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Estill discusses financial matters, religion, and his intention to shake off "the
                    very dust of celibacy."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-01-20">Jany 20th 1859<lb/>At any time I would be glad to
                            hear from you at Mossy Creek P. office--B E</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Friend</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>In answer to yours of last month I write to express my gratification at its
                    perusal as well as to add one or more reflections relating to things in general
                    &amp; to one or two in particular. With or without your kind assurance
                    relating to my small claim, I never had &amp; do not now entertain the
                    slightest doubt about your entire willingness &amp; determination to
                    liquidate the same so soon as the state of your finances justify it, and I shall
                    only add on this subject that in as much as I expect to be very much pressed for
                    means during the next 5 4 or 3- months (wherewith to meet my Shenandoah
                    engagements) I know--if at all convenient for you?--it will be as much your
                    compliance to pay as it would be for me to receive the amount of your note
                    between this &amp; the first of March, or as soon thereafter as possible.
                    Your note bearing date the 7th day of October 1857, will be left in the hands of
                        <abbr expan="John">Jno</abbr> D Imboden for the reason that you would not
                    know where to send to me or write me, &amp; at Staunton with the
                        <unclear>clerk</unclear> it &amp; its wherebouts will always be
                    thoroughly accessible. Unless circumstances or some<pb n="2"/>clever woman turns
                    my course I expect--if life &amp; health be graciously spared me?--to set
                    off for Kentucky in a week or ten days, for the purpose of making a final tour
                    among old grand mama's Eve's fair descendants, to ascertain whether or not
                    indeed this individual can gather up the scattered fragments of his heart's
                    affections so as to concentrate them upon some one whose charms &amp;
                    attractions ((personal &amp; social)) shall be sufficient to lead me right
                    up to Heymen's altar!! The truth is every day's experience like the atmosphere
                    around is pressing me with the conviction that it is not good &amp; never
                    was designed to be, for man to be alone!! that his living is but a mere animal
                    existence floating upon the surface of things, drifting hither &amp; thither
                    after crumbs &amp; scraps of comfort &amp; having like an old shoe-sole
                    from the wheels of time, <orig reg="dropped">droped</orig> his mortal
                        <unclear>evil</unclear>, he goes down to his last resting place with this
                    appropriate epitaph<lb/>"Here lies old Bach stone dead<lb/>Here's his feet
                    &amp; there's his head<lb/>Where old Bach is &amp; where he
                        <unclear>lairs</unclear><lb/>Nobody knows &amp; nobody cares".</p>
                <p>Depend upon it my dear sir, as I should have said to my friend the gentleman from
                        <unclear>Cuting</unclear>!! at the Hospital I have just lingered on the
                    borders of<pb n="3"/>single-wretchedness long enough to discover that there is
                    not in her wide <unclear>haste</unclear> one single oasis on which my eyes or my
                    hopes might rest, and therefore I announce to you, to all the world &amp;
                    the rest of mankind, but rather more of woman kind, that <orig reg="before"
                    >ere</orig> long I design to shake the very dust of celibacy off my
                    understandings &amp; take up my line of march gladly &amp; joyously
                    for<lb/>That land of mixed delight<lb/>Where Bachelors nowhere tarry<lb/>Where
                    Hymen's says dispel the night<lb/>And lead me on to marry!!!!.</p>
                <p>In reply to your &amp; your wife's kind &amp; generous invitation to call
                    &amp; see you at any time, allow me to say that whenever &amp; wherever
                    my lot should be cast near you I shall esteem it both a privilege &amp;
                    pleasure to fill awhile some corner under your hospitable roof, where many hours
                    doubtless would <unclear>glide</unclear> away filled with the memories of the
                    past, comments on the present, &amp; speculations on the future. I think I
                    can sincerely say that within the range of my entire acquaintance or friendship
                    few or none are more esteemed, or whose interests I would sooner turn aside to
                    promote than yours &amp; those of your beloved household, and when I bring
                    my mind to bear upon our wonderful constitution &amp; relation to one
                    another here as well as our <orig reg="connection">connexion</orig> with what
                    follows hereafter<pb n="4"/>I am struck with the boundless wisdom &amp;
                    goodness of Him who has created us &amp; placed us here
                        <unclear>protationers</unclear>in time &amp; candidates for eternity.
                    All these tender &amp; endearing confessions of life that go to make up <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> much of the sum of human happiness, are so
                    <unclear>little</unclear> &amp; liable to be shaped asunder, as to convince
                    us that we should not set our affections upon them for we can not hold to them,
                    nor can life <unclear/> be extended to us beyond a fitful fleeting years or
                    months or days. Then indeed <unclear>confident</unclear> with the
                        <unclear>divine</unclear> injunction, philosophy would point &amp; urge
                    us forward to that land of pure delight where saints immortal reign!! where
                    infinite days exclude the night &amp; pleasures vanish pain!!,, you kindly
                    invoked the divine blessing upon me at the close your letter &amp; returning
                    most heartily the same upon yourself, let me remind you of the truth that the
                    divine blessing can only descend upon any of us within the limits of the Mercy
                    of God. Remember the solemn words of Dr Alexander<lb/>There is a time we know
                    not when<lb/>A point we know not where<lb/>That marks the destiny of man<lb/>To
                    glory or despair!!!!</p>
                <p>Present if you please my kindest regards to Cousin Liz &amp; to your beloved
                    children, &amp; hoping &amp; trusting &amp; praying that by Almighty
                    grace you may be enabled &amp; induced to set out NOW!! in the narrow way
                    along which I believe your beloved wife has been journeying &amp; which she
                    with the angels &amp; perhaps a mother in heaven would rejoice to find you!!</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>very sincerely, Your Friend &amp; Kinsman</salute>
                    <signed>B. Estill</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
