<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9500"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9500">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: James M. Schreckhise to G. T. Tifer,
                    April 20, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county james m schreckhise to g t tifer, april 20 1861</title>
        <author>Schreckhise, James M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9500</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502743</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: James M. Schreckhise to G. T. Tifer, April 20, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county james m schreckhise to g t tifer, april 20 1861</title>
            <author>James M. Schreckhise</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: James M. Schreckhise Papers,
                            Special Collections Library, Duke University, Durham, North
                        Carolina.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-04-20">1861-04-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Enlistment, Family, Home Front, Patriotism, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-06">June 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9500T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Schreckhise letter describes the jubilation over the attack on Fort Sumter, and
                    he confidently claims that all of Virginia is in faver of secession.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Prof. G. T. Tifer</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-04-20">April 20<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Mt. Sidney, Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I hereby acknowledge the reception of your letter. I was glad to hear from you
                    &amp; to get the news from <abbr expan="South">S.</abbr> Carolina. There was
                    great excitement here when it was known Fort Sumter was attacked. You say you
                    have excitement in your town but I suppose it is not to be compared with what we
                    have here. There never has been such a time in Virginia. I thought that whilst
                    in Richmond I saw men excited but since then it has reached the acme. The
                    committee sent by the Convention to find out the policy of old Lincoln received
                    no satisfactory answer. Virginia has seceded &amp; I understand it is not to
                    go back to the people &amp; I am glad of it. I do not believe one thousand
                    votes could be obtained in this state to remain in the Union. The military have
                    been called out. My brother left yesterday with his company for Harpers Ferry.
                    For 10 volunteer companies have already left our county &amp; a number are
                    expecting to go in a day or two. The Old Dominion has at length arisen from her
                    slumber to shake off the chains <pb n="2"/>of the abominable abolition tyrant.
                    Old father Abraham has learned that Southern blood <orig reg="doesn't"
                    >dont</orig> course through <orig reg="cowards'">cowards</orig> veins &amp;
                    I hope he that the day is not far distant when he will <hi rend="underline"
                        >sensibly</hi> feel <hi rend="underline">"that somebody is hurt."</hi> There
                    seems to be but one determination here and that is to defend even unto death
                    Southern rights &amp; principles. I found my mother still alive but have
                    been looking for her death almost every hour since. She cannot live long so far
                    as we can judge. When I will get back to Newberry I know not. I thought of
                    re-turning immediately but affairs here are in such a condition that I do not
                    like to leave. My brother has gone to the seat of war &amp; my brothers in
                    law expect to leave in a day or two &amp; my father desires me to remain a
                    few days longer if possible. Excuse this badly written letter as I am in a very
                    sad condition to write. I will be glad to hear from you at any time. I will try
                    to get back as soon as I can. Give my kindest regards to the Faculty. I will
                    send you a few newspapers in a day or two. I would like to get a copy of the
                    Columbia or Charleston papers.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Truly</salute>
                    <signed>J.M. Schreckhise</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
