<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9608"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9608">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December
                    18, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 18 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9608</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502770</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December 18, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 18 1870</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden Papers,
                            1831-1895, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                            University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-12-18">1870-12-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-03-29">2007-03-29</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9608T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden again shares his thoughts on the importance of marriage and reassures
                    Annie that they will be happy together.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-12-18">Sunday Dec. 18, 1870</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My precious Annie,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>On last Thursday I <abbr expan="received">recd.</abbr> your sweet letter of the
                        10<hi rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    </hi> and was glad to learn that you are again at home where you will write to
                    me by every mail.</p>

                <p>I thought there was a tone of sadness apparent in your letter when I first read
                    it that made me uneasy lest there might be moments when you doubted whether your
                    happiness was assured in our prospective marriage. On a closer study of your
                    letter I think perhaps I may trace its tone to the very natural regret you
                    experienced in leaving Brunswick with the Conviction that it was the last time
                    you would ever be one of the gay young parties that so grace the Society of that
                    pleasant old County. And that whilst you regretted the probable loss forever of
                    this source of <pb n="2"/> happiness I have no right to conclude that you felt
                    misgivings about the future.</p>

                <p>You refer to the limited opportunities we have had to become well acquainted.
                    That is true, but so far as <hi rend="underline">I</hi> am concerned I trust so
                    implicitly in my knowledge of human nature, and my ability to read a woman's
                    character, that before I had been 24 hours in your Society I saw &amp; felt
                    that you possessed every element of "head &amp; heart" to make any man happy
                    as your husband, who had heart &amp; soul enough to appreciate you. I knew
                    that if I could win your love I should find in you one of the dearest and best
                    little wives man was ever blessed with, and I needed no further acquaintance to
                    induce me to give you my whole heart, and ask for yours in return. You have not
                    had the experience of the world that I have, and I do not wonder at your desire
                    to see more of me, and to know me better before you sever all the tenderest ties
                    of life, and <pb n="3"/> Come with me amongst strangers. It is my thorough
                    knowledge of how great the sacrifice - and how perilous the step - a young girl
                    makes in marrying, that will make me always the tenderest of husbands to you. I
                    will aim to make you trust me, and lean upon me with that perfect confidence
                    that will dispel every feeling of apprehension from your mind, so that when you
                    pronounce the solemn vows that make you mine forever - adopt my name - sever
                    your connection with home &amp; family - give to father &amp; mother -
                    sisters &amp; brothers your farewell kiss, and leave all to "cleave unto"
                    me, you will feel that in my love, my devotion, and strong protecting arm, a new
                    world of happiness is opened up to you that is more than an equivalent for that
                    you leave behind.</p>

                <p>The more I can be with you before our marriage - the more you can see of me the
                    more certainly do I hope to bring you to look forward to the day of our union
                    with impatient delight, &amp; not of anxiety.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>The still continued absence in Europe of <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> M<hi
                        rend="super">c</hi>Kaye, and the delay of <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr>
                    Flournoy to join me here, renders the day of my return to Virginia still
                    uncertain. I <add hand="h1" place="inline">do</add> not yet despair of getting
                    home this month but I am not sure of it. Should I be delayed till after the
                        <orig reg="holidays">holydays</orig>, the I will so arrange my business here
                    as to make it unnecessary for me to come back from Virginia till Spring, when
                    you will come along. I often picture to myself the pleasure it will give me to
                    have you here to caress &amp; pet, when I come up town from a hard day's
                    work, and in your sweet society to forget for a while the din and uproar of this
                    great bray thing in which I daily move. Amongst all the hundreds of thousands of
                    men and women around me, you alone in some bright cheerful room, will constitute
                    my world of happiness. And together we will go out and be amused by the throng
                    in which we shall have no interest, beyond that they afford us a mere spectacle
                    to gaze upon.</p>

                <pb n="5"/>

                <p>You cannot realize how utterly indifferent I feel towards the great mass of
                    mankind. Every day's experience but confirms me in the opinions of years, that
                    there is but one mode of existence in this world that satisfies our natural
                    craving for happiness - and that is in the married relation, founded upon
                    perfect love &amp; confidence between husband &amp; wife. A man
                    &amp; woman <hi rend="underline">can</hi> make for each other <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">of</add> this world, a foretaste of that more perfect
                    existence hereafter, that we all look forward to so hopefully. On the other hand
                    they may render life a burden almost too intolerable to be borne. I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> believe much in any <hi rend="underline">middle</hi>
                    ground between happiness and misery in married life. My experience in that
                    relation was one of supreme happiness. I can well conceive how it could, under
                    less favorable circumstances, have been one of wretchedness, if it had lacked
                    the essential foundation of profound mutual respect &amp; perfect love.</p>

                <pb n="6"/>

                <p>I am glad to see from your last letter that you think so gravely of the important
                    step you are so soon to take. It proves that you appreciate its importance, and
                    that unless you felt perfectly satisfied in regard to your own heart you would
                    not incur the tremendous consequences of an irrevocable ceremony. The more
                    gravely and seriously you think of it now, the better assured am I, that your
                    mind will never change its deliberate decisions.</p>

                <p>I wish I could be with you Christmas. I shall think all day of you, and I belive
                    you will not forget me. I look forward a year, &amp; see you a happy little
                    wife when this festive seeason comes around again. And may it always be a merry
                    and a happy time with you.</p>

                <p>I shall write today to Sister Lou. Miss Ella will not write to me I suppose. I am
                    pained to learn from you that her health is still so delicate. I appreciate on
                    that account your anxiety to gratify her wish to be present at our marriage, and
                    I will not urge you too much against your will to forego that pleasure, merely
                    to gratify me. Therefore it is I leave open the question of "a day," till we
                    meet.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With love to all, I am with the most unalterable affection yours as
                        ever,</salute>
                    <signed>JD Imboden</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">You ask whether you may engage yourself a little while to
                        a poor fellow who <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> believe you when you discard
                        him. No Annie dear! No. It would not be right to create in his heart a false
                        hope. The pain to him of discovering he had been trifled with is such as you
                        ought not to inflict. Better bear with him a while longer. He will find out
                        soon no doubt that there is no hope for him. Do not create a false hope, by
                        encouraging his suit, unless you intend to sacrifice me &amp; take
                    him.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
