<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9602"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9602">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, September
                    7, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, september 7 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9602</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502764</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, September 7, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, september 7 1870</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>12 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden Papers,
                            1831-1895, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                            University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-09-07">1870-09-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Arts/Leisure, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-03-28">2007-03-28</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9602T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden teases Annie about his encounters with young women in New York but then
                    tries to persuade her to consider more fully his offer of marriage. He also
                    mentions an upcoming meeting of the Board of Directors of his "land
                company."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-09-07">Sept. 7, 1870</date>
                        <name type="place">257 Broadway New York</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Miss Annie,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Mails move more slowly between Lombardy Grove &amp; this great City than
                    suits the wishes &amp; feelings of one <hi rend="underline">male</hi> you
                    wot of. Your sweet but most provoking letter of the 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst.</abbr> only reached me yesterday evening. I would
                    have replied to it last night but for an unexpected but very agreeable
                    interruption. An Old friend of mine from Orange in this State, a millionaire by
                    the way, <pb n="2"/> arrived here from New Port yesterday with his only
                    daughter, a charming young thing of sweet 16. Miss was bent on going to Boothe's
                    Theatre to see Jefferson play Rip Van Winkle. The father didn't want to go with
                    her as he is a widower &amp; had in charge another young lady. So he called
                    at my office and asked me to call upon them at the 5 Avenue Hotel &amp;
                    escort his daughter to the play, which I did &amp; afterwards took supper
                    between 12 &amp; 1 o'clock with the party. He honored me with this
                    invitation because of my age and discretion, and little Miss seemed satisfied.
                    So you <pb n="3"/> see that I find some compensation for your taunting
                    information of the ride with that handsome young fellow who live beyond the
                    Roanoke. (I wish <hi rend="underline">he</hi> was on the other side of Jordan).
                    The ride must have been dreadfully fatiguing to the poor fellow as he had to
                    remain two or three days at Lombardy Grove to recuperate sufficiently to go
                    beyond the Roanoke. Now I should like to know who this owner of the elegant
                    Coupe is. His business I can very well guess, and I mean to break that up if
                    such a thing can be done fairly.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>I dont believe you missed the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> &amp; me a
                    bit, the day we left you. I told you in my note from Buffalo how I was haunted
                    &amp; bewitched, and you <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> express a word of
                    sympathy, nor a single suggestion of how I am to be cured. Are you perfectly
                    sure that you have what most women possess <hi rend="underline">a heart</hi>.
                    You must have had one at some period of your life, but I am afraid you have lost
                    or mislaid it. And if I thought I could recover it I would advertise for it in
                    the Metropolitan Journal of Boydton with a reward, under a flowing caption of
                    "Lost, Stolen or Mislaid." If you <pb n="5"/> had it back in your possession you
                    would have at least felt sorry for sufferings I "owned up" to. Well wait till I
                    see you again. There will be a most thorough search made for it, and if found I
                    shall claim its ownership by right of discovery.</p>

                <p>I had made up my mind to write you a brief biographical sketch &amp;
                    historical Memoir of myself, but I am not yet sure I would find in you a very
                    appreciative reader, and I should thus be greatly mortified to see so much
                    labour thrown away. With the designs <pb n="6"/> upon you which I have, perhaps
                    it best to let you act as all attacked people do, find out all you can yourself
                    about the enemy and then decide upon your measures of defence or surrender as
                    may seem most expedient. As I have always held, a man is a fool to try to win a
                    woman on paper. It gives her too long to think and make up her mind that she
                        "<orig reg="won't">wont</orig>." Therefore I am not going to <hi
                        rend="underline">write</hi> rhapsodies of love to you, but I am coming to
                    see you, to sit by you, walk out with you, talk you incessantly, stay a week if
                    necessary and with your hand in mine make you <pb n="7"/> answer questions like
                    a witness in Court. You <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> believe me yet, when I
                    tell you how deeply I fell in love with you. But you <hi rend="underline"
                    >shall</hi> believe it. I will say to you very frankly <hi rend="underline"
                    >why</hi> you have filled a void in my heart. It is not simply because you are a
                    beautiful girl, that joyous happy beauty that always charmed me. I know others
                    as beautiful. But I detected in you traits of character that I can love
                    &amp; worship. I saw that towards those who had claims upon you, you were
                    all affection &amp; gentleness. A sister &amp; a daughter so loving as
                    you are in your own family, would make <pb n="8"/> Heaven of any man's home upon
                    whom you would lavish your overflowing affections. I should feel if once
                    completely master of your heart that you would be one of the dearest, truest,
                    sweetest, most loving little wives in the world. One of those rare wives
                    nowadays, to <del hand="h1">which</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">whom</add> a weary husband would fly after a day
                    of work &amp; harassment, as the one loving soul to <orig reg="sympathize"
                        >sympathise</orig> with him, to receive his caresses &amp; pettings, and
                    to make him feel that his <hi rend="underline">home</hi> was of all places on
                    earth, the only refuge from care and trouble.</p>

                <pb n="9"/>

                <p>You may not know it, but I have discovered, that as a married woman you would
                    make <hi rend="underline">home</hi> your world. Now such a woman ought to have
                    an <orig reg="appreciative">appreciate</orig> husband, for if she is not loved
                    as dearly as she loves, her dreams of life are blasted. <hi rend="underline"
                    >You</hi> have no middle ground to live upon in your future. You must be almost
                    supremely happy or you will be miserable in your wedded life. It is a high
                    responsibility to undertake to guarantee your happiness, but if you will learn
                    to love me I think I could safely promise you a very happy life. I am sure <pb
                        n="10"/> that if my suit every prospers I shall be safe, for I am painfully
                    conscious that I have no ground to hope for your favor unless I win your <hi
                        rend="underline">heart</hi>. There are no external considerations in my case
                    to dazzle or flatter a fair young girl like you.</p>

                <p>If you are ever mine it will be a love match. This conviction it is that excites
                    my apprehensions so much, for no indications have you ever given me of any favor
                    in your sight beyond friendly regard, except the promise you made me that you
                    would <hi rend="underline">try</hi> to think favorably of my suit. Are you <hi
                        rend="underline">trying</hi>?</p>

                <pb n="11"/>

                <p>I am so sorry Mrs Sharp will be away when I am again in Mecklenburg. My
                    admiration for her had no small share in your winning my heart. She is as sweet
                    &amp; good as she can be, and you are her sister &amp; like her in many
                    traits.</p>

                <p>My departure hence to Virginia is a little indefinite. I Cannot leave <abbr
                        expan="New">N.</abbr> York till after I get together the Board of Directors
                    of our land <abbr expan="Company">Compy</abbr>. And as some of them are out of
                    the city, and their return uncertain I have fixed no day for the meeting. I will
                    inform you when <pb n="12"/> I go back, &amp; then when I can spare a week
                    to Mecklenburg. I hope it will be very soon.</p>

                <p>Write to me at once, and please write me long letters. You <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> know what a pleasure it is to get your letters. When you are my
                    little "wifey" &amp; come here with me I shall not be in such a hurry to go
                    home, for home will be where you are. <hi rend="underline">Tell me if you are
                        keeping your promise</hi> to <hi rend="underline">try</hi>. Will deliver
                    your message to <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> F. when I see him. Good bye.
                    Affectionate messages to all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Most truly &amp; sincerely Yours</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">J.D. Imboden</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
