<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9619"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9619">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, May
                    18, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, may 18 1861</title>
        <author>Lightner, John P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9619</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502781</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, May 18, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, may 18 1861</title>
            <author>John P. Lightner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-05-18">1861-05-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Enlistment, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9619T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>Lightner complains to Kate that excitement and preparations for the war have
                    taken over the town of Lexington, interrupting classes at Washington College. He
                    also describes some of the enlistment rallies and prayer meetings held in
                    Lexington, and considers the possiblity that he will soon have to join the army
                    as well.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-05-18">May 18<hi rend="super">th</hi> "61</date>
                        <name type="place">Washington College</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend;</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your eyes no doubt have grown dim, in looking for an answer from your old firend.
                    It is a great pleasure, or rather a privilege to have whom you can call a
                    friend. Friendship has ever been considered the purest affection of the human
                    heart. A person who has none in whom she or he can <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >con</add>fide, or call a true friend, is certainly in want of some of the
                    best qualities peculiar to our common humanity.</p>

                <p>I hardly know what to write about, for you hear nothing but war, war, all the
                    time. People are entirely too much taken up with the excitement. Their minds
                    should be elevated above <pb n="2"/>it, if such a thing could be possible. I
                    never saw such a time since my existence, &amp; never want to again, as was
                    in the streets of Lexington when the first companies were called out. Every body
                    nearly was crying, when they were prayed for by Dr. M<hi rend="super"
                    >c</hi>Farland.</p>

                <p>An old man, standing upon an elevation with his arms stretched towards the
                    heavens, presented the most effecting scene I ever witnessed. In a most solemn
                    tone, and it appeared like it came from his very heart. I suppose you have heard
                    so much about war, that you are like myself, and are tired of it. I have the
                    blues very badly, I felt this morning like taking the woods &amp; staying
                    there</p>

                <p>My class has but very little studying to do, &amp; they wont quit, graduate
                    us, give us more to do, nor nothing else. I am getting extremely tired of <pb
                        n="3"/>this sort of doing. You have no idea how wearisome it is to stay here
                    without doing anything. I would almost as soon be in jail, if it were not for
                    the name of the thing.</p>

                <p>May-be, I'll get there soon enough. I did not think you were so hard hearted, as
                    to reject the love of him who had once been true to you, had again confessed
                    &amp; come back, how could you decline him? ah well it is all for the best,
                    I <orig reg="reckon">recon</orig>. I visited the lady you sent your love to, who
                    sent me the apple while I was "lying in" as the saying is. I did not give her
                    your thanks, merely because I did not think of it. She seemed to be right
                    smartly down-cast; her only brother, started for war a few days ago, in the
                    "Rock-bridge Grays". I suppose you will handily present the flag, to the <pb
                        n="4"/>Augusta Grays, as they have been called out. I'm much obliged to you
                    for your invitation, to attend the delightful scene. You spoke of <abbr
                        expan="William">W<hi rend="super">m</hi></abbr> Brand in very favorable
                    terms. I'm glad he has reformed, if many more would only follow his foot-steps.
                    They have a daily prayer-meeting appointed here now as time set apart to pray
                    for the soldiers. It is not very well attended. But if there are but 2 or 3
                    &amp; have met for the right purpose God has <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >promised to</add> be one in their midst.</p>

                <p>I don't believe there is any news in the neighborhood here. I was at home last
                    week. It was quite a treat to me. But did not stay there but two or three days.
                    So I did not get to see my old friend on South River. But I shall visit you next
                    Summer, if nothing happens. No doubt I'll have to shoulder my musket before that
                    time, but I hope &amp; pray that a higher power will frustrate the plans
                    &amp; schemes of wicked men. But it is the will of the Almighty, &amp;
                    we should submit willingly</p>

                <p>Give my love to who you please &amp; write soon. <pb n="1"/>You must excuse
                    me for this hastily written. I promise to do better the next time may be we will
                    communicate face to face, for it is very uncertain about my staying here much
                    longer. I still remember you, Remember me</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your True Friend</salute>
                    <signed>Jno. P. L.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
