<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9610"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9610">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December
                    25, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 25 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, John D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9610</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502772</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, December 25, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john d imboden to annie lockett, december 25 1870</title>
            <author>John D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: John D. Imboden Papers,
                            1831-1895, Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                            University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-12-25">1870-12-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Women, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2007-03-29">2007-03-29</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofed</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9610T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In this Christmas letter, Imboden imagines future holidays with Annie and urges
                    her, once again, to set a firm date for their wedding. He promises that he will
                    return to Virginia as soon as he meets with the other board members of his land
                    company. He also notes the importance of a new railroad for Mecklenburg County
                    and the rest of Virginia's tobacco-producing region.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-12-25">Christmas night 1870</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dearest little darling-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Although it is nearly midnight I will not go to bed till I have had a bit of
                    holiday talk with you.</p>

                <p>This has been as dull and stupid a day as you can imagine. It is too cold to go
                    out of doors much. So I have remained in all day, reading, talking, and tonight
                    writing several letters. I have thought if I was with you how differently I
                    would spend the day. Thank Goodness I will not much longer be spending these
                    long lonesome evenings away from you. I wonder sometimes if you <orig
                        reg="won't">wont</orig> get tired of being petted like a spoilt child when I
                    get you in hand.</p>

                <pb n="2"/>

                <p>You threatened in your last letter received nearly a week ago, that you would not
                    write to me again soon, saying that I ought to write you 3 letters for 1
                    received. I have been doing that I think, but I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    see the justice of the rules, even if you have "a number of other poor fellows
                    to attend to" - and I only you &amp; Miss Parke to write to. By the way I
                    wrote her a mighty sweet <abbr expan="Christmas">Xmas</abbr> letter to day,
                    which I know she will enjoy when she gets it next Friday. I <orig reg="won't"
                        >wont</orig> tell you what pretty things I said to her in wishing her many a
                    merry Christmas.</p>

                <p>When I contrast in my mind the difference in the enjoyment of this festive season
                    down in our dear old Virginia, with what it was ten years ago, it makes me very
                    sad. The bright joyous happy homes we then had, no longer exist. And it will be
                    many long, long years before they are returned.</p>

                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>I am becoming very impatient to get away from <abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> York.
                    Tomorrow's steamer from Liverpool will I hope enable me almost to name a day
                    when I will get off, though it may be two or three weeks distant. <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> Flournoy has not come to <abbr expan="New"
                    >N.</abbr> York and writes that he will not until <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col</abbr> M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Kaye arrives from England.</p>

                <p>You must not be disheartened about the <abbr expan="railroad">R.R</abbr>. The
                    Norfolk people, and many on the line of the Eastern end are pondering a course
                    to embarrass &amp; delay it very much, but they will be obliged in the end
                    to do what we have so urgently inpressed upon them - make the necessary
                    subscriptions, especially in lands to insure the work.</p>

                <p>If you do not get a <abbr expan="railroad">R.R.</abbr> your part of the State
                    will become literally a wilderness in a few years more. The people cannot stay
                    there &amp; pay taxes on their waste lands, and live. They must build the
                    road or go away.</p>

                <pb n="4"/>

                <p>I want you to have thought over the subject in all its bearings, and be prepared
                    when I come to <hi rend="underline">name</hi> that all important day, so that I
                    may then work my business into such a shape, that when we are married, I will
                    have a few weeks of comparative <orig reg="leisure">leizure</orig> to <del
                        hand="h1">bestow</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">devote</add> my time exclusively to the pleasure
                    of my sweet little bride. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> intend to permit
                    business or anything else to <hi rend="underline">separate</hi> as much. If I
                    have much running about to do, I am going to take you along. Life is too short
                    for people who love each other to be spending it apart. Until you are actually
                    my wife, I can bear the Separation patiently - indeed I don't know, but that it
                    is less painful not to meet too often &amp; have to part again - but it will
                    not be so when people call you "Mrs. Imboden."</p>

                <p>With a thousand kisses I wish you a happy Christmas &amp; New Year. And trust
                    that for many long years to come it will be in my power to make you feel that
                    each recurrence of the season is more delightful than the last.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>With kind regards to all, I am sincerely and with all my heart yours,</salute>
                    <signed>JD Imboden</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I have not yet got the run of your slow mails in your
                        mind. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know what days to look for letters.
                        This I suppose will not reach you till Friday next. It is too bad to have to
                        wait ten days or a fortnight for a reply to a letter. But it must be borne I
                        suppose. But how long? Oh! how long? You will tell me when I come, till then
                        patience - patience.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
