<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9616"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9616">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout,
                    February 16, 1861</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, february 16 1861</title>
        <author>Lightner, John P.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9616</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502778</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: John P. Lightner to Kate Armentrout, February 16, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta john p lightner to kate armentrout, february 16 1861</title>
            <author>John P. Lightner</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-02-16">1861-02-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9616T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>Lightner apologizes to Kate for not writing her more often; he then continues to
                    discuss family, friends, and local social events. He mentions the formation of a
                    "Union Prayer meeting" in Lexington as well as other cities and towns. It is not
                    clear if this is a prayer meeting for the benefit of the United States
                    government or one that involves several different religious denominations.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-02-16">Feb. 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1861</date>
                        <name type="place">Washington College</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Friend;</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I <abbr expan="received">recd</abbr> your letter dated Jan 1<hi rend="super"
                    >st</hi>. I was much gratified on its reception. I can hardly realize that
                    nearly 2 months have elapsed since I <abbr expan="received">rec'd</abbr> it.</p>

                <p>Your intentions were very pious, in the beginning of your letter, but they did
                    not have very much influence on me, as I have been very remiss in not answering
                    sooner. I have been very unwell for several days. A <hi rend="super">cold</hi>
                    was so cruel as to catch me by <hi rend="super">stratagem</hi> or I caught it,
                    one or the other of the ways. I am almost speechless, a certain young <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">lady</add> manifested a great deal of sympathy for
                    me, sent me a very nice apple &amp;c. You made inquiry as to how I enjoyed
                    myself Holidays. In reply, I had a <unclear>
                        <hi rend="underline">soster</hi>
                    </unclear> of a time. I was in need of exercise, corporeal <pb n="2"/>exercise
                    especially. You seemed to be very much grieved because I did not come to see
                    you, when I was so close, &amp; used such an expression, that I had forsaken
                    you, so true a friend. But I can reply for your consolation, that I have not
                    forgotten nor forsaken you, though you think my actions may be that way in their
                    tendency. Oh! no, it could not be possible. I cannot be very punctual in my
                    correspondence, because I have a great many letters to write, &amp; College
                        <add hand="h1" place="inline">duties</add> are getting more burdensome. Our
                    examinations have been going on for <del hand="h1">A</del> about 3 or 4 week;
                    had it not been for them I certainly would have responded sooner than now. I
                    could not well visit you when i was down, for the simple reason that I took home
                    with me one of my schoolmates, &amp; was expecting him every day to see me,
                    &amp; furthermore my mammy told me, as I had been away from home so long, I
                    must stay with her. Had it not been for these two obstacles in the way, with
                    pleasure I would certainly have visited you. Though you did not demand any
                    excuse for my selfishness, or whatever term you may give to it, yet I thought I
                    had better give one "ane way" as the fellow said. You have gotten my likeness at
                    last. You thought I looked very solemn, most assuredly I did, for had I laughed,
                    the old machine would have broken into innumerable fragments. That would have
                    been a pity wouldn't it? You spoke of having relations near town, have not
                    become acquainted with them yet. One of them came to College bearing a message
                        <pb n="3"/>for your old Friend, but we missed each other some how or other,
                    &amp; I have not gotten it yet. Cannot think who it is from, unless from my
                    friend Miss Kate. am solicitous to know what it may be.</p>

                <p>I remember of seeing Miss Sallie <unclear>M<hi rend="super">c</hi>C.</unclear>
                    the evening I was down in your neighborhood. I did not think she would recognize
                    me, having been separated so long. How are you getting along with your singing
                    society on the Creek. It would afford me pleasure to attend as scenes there have
                    occured that time can never obliterate from my memory. I can almost imagine my
                    self within the walls of that schoolroom, &amp; mingling my voice with the
                    voices of those who are near &amp; dear to me.</p>

                <p>But such days as those have gone a glimmering. I think that was a mighty cruel
                    wish in that young man to make, whom you had reference to in yours. I think I
                    could harly let my tongue use such language, though it <del hand="h1">get</del>
                    deceives me sometimes, what is Lucian doing anyhow? I heard that Astidore was
                    very sick. I hope he will recover. You spoke of something about war I think
                    there can hardly be any such in this Christian land, I can hardly believe that
                    the cup of her iniquity is yet full, &amp; <hi rend="underline">this</hi>
                    require many years, as we are taught in the Bible.</p>

                <p><pb n="4"/>You spoke of getting a Christmas gift a "gold heart." If you have mine
                    I hope it is not quite so <hi rend="underline">hard</hi> as that gold one. Well
                    I must <del hand="h1">close</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">stop</add> until Society closes. I have again
                    seated myself to finish this uninteresting epistle to you. I have no news worth
                    your attention. They have formed a Union Prayer meeting in <abbr
                        expan="Lexington">Lex</abbr>. A great deal of interest is manifested in it.
                    You have no doubt read about the Union prayer meeting in some of our Northern
                    cities. The students of College have a prayer meeting once a week. Sometimes it
                    is very attended, other times it is not.</p>

                <p>Well I must close, asking pardon for this scribble. Remember me, at all times, I
                    close, with the assertion, I remain</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>your true Friend</salute>
                    <signed>Jno. P. Lightner</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
