<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9624"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9624">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta: Annie Armentrout to Kate Armentrout,
                    February 8, 1862</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta annie armentrout to kate armentrout, february 8 1862</title>
        <author>Trenton, Annie</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Jaime Martinez</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9624</idno>

                <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
                <availability status="public">
                    <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                    <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
                </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
                <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502786</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Annie Armentrout to Kate Armentrout, February 8, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta annie armentrout to kate armentrout, february 8 1862</title>
            <author>Annie Trenton</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: William Brand Papers, Albert and
                            Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library,
                    University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-02-08">1862-02-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Enlistment, Home Front, Patriotism,
                        Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9624T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 id="d3" type="summary">
                <p>Annie writes to Kate with news of their friends and family, including visits from
                    soldiers and deaths and illness among their acquaintances. She also discusses
                    the "traitors" from West Virginia. Included among her other news, Annie mentions
                    the wedding of David Hourtz and Margaret Freeman, whose marriage announcement
                    appeared in the Staunton Spectator, January 26, 1862.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 id="d5" type="letter">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Miss Kate Armentrout <lb/>Greenville <lb/>Augusta Co.
                    Va.</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-02-08">Feb the 8<hi rend="super">th</hi> '62</date>
                        <name type="place">Rose Dale Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister Kate,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>If you think it is so lonely since the "V. Rts." left I will try &amp; have
                    you forget them a few moments, by reading a letter from Home for fear if you
                    think of them so much you will become troublesome on aunt's hands. And I now
                    don't wonder at you feeling lonely, since I have heard that that <hi
                        rend="underline">certain <unclear>Mister</unclear></hi> is out of reach of
                    his "<hi rend="underline">Plug of tobacco</hi>," &amp; so far away from "<hi
                        rend="underline">his Cousin Janey</hi>." Now Kate dont go to grieving about
                    him, for I will have <hi rend="underline">him a plug</hi> by the <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">time</add> you get home, not <hi rend="underline">worth</hi>
                    while though to get it before <hi rend="underline">as you have forbid him coming
                        until you return "for fear he would fall in love with me</hi>."</p>

                <p>You did not think Miss I would hear all of that but it was too good for the boys
                    to keep; they were still in town, last night, but expected to start this
                    morning. Frank came out Tuesday night &amp; he John Hinton &amp;
                        <unclear>Rubing</unclear> R. came out Wednesday evening &amp; stayed
                    until yesterday morning. John &amp; Doc said yesterday morning that they
                    were coming out tonight if they did not have to leave, by the way Jno. is a
                    pleasant boy; I would never known him.</p>

                <p>Kate we got a letter from John Thursday, he is very well &amp; five miles
                    from Winchester, busy making their cabins, expect to stay there two or three
                    months, but I expect "Will" has given you all that information, as we have not
                    had the pleasure of reading a letter from him you were mindful enough to let him
                    know where to direct his. Capt Newton is at home expects to go back next week.
                    Jim &amp; George started yesterday, they were here <del hand="h1">Saturday</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">Sunday</add> night I believe Jim looked sadder
                    than he did when he first went away, spoke of having to go alone, without his
                        <orig reg="comrade">comrad</orig>: <hi rend="underline">Sallie &amp; Sue
                        will sympathize with you!!!</hi></p>

                <p>Kate, George Jr. is still improving but John is worse he was so much deranged the
                    first of this week that it took four men to keep him in bed <pb n="2"/>his
                    Father is still with him &amp; says he has but little hopes of his recovery.
                    I am sorry, but John is a good <orig reg="pious">pius</orig> boy, &amp; God
                    knows all things best. I have something sad to tell you. Andy Mallure's little
                    boy Frank fell in the fire last Friday &amp; was burned so bad that it died
                    Saturday evening. Sue S. wrote to me that she would never forget its screams so
                    severe was its suffering, its little head was burnt very bad &amp; one arm
                    nearly burnt off. Sue said Mrs. Mallure is almost distracted about it there was
                    no one in the room except little Phebe &amp; you know her helplessness. The
                    nurse had just left the room &amp; he got up to walk across the hearth
                    &amp; fell. Dr Tate also buried his little boy last week, it died with the
                    diphtheria.</p>

                <p>Miss Jinnie's school closed yesterday none of us was over it was late before Doc
                    Jno. Rubing left &amp; I did not feel like going. Hetty has only went one
                    week since you went away she had such a bad cold &amp; pain in her head that
                    she told her to bring her books home, &amp; you know that pleased her very
                    well.</p>

                <p>Cousin George Armentrout is at home, he came home Thursday. George Kiser has gone
                    to his company again. Tom brought Sue up Thursday. George started from home. I
                    have not seen Mag or Rachel nor Sam since I got your letter but will deliver
                    your messages when I see them. Mr <unclear>Shieles</unclear> was at Strausburg
                    last week did you see him pass by the Springs, he went with the <orig
                        reg="wagon">waggon</orig>. I would have written to you that he was coming in
                    my other letter but Lizzie &amp; Ma told me I had dreamed it, &amp; I
                    thought perhaps I was mistake, but the next day I saw Mary Catherine at the
                    school house &amp; she said he had started on Friday, he took Soldiers <orig
                        reg="clothes">cloths</orig> down. Cib got home last Tuesday I have not seen
                    him yet. Father says he looks tolerable well.</p>

                <p>Kate I have a notion to make me a muslin quilt. I want you <pb n="3"/>to ask
                    Fannie Lincorn &amp; Jany Eliza Koontz, Mag &amp; Kate C. Cous A: all my
                    acquaintances for a peace of their dresses to put in it to remember them, if you
                    get any you must send them by Pa he still talks of coming but I dont know when.
                    Ma says the weather is too uncertain to leave home with Flossie now.</p>

                <p>Flossie was delighted to think that letter was directed to her she had just been
                    wishing to Ellen that she would get a letter from the post office directed to
                    her &amp; Ellen told on her after she got yours: she wants you to tell her
                    how you stewed your fruit. Said I should tell you John wrote he was going to
                    make her a ring out of <orig reg="laurel">Laural</orig> root, &amp; that she
                    had broke Willie's other arm off, &amp; Strawberry was married to Mr
                    Woodrow. She would like to see Cous Amanda: Mary &amp; Ella, you must bring
                    Amanda home with you!</p>

                <p>Miss Freman &amp; Mr Hurtz was married last Thursday a week. I heard last
                    Sunday that she was taking the fever. I dont know whether it is so or not she
                    was down at Mr Shovers he married Jane's sister. Kate I reckon you saw that
                    piece in the register that spoke of hanging those traitors from western Virginia
                    among them George Aubry. I dont <orig reg="pity">pitty</orig> him much for he
                    had taken up arms against our boys out there &amp; was orderly <orig
                        reg="sergeant">sargent</orig> in a <orig reg="Lincoln">Lincorn</orig>
                    company, so Jim Hawpe told me.</p>

                <p>Well Kate I have some work to do today &amp; must soon close. Uncle Peter
                    &amp;c all well. Bell &amp; John were in town to see the boys last week
                    &amp; Kate tell Mag &amp; Kate I would like to see them give my love to
                    them Fannie &amp; Eliza Jany <unclear>vine</unclear>, S. &amp; all my
                    acquaintances. Mother says tell Aunt she would like to come down but the weather
                    is so bad &amp; the roads so muddy that she cant this winter, but I will try
                    to get Sam to come, if the <orig reg="militia">Malitia</orig> dont get him. Jake
                    talks of joining a Cavalry company if he goes in the Spring.</p>

                <p>Now I must stop dont forget to answer soon all join me in love to you &amp;
                    all kinfolks. Lizzie says she will write soon. Take good care of your health
                    &amp; <hi rend="underline">tobacco</hi>.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Be good good bye <lb/>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Aff</abbr> Sister</salute>
                    <signed>Annie Trout</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><pb n="2"/>P.S. Oh Kate I forgot to tell you that <hi
                            rend="underline">Rubing</hi> is so much smitten with you too, he was
                        looking in <orig reg="every">evry</orig> corner to see your name or
                        something that resembled you. now if you dont do something for yourself this
                        trip as Lizzie Pilson says you need not try any more. Kate you have got to
                        let me know when you hear from Moses or Rubing. Kate you will think I have
                        got right funny since you left after you read this. Well its no use to be
                        always sad. Write soon Annie</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
