<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9703"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9703">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: William Cabell Rives to Alexander H.
                    H. Stuart, January 7, 1868</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county william cabell rives to alexander h h stuart, january 7 1868</title>
        <author>Rives, William Cabell</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Philip Herrington</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9703</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502814</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: William Cabell Rives to Alexander H. H. Stuart,
                            January 7, 1868</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county william cabell rives to alexander h h stuart, january 7 1868</title>
            <author>William Cabell Rives</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Alexander H. H. Stuart Papers,
                            Manuscript Collection 228-a, Special Collections, University of Virginia
                            Library</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1868-01-07">1868-01-07</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9703T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Citing ill health, William Cabell Rives declines to write a national political
                    address; the context of the letter links the address with the constitutional
                    convention of Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1868-01-07">7 Jan. 1868.</date>
                        <name type="place">Castle-Hill</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Ever since the receipt of your letter of 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> ult., I have
                    been exceedingly indisposed, &amp; unable to give you a satisfactory answer
                    on a subject into which the state of my health necessarily intrudes as a ruling
                    element. Allow me first to address to my very deep sense of the great honor you
                    did me by placing me at the head of the committee to propose an address to the
                    people of the United States, &amp; I assure <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >you</add> of the devoted zeal with which I should assist in the execution
                    of this most important task, if my health enabled me to undertake it - on my
                    return from the Springs last autumn, I had a very violent &amp; obstinate
                    attack of nervous, inter<pb n="2"/>mittent fever, from the effects of which I am
                    still suffering. My health is so precarious that I cannot count upon it to
                    sustain me in any serious intellectual effort. Unless it should greatly improve,
                    therefore, it would be impossible for me to engage in the task, which, I
                    understand from what you say, devolves, in your opinion, on me as chairman of
                    the committee, unless <del hand="h1">it should be</del> otherwise ordered by the
                    committee themselves. - If an address be expected at present, or at any early
                    period, I must of necessity decline the preparation of it in the actual state of
                    my health, &amp; turn it over to the able gentlemen you have associated with
                    me on the committee. If, on the contrary, the address be not expected now, or at
                    some early period, anx<pb n="3"/>ious I am to do whatever might be in my power
                    to justify your selection. I would still hold the matter under further
                    advisement. - I observed, from the proceedings of your convention published in
                    the newspapers, that the central or executive <add hand="h1" place="inline"
                        >committee</add> was to designate the time when the address should be
                    published, and I thought it likely that they would <del hand="h1">think</del>
                    <add hand="h1" place="inline">consider</add> it expedient to postpone it, until
                    the convention now in session in Richmond should close their labours, &amp;
                    enable us to see what sort of constitution they intend for us. But I infer from
                    a letter received from Mr. Randolph <unclear>Tucker</unclear>, a day <pb n="4"
                    />or two ago, that an address is expected from the committee at an early day,
                    &amp; under these circumstances, I feel constrained to decline a task for
                    which I have <add hand="h1" place="inline">not</add> now requisite strength,
                    &amp; cannot expect from my present condition, to have in any short time. I
                    will, nevertheless, most cheerfully contribute my services as a member of the
                    committee in consultation with my colleagues when any address which shall be
                    proposed by any one of them. -</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I remain, my dear sir, with the greatest respect most truly yours</salute>
                    <signed>W. C. Rives</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Honble</abbr> A. A. Stuart
                            &amp;c &amp;c</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
