<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9806"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9806">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta: Patrick Brady to Alexander H. H. Stuart,
                    July 13, 1867</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta patrick brady to alexander h h stuart, july 13 1867</title>
        <author>Brady, Patrick</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Andrew Meade McGee</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew Meade McGee</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9806</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502830</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta: Patrick Brady to Alexander H. H. Stuart, July 13, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta patrick brady to alexander h h stuart, july 13 1867</title>
            <author>Patrick Brady</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Patrick Brady to Alexander H. H.
                            Stuart, July 13, 1867, Alexander H. H. Stuart Papers, Albert and Shirley
                            Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-07-13">1867-07-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9806T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Patrick Brady of Philadelphia writes to A. H. H. Stuart regarding a pending
                    lawsuit against Daniel Brady of Buffalo Forge in Rockbridge County, his
                    financial woes, and a missing ledger.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Hon H. H. Stuart Esq Staunton Va</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-07-13">July 13. 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Philad<hi rend="super">a</hi></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I now beg to give you my views with regard to a settlement with Brady. I want him
                    to give me a deed for the Bath iron works, also the Bonds for Five thousand
                        <abbr expan="Dollars">Doll</abbr>, to be transferred to me and to pay me one
                    thousand <abbr expan="Dollars">dolls.</abbr> Semi Annually for ten years with
                    interest, the first payment to be made on the first January next, and to pay
                    your fee for effecting a settlement with him. <pb n="2"/>I must have something
                    tangible as I have debts that must be paid or secured by something substantial,
                    he must have the control of money or securities as his own family are to
                    received Nearly all the legacies left by Weaver. My Claim for the amount <hi
                        rend="underline">stolen</hi> with interest amounts to 32.160 <abbr
                        expan="Dollars">Dolls</abbr> which amount I must have paid to me and to
                    Cover up which my Ledger has been stolen from my Office. But fortunately I have
                    copies of the transaction which I can prove by two witnesses who took the copies
                    from the Ledger &amp; compared with the Cash Book.</p>
                <p><pb n="3"/>Mr. Dickson is also aware of the alteration of Book, having comparred
                    the entries on the Cash Book &amp; Ledger.</p>
                <p>I consider this last theft as bad or worse than the first and I am determined to
                    sift it to the bottom as no person but Brady could have had any interest in
                    taking the ledger from <hi rend="super">my</hi> office, under these
                    circumstances, I must insist on having some justice done Me for God knows he has
                    caused me a large amount of trouble by his Course, when it should have been
                    other wise after all I did for him -- <pb n="4"/>My dear Mr. Stuart I hope You
                    will succeed making this settlement for me as soon as possible and in getting
                    all the Security that is possible for I have lost all Confidence in him, in whom
                    unfortunately I had paled too much I beg you will urge a speedy settlement as I
                    have pressing claims on Me.</p>
                <p>I trust your Son has recovered entirely from illness. Waiting your answer I
                    remain</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very truly Yours &amp;c</salute>
                    <signed>P Brady</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
