<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="A9904"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="A9904">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett,
                    October 20, 1870</title>
        <title>[electronic resource] </title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, october 20 1870</title>
        <author>Imboden, J.D.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Josh Botts</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">A9904</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://valley.vcdh.virginia.edu/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1993-2005, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1993 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:502847</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: John D. Imboden to Annie Lockett, October 20, 1870</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county john d imboden to annie lockett, october 20 1870</title>
            <author>J.D. Imboden</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: J.D. Imboden to Miss Annie, Oct.
                            20, 1870, John D. Imboden Papers, University of Virginia Library,
                            Accession Numbers 38-23, 580, 599, 2983a</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1870-10-20">1870-10-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Reunification, Economy, Women, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="A9904T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Imboden explains his delay in returning to Virginia to visit a young woman. He
                    delivered a speech about Robert E. Lee in New York.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1870-10-20">Oct. 20, 1870</date>
                        <name type="place"><abbr expan="New">N.</abbr> York</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear dear Miss Annie</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am sure my reputation with you is almost gone, as a wave of truth and fixed
                    purpose. But never since I came on here have I had it in my power to say when I
                    would get away. At one time I was about ready to go when my brother's affairs
                    got tangled and delayed me two weeks. During that time I became involved in
                    matter of my own of so much importance that I could not let go and return to
                    Virginia. Now all is arranged so that so far as business is concerned I could
                    &amp; would start home on Saturday. But this week the admirers of <abbr
                        expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee have held several preliminary meetings and
                    resolved to hold here on Monday night a Minister meeting to do honor to his
                    memory. I was appointed chairman of the committee on resolutions, and <pb n="2"
                    />last night reported what I had written, which was received with so much favor
                    that I was unanimously approved to present the paper to the Mass Meeting at
                    Cooper Institute on Monday night. I begged to be let off, but no excuse would be
                    taken &amp; I was compelled to consent to do so. I enclose you a copy of
                    what I wrote. It was a difficult thing to prepare anything that would be just to
                        <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee's memory and yet not offend these
                    people. I am told I have succeeded. I shall sail from here for Norfolk on
                    Tuesday's steamer. Reaching there on Wednesday I may have to run over to <abbr
                        expan="North Carolina">N.C.</abbr> for two or three days &amp; then up
                    to Richmond. This will bring me so near the State Fair that I will not have time
                    to go to Mecklenburg before the fair and stay as long as I wish. I regret this
                    the less since receiving a letter from <pb n="3"/><abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr> Flournoy this week that he has certain propositions from Brunswick,
                    Lunenburg, &amp; Mecklenburg people about land, that he wishes me to go
                    there and attend to in November immediately after the Fair. It will take me from
                    2 to 4 weeks to attend to it, and I am arranging in my mind a plan for
                        <unclear>work</unclear> at after this Fair ends. That I will take a good
                    horse &amp; buggy from Richmond &amp; I make my headquarters at Lombardy
                    Grove &amp; branch out from there in all directions returning two or three
                    evenings in the week to spend a night there. I like that prospect for instead of
                    one short visit of a few days it will give me 10 or 15 visits of a night at a
                    time, and if I can't in that time make some impression on you, I will despair of
                    ever doing so, and will leave Mecklenburg forever a wiser &amp; a sadder man
                    - wiser by teach<pb n="4"/>ing me the folly of asking one so young, so sweet, so
                    good to love me - and sadder because I shall go out into the world again a man
                    denied.</p>

                <p>There is another reason I do not regret this delay. My daughters will reach
                    Richmond <abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr> 1<hi rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">st</hi>
                    </hi> and I will have a full and comfortable conversation with them about my
                    hopes and intentions. I wish you could be at the Fair. I want them to know you
                    as well as I do, and am sure they will love you as tenderly.</p>

                <p>Your last long sweet letter to Richmond was sent to me yesterday. A thousand
                    thanks for it dearest Miss Annie. I hope this will not be 8 days in reaching
                    you. So the <abbr expan="Post Master">P.M.</abbr> at Boydton guesses your <abbr
                        expan="New York">N.Y.</abbr> correspondent does he? &amp; caught you so
                    nicely. Love to all. And God bless you. I will now soon see you I hope.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Devotedly yours</salute>
                    <signed>J.D. Imboden</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">By my plan in <abbr expan="November">Nov.</abbr> I will
                        catch some of your other friends there &amp; see how things are going.
                        You can hardly keep them away a whole month. You might for a week.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
