<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AD1008"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="AD1008">
<teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Augusta County: Diary of James E. Beard (1861-1862)</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county diary of james e beard 1861 1862</title>
        <author>Beard, James E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Elizabeth Crocker</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Elizabeth Crocker</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 42 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">AD1008</idno>

        <!--
<availability>
<p>Publicly accessible </p>
<p n="public">URL:
http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
<p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the
University of Virginia</p>
</availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500330</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt> 
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow:  Two Communities in
the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Diary of James E. Beard</title>
            <title level="m"> </title>
            <title type="sort">diary of james e beard</title>
            <author>James E. Beard</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp>e.g. Translator</resp>
              <name>Ben
Ritter</name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt> 
            <p> </p> 
          </editionStmt>
          <extent/>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Diary of James E.
Beard.  Photocopy from the collection of the Fredericksburg-
Spotsylvania County Battlefields National Memorial Military
Park, Fredericksburg, Virginia.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>The Valley of the Shadow:  Two Communities in
the American Civil War</p>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt> 
            <note>
              <p>The Fredericksburg-Spotsylvania County
Battlefields National Memorial Military Park in
Fredericksburg, Virginia, holds a transcribed copy of the
Diary of James E. Beard.  The diary has possibly undergone a
minimal degree of revision by James Beard or subsequent
editors.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania National Battlefield Park</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <dateRange to="1861-08-08" from="1862-08-28">1861-08-08; 1862-08-28</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>
Camp Life, Battle Description, Enlistment, Death/Casualties,
Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement
</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-05">May 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against the transcription obtained from the
collections of the Fredericksburg-Spotsylvania County
Battlefields National Memorial Military Park in
Fredericksburg, Virginia.  According to the original
transcriber:  "The diary is in one note book, strung together
with a lot of commas, very few periods so the paragraphs are
my doing.  I read it into a tape recorder and wrote it out in
long hand and then typed it, so the original spelling and
maybe some of his meaning was lost."  Typographical errors by
the original transcriber, like "founght" for "fought," have
been corrected without comment.  The version from the National
Memorial Military Park contains notations in parentheses by
the original transcriber.  These notations have been tagged
according to TEI guidelines.  Dates in parentheses in the
version from the National Memorial Military Park have been
retained in this version.  In addition, for the sake of
clarity, this version of the Diary of James E. Beard includes
dates in [brackets] which are not in the version from the
National Memorial Military Park.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>

<text id="AD1008T">

<front id="d2">

<div1 id="AD1008bio" type="bio">
<head>Biography
<!-- <ref>AD1008bio</ref> -->
</head>

<p>James E. Beard, a 38-year-old farmer from Augusta County,
joined the 5th Virginia Infantry in August 1861.  His diary
recounts his life as a soldier in this regiment, including
details about engagements at Manassas and Winchester.  He also
describes his work as a paymaster for his company.  His diary
ends in 1862, when he was wounded at the Second Battle of
Manassas.  After the war he returned to farming and died in
Augusta County in 1906.</p>

</div1>
</front>

<body id="d4">



<div1 id="AD10081861" type="part" n="1861">
<head>1861
<!-- <ref>AD10081861</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1861-08" id="d6">
<head>August 1861
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Battle Description, Troop Movement</ref>
-->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-03" id="d7">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-08-03" to="1861-08-13">August 3 to August 13</dateRange>]</head>

<p>James E. Beard's</p>

<p>Diary of camp life commencing Aug. 3, 1861, left home in
the County of Augusta, State of Virginia, Aug. 11 (1861).
Started from Staunton on the morning of the 13th (Aug. 1861)
for Manassas by railroad. Traveled through the counties of
Albemarle, by Charlottesville, through Orange, Culpeper,
Fauquier, <abbr expan="Prince">Pr.</abbr> William and Fairfax,
nothing of interest occurring by the way. Arrived at Manassas
the same evening about 3 o'clock, left Manassas to join
Company D, of the 5th Virginia <abbr
expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> of <abbr
expan="Volunteers">Vols</abbr>, commanded by <abbr
expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> H. J. Williams, reached Bull's
Run, the stream being too full to cross that evening, went up
the stream a mile or more, lodged with the Washington
Artillery that night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-14" id="d8">
<head>[August 14, 1861]</head>
<p>Went on the next morning going over part of the ground
<orig reg="that"></orig> the great battle of Manassas Plains
was fought on the 21st of July 1861. Seeing many wrecks of
different kinds, from the effects of a <orig
reg="routed">rounted</orig> army. Crossed the stone bridge,
over the run, passed through the Village of Centerville, and
joined the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> at Camp Harman
near that place. We reached the camp about 9 o'clock a.
m.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-23" id="d9">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-08-23" to="1861-08-25">August 23 to August 25</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Nothing of interest transpired in camp until the evening of
the 23rd (Aug. 1861) of the same month, when were ordered down
below Fairfax <abbr expan="Court">C.</abbr> House and returned
the same evening about 11 o'clock p. m. and on the 25th (Aug.
1861) we marched two miles on the same road and
returned.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-08-28" id="d10">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-08-28" to="1861-09-29">August 28 to September 29</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Then on the 28th (Aug. 1861) we marched down to the <abbr
expan="Courthouse">C. H.</abbr> and returned the same same
day.</p>
<p>We remained in this camp until the 10th of Sept. 1861, when
we moved to a camp near Fairfax <abbr expan="Courthouse">C.
H.</abbr> where we remained until the 15th of October 1861.
While in this camp we went on picket twice, the first time we
went to Mason's Hill, the 23rd (Sept. 1861) where we had a
view of the dome of the once  Capitol of the <abbr
expan="United States">U. S.</abbr>, from thence went down to
the road leading to Alexandria at Padgets Tavern. On said road
about 5 miles from the city, we stayed there <abbr
expan="until">til</abbr> the night of the 27th (Sept. 1861),
when were marched back by <orig
reg="Accotink">Acquitink</orig> on the old Braddock Road.
After crossing the creek we camped at daylight on the morning
of the 28th (Sept. 1861) after marching all night, where we
remained during the day and night, and started the next
morning for our camp at Fairfax <abbr expan="Courthouse">C.
H.</abbr>, where we arrived about 11 o'clock in good
spirits.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1861-10" id="d11">
<head>October 1861
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, State Government</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-11" id="d12">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-10-11" to="1861-10-16">October 11 to October 16</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Nothing of note transpired in camp <abbr
expan="until">til</abbr> the 11th of October (1861), when we
started on picket to <orig reg="Accotink">Acquitink</orig>
where we remained 5 days, when we came back to camp on the
evening of the 15th (Oct. 1861) we got orders that night at 9
o'clock to strike our tents, and be ready to march next
morning at 3 o'clock, which we did, and marched to
Centerville, where we pitched our tents about 2
o'clock.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-10-30" id="d13">
<head>[October 30]</head>
<p>On the 30th October (1861) <abbr
expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Letcher was present and all the
Virginia <abbr expan="Regiments">Regts.</abbr> in this
encampment were paraded and a flag presented to each one, 17
in number and on the following evening there was a grand
review of all the troops in the encampment by the <abbr
expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> of Virginia.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1861-11" id="d14">
<head>November 1861
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-11-01" id="d15">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-11-01" to="1861-11-08">November 1 to November 8</dateRange>]</head>
<p>While here our regiment was on picket near Germantown, on
the road that leads from Fairfax <abbr expan="Courthouse">C.
H.</abbr> to Leesburg in Loudoun County, from the 1st to the
5th of November (1861). We remained in this camp until the 8th
of November (1861) when we broke up our encampment and marched
to Manassas and took the cars for Strasburg at 7 o'clock that
evening.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-11-09" id="d16">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-11-09" to="1861-11-18">November 9 to November 18</dateRange>]</head>
<p>At which place (Strasburg) we arrived next morning at
daylight. After getting breakfast we took up the line of march
toward Winchester, and pitched our camp near Kernstown, we
arrived at this camp the same evening through a drenching
rain. I stayed in Newtown this same night.</p>
<p>There was nothing of interest happened while here. We
remained here until the 18 (Nov. 1861) <orig reg="of this
month">inst.</orig> when we again broke up our encampment and
marched through Winchester and on below that place 4 miles
towards Martinsburg, where we encamped the same evening about
10 o'clock, Camp Stephenson.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-11-19" id="d17">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-11-19" to="1861-12-15">November 19 to December 15</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We remained in this camp until the evening of the 9th of
Dec. (1861) at 11 o'clock when 4 companies wore ordered out of
the regiment to go to dam No. 4, by way of <orig
reg="Charleston">Charles Town</orig> and Shepherdstown. Our
Company being one of the number. We took the cars at
Stephenson's Depot which is about a half a mile from where we
were then camped for <orig reg="Charleston">Charles
Town</orig>, getting there by daylight (10 Dec. 1861) at which
place we remained until midnight or some 18 hours and then set
out for the dam going by Shepherdstown. We stopped in the
sight of this place and ate some breakfast and then went on
going through the town without stopping.  Just after we passed
the town one of the companies was detailed to fire on some
boats belonging to the enemy that were coming up the canal,
the fire was returned but without effect on either side, so
far as we know.</p>

<p>Nothing worthy of note <orig
reg="occurring">occurring</orig> <abbr
expan="until">til</abbr> we came to Scrabble, from
Shepherdstown to this place we traveled through a fine section
of country. While here <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Ashby
and <abbr expan="Company">Com.</abbr> captured 8 of the enemy,
a Captain and seven privates belonging to the 12th Indiana
<abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr>. After remaining here about
3 hours we set off for Martinsburg where we arrived about 8
o'clock the same evening.</p></div3>
</div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1861-12" id="d18">
<head>December 1861
<!-- <ref>Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1861-12-17" id="d19">
<head><dateRange from="1861-12-17" to="1861-12-21">December 17-21</dateRange></head>
<p>We remained in this place (Martinsburg) until the evening
of the 17th (Dec. 1861) when the Brigade came on here, we then
marched to near Dam No. 5 arriving there about 9 o'clock P.
M., where we stayed overnight and fell back in the morning
acting in this way until the morning of the 21st (Dec. 1861).
Having destroyed the dam we set out for our camp beyond
Martinsburg, 15 miles distance, we stayed <unclear>2
1/2</unclear> miles above Martinsburg that night, and set out
early next morning for Camp Stephenson, and arrived there the
same evening.</p></div3></div2></div1>

<div1 id="AD10081862" type="part" n="1862">
<head>1862
<!-- <ref>AD10081862</ref> -->
</head>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-01" id="d21">
<head>January 1862
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement</ref>
-->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-01" id="d22">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-01-01" to="1862-01-02">January 1 to January 2</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Well nothing of interest in camp until the morning of the
1st day of January 1862, when we left this camp and marched in
the direction of Bath, Morgan <abbr expan="County">Co</abbr>.
We marched 12 miles that day through a mountainous and poor
country and stopped for the night. The next morning (Jan. 2,
1862) we left our camp again and marched to the cross roads
near Ungers Store on Sleepy Creek, the country still poor and
mountainous.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-03" id="d23">
<head>[January 3]</head>
<p>The next day (Jan. 3, 1862) we marched to within 6 miles of
Bath and camped for the night. It commenced snowing about
dark, it fell some 2 inches deep, we started next morning
(Jan. 4, 1862) about daylight for Bath, which place we reached
about 2 o'clock, where we put up for the night. The wagons did
not get up that night and we had to go without
supper.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-05" id="d24">
<head>[January 5]</head>
<p>The morning of the 5th (Jan. 1862) we had to go back about
a mile to meet our wagons. We then went on through Bath toward
Hancock on the river, where we stayed all day and in the
evening fell back a short distance and camped for the night,
the snow was falling fast, we remained here overnight. Our
wagons came up about 10 o'clock at night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-06" id="d25">
<head>[January 6]</head>
<p>The next morning (Jan. 6, 1862) we struck our tents and
moved back about a mile and pitched our tents and stayed all
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-07" id="d26">
<head>[January 7]</head>
<p>The next morning (Jan. 7, 1862) we again struck tents and
sent our baggage off by daylight. The Army had to remain <abbr
expan="until">till</abbr> the whole train of wagons, about
500, passed which took <abbr expan="until">til</abbr> 1
o'clock in the day. We then took up the line of march and
moved on slowly until after we passed through Bath some two
miles. We then commenced passing the train and moved on at a
brisk rate until we came to the cross roads, which place we
reached about <unclear>1</unclear> o'clock.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-08" id="d27">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-01-08" to="1862-01-15">January 8 to January 15</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We remained here with but little change in our camp until
the morning of the 13th (Jan. 1862) when we again struck tents
and took up the line of march for Romney at which place we
arrived on the evening of the 15th (Jan. 1862) <orig reg="of
this month">inst.</orig>, after a heavy and toilsome march of
45 miles through a mountainous and ragged country.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-01-16" id="d28">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-01-16" to="1862-02-07">January 16 to February 7</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Nothing of interest transpired while we were in this place
(Romney), being <orig reg="quartered">quarted</orig> in houses
we had no use for our tents. We stayed here until the morning
of the 23rd (Jan. 1862) when we started back to Winchester by
way of the Northwestern Grade and arrived near here on the
25th (Jan. 1862) and encamped 3 miles on the Romney Road.</p>
<p>I left Romney on the same morning for the Hospital in
Winchester sick with a cold a sore throat, I remained at this
place until the 3rd day of February 1862, when I again
rejoined the Company at Camp Zollicoffer to which place the
regiment moved on the 29th of Jan. (1862), and made
preparations for winter quarters, which we got into on the 7th
(Feb. 1862) <orig reg="of this month">inst</orig>.</p>
</div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-02" id="d29">
<head>February 1862
<!-- <ref>Medicine/Hospitals, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-02-22" id="d30">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-02-22" to="1862-02-27">February 22 to February 27</dateRange>]</head>
<p>I took the mumps the 22nd (Feb. 1862) <orig reg="of this
month">inst.</orig> and stayed in camp until the 27th (Feb.
1862) when I went to Winchester to the Hospital where I
remained until the 2nd March (1862), when I was sent to
Strasburg where I remained over night, and on the evening of
the 3rd (March 1862) started for the Hospital at Mt. Jackson
which place we arrived at 10 o'clock the same evening.</p>
<p>The <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> left their camp at
Zollicoffer on the 27th (Feb. 1862) and moved to within three
quarters of a mile of Winchester and went into their
tents.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-03" id="d31">
<head>March 1862
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Battle Description, Troop Movement</ref>
-->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-03-05" id="d32">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-03-05" to="1862-03-22"> March 5 to March 22</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The 5th of March (1862) the <abbr
expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> left this camp and moved about 5
miles and camped and then moved on next morning as far as
Cedar Creek where we camped until the morning of the 15th
(March 1862), when we again struck our tents and moved back as
far as Narrow Passage where we remained one night.</p>
<p>Then we fell back to within 4 1/2 miles of Mt. Jackson. I
left the Hospital at Mt. Jackson on the 6th (March 1862) and
joined the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> at Narrow
Passage about the time they were ready to move. I went down on
the cars as far as Edinburg and then walked out to the <abbr
expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> and marched back with it to a
camp some three miles from Mt. Jackson where we remained until
the 20th (March 1862) when we march 4 miles above Mt. Jackson
and remained about 24 hours, and then struck tents and marched
41 miles below Mt. Jackson and stayed one night, and again
struck tents and marched to near Cedar Creek 24 miles and
camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-03-23" id="d33">
<head>[March 23]</head>
<p>In the morning we again took up the line of march toward
Winchester, arrived at Newtown about 12 o'clock and passed on
through <unclear>22</unclear> miles, where we stayed some two
hours, while the Artillery and Cavalry were engaging the
enemy, we got into the fight about half hour by <del rend="none" hand="h1"></del>
where we remained until dark being twice repulsed by the
enemy, this happened on the 23rd (March 1862), when we left
the field in good order and fell back 4 miles and stayed all
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-03-24" id="d34">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-03-24" to="1862-03-26">March 24 to 26</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The next morning (March 24, 1862) we fell back to Cedar
Creek and cooked one days rations, before we had it <orig
reg="cooked">cook</orig> the enemy were advancing, and
commenced throwing bombs at us, we then fell back to the
Passage and stayed all night and until the next morning (March
25, 1862) when we marched up to a camp 4 1/2 miles from Mt.
Jackson and stayed all night and until the next morning (March
26, 1862) when we went back to the Passage and stayed two
nights and one day without anything of <orig
reg="occurrence">occurance</orig> happening while
there.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-03-28" id="d35">
<head>[March 28]</head>
<p>On the morning of the 28th (March 1862) we marched back to
a camp 4 1/2 miles from Mt. Jackson, this morning the enemy
was not advancing.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-04" id="d36">
<head>April 1862
<!-- <ref>Enlistment, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-01" id="d37">
<head>[April 1]</head>
<p>We left camp 4 1/2 miles from Mt. Jackson on the 1st day of
April (1862) and marched one mile down the pike where we
remained about one hour and then faced about and marched up
the road 4 miles and camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-02" id="d38">
<head>[April 2]</head>
<p>The next morning (April 2, 1862) we continued to go up the
pike until we got four miles above Mt. Jackson where <orig
reg="we"></orig> camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-04" id="d39">
<head>[April 4]</head>
<p>The next morning at 4 o'clock we took up the line and
marched down the road 9 miles and spent the day and in the
evening back to our camp 4 miles above Mt. Jackson, where we
are today at 12 o'clock 4th day of April 1862.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-06" id="d40">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-04-06" to="1862-04-10">April 6 to April 10</dateRange>]</head>
<p>On the 6th (April 1862) still in camp on Rood's Hill, spent
the day in the Militia Camp. On the 7th it rained and snowed
all day, 8th <orig reg="and"></orig> 9th the same and on the
morning of the 10th it cleared off.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-10" id="d41">
<head>[April 10]</head>
<p>We are still in the same camp on Rood's Hill, April 10th
1862. Nothing of interest transpiring.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-13" id="d42">
<head>[April 13]</head>
<p>April 13th (1862) the <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr>
went on picket below Mt. Jackson. I with others of the camp
were detailed as guard at Headquarters.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-17" id="d43">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-04-17" to="1862-04-22">April 17 to April 22</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We left our camp on Rood's Hill on the morning of the 17th
(April 1862) and moved toward Harrisonburg. I being detailed
to go with the baggage. I stayed in Harrisonburg that night
and the next morning, we started for Staunton which place we
reached the same day.</p>
<p>I stayed in Staunton that night and next morning was
started toward <orig reg="Waynesboro">Waynesborough</orig>,
got as far as Fishersville and stayed that night and on Sunday
went as far as Lebanon Church beyond
<unclear>Brookesville</unclear>, where we remained until the
morning of the 22nd (April 1862) when we went as far as
Mecham's River, unloaded our baggage in the Depot and turned
toward Staunton.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-04-23" id="d44">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-04-23" to="1862-05-03">April 23 to May 3</dateRange>]</head>
<p>I took the cars and came on to Staunton and out home that
night, I reenlisted on the 12th (April 1862) and was mustered
into service. I again left home on the 28th (April 1862) and
joined the Army on the 3rd day of May
(1862).</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-05" id="d45">
<head>May 1862
<!-- <ref>Battle Description, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-04" id="d46">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-05-04" to="1862-05-06">May 4 to 6</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We crossed the mountains into Albemarle the next day at
Brown's Gap. Went by Mecham's Depot and crossed the Blue Ridge
through the tunnel and went on to near Staunton on the 6th of
May (1862) where we stayed over night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-07" id="d47">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-05-07" to="1862-05-12">May 7 to May 12</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The next morning we took the Parkersburg Road went on
through Buffalo Gap and out to Highland County to near the
Bull Pasture Mountain the 8th day of May (1862). A fight
between our men and the enemy came off on the morning of the
8th near McDowell in which our men drove them back, each party
sustained a considerable loss, and the enemy continued to
retreat.</p>
<p>We followed them as far as Franklin in Pendleton County
where we skirmished around a little and then on the 12th (May
1862) we commenced falling back. We fell back some 9 miles and
stayed over night and in the morning continued our march on
the way back to the Valley. We <orig reg="laid">layed</orig>
over on the <unclear>10</unclear>th at the foot of Shenandoah
Mountain.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-13" id="d48">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-05-13" to="1862-05-16">May 13 to 16</dateRange>]</head>
<p>It commenced raining on evening of the 13th (May 1862).
<orig reg="It's">Its</orig> still raining on the morning of
the 16th (May 1862). Remained in camp today.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-17" id="d49">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-05-17" to="1862-05-19">May 17 to May 19</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The morning of the 17th (May 1862) we again took up the
line of march and marched as far as Augusta Springs and
camped. We remained in camp from Saturday evening until Monday
morning the 19th (May 1862), when we again left our camp and
went on through Mt. Solon and Bridgewater to a camp beyond the
<orig reg="latter">later</orig> place and remained over
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-20" id="d50">
<head>[May 20]</head>
<p>The next morning (May 20, 1862) we again set out and passed
on through Harrisonburg <unclear>having</unclear> our
knapsacks, etc., to near the Big Spring and camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-21" id="d51">
<head>[May 21]</head>
<p>The next day (May 21, 1862) we marched on down the Valley
to New Market and there we left the Pike and turned to the
right and crossed the mountain at Massanutten Gap, into Page
<abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr> and on through Luray and
camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-22" id="d52">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-05-22" to="1862-05-23">May 22 to 23</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We stayed in this camp (Luray) until after 12 o'clock on
the 23rd (May 1862), when we again drove on, the <abbr
expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> started soon in the morning.
Nothing of interest occurring today.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-24" id="d53">
<head>[May 24]</head>
<p>Saturday 24th (May 1862) we went as far as Front Royal,
stayed all night, started early next morning. The <abbr
expan="Regiment">Regt.</abbr> was marching and under arms all
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-25" id="d54">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-05-25" to="1862-05-29">May 25 to May 29</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Sunday morning (May 25, 1862) early the enemy commenced
throwing shells which had little effect on our men, we <orig
reg="succeeded">succeded</orig> in driving the enemy from all
the Towns as far as Winchester and had but little trouble in
clearing that place.</p>
<p>Sunday night we camped near Stephenson Depot, where we
remained until <orig reg="Wednesday">wednesday</orig> morning.
When we again took up the line of march for <orig
reg="Charleston">Charles Town</orig>, which place we reached
about noon and found some 3,000 Yankees there which we routed
and took some 200 prisoners. We pursued them about 8 miles
toward the Ferry, we then came back near to <orig
reg="Charleston">Charles Town</orig> and camped. The whole
Brigade was ordered out the next day in the direction of the
Ferry.</p></div3>


<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-30" id="d55">
<head>[May 30]</head>
<p>On the morning of the 30th (May 1862) we started again in
the same direction and returned to camp <orig reg="in"></orig>
the evening, while out today our company was thrown out as
skirmishers and advanced to within a short distance of the
enemy's lines. They never fired a shot at us.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-05-31" id="d56">
<head>[May 31]</head>
<p>31st (May 1862) we marched this morning in the direction of
Winchester and passed on and camped 2 miles above
Kernstown.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-06" id="d57">
<head>June 1862
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Battle Description, Death/Casualties,
Military Authority, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-01" id="d58">
<head>[June 1]</head>
<p>Then on the 1st day of June (1862) we continued marching up
the Valley getting to Strasburg about noon, where we made a
stand but the enemy did not advance. <abbr
expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Ewell encountered them in the
morning and completely repulsed them at this place. We fell
back some distance and camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-02" id="d59">
<head>[June 2]</head>
<p>Early on the 2nd (June 1862) we took up the line of march,
the enemy still pursuing until we came to Woodstock where we
were drawn up in line of battle, but they did not advance. We
came over to near Mt. Jackson and camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-03" id="d60">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-06-03" to="1862-06-04">June 3 to June 4</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The next morning (June 3, 1862) we again started up the
road and stopped near New Market. We remained there over night
and the greatest part of the next day (June 4, 1862) we then
marched to near Big Spring where we stayed all
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-05" id="d61">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-06-05" to="1862-06-07">June 5 to June 7</dateRange>]</head>
<p>5th (June 1862) we started early in the morning from camp
and came on through Harrisonburg, after leaving this place we
took the road leading to Port Republic and camped about a mile
from the <orig reg="latter">later</orig> place, where we are
still camped on the morning of the 7th (June 1862), having
been here all day yesterday. Their wagons are gone and <abbr
expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Ashby was killed yesterday evening
in an engagement with the enemy near Harrisonburg.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-08" id="d62">
<head>8th June 1862, Sunday morning,</head>
<p>the enemy attacked us about 8 o'clock both in front and
rear, those in front did not stand but fell back <orig
reg="immediately">immediatly</orig> but those in the rear
fought at the least 4 hours, <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr>
Ewell and Johnson's Divisions were engaged. Fremont on the
opposite side, there were many killed and wounded on both
sides, each party held their own ground. The fight continued
until dark.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-09" id="d63">
<head>9th June 1862, Monday morning</head>
<p>we left camp at dawn and marched down the river, crossed
South River at Port Republic and went down the same about 2
miles where we encountered the enemy and commenced an attack
which was very severe. It lasted about 2 hours, our regiment
fought on the river bank against great odds, we had to give
back at one time but reinforcements coming up we recovered.
<del rend="none" hand="h1"></del> then we lost John Brubeck, and James Berry were
killed dead on the ground, some 12 wounded, more or less
severely. We <orig reg="succeeded">succeded</orig> in getting
our dead and wounded off of the field, we took some 300
prisoners, our Regiment lost some 72 in killed and wounded and
missing.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-10" id="d64">
<head>[<dateRange from="1861-06-10" to="1862-06-12">June 10 to June 12</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We fell back to the top of mountain at Brown's Gap, and are
still there on the morning of 11th (June 1862). It rained all
day yesterday, we stayed all day on the mountain and left soon
on the morning of the 12th (June 1862) and came to about 4
miles above Port Republic and camped for the night.</p>
</div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-13" id="d65">
<head>13th (June 1862)</head>
<p>remained in camp today, I was engaged in making up the
payroll for the company.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-15" id="d66">
<head>15th (June 1862)</head>
<p>attended <orig reg="divine">devine</orig> services
today</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-16" id="d67">
<head>16th (June 1862)</head>
<p>still in same camp, writing for the company.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-17" id="d68">
<head>17th (June 1862)</head>
<p>still engaged in writing.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-18" id="d69">
<head>18th (June 1862)</head>
<p>we left our camp 4 miles above Port Republic this morning
at 5 o'clock for Rockfish Gap, which place we reached about 6
o'clock and camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-19" id="d70">
<head>19 (June 1862)</head>
<p>the drum beat at 3 this morning calling us from our
slumber. We prepared our breakfast and ate, then we got ready
to move, the enemy went over the mountain and I went home to
finish the payrolls for the company getting there that
evening, now at home writing.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-21" id="d71">
<head>21st (June 1862)</head>
<p>at home.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-22" id="d72">
<head><dateRange from="1862-06-22" to="1862-06-23">22nd, 23rd</dateRange></head>
<p>still at home.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-24" id="d73">
<head>24th (June 1862)</head>
<p>went to Staunton to go to the Army but no transportation.
Went back home and stayed until the morning of the
2<unclear>6</unclear> when I again went to Staunton, had to
stay in that place all day.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-27" id="d74">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-06-27" to="1862-06-29">June 27 to June 29</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Started on the morning of the 27th (June 1862), went as far
as Ashland Station, stayed there that night. Went to the
Brigade wagons, remained in that camp until the 29th (June
1862) when we moved 4 or 5 miles farther and are
camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-06-30" id="d75">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-06-30" to="1862-07-02">June 30 to July 2</dateRange>]</head>
<p>We again started on the 30th (June 1862) to join the
Regiment which I <orig reg="succeeded">succeded</orig> in
doing on the 2nd of July (1862). The Regiment was in the fight
on the 27th (June 1862), Captain Randolph, John J. Bowers,
James Lucas was killed on the same day, our <abbr
expan="company">comp</abbr> was in the fight on the 1st of
July, some killed or wounded.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-07" id="d76">
<head>July 1862
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-03" id="d77">
<head>3rd (July 1862)</head>
<p>we fell back toward the river.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-04" id="d78">
<head>4th (July 1862)</head>
<p>we were drawn up in line of battle from noon until after
dark when we fell back in the woods a short
distance.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-05" id="d79">
<head>5th (July 1862)</head>
<p>still in same place.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-06" id="d80">
<head>6th (July 1862) Sunday,</head>
<p>still in same place.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-07" id="d81">
<head>7th (July 1862)</head>
<p>on picket today, fell back in the evening about one mile
and camped for the night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-12" id="d82">
<head>[July 12]</head>
<p>Still here today on the <unclear>12th</unclear> (July 1862)
at 3 we fell back some 12 miles and camped for the
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-09" id="d83">
<head>9th (July 1862)</head>
<p>we remained here until 3 o'clock this evening when we again
marched about 9 miles and stayed all night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-10" id="d84">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-07-10" to="1862-07-15">July 10 to July 15</dateRange>]</head>
<p>Then on the morning of the 10th (July 1862) we started
again at day break and marched to a camp 3 miles from
Richmond. We remained in the camp until the morning of the
15th (July 1862) with nothing of interest transpiring during
this time.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-15" id="d85">
<head>[July 15]</head>
<p>On the morning of the 15th (July 1862) we took up the line
of march going to Richmond and taking the care and riding as
far on the bridge that was burnt on the <orig
reg="Pamunkey">Pamunky</orig> where we remained over
night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-16" id="d86">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-07-16" to="1862-07-27">July 16 to July 27</dateRange>]</head>
<p>16th (July 1862) traveled on the cars as far as Louisa
<abbr expan="Courthouse">C. H.</abbr>, where we remain until
the morning of the 19th (July 1862) when we again took up the
line of march and went as far as Gordonsville and just beyond,
where we remained until the morning of the 21st (July 1862),
when we again marched between 4 and 5 miles and camped until
the morning of the 27th (July 1862), when we were ordered to
move. We marched as far as Gordonsville and lay in the woods
until the evening when we again returned to the same camp we
left in the morning.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-27" id="d87">
<head><unclear>27th</unclear> (July 1862)</head>
<p>in Camp.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-29" id="d88">
<head>[July 29]</head>
<p>We left camp McGruder on the morning of the 29th (July
1862) and marched 12 miles through Gordonsville to a camp near
the Three Notch Road and 19 miles from Charlottesville, in
camp here drilling.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-30" id="d89">
<head>30th (July 1862)</head>
<p>the same.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-07-31" id="d90">
<head>31st (July 1862)</head>
<p>the same.</p></div3></div2>

<div2 type="section" n="1862-08" id="d91">
<head>August 1862
<!-- <ref>Camp Life, Battle Description, Death/Casualties,
Troop Movement</ref> -->
</head>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-01" id="d92">
<head><dateRange from="1862-08-01" to="1862-08-04">August (1862) 1st, 2nd, 3rd,
4th,</dateRange></head>
<p>the same.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-05" id="d93">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-08-05" to="1862-08-07">August 5 to August 7</dateRange>]</head>
<p>The 5th (August 1862) we left Camp Garnett and moved to
camp near Liberty Mills. remained in camp drilling until
evening of the 7th (Aug. 1862) when we set out on the march
toward Orange <abbr expan="Courthouse.">C. H.</abbr> We <orig
reg="laid">layed</orig> in the W. field 1 1/2 <orig
reg="miles"></orig> from that place.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-08" id="d94">
<head>[August 8]</head>
<p>The next morning (August 8, 1862) we marched on through
that place taking the road leading to Madison Mills. We then
took down the river and went one mile and camped and stayed
all night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-09" id="d95">
<head>[August 9]</head>
<p>The next morning (August 9, 1862) we went on down the road
toward Culpeper <abbr expan="Courthouse">C. H.</abbr>, marched
some <unclear>2</unclear> miles this evening.</p>
<p>The 9th (Aug. 1862) we got into the fight between 5 and 6
in the evening which lasted <abbr expan="until">til</abbr>
after dark, we drove them from the field. We lay in the field
all night and fell back the next morning, other troops taking
our place.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-10" id="d96">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-08-10" to="1862-08-12">August 10 to 12</dateRange>]</head>
<p>10th (Aug. 1862) fell back about 4 miles and camped and
stayed in this camp until the morning of the 12th (Aug. 1862)
when we again fell back to our camp near Liberty Mills,
reached that place about sunset, in camp.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-13" id="d97">
<head>13th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p><orig reg="paid">payed</orig> March and April
pay.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-14" id="d98">
<head>14th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>still in camp.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-15" id="d99">
<head>15th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>cooking two days rations.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-16" id="d100">
<head>16th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>left camp at sunrise and marched in the direction of 0range
<abbr expan="Courthouse">C. H.</abbr>, marched 15 miles and
camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-17" id="d101">
<head>17th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>in camp.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-18" id="d102">
<head>18th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>in camp.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-19" id="d103">
<head>19th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>witnessed the execution of one of the soldiers for
deserting our Regiment.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-20" id="d104">
<head>[August 20]</head>
<p>The Regiment left this camp on the morning of the 20th
(Aug. 1862) with 3 days rations in our haversacks and marched
in the direction of <orig reg="Rapidan">Rapid Ann</orig>
River, which place we reached about noon, we crossed the river
by wading, marched on through Stephensburg camped for the
night, 15 miles.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-21" id="d105">
<head>21st (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>we marched on toward Rappahannock River but did not attempt
to cross. We camped close to the river.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-22" id="d106">
<head>22nd (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>marched about 7 miles, on picket tonight, nothing worth
relating occurred.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-23" id="d107">
<head>23rd (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>changed our direction to the left marched 6 miles and
camped.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-24" id="d108">
<head>24th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>marched 4 miles, drew rations for 3 days and cooked
same.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-25" id="d109">
<head>25th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>we again took up the line of march passing through little
Jefferson, here we left our knapsacks, here we again changed
our directions getting on the Alexandria turnpike, passing
through <unclear>Amissville</unclear>. We then turned to the
right and crossed the Rappahannock River, passed through
<unclear>Orlean</unclear> and marched until 12 o'clock at
night, 25 miles.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-26" id="d110">
<head>26th (Aug. 1862)</head>
<p>again on the march going through Salem, <orig reg="White
Plains">White Plaines</orig> and Haymarket, some 24 miles,
when we <orig reg="laid">layed</orig> down to rest for an hour
or two.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-27" id="d111">
<head>[August 27]</head>
<p>We were called up in the morning of the 27th (Aug. 1862)
before daylight and on the march for Manassas, which place we
reached about 8 o'clock. We had some Yankees to contend with
here, but they hurt none of us. We got plenty of provisions
here which came in very good indeed for we were all very
hungry. We remained here all day and until 11 o'clock at
night, when we started for the old battleground of Bull Run or
near, marching about 7 miles, we <orig
reg="halted">haulted</orig> about daylight and <orig
reg="laid">layed</orig> down to try <orig reg="to"></orig>
sleep some, we marched round here all day <abbr
expan="until">til</abbr> night.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-28" id="d112">
<head>[August 28]</head>
<p>This being the 28th (Aug. 1862), when we got into a regular
engagement with the enemy about dark which lasted some 2
hours. I was wounded in the left leg, the ball taking out some
pieces of bone and the <abbr expan="Surgeon">Surg.</abbr>
taking still more.</p></div3>

<div3 type="entry" n="1862-08-28" id="d113">
<head>[<dateRange from="1862-08-28" to="1862-09-24">August 28 to September 24</dateRange>]</head>
<p>I was taken to the Crawford Cushing where I remained from
the 28th of August <orig reg="until">till</orig> the 3rd of
September (1862) when I was removed to Aldie in Loudoun
County, where I remained until the 20th (Sept. 1862), when I
started for home, which place I reached on the 24th (Sept.
1862).</p></div3>

</div2></div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI.2>
