<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="AD3000"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="AD3000">
  <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title id="VShadow" type="main">Augusta County: Diary of Roland E. Bowen (1863)</title>
        <title type="sort">augusta county diary of roland e bowen 1863</title>
        <author>Bowen, Roland E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Doug O'Reagan, Virginia Center for Digital History</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>
        <num type="kilobytes"> 54 kilobytes</num>
      </extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">AD3000</idno>

        <!--
<availability> 
<p>Publicly accessible </p> 
<p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p> 
<p>copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p> 
</availability>
-->
        <availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
            Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2002">2002</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500335</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Augusta County: Diary of Roland E. Bowen</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">augusta county diary of roland e bowen</title>
            <author>Roland E. Bowen</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent> pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From Ball's Bluff to Gettysburg... And
              Beyond: The Civil War Letters of Private Roland E. Bowen, 15th Massachusetts Infantry
              1861-1864, ed. Gregory A. Coco, p.214-233; Thomas Publications, Gettysburg, PA</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note/>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Published Source</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <dateRange from="1863-07" to="1863-08-07">07-1863 - 08-07-1863</dateRange>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Camp Life, Home Front, Patriotism, Prisons/Prisoners, Women</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Kid W.</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia
            Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD
          (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>

  <text id="AD3000T">

    <front id="d2">
      <div1 id="d3" type="section">
        <head>Biography <!-- <ref>AD3000bio</ref> -->
        </head>
        <p/>
      </div1>
    </front>

    <body id="d4">


      <div1 id="AD30001863" n="1863" type="part">
        <head>1863 <!-- <ref>AD30001863</ref> -->
        </head>

        <div2 id="d6" n="1863-07" type="section">
          <head>July 1863
            <!-- <ref>African Americans, Camp Life, Home Front, Prisons/Prisoners, Patriotism, Women</ref> -->
          </head>

          <div3 id="d7" n="1863-07-xx" type="entry">
            <head>[The diary section begins partway through this entry]</head>
            <p><abbr expan="rebels">rebs</abbr> any. They openly declared themselves for the Union.
              One young lass of about 18 sweet summers came out on the piazza with something to give
              the prisoners. A crowd stopped to talk with her. Up dashed a <abbr expan="rebel"
              >reb</abbr> Officer and swearing furiously, commanded the prisoners to go on, which
              they did. His <orig reg="sword">swoard</orig> was drawn, he told her to go into the
              house flourishing his <orig reg="sword">swoard</orig> at the same time. My Lord! you
              had ought to have seen her snarl at him. She stepped right up to the front of the
              piazza to his face and said, "O Southern Chivalry, Southern Chivalry, Chivalry." He
              was mad, and we were glad. I will only add she did <hi rend="underline">not</hi> go
              into the house.</p>
            <p>The <abbr expan="railroad">Rail Road</abbr> here was utterly destroyed. God bless the
              good people of <abbr expan="Martinsburg">Mg</abbr>. The guard said, "Oh let them have
              Martinsburg and go to hell with it." We camped 3 miles to the South of good old
              Martinsburg.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d8" n="1863-07-11" type="entry">
            <head>July 11th</head>
            <p>Moved out to <abbr expan="Bunker">Bnker</abbr> Hill and drew rations, then let out
              for Winchester <orig reg="which">wich</orig> is 22 miles from <abbr
                expan="Martinsburg">Marg</abbr>. Order of March, 1st all Officers. 2nd noncommission
              Officers, privates and citizens. 3rd Niggers. We were not allowed any communication
              with the Officers whatever. They had a camp by themselves each night and were not
              allowed to come near us. Mr. Scandlin was considered a citizen and was with the 15th
              boys all the time. Poor man, he was not used to marching and he suffered very much. We
              (the 15th boys) carried a good part of his things for him for more than a hundred
              miles. At 11<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> at night we arrived at Winchester. Althought it was once a beautiful <orig
                reg="macadamized">accadamised</orig> road, deep ruts had been cut in it by the
              passage of <orig reg="contending">conending</orig> armies. And owing to the rain,
              darkness of the night and rough road, the march extremely wearisome, and marching over
              small pebbles in the dark is very tiresome to ones feet and ankles. The Chaplain could
              hardly stand up when we arrived at <abbr expan="Winchester">Wr</abbr> Saturday
            night.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d9" n="1863-07-12" type="entry">
            <head>July 12th</head>
            <p>This being Sunday we did not go but a short distance. In the morning we passed
              through the town (I had almost said City for it is a large place). Many of Milroy's
              wounded were here. The people were decidedly <abbr expan="Secessionists"
              >Secesh</abbr>, they looked upon us with scorn. There was a <orig reg="terrible"
                >terible</orig> shower just after we got through the place. We camped two miles to
              the South of Winchester, drew 3 days rations, and were told that must last us until we
              got to <abbr expan="Mount">Mt</abbr> Jackson (40 miles). I think I eat mine all that
              day.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d10" n="1863-07-13" type="entry">
            <head>July 13th</head>
            <p>The rain poured down in torrents, marched 16 miles <orig reg="wading">wadeing</orig>
              through the swollen creeks waist deep. We camped 1/2 miles out of <orig
                reg="Strasburg">Strawsburg</orig>. From <abbr expan="Winchester">Wr</abbr> to
              Staunton the road is <orig reg="macadamized">accadamised</orig> all the way and is the
              most splendid road I ever saw, yet it is awful for ones feet for it is just like a
              rock.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d11" n="1863-07-14" type="entry">
            <head>July 14th</head>
            <p>Marched early in the morning, went 20 miles and camped 4 miles out of Mount Jackson.
              The boys were <orig reg="terribly">terible</orig> hungry and out of rations. The
              Shenandoah valley is a rich and beautiful Country. The crops look fine. The people
              were <orig reg="staunch">stanch</orig> followers of Uncle Jeff.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d12" n="1863-07-15" type="entry">
            <head>July 15th</head>
            <p>Off early for <abbr expan="Mount">Mt</abbr> Jackson, drew rations, halted a few hour
              and finally camped 7 miles beyond, near New Market.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d13" n="1863-07-16" type="entry">
            <head>July 16th</head>
            <p>Twenty two miles this day and turned in four miles beyond <orig reg="Harrisonburg"
                >Harisonburg</orig>. We worried away the night in mud and water, drew a scanty
              ration. I bought a load of bread for $2.00 in Greenbacks and was instantly offered
              3.00 for half of it. I saw one man offer 9 dollars for a loaf of bread but it could
              not be bought for money.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d14" n="1863-07-17" type="entry">
            <head>July 17th</head>
            <p>Made 19 miles and camped 4 miles out of Staunton. I never had my feet ache so in all
              my life. Scandlin would puff and blow like an Elephant.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d15" n="1863-07-18" type="entry">
            <head>July 18th</head>
            <p>We fell in quickly at the order, all hands expecting to go straight to the depot and
              take the cars for Richmond. But instead of this we were marched through the town and
              one and a half miles up the <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> Central <abbr
                expan="Railroad">R.R.</abbr> and went into the field at a place called the
              "Springs." Very appropriately too for here was one of the most splendid springs God
              ever made oozing from under a huge rock. I believe it would furnish an army of 50,000
              men with water. I had half shelter and a rubber, I had nothing else under Heaven in
              the way of clothing except what I had on. <abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> Imboden
              ordered all shelters and rubbers to be taken from the prisoners as they passed into
              this field, but not to take overcoats nor blankets, neither of <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> I had. As I passed into the lot I <hi rend="underline">tried</hi> to beg
              off, telling the guard I had no overcoat or blanket. He said he could not help that,
              he must obey his orders. Well! your friend Bowen was cleaned out or else he is a liar.
              I am not sure as there can be any circumstances under which profanity is justifiable.
              (Dave do you think there is?) Nights I crawled in with some who had blankets. All of
              us were getting very lousy in consequence of not having a change of clothes, nor any
              chance to wash ours, or even skirmish them as they should be. (It pleased me to see
              Scandlin with his clothes off hunting grey-backs. I pitied him too.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d16" n="1863-07-19" type="entry">
            <head>July 19th</head>
            <p>A small squad of prisoners left today on cars for Richmond</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d17" n="1863-07-20" type="entry">
            <head>July 20th</head>
            <p>700 left <orig reg="today">to day</orig> for Richmond. Scandlin has gone.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d18" n="1863-07-21" type="entry">
            <head>July 21st</head>
            <p>Seven hundred <orig reg="today">to day</orig> for Richmond.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d19" n="1863-07-22" type="entry">
            <head>July 22nd</head>
            <p>Eight hundred went to the depot but all returned.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d20" n="1863-07-23" type="entry">
            <head>July 23rd</head>
            <p>Rainy. 700 got off this day for Richmond.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d21" n="1863-07-24" type="entry">
            <head>July 24th</head>
            <p>Nothing particular except <abbr expan="it is">
                <orig reg="it's">its</orig>
              </abbr> mighty hot weather.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d22" n="1863-07-25" type="entry">
            <head>July 25th</head>
            <p>Left camp. All hands went to the depot but there was no train for us so we camped on
              top of the hill close by the depot. A large number of citizens came to look at a
              Yankee. Peddlers were plenty, and those that had money could have plenty to eat.
              Greenbacks 3 for 1.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d23" n="1863-07-26" type="entry">
            <head>July 26th</head>
            <p>Still on the hill by the depot.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d24" n="1863-07-27" type="entry">
            <head>July 27th</head>
            <p>Got a Richmond paper, nothing of importance.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d25" n="1863-07-28" type="entry">
            <head>July 28th</head>
            <p>Getting sick of <orig reg="stopping">stoping</orig> around here.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d26" n="1863-07-29" type="entry">
            <head>July 29th</head>
            <p>I have been two years in the service of the United States this day. Now a new era
              commences. My money was nearly exhausted. I had become dissatisfied at their taking
              everything from me, our snail like progress and scant rations growing more scanty. I
              looked forward with horror to the time when I should be destitute of the "I promise to
              pay etc.," and shudder at the thought of starvation being my inevitable doom. I had
              been nearly "broke" once or twice and resorted to buying and selling at a profit. What
              some call "taking advantage of your poor starving comrades," but I looked upon it as a
              "military necessity," not perhaps for the existance of the Nation, but my own
              individual life. Thus when I sw a man that had more money than I, I resorted to this
              trick to get (some say "extort") it from him. However unmanly this may appear, I have
              only to say I done it and would do it again if I ever got in the same circumstances
              again.</p>

            <p>I had become acquainted with one Leroy Addams who belongs to the 24th <abbr
                expan="Michigan">Mich.</abbr>
              <abbr expan="Volunteer">Vol.</abbr>
              <abbr expan="Infantry.">Inf.</abbr> They too were tainted with an insubordinate
              inclination as well as myself. We had been talking of migrating for a day or two but
              had not really come to any conclusion. The subject was again broached <orig
                reg="today">to day</orig> and at once agreed upon to decamp that night. Now for the
              "Modus operandi." Jim had a splendid map of the State of <abbr expan="Virginia"
              >Va.</abbr> We went and sat down by a large tree and after looking over the map and
              consulting the matter <orig reg="a while">awhile</orig> came to the unanimous
              conclusion that Beverly would be the most feasible point to reach. This was in the
              Northwesterly direction and about 100 miles distant. This we thought "Dei gratia"
              might be accomplsihed in seven days. We all agreed to keep in the mountains and travel
              no road after reaching <orig reg="Swoopes">Swoops</orig> Station. We went down upon
              the side hill and all the plans and directions were agreed upon. As for rations, we
              were to get all we could and let it go at that, "Quantum sufficit" not to be expected.
              On the lower side of the field the guard had a pretty long beat and in the dark we
              thought by going out one at a time we could pass the guard on the sly and not be
              discovered. As the guard being done rather on the "Sans souci" principle. The
              afternoon passed on. I bought a bunch of matches for <orig reg="which">wich</orig> I
              gave 25 <abbr expan="cents">cts</abbr>. At this time we got 4 <orig reg="hardtack"
                >hard tack</orig> a day with a small piece of bacon. I bought and traded around so
              that I made out 9 hard tack and about a pound of bacon. Jim &amp; Leroy had a
              chance to buy some and had 12 hard-tack a piece with some bacon. Jim had a piece of an
              old blanket, Leroy and myself had nothing. We all had haversacks &amp; canteens.
              (Our camp was <orig reg="searched">scearched</orig> for canteens but we did <hi
                rend="bold">not</hi>
              <hi rend="bold">have</hi>
              <hi rend="bold">any.</hi>)</p>

            <p>As soon as it was dark Jim led off as agreed, Leroy and I watching to see what
              success. Just as Jim was going over the guard line the guard shouted, "Halt! get back
              ar." Jim pretended he did not know he was so near the guard line and returned to us.
              Well I'll be "burst" if that want a "bumper." The boys began to be disheartened.
              Although it looked cloudy and likely to rain, still it was not dark, as the Moon was
              almost at its full. Jim said it was not dark enough, that he thought we had better
              wait a day or two and the nights would be darker. Part of the guard line ran through
              an oak of grove. I proposed to go in there and perhaps under cover of the trees we
              might be more successful. "Una Voce" we all went. Here we found the guard sitting down
              with 5 or 6 "Yanks" around him talking over the various scenes of the war, what
              battles they had been in etc. This was just the fellow we wanted to find, somebody
              that was telling stories instead of walking his beat. Jim edged up slowly to the guard
              and then gradually got behind and then on tip-toe he toddled straight to the rear and
              was soon out of sight. Now according to agreement it was my turn. I waiting <orig
                reg="until">untill</orig> the guard got right in the midst of one of his battle
              yarns and then "ah la" Jim. I did not shout but my thoughts ran thus, ha ha how <hi
                rend="bold">ware</hi> you Johnny. I went part way down the hill and found Jim hid in
              the bushes under a fence at a spot agreed on. Pretty soon came Leroy. The "yanks" of
              course see us as we came out, but they <orig reg="kept">kipt</orig> "mum," all the
              while pretending to be deeply interested in Johnny's blood and thunder story.</p>

            <p>Now we were out-side the guard. It was not yet 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi>. We had got to go by two houses and cross a much traveled road and pass the
              Insane Asylum before we could get out into clear sailing. So we concluded to top here
              by the fence and went down toward the road to see if it was right. He came crawling
              back and said there was a devilish big ditch there <orig reg="which">wich</orig> he
              did not believe we could get over. I told him keep still, never mind the ditch, I'd
              risk that. Not another word was whispered for 15 <orig reg="minutes">minits</orig>,
              when to my great astonishment I heard a guard coming down the hill. I supposed we had
              been discovered and that the guard was after us. I saw that there was three. I did not
              dare run, so I huddled myself down into the bushes making myself as scarce as
              possible. Just before they got to us they <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig>, whispered
              a moment, then hid in the bushes just as we had done. I thought I saw one go back. I
                <orig reg="supposed">suposed</orig> they had discovered Leroy who was 10 or 12 feet
              above me in the bushes, and had sent back for more help so as to make sure of us, the
              two watching our movements while the third went for help. I never was so frightened in
              my life. I could hear my heart beat as plain as you could hear an engine puff. <orig
                reg="Everything">Every thing</orig> was still as death. Leroy was so far off I could
              not whisper to him, and Jim was the other side of the fence. I give up all hope and
              considered myself as good as captured. So I <orig reg="stepped">steped</orig> up to
              where I saw those fellows go into the bushes and said I, who the Devil are you. My God
              sir! If here want 3 fellows who saw us go by the story teller and had done the same
              thing themselves. ButI had got enough of this, I didn't want to be scared to death for
              nothing. Said I, come Leroy let us be out of this. We both jumped over the fence. Well
              if Jim did not lay here sound asleep my name ain't Bowen. I <orig reg="grabbed"
              >grabed</orig> him by the collar and jerked him into a sitting position. What in the
              Devil you doing here, didn't you know the <abbr expan="rebels">Rebs</abbr> were after
              us. We all went down the hill almost on our hands and knees. When we got near the
              fence I made for it. Says Jim, don't go there, you can't get down that way. I did not
              stop, but over I went and that ain't all. I went down a 20 foot bank head foremost. I
              ran through a little garden then across the road. Here was a board (perpendicular)
              fence about 12 feet high <orig reg="which">wich</orig> enclosed the Insane Asylum
              grounds. I now kept up the road leaving the fence to my left and passing a house <orig
                reg="which">wich</orig> was on the right. As soon as I reached the corner I turned
              in to the left into a cornfield, still <orig reg="having">haveing</orig> the high
              board fence on my left and corn to the right. Here was quite a large brook. I crossed
              that and went under an apple tree and halted for my comrades. Jim and Leroy had passed
              in the rear of the house and scared up 3 or 4 dogs who commenced a hellish barking. I
              knew they would pass through this corn field as that was the agreement in the
              afternoon. I heard a rustling in the corn. I made for it, and behold it was one of
              those other fellows. I told him to go right on, no wait for us, as six in a squad
              would be too many. I had been pretty well worked up about the guard being after us,
              then the barking of the dogs and then those other 3 men being bound to follow us
              irritated me very much. I don't suppose it was but a <orig reg="minute">minit</orig>
              or two before Jim &amp; Jim came up but it seemed as if they never would come. As
              soon as they came up we went on. Just as we got through the cornfield and went over
              the fence into the pasture we ran on to those three fellows again and they were bound
              to go with us. I was <orig reg="terribly">teribly</orig> provoked but I see they did
              not know where to go. Said I, look here, it sno use for six of us to go together for
              we will all be caught. Now I will tell you just our <orig reg="route">rout</orig> then
              you can do the same if you choose. (We were now going due South) As quick as we cross
              this field we are going to turn square to the right and keep due West until we strike
              the <orig reg="railroad">Rail Road</orig>, then we are going up to <orig reg="Swoopes"
                >Swoops</orig> Station, 8 miles from here. Then without <orig reg="regard"
              >reguard</orig> to Roads, Rivers or Mountains we shall go exactly North West and
              intend to strike Beverly <orig reg="which">wich</orig> is 100 miles from there. This
              seemed to satisfy them and I never saw them afterwards. Jim and Leroy had got some
              distance ahead, I soon overtook them. After crossing the pasture we got over the
              fence, filed right and kept along under the fence toward the <orig reg="Lynchburg"
                >Lintchburg</orig> pike <orig reg="which">wich</orig> we crossed. I thought I saw a
              short distance down the road near a house, but it may have been all <orig
                reg="imagination">immagination</orig>.</p>

            <p>We now struck into a kind of a swail where the grass was very tall and wet. Our feet
              were soon wet, also our pants to our knees. Now we pushed <orig reg="rapidly"
              >rappidly</orig> on over hills, through swamps and woods, occasionally running
              suddenly on to a house and as quick disappear into the woods again leaving the dogs to
              bark at nothing. It being very cloudy we could only get a glimpse at the moon once in
              a while, and it was very difficult to keep our direction. Often times the moon would
              be hid so long that when the clouds thined away so we could see whereit was, we would
              find our-selves going directly South or "vice versa." We wandered on until perhaps
                11<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> but no R.R. We held a council and came to the conclusion we had been going <abbr
                expan="southwest">S.W.</abbr>
              <orig reg="which">wich</orig> would never bring us to the <abbr expan="railroad"
              >R.R.</abbr> We now turned our course North as near as we could. About 12<hi
                rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> it was my turn to lead. I had not had the lead but a few <orig reg="minutes"
                >minits</orig> when crawling through a thick jungle I came to a <abbr
                expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> rail fence <orig reg="which">wich</orig> was all covered
              with briers and bushes. As I was triyng to get under, through or over this fence, I
              happened to look up and saw a telegraph wire running along just above. Jim was close
              behind. Said I, Glory to God! here is a telegraph, we are close to the <abbr
                expan="railroad">R.R.</abbr> Another <orig reg="minute">minit</orig> and we were on
              the <abbr expan="railroad">R.R.</abbr> This cheered us up and we pushed on with new
              vigor. We had not gone far before we struck the 139th mile post <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> told the sad story that we were only 3 miles from Staunton (139 miles
              from <abbr expan="Richmond">Rich</abbr>). I think we had traveled six mile (one of the
              boys remarked that the furthest way round was the nearest for a dog). But we were not
              to be disheartened now. We moved quick but cautious, did not meet a single person on
              the road. I was greatly in dread of sentries but Jim &amp; Leroy thought there was
              no danger. We passed a number of houses just by the side of the <orig reg="railroad"
                >rail road</orig> always going on tip-toe, fortunately no one was disturbed except a
              few cursed dogs. At about 1.30 we arrived at <orig reg="Swoopes">Swoops</orig> Station
                <orig reg="which">wich</orig> was 8 mile by rail from Staunton. It began to rain now
              right merrily. We now took an old cart path <orig reg="which">wich</orig> led us into
              a swamp. After being in the swamp helf an hour we got a <orig reg="glimpse"
              >glimps</orig> at the moon and so near as we could judge were going <abbr
                expan="northeast">N.E.</abbr> We were all much mortified at this, for we were all
              anxious to reach the mountains by day light. We changed our course and in another 30
                <orig reg="minutes">minits</orig> were out of the swamp. We discovered a pretty high
              hill, we made for that <orig reg="hoping">hopeing</orig> that we might be able to see
              the mountains. But it was so dark and rainy that we could not see the slightest sign
              of a mountain. We rushed on and soon came to a pike quite unexpectedly. We were in a
              quandry to know what road this was but could not tell. It was quite muddy and getting
              near morning. I says let us all go backwards across the road, should they see our
              tracks they (any body) would think we were going the opposite direction. Now there was
              a long pasture and a ploughed field laying side by side. Our direction would have been
              across the field, but we concluded to go around a little rather than to run the risk
              of being tracked, as we it was growing more evident every <orig reg="minute"
              >minit</orig> that we should not reach the mountains before light. We went on but to
              our great dismay could see no mountains. It seemed as if every rod we went the
              mountains must leap up in front of us. We went into a heavy timber, the Moon was no
              more to be seen, not a star was visible, my compass I had sold, and <orig reg="which"
                >wich</orig> way we were going we did not know. We talked the matter over and
              concluded that we must be in close proximity to the mountains. If we went on we were
              as likely to go from as toward them and that we had better stop where we were until
              light. We broke a few bushes and laid down upon them, we were soaking wet. Jim and
              Leroy soon fell asleep, but not a wink of sleep for me. I was wet, chilly and nervous
              and the mosquitoes were thicker than the Devil. The clouds began to break away and
              soon the red sky seemed to say, this is East, go on. I awoke the boys, we eat a hard
              tack <orig reg="a piece">apeice</orig> and away we flew to the <abbr expan="northwest"
                >N.W.</abbr> We soon emerged from the woods and the glorious mountains stared us in
              the face. They appeared about a mile distant. It was growing light fast. We hurried on
              to reach the mountains before anybody was up. But these mountains are deceptive. After
              we had gone a mile they still appeared another mile off. Now the farmers began to get
              out and we had to move more cautious, often times going considerably out of our way to
              shun a house or a man in the field, and keeping in the woods as much as possible. In
              passing through a piece of wood we suddenly came to a road. I was ahead. Looking down
              the road I saw a man coming up the road on horseback. I gave the alarm and in instant
              we were all hid. After the man passed we crossed the road into the woods again. It
              seemed as if those mountains actually moved from us as we did not appear to near them
              at all. Some of the fields are almost black with black berries. We would stop, scratch
              up a handful and then hurry on. We soon had a "Quantum sufficit" of blackberries. We
              passed on through fields and woods and <orig reg="shunning">shuning</orig> all "ye
              Godly citizens" as we would a pestilential plague. At 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> A.M. we struck the very base of the first moutain. Here was a sparkling spring
              such as is only known in a mountainous region. We filled our canteens and after an
              hour of hard pulling, hauling and tugging, (slip, kick &amp; scratch) we reached
              the top. Hallelujah, my Kingdom come. "How ware you Johnny."</p>

            <p>Now we loitered around "Ad infinitum Ad libitum," that is the way I translate it.
              Just as we Damn pleased. It was quite how now and we were tired and hungry. We partook
              of our <orig reg="hardtack">Hard tack</orig> &amp; Pork very sparingly as it was
              more previous than gold. We disrobed ourselves and picked lice a half hour or so and
              then after resting a spell, started down the mountain only to climb another three
              times as high. As we were going down the mountain only to climb another three times as
              high. As we were going down the mountain a shower came up almost a <orig reg="minute"
                >minit</orig>
              <orig reg="which">wich</orig> soaked us through. We osoon were down the mountain
              scross the brook and on the way up the next. This was a tough one. To make a long
              story short, we puffed and flowed until three o'clock in the afternoon when the
              "Maximum" point was reached. I had never been so high before, and such a vast area and
              splendid scenery had never before come within my view. To the <abbr expan="southeast"
                >S.E.</abbr> lay the great Shenandoah valley whose width is 30 miles, with one range
              of the Blue Ridge on its opposite side. We could look down the Valley until the range
              of moutains on either side seemed to draw near to each other and finally merge into
              one, and the valley had lost in distance. Two large hills under <orig reg="whose"
                >whoes</orig> shadow Staunton is situated were plaintly visible out in the center of
              the valley 15 miles distant. To the <abbr expan="northwest">N.W.</abbr> was one of the
              roughest regions that ever man beheld. One range of mountains the other generally
              running <abbr expan="northeast">N.E.</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="southwest"
              >S.W.</abbr> A little further to the South West were 4 or 5 short ranges <orig
                reg="which">wich</orig> seemed to cut the others in two, for their range was exactly
              the opposite Viz. <abbr expan="northwest">N.W.</abbr> &amp; <abbr
                expan="southeast">S.E.</abbr> And then as we looked away in the distance nothing but
              the peaks could be seen, <orig reg="which">wich</orig> reminded one of a distant City
              were nothing but the steeples and domes were visible.</p>

            <p>Then the immediate valley below where all the houses, roads, fields, and patches of
              woods were spread out for us to gaze down upon a la a hawk upon a chicken. Then a few
              "Secesh" moving around here and there who looked more like <abbr expan="General"
              >Gen.</abbr> Tom Thumb, <orig reg="Commander">Com.</orig> Nutt, Miss Warren (are sum
              thine ere folks). We found that Staunton was Nearly East of us and that instead of
              going <abbr expan="northwest">N.W.</abbr> we had been nearly <abbr expan="west"
              >W</abbr>. So we kept along on the top of the <abbr expan="Mountain">M</abbr> going
                <abbr expan="northeast">N.E.</abbr> about 2 miles. We were all very tired and it was
              agreed to stop over night. A <orig reg="terrible">terible</orig> shower came upon us
              almost in an instant. I never saw it rain so in all my life. The cloud was just over
              our heads. I told the boys that I believe these Virginia mountains the only place in
              the world where it Thundered and Lightened afterwards. In ten <orig reg="minutes"
                >minits</orig> the sun was shining again, but there <orig reg="wasn't">want</orig> a
              dry thread within a mile of us, even my shoes was full of water. There was a cold wind
              and being wet I soon began to shiver. And taking out my matches, lo and behold, they
              were all wet. said I, God only knows what we shall do. We gathered up some of the
              dryest limbs we could find and split them (we had a butcher knife). I had some
              Richmond papers <orig reg="which">wich</orig> I intended to send to you (Guild) when I
              got to Beverly. One of these was only partly wet. I tore it up. I got a dry stone from
              under a cliff of the rocks and began to rub my matches. I worked 15 or 20 <orig
                reg="minutes">minits</orig> but not a spark of fire could I raise. The boys give up
              all hopes but it seemed as if my life almost depended upon it. I took 4 matches and
              helf them all together and commences to rub them gently on my pants. It would not do
              to rub them on a stone as it would wear the brimstone off before it would dry them. I
              continued to rub them until I made a dry paper there was. We finally got it to going.
              In these mountains there is an abundance of dead wood and all you have to do is to
              pile it on. Instead of <orig reg="having">haveing</orig> no fire we soon had one that
              you could not stand within ten feet of. Its a singular fact that on top of this
              mountain among the rocks we found quite a quantity of <orig reg="gooseberries"
                >goosberries</orig>. By 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> everything was dry, matches and all. We passed a very <orig reg="comfortable"
                >comfortible</orig> night by our huge fire on one of the highest points of the Great
              North Mountain.</p>
            <p>Two days in one</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d27" n="1863-07-31" type="entry">
            <head>July 31st</head>
            <p>This morning we continued along on top of the mountain intending to go to a point
                <orig reg="which">wich</orig> appeared about half a mile to the <abbr
                expan="northeast">N.E.</abbr>, and from there to take directions for another days
              travel. this point we had seen the night before. The fog was so thick we could not see
              more than two or three rods in any direction. We soon became bewildered and all
              disagreed as to the direction we were traveling. I was completely turned around and as
              I afterwards discovered wanted to go <abbr expan="southeast">S.E.</abbr>
              <orig reg="which">wich</orig> would have took us down the same side of the mountain we
              came up. So we all agreed to wait till the fog should clear away that we might see the
              Sun. In a short time the fog cleared away from the top of the mountain so we could see
              the point above spoken of. It was yet a mile distant. We soon reached it, but another
              cloud of fog had come so we could see nothing. In about an hour the fog settled into
              the valley so we could see the tops of the mountains to the <abbr expan="northwest"
                >N.W.</abbr> loking over the fog in the valley. But we harldy knew <orig reg="which"
                >wich</orig> point to <orig reg="make">mak</orig> for. They proposed to go for a
              high peak about 15 miles distant. I wanted to farther to the right as I thought that
              peak not much north of <hi rend="bold">west</hi>, and to prove my argument, pointing
              back into the fog in the Shenandoah, saying, Staunton is that way. No, they could not
              see it, so we waited another hour for the fog to clear up from the valley. When we saw
              two little mountains near by Staunton, they said no more and down we started,
              sometimes coming to a high precipice and then climb back and go down another way. We
              were soon in the valley. Here the water ran <abbr expan="south-southwest"
              >S.S.W.</abbr> indicating that we had passed the head waters of the Shenandoah and
              struck those of the James River.</p>

            <p>We went over Cow Pasture <abbr expan="Mountain">Mt.</abbr> this day and about 3<hi
                rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> in the afternoon we unexpectedly ran on to the Beverly pike near Stewarts Gap.
              Quite a river comes down through the Gap <orig reg="running">runing</orig>
              <abbr expan="southeast">S.E.</abbr> and cutting two or three ranges of <abbr
                expan="mountains">Mts.</abbr> in twain, precisely as the Potomac does the Blue Ridge
              at Harpers Ferry.</p>

            <p>It was evident could we get through this Gap it would save us many a hard hours toil.
              I strenuously opposed it, but Jim and Leroy were bound to go through it, and as the
              majority ruled, I had to go. This gap is 40 or 50 rods wide. We moved along cautiously
              keeping close under the mountain and as far from the pike as possible. When we saw
                <orig reg="anybody">any body</orig> passing up or down the road we would hide in the
              bushes <orig reg="which">wich</orig> we had to do quite often. We continued this for
              an hour or two. I grumbled considerable as the <orig reg="operation"
              >opperation</orig>. We passed any quantity of old log huts <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> showed that troops had formerly been stationed here. I proposed to wait
              till after dark before we went any further, and then go through in the night. After
              some hesitation they consented.</p>

            <p>We hid away in the brush and waited until dark, then went slyly into the road. we had
              not gone far before I heard a noise like the tramping of horses. We listened and we
              could hear the sabres jingle. In an instant they were upon us. Well if we did not get
              and dust for the mountain then I am no judge. I was behind, said I, run, run, for
              God's sake run, they are after us. It was quite dark. I struck both feet against a
              stump and six or 8 feet beyond my head in the mud. We reached the brook but alas, on
              the opposite side was a perpendicular rock 40 feet high, so down the brook we went
              pell mell. We soon came to a huge tree <orig reg="which">wich</orig> had partly blown
              over, the top leaning over against the mountain and forming a natural bridge over the
              river. Jim was ahead, he bounded up the trunk of the tree and passed through the top
              into the mountain, Leroy &amp; myself bringing up the rear in masterly style.
              After leaving the tree we had to go to the right. The mountain was awful steep. I lost
              my foot hold and was about to be dashed over the precipice into the rocky river below
                <orig reg="which">wich</orig> would have killed me instantly, when foruntately I
              grasped a small bush growing out from the cleft of a rock, regained my foothold and
              proceeding a little more cautious went safely up. We never saw anything more of the
              cavalry. We continued up the mountain <orig reg="until">untill</orig> about 11 o'clock
              when we built a monstrous fire and had a hearty laugh over our narrow escape, and all
              agreeing that had been daylight we could never have got over the brook and up the
              mountain.</p>
          </div3>
        </div2>

        <div2 id="d28" n="1863-08" type="section">
          <head>August 1863
            <!-- <ref>African Americans, Camp Life, Home Front, Prisons/Prisoners, Women</ref> -->
          </head>

          <div3 id="d29" n="1863-08-01" type="entry">
            <head>August 1st</head>
            <p>Off early in the morning, past through the valley and thence to Bull Pasture <abbr
                expan="Mountain">Mt.</abbr> Took directions and made for Jack <abbr expan="Mountain"
                >Mt.</abbr> Passed through Shaws Ridge this day and quite a number of small
              Mountains and streams. Our rations began to run short. Just before dark we discovered
              a little log house up on the side of the <abbr expan="Mountain">Mt.</abbr> On
              approaching it we were saluted by three or four snarling dogs who made mountain echo
              with their boistrous yelping. Here lived a young lady whose Husband was in the
              Confederate army. She had three little children who were fat, ragged and pretty (not
              saucy). They were not used to seeing many of this <abbr expan="world's">Worlds</abbr>
              people and consequently were a little bashful and approached us with considerable
              hesitation. But this made them all the more charming. I shall never forget how
              cautious, (when we urged them to come to us). With one finger in their mouth, they
              would come step by step, first looking you in the face and then upon the floor, and
              then when we would finally take them up in our lap, it would be a long time before
              they would speak the first solitary word.</p>

            <p>This Lady had an aged Mother who also lived with her. She was one of the most
              inquisitive old women I ever saw. She asked questions enough to fill a volume. In
              short we told her that We belonged to the 62nd <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, were
              taken <orig reg="prisoners">prisioners</orig> by some of the Yankee Kilpatrick's men
              near Williamsport, <abbr expan="Maryland">Md</abbr>. Had been paroled by the Yankees,
              that we lived 2 1/2 miles from Franklin in Pendleton <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>,
              that our <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg<hi rend="super">mt.</hi></abbr> (the 62nd <abbr
                expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>) were going to be mounted and serve under Imboden, that
              we were going home to recruit, get some horses, and when we were exchanged return to
              Staunton or wherever Imbodem might then be. She was completely sold. She had a great
              deal to ask about Lee's going into <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penn</abbr>. Said she
              did not think it would do much good because "It made the Yankee's so cross."</p>

            <p>The young Lady boiled some potatoes and fried some ham and fussed and flew around to
              get us a good supper. We urged her not to put herself to so much trouble on our
              account, further more that we were in somewhat of a hurry as we wanted to get over to
                <orig reg="Monterey">Montery</orig> that night. She said that was only 7 miles and
              would not hear a word us, but made us stop and have a nice supper. And then she would
              not take a cent, saying that "Our Soldiers suffered everything." I told her she should
              not put herself to so much trouble without being payed for it, but No, she would not
              hear a word of it. So I left 75 <orig reg="cents">cts</orig> on the table. It was now
              quite dark. She said she would go out and show us where the road was. We told her we
              guessed we could find it, but she was afraid we could not, so she actually went near a
              half a mile into the woods with us in the night to show us the road. As soon as she
              returned to the house we left the road and keep up the <abbr expan="Mountain"
              >Mt.</abbr> as we had no intention of going to Monterey. God bless that woman and the
              children. We went part way up the mountain and camped for the night.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d30" n="1863-08-02" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug</abbr> 2nd</head>
            <p><orig reg="Very">Verry</orig> pleasant, started early in the morning. <abbr
                expan="After">Af</abbr> going a mile or so discovered a house. Leroy and I went
              picking berries <orig reg="which">wich</orig> grew here in great abundance, while Jim
              went to the house, got some breakfast and returned with quite a lot of <orig
                reg="eatables">eatibles</orig> for us. Jim said the old man was mighty inquisitive
              and asked him all sorts of questions, rather more than he liked to have him, but he
              lied to him the best he could. After eating quite a good lunch <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> Jim brought we proceeded on to the top of Jackson Mountain where we
              arrived about 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> A.M. Singular to say near the top of this <abbr expan="mountain">Mt.</abbr>
              <orig reg="which">wich</orig> is very high, there were any quantity of whortleberries.
                <unclear>After</unclear> eating a "Quantum sufficit" we ascended to the highest
              point <orig reg="which">wich</orig> terminated in a huge rock <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> we had seen when many miles away and used it for a guide, <orig
                reg="which">wich</orig> looked like a little house built upon the pinnacle of the
              mountain. Here agian we cold see a great distance in all directions. Forty miles to
              the <abbr expan="northwest">N.W.</abbr> we could see what we supposed to be Rich
              Mountain <orig reg="which">wich</orig> was in our lines near Beverly. The <orig
                reg="Alleghany Mountains">Alaganies</orig> were stretched out before us. These range
              after range must be crossed before we could get to Beverly. Jim and Leroy gazed at
              them, and Alas! their hearts failed them. They said it was useless to try to cross
              those mountains with shoes just hanging to our feet and without rations, when we could
              just as well go the road. I reminded them of our once narrow escape in attempting to
              go the road but to no effect. One word brought on another until they declared they
              would not climb another mountain. If I wished to go on over the mountains I could go,
              but they would not move another step. I reminded them of the agreement before leaving
              Staunton and of the probability of running into picket posts and scouting parties, or
              even being seen by citizens and scouts set upon our tracks. Moreover I contended that
              they had no right to change the original plan without my consent without they could
              show it to be impracticable, <orig reg="which">wich</orig> in my opnion they could not
              show. But they said under the circumstances it was not practicable to keep in the
              mountains any a <orig reg="piece">peice</orig> with us. I began to think now that we
              were all right. We had not gone far before we came to another house at a place called
              the "Forks." Here two more guards came out! all under <abbr expan="Sergeant"
              >Sergt.</abbr> Wilson. By Heavens we were now in a pretty fix, caught sure as the
              Devil!</p>

            <p>Now <abbr expan="Sergeant">Sergt.</abbr> Wilson kindly informed us that his orders
              were to pass nobody by this point without a pass from the proper Authorities, that he
              did not doubt our story, but not having a pass he was obliged to obey orders and would
              have to take us up to camp 5 miles above Crab Bottom or 10 miles from there, and <abbr
                expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Rider (who was in command of 3 <abbr expan="companies"
                >Co's</abbr> of William L. Jacksons cavalry at the above named place) would send us
              to Franklin in the morning. Here was a guide board near by. I <orig reg="stepped"
                >steped</orig> out to that, Leroy followed me, it said (15 miles to Franklin). Leroy
              whispering said we had better show resistance and try to get away. I opposed this
              saying if we could sneak off after dark I was in, but it was no use to oppose armed
              men when we had nothing to defend ourselves with. So we started for camp under Wilson
              and the two guards, we going ahead and they upon their horses behind.</p>

            <p>Soon a <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> came along and began to ask us questions.
              Jim done the talking, I said nothing excpet yes or no, and not even that if I could
              avoid it. As it happened this <abbr expan="Captain">Cap<hi rend="super">t</hi></abbr>.
              belonged to the 62nd <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>. and was at home on a furlough.
              So you see when we told him we belonged to the 62nd he just had us tight. He asked us
              all manner of questions about the <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg<hi rend="super">mt.</hi></abbr>
              <orig reg="which">wich</orig> we had belonged to it as we pretended, of course could
              have answered correctly. Such as, "What <abbr expan="company">Co.</abbr> do you belong
              to?" <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> I Sir. "Who is <abbr expan="Captain"
              >Capt.</abbr> of <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> I?" <abbr expan="Captain"
              >Capt.</abbr> so &amp; so. "God Damned lie, there is no such <abbr expan="captain"
                >Capt.</abbr> in the <abbr expan="Regiment">Reg<hi rend="super">mt.</hi></abbr>, I
              belong to it myself." He asked me what <abbr expan="company">Co</abbr> I belonged to.
                <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> D. Sir. I expected he was going to ask who was
                <abbr expan="captain">Capt</abbr> of <abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> D., but as I
              was making up my mind what to tell him he turned on to another road, telling <abbr
                expan="Sergeant">
                <abbr expan="Sergeant">Serg<hi rend="super">t</hi></abbr>
              </abbr> W. to take us up to Camp to tell <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Rider we
              were Damned run-a-way Yankees from Staunton.</p>

            <p>We arrived at camp just before dark. All the men flocked out to see us. <abbr
                expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Rider asked us who we were. We told him we supposed it
              was no used to lie about it any more, that we were Yankees and escaped from Staunton.
              This brought down the house, (woods). We laughed too in order that all might be merry.
                <abbr expan="Captain">Capt.</abbr> Rider asked us if we were hungry. We told him
              that was no word for it. He went away telling the cooks to give us all the supper we
              wanted. They baked some bread and fried some meat, and we eat to our hearts content.
              Then they wanted to hear some yankee songs. Jim sung one or two <orig reg="which"
              >wich</orig> pleased them mightily, then they would sing. They treated us more like
              brothers than enemies. Finally we were put in a commissary building under guard and
              again we lay down to sleep prisoners of war.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d31" n="1863-08-03" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 3rd</head>
            <p>After breakfast we had orders to return to Staunton at 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> Two teams were to go to Staunton with us for provisions, three guards and Wilson
              who captured us. At 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> we proceeded on the pike nine of us in all. At Monterey they had another
              prisoner who they took along with us. He had been captured a week before near the
              "Forks," he ran away from Staunton too, and belonged to an Ohio <abbr expan="Regiment"
                  >Reg<hi rend="super">mt</hi></abbr>. At noon we <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig>
              at a farm for dinner, had a splendid dinner for <orig reg="which">wich</orig> the
              guard generously paid, costing 25 <abbr expan="cents">cts.</abbr> a head or 2.50. We
              made 21 miles and <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> on Cow Pasture river at Wilson's
              Tavern (A cousin on the <abbr expan="sergeant">Sergt</abbr>'s). We had 3 days rations
              of flour and pork. The Coloured Servant cooked the flour and meat. Had plenty to eat
              and slept in the old School House.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d32" n="1863-08-04" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 4th</head>
            <p>Hot. Off early and made 25 miles. Going down the <abbr expan="mountains">Mts.</abbr>
              we were permitted to ride, as we were footsore. At night we camped at the Valley Mills
              6 miles from Staunton.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d33" n="1863-08-05" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 5th</head>
            <p>Arrived at Staunton about 9<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> A.M., were taken to the Provost Martial's office who took our names and sent us
              to the guard house and put us in among their deserters. This is all the close
              confinement I received, and that for one day only. We had enough to eat and fared
              better than we expected.</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d34" n="1863-08-06" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 6th</head>
            <p>This day the last of the Gettysburg Prisoners left for Richmond. Only two hundred all
              told, consequently we were turned in with the other prisoners and sent to Richmond
              too. Thus very fortunately we escaped all punishment for trying to escape. We had been
                <orig reg="forgotten">forgoten</orig> until all the other prisoners had gone to the
              depot and got aboard the cars, when a <abbr expan="Sergeant">Serg<hi rend="super"
                >t.</hi></abbr> with two guards came to the guard house in great haste after us. We
              had quite a lot of flour, also some bread baked. We drew a small quantity of sugar
              that morning, the only sugar I ever drew in the Confederacy, but they would not wait
              for us to take the first identical thing, in fact they wanted we should leave our
              haversacks and canteens. But I could not see that, so I <orig reg="grabbed"
              >grabed</orig> those in my hand and ran. The depot was but a short distance and in a
              few <orig reg="minutes">minits</orig> we crowded aboard some old freight cars. The
              shrill whistle, if I understand the language of steam, shouted or squealed "all
              aboard." And for the second time we bid adieu to <orig reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig>,
              Augusta <abbr expan="County">Co.</abbr>, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr>, under very
              different cirucmstances from those recorded above. The road being rough and unever our
              progess was <orig reg="necessarily">necessarly</orig> slow. About noon we arrived at
              the great tunnel in the Blue Ridge <orig reg="which">wich</orig> is one mile and a
              quarter in length. here my inclination was great to run away again, keep up the Blue
              Ridge, pass to the left of Lee's Army and amde in for Warrenton or vicinity. But the
              train was strongly guarded and my shoes were utterly ruined. They were a pair <orig
                reg="which">wich</orig> I had bought while at home on a furlough and had marched
              upwards of Five Hundred miles with them.</p>

            <p>We passed through Charlottesville in the afternoon, arriving at Gordonsville about
              dark. Here for some cause <orig reg="which">wich</orig> I have yet to learn we halted
              for the night, sleeping or rather worrying out a miserable night and the cars so
              crowded that there was not respectable room for one to stand up in. I had no rations
              nor money, no, not even a solitary cent in worthless "Confed."</p>
          </div3>

          <div3 id="d35" n="1863-08-07" type="entry">
            <head><abbr expan="August">Aug.</abbr> 7th</head>
            <p>We left Gordonsville at daylight. As we <orig reg="stopped">stoped</orig> along the
              road we saw a great many <orig reg="vendors">venders</orig> of pies, cakes, apples,
              etc. but they asked an awful price in <abbr expan="Confederate money">Confed.</abbr>
              One of the prisoners got out and <orig reg="stepping">steping</orig> up to an old
              Nigger as if to buy, suddenly hit his basket a violent kick and how <hi rend="bold"
                >ware</hi> you gingerbread. We made a rush after it and I succeeded in <orig
                reg="capturing">captureing</orig> one slab of it, but it was sour miserable stuff
              anyhow, and when you broke it in two as the phrase is, "how the spider webs would
              string out," but that was nothing, I demolished it instantly. And the old nigger
              disappeared into the woods swearing vociferously. We reached Hanover Junction before
              noon, and soon passed through the Rebel fortifications near the Chickahominy. They
              were not so numerous for formidable as I had been led to believe. Very few of them
              were <orig reg="garrisoned">garisoned</orig> or had any guns.</p>

            <p>At 1<hi rend="super">
                <abbr expan="o'clock">oc</abbr>
              </hi> P.M. we arrived in the City. Here we were formed into fours and proceeded to
              Libby Prison. <orig reg="Everything">Every thing</orig> wore an extreme military
              appearance and vast had been the change since I had passed through it a few years
              previous. What an idea it would have then been to think the next time I should enter
              Richmond it would be as a prisoner of war. The burdens of war were apparent, still
              those stories about their extreme destitution, half clad and starvation <orig
                reg="staring">stareing</orig></p>

            <p>[This is the end of the diary segment]</p>
          </div3>
        </div2>

      </div1>





    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
