<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B0058"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B0058">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Contract of Indenture of
                    Punch Fox to John H. Rippitoe, May 24, 1850</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records contract of indenture of punch fox to john h rippitoe, may 24 1850</title>
        <author>Rodes, Ryland</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>HIUS 403 Students</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Peter Brownfeld</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B0058</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1999">1999</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500423</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Contract of Indenture of Punch Fox to John
                            H. Rippitoe, May 24, 1850</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records contract of indenture of punch fox to john h rippitoe, may 24 1850</title>
            <author>Ryland Rodes</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>e.g. Translator</resp>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and
                            Abandoned Lands, Record Group 105, Box E4269</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1850-05-24">1850-05-24</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Employment/Labor</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-08">August 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B0058T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This contract details the terms of indenture of Punch Fox to John H.
                Rippitoe.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                

                <p>This Indenture made this 24th Day of May in the Year of our Lord one thousand
                    eight hundred and fifty between Ryland Rodes and John W. Dickinson overseers of
                    the <orig reg="poor">poore</orig> of District in the County of Nelson of the one
                    part and John H. Rippetoe of said County of the other part.</p>

                <p>Witness that the said Ryland Rodes &amp; <abbr expan="John">Jno.</abbr> W.
                    Dickinson overseers of the <orig reg="poor">poore</orig> as aforesaid by virtue
                    of an order of the court of the aforesaid County.</p>

                <p>County bearing date on the __ day of __ in the year 1850 have put placed and
                    bound and by these presents do put place and bind Punch Fox of the age of 10
                    years to be an apprentice with him the said John H. Rippetoe so he will from the
                    date of this presents, until the said Punch Fox shall come to the age of 21
                    years, according to the act of the General Assembly in that case made &amp;
                    provided by and during all which time and tenure the said Punch Fox shall the
                    said John H. Rippetoe, his said master well and faithfully serve in all such
                    lawful business as the said Punch Fox shall be put unto by his said master,
                    according to the power wit and ability of him the said Punch Fox and honestly
                    and obediently in all things shall behave himself towards his master, and
                    honestly and duly toward the rest of the family of the said John H. Rippetoe,
                    and the said John H. Rippetoe for his part himself for execution and
                    administration doth hereby promise and covenant to and with the said overseers
                    of the poor, and every of them their and every of their <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, and
                    administrators, and them and every of their successors, for the <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">time</add> being and to and with the said Punch Fox that he
                    the said <pb n="2"/>John H. Rippetoe shall the said Punch Fox in the craft and
                    occupation of a brick mason such he the said John H. Rippetoe now <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">use</add> with after the manner that he can or may teach
                    instruct and inform or counsel to be taught, instructed, &amp; informed as
                    much as therewith belongeth <add hand="h1" place="inline">or or in any wise
                        appertaineth <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> J. H. Rippitoe</add> , shall also find and
                    allow unto the said aprentice sufficient meat, drink, apparel, washing, lodging,
                    and all other things needful or meet for an apprentice. During the time
                    aforesaid.</p>

                <p>And will moreover pay to the said Punch Fox the sum of forty dollars at the
                    expiration of the aforesaid time in witness of the parties to these presents
                    have interchangeably set their hands and seals the day and year find above
                    written.</p>

                <p>Ryland Rodes {seal}<lb/> Jno. W. Dickinson {seal}<lb/> J. H. Rippetoe {seal}</p>

                <p>A true copy of Indentures Punch Fox to J. H. Rippetoe and on record.<lb/> J. H.
                    Rippetoe</p>

                <p>At a court held for Nelson County the 27th day of May 1850 This deed of
                    apprenticeship was produced into the Court and acknowledged by J. W. Dickinson
                    &amp; Ryland Rodes parties thereto and ordered to lie.<lb/> Teste S. P.
                    Garland Ck.</p>

                <p>And at a court held for said county the 1 day of __ 1857, this deed was <abbr
                        expan="acknowledged">ack<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> by John H. Rippetoe a
                    thrid party thereto &amp; ordered to be recorded.<lb/> Teste--Th. J. Massee
                    Ck.<lb/> A Copy--Teste--S. St. Loving, Ck </p>

                <p>Fee 25c pd by L. Stevenson</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed/>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
