<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1035"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1035">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: George T. Cook to R. S.
                    Lacey, July 31, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george t cook to r s lacey, july 31 1866</title>
        <author>Cook, George T.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1035</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500903</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: George T. Cook to R. S. Lacey, July 31,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records george t cook to r s lacey, july 31 1866</title>
            <author>George T. Cook</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 59.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-07-31">1866-07-31</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Legal System, Slavery, Family, Women, Race Relations, Violence/Crime</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-05">May, 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1035T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Cook's report details two legal cases that he states are representative of the
                    injustices suffered by freedmen in the local courts.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Bureau Refugees, Freedmen, and <abbr expan="Abandoned Lands"
                        >A.L.</abbr><lb/>Office <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Sub-District">Sub-Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 10
                    <name type="recipient">Captain R. S. <orig reg="Lacey">Lacy</orig><lb/><abbr
                            expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr> Seventh <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr><lb/>Lynchburg <abbr expan="Virginia"
                        >Va</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-07-31">July 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have the honor to report in compliance with <abbr expan="paragraph">Par.</abbr>
                    6 Circular <abbr expan="Number">No.</abbr> 10 C S. from <abbr
                        expan="Headquarters">H<hi rend="super">d</hi> qrs</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Assistant">Asst</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Commissioner">Com<hi rend="super">r</hi></abbr> State <abbr
                        expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr> - that as far as notified I have attended
                    criminal trials in which freedmen were concerned in this <abbr
                        expan="Sub-District">sub-Dist</abbr> during the past month. The trials have
                    chiefly been preliminary hearings before Magistrates and almost without
                    exception where white persons have been parties the decisions have been in their
                    favor - there have been several cases assualts upon freedmen - in not one
                    instance has any satisfaction been given the freedmen it is only by the most
                    strenuous exertions that I can get Magistrates to hear the cases and <pb n="2"
                    />the results of trials are so unfavorable as to make it better in most
                    instances not to try the case, for instance if the freedman makes complaint and
                    it is clearly proven the Magistrate will probably bind both parties to keep the
                    Peace, then the freedmen must get bail or go to jail for making the complaint.</p>

                <p>I give the following synopsis of two trials to show the impartiality of the
                    trials the cases are not exceptions, but fair specimens of the rule.</p>

                <p><abbr expan="Charles">Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi></abbr> K. Saupe (white) vs.
                        <abbr expan="William">W<hi rend="super">m</hi></abbr> Gearing (<abbr
                        expan="Freedman">F</abbr>) -- Evidence went to prove that Gearing and his
                    wife live in house adjoining and belong to Saupe. Gearings wife had been abused
                    by the wife of Saupe, Gearing, a quiet mulatto, went in a respectful manner to
                    Mrs. Saupe and asked what the difficulty was - She was angry at being questioned
                    by him, "a nigger" - her husband came in and without remark struck Gearing
                    heavily with a chain, three blows - disfiguring his face. Saupe then got <pb
                        n="3"/>the boy Gearing arrested, and swore the peace, the Magistrate binding
                        <hi rend="underline">Gearing</hi> to keep the peace, it not having been
                    proven that he committed, or threatened to commit any over act.</p>

                <p>2<hi rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    </hi> Alexander Props vs. Taylor Dunlap and Robert Dunlap - Trial proved that
                    the parties with the addition of Props brother Charles were working in hay when
                        <abbr expan="Charles">Cha<hi rend="super">s</hi></abbr> remarked to one of
                    the white men in a laughing way that he would let the white man take a certain
                    part of the work - at which the white man struck Charles - Robert then remarked
                    come work, don't fight, when the remaining white man struck Robert with Pitch
                    fork after some blows Robert resisted, and came out best in the fight, whereupon
                    the whites together gave him a thrashing, after tea they told their father when
                    the old man unable to find his slave whip, had a number of rods cut, and
                    together the party whipped the boy for having resisted. The case after hearing
                    before County Magistrate, in town was dismissed. It was difficult to get a
                    warrant issued in the case - the white men admitted the <pb n="3"/>statement of
                    the boy, Robert, and also admitted his general good character, still <orig
                        reg="although">altho'</orig> they had threatened him with further
                    punishement no action was taken.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very Respectfully<lb/>Your <abbr expan="Obedient">Ob<hi rend="super"
                            >t</hi></abbr> Servant</salute>
                    <signed>Geo. T. Cook<lb/>1<hi rend="super">st</hi>
                        <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Veterans Reserve Corps">V.R.C.</abbr> and <abbr
                            expan="Assistant">Asst.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Superintendent">Supt.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
