<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1092"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1092">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Statement of David Fultz,
                    February 8, 1867</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records statement of david fultz, february 8 1867</title>
        <author>Fultz, David</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1092</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:500960</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Statement of David Fultz, February 8, 1867</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records statement of david fultz, february 8 1867</title>
            <author>David Fultz</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 26.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1867-02-08">1867-02-08</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Administration/Bureaucracy, Legal System</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-07">July 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item checked against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1092T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Fultz, a lawyer in Staunton, offers a statement about his acquaintance with
                    Frederick Tukey. Fultz states that he had the confidence of the local black
                    population, and would therefore have known about any complaints against Tukey,
                    of which, he says, there were none.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="statement" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1867-02-08">February 8. 1867</date>
                        <name type="place">Staunton</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>With surprise I have learned that complaints have been lodged against Mr Tukey in
                    connection with the Freedmens Bureau at this place. I made the acquaintance of
                    Mr T. very soon after he first came to our town; and my Office being in close
                    proximity with his, and having frequently attended professionally to
                        <unclear>business</unclear> which came up before him officially, I had a
                    better opportunity perhaps than any other person to view his conduct both as a
                    private citizen and a public officer.</p>

                <p>And it is but justice to say, that his course has given universal satisfaction to
                    all colors and all shades of party. He has happily mingled a spirit of
                    moderation and conciliation, with a <unclear>firm</unclear> upright and
                    impartial administration of justice to black and white, loyal and disloyal. I am
                    satisfied that no man could <unclear>accept</unclear> that office who would be
                    more acceptable to our people <add hand="h1" place="inline">without regard to
                        color</add> than Mr T.</p>

                <p>I am not the less qualified <pb n="2"/>to judge of the conduct private and public
                    of Mr T. because of the <unclear>sentiments</unclear> I have
                        <unclear>entertained</unclear>, and maintained in relation to the rebellion.
                    I never have had but one opinion on that subject, and that was, that such folly
                    and wickedness never was exhibited in any age by any <orig reg="civilized"
                        >civilised</orig> people. This opinion I have expressed on all suitable
                    occasions, for which I have been frequently insulted and threatened with
                    personal violence.</p>

                <p>After the order directing a Freedmans Court, I was selected by the Freedmen to
                    attend to their interest in said court, but owing to my professsional
                    engagements I had to decline. This would show that I had their confidence, and
                    never having heard a solitary complaint from any one of them, I take it, that
                    there could have been no cause for it.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>David Fultz</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
