<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="B1245"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="B1245">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Freedmen's Bureau Records: Emily Rodney to Orlando
                    Brown, April 2, 1866</title>
        <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records emily rodney to orlando brown, april 2 1866</title>
        <author>Rodney, Emily</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">B1245</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501093</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Freedmen's Bureau Records: Emily Rodney to Orlando Brown, April 2,
                            1866</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">freedmens bureau records emily rodney to orlando brown, april 2 1866</title>
            <author>Emily Rodney</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: National Archives and Records
                            Administration, Records of the Assistant Commissioner for the State of
                            Virginia, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865-1869,
                            Record Group 105, M1048, roll 18.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1866-04-02">1866-04-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Property, Legal System, Race Relations</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2004-06">June 2004</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Ryan Fleenor</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="B1245T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Emily Rodney writes to protest her being barred from preaching to the black
                    population of Staunton by Frederick Tukey and the Freedmen's Court. She writes
                    that the people should be free to worship as they choose, and complains that she
                    was not given a proper hearing. The attached endorsement by Tukey states his
                    side of the case, in which he argues that Miss Rodney was undermining the unity
                    of the community.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="section" id="endorsement">
                <p>Bureau of Refugees, <abbr expan="Freedmen">F.</abbr> &amp; <abbr
                        expan="Abandoned">A.</abbr> Lands<lb/>Sub <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                    "B", 6th <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr><lb/>Staunton, <abbr expan="Virginia"
                    >Va</abbr>, <abbr expan="April">Apr</abbr> 9, 1866</p>

                <p>Respectfully returned to <abbr expan="Major">Maj.</abbr> W. S. How, <abbr
                        expan="Superintendent">Supt</abbr> 6th <abbr expan="District">Dist</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.<lb/>During the absence of Miss Rodney the
                    first time, the colored people of Staunton bought a building for a church, for
                    which they were to pay Two thousand (2000) dollars; one third cash; the balance
                    in one, two and three years; but on account of their impoverished conditions,
                    they were unable to make the first payment as agreed upon; and while striving by
                    all means to do so, Miss Rodney returned and at once commenced holding meetings
                    and dividing the people in religious sentiments by advising them not to give
                    their money towards the payment for the church, because it was presided over by
                    the <hi rend="underline">White</hi> bishop: thus preventing the people from
                    meeting their first payment and making them liable to lose what they had already
                    paid.<lb/>On the facts being represented to me I sent for Miss Rodney, and asked
                    her if she had credentials, authorizing her to preach; it appearing that she had
                    not, and, thinking that the people ought to be united in one body in order to
                    make their organization more efficient, I advised her, in the presence of the
                    Superintendent, to desist from her course, telling her kindly the consequences
                    thereof; she promised to do so, which she did for a short time and then
                    commenced again; I then summoned her to appear before the Freedmen's Court, and
                    gave all parties an opportunity to say all that was necessary to be said for a
                    complete understanding of the case.<lb/>The decision of the Court was that it
                    was for the interest of the whole colored population that she should stop
                    preaching here and she was so instructed to do.</p>

                <p>F.S. Tukey<lb/><abbr expan="Assistant Superintendent">Asst Supt</abbr> Sub <abbr
                        expan="District">Dist</abbr> "B"<lb/>Sixth <abbr expan="District"
                    >Dist</abbr>, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d5">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="General">Gen</abbr> O Brown<lb/><abbr
                            expan="Assistant Commissioner, Freedmen's Bureau">A.C.F.B.</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1866-04-02">April 2d 1866</date>
                        <name type="place">Richmond <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Last fall about 1st <abbr expan="September">Sept</abbr> I was sent on a Mission
                    by our church to Staunton <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr> to look after the
                    Spiritual interest of My People. I found them without any shepherd and
                    worshipping in the abasement of the Church South. I read our discipline to them
                    and almost all of them voted to join our Church numbering about 500; and the
                    list enclosed of 139 names are those who agreed to contribute towards building a
                        <abbr expan="African Methodist Episcopal">A.M.E.</abbr> Church. </p>

                <p><abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> W. D. Harris by authority from Bishop Payne
                    sent <pb n="2"/>a Preacher (<abbr expan="Reverend">Rev.</abbr> Mat. Marshal to
                    preach for them, who went up and labored with the people very acceptably for 3
                    or four weeks and the people were willing to unite with our church and were
                    anxious to do so. But Mr. Tukey advised him to let them remain where they were
                    until Spring so Mr. Marshal complied with Mr Tukeys wishes and left them but
                    during the winter the Washington Conference sends a man there who receives Mr.
                    Tukeys cooperation and a portion of the members join the Washington Conference
                    Church we have nothing against their having all the members who desire to belong
                    there but we do ask as in the the name <pb n="3"/>of Justice and Religious
                    Liberty that the people be allowed to worship God according to the dictates of
                    their consciences and that they be allowed to join the Church of their first
                    Choice, and that your humble servant be allowed to preach and hold meetings with
                    the people in the usual orderly and peaceful Manner. I was sent for by the
                    people, I went and found them divided and in a very unsettled and dissatisfied
                    state, I labored for Union, and love, and peace among them. By false accusations
                    I was summoned to appear before Mr. Tukey who advised me to desist from
                    preaching until some money was raised for the preacher of the <abbr
                        expan="Washington Conference">W.C.</abbr> Church. I complied until he went
                    away <pb n="4"/>I commenced holding my meetings again far away from their place
                    of Meeting and Mr. Tukey summoned me before him, to a trial. I took witnesses
                    along with me but he heard the testimony and statements of my enemies and
                    refused to hear any statement of facts from my friends or witnesses and then
                    decided that I should not hold any <hi rend="underline">more</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">meetings</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">in Staunton</hi> and that I should stop <hi
                        rend="underline">preaching</hi> there. I told him that I should appeal to
                    you from his decision. He stated that he believed me to be a lady and that my
                    motives were pure. I now respectfully but earnestly ask that I be allowed to
                    continue to hold meetings in a lawful way in Staunton. The people are determined
                    to join the <abbr expan="African Methodist Episcopal">A.M.E.</abbr> Church and
                    have sent for a Minister to come and organize them into a church according to
                    agreement last fall.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Most respectfully submitted</salute>
                    <signed>Emily Rodney</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
