<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0015"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F0015">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    January 15, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 15 1863</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0015</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501190</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, January 15, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 15 1863</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Pennsylvania Historical and
                            Museum Commission, Civil War Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters,
                            Microfilm, MG-132.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>This transcription was made from a typescript of the original
                            letter.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-01-15">1863-01-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Family, Homefront, Medicine/Hospitals, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against transcript; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0015T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter describes the relatively comfortable conditions in his new camp and the
                    unusually pleasant weather. He also mentions that the Confederate forces across
                    the Potomac River appear to be preparing for a fight. His letter includes a
                    postscript to a person named Janey.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                
          

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-01-15">Jan 15th 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Gregg Near Falmouth Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>About an hour ago the mail came in &amp; I got 3 letters one from Aunt Mary
                    Ann Spriggs one from sister Mary &amp; the other, the first that I have got
                    for a good while, from you. Some jackass had sent home word that we were going
                    to Texas &amp; I suppose that is the reason that you did not write. It is
                    nearly 4 weeks since I have got a letter from you, but today I am well paid for
                    waiting. Your letter was like a good dinner to a hungry man. I have to sit down
                    &amp; read it over &amp; then over again. I had not heard until today
                    that Josey got hurt. I wish in your next letter you would tell me how it
                    happened &amp; all about it. On yesterday I rode over to see the 140th. I
                    saw Josiah Carrol, Tom Lucas, Warren Burns, Ben Ernest &amp; all the rest of
                    the West Finley boys. They were all fat &amp; hearty. They have built
                    themselves log cabins &amp; live very <orig reg="comfortably"
                    >comfortable</orig>. Then I went on to Falmouth &amp; rode on the river
                    banks while the rebel pickets were on the other side about 60 yards over. The
                    river here is very narrow &amp; rocky. I could see the rebels digging their
                        <orig reg="entrenchments">intrenchments</orig> preparing for another fight.
                    I was about a mile above Frederick in full view of the town &amp; intended
                    going down to get a better view when a guard stopped me &amp; told I must
                    have a pass from <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Burnsides so I turned back
                    &amp; came to our camp in the woods again &amp; here we are getting
                    along <orig reg="fine">finely</orig>. We have our hospital tents all up our
                    stoves &amp; plenty of wood to keep us warm. The other Steward &amp;
                    myself have a tent to ourselves. We have a nice pine board floor in it &amp;
                    I am now sitting on the edge of our bed made by driving 4 forked sticks in the
                    ground laying crosspieces on the forks &amp; then a lot of hoop poles on
                    that. We have a bed tick filled with hay &amp; then our blankets making the
                    best kind of a bed. For the hospital we have iron bed steads &amp; plenty of
                    bed clothing to keep the sick warm. The soldiers here have all built log cabins
                    with fire places in them &amp; have them comfortable. The weather here has
                    been very nice warm &amp; pleasant. I am going in my shirt sleeves for some
                    days. The boys are all in good health here there are not very many in the
                    hospital/</p>

                <p>I wish I was at your side to get a piece of your bread &amp; apple butter
                    with Josey. I feel so sorry about his arm. You must write to me how it happened
                    &amp; I did not know anything of it until today.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Can't">Cant</orig> you give Jimmy a piece &amp; let Lucy nurse him
                    in the big arm chair while my little Bell sings to him. Well Cynthia you weigh
                    more than I do. My weight is about 150 lbs. About Simon Carrol do not let it run
                    too long or you can get nothing from him. You had better give the note to Squire
                    Frazier soon while Simon has something in his hand. Give the note to the Squire
                    to collect. I sent my carpet sack home to you &amp; sent you a letter with
                    the key in it. Write and let me know if you get it. I will have to close soon.
                    Cynthia direct your letters to Washington City as you have been &amp; they
                    will follow me any place. </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>God bless you dear wife &amp; may he take you and the children under
                        his care is the prayer of your husband &amp; father</salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Well Janey you will excuse me for not writing a long
                        letter to you as Cynthia's contains about all I can tell you. Today we had a
                        pleasant march from Washington down. Only one man was hurt. His pistol went
                        off and he pulled it through the bushes &amp; shot him in the flesh of
                        the arm not very dangerous but will make him take more care how he handles a
                        pistol.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
