<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0016"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0016">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    February 3, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 3 1863</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0016</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501191</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, February 3, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 3 1863</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Pennsylvania Historical and
                            Museum Commission, Civil War Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters,
                            Microfilm, MG-132.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>This transcription was made from a typescript of the original
                            letter.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-02-03">1863-02-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Death/Casualties, Family, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against transcription; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0016T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter writes to his wife about the new camp where his regiment has settled. He
                    also mentions news from his sister Mary about the loss of several family members
                    in one battle.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-02-03">Feb. 3rd 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16th Pa. Cavalry</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Mr Frazier who came with <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> Gunn brought me a
                    couple pair of socks with some butter &amp; a late Wash. Co. newspaper from
                    home &amp; also in the socks a letter from you. I was glad that you are all
                    well &amp; Joseys arm well enough to go to school again so that he could use
                    his new second reader. I am pleased to hear of him being such a good boy
                    &amp; learning so well. I would be very much pleased too if Lucy would go
                    with Josey &amp; learn to read with him. &amp; then she could teach Bell
                    her letters &amp; Jimmy Sloan too when he learns to talk. Ask Lucy if she
                        <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> go to school for Pa &amp; he will send her
                    something nice. Mr Frazier says <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut.</abbr> Gunn took
                    sick in Washington City &amp; could not come down to the army of the
                    Potomac. Well we have no particular news here. We have moved into our new camp
                    in the Pine Woods which was a cornfield 25 years ago &amp; you can see the
                    ridge of each corn row yet. Some of the trees are as thick as a <orig
                        reg="man's">mans</orig> body. The boys all have put up their cabins again
                    &amp; have made them very comfortable with fireplaces to burn wood in. They
                    are all well except Adam Hewitt who has inflamation of the lungs I think. We
                    have quite a number in the hospital from other companies &amp; the Doctor is
                    having a large log house built for the use of the sick. When that is finished we
                    will have ample room for the sick. You tell me not to go near the rebs for fear
                    of being shot. There is no danger of that now. They are 7 or 8 miles from us.
                    The time I was so near them was when I was on a visit to some other regiments. I
                    have not had time since for riding out &amp; expect will not for some time
                    to come &amp; as we are in the woods with the army all <orig reg="around"
                        >round</orig> us the rebels would have some trouble in getting here to get a
                    pop at us. (I think so) I got a letter a few days ago from Mary. She tells me
                    that they are all well at home but has sad news from Uncle <orig reg="John's"
                        >Johns</orig> family. Cousin David was killed at the Murphysboro fight,
                    Cousin Jimmie wounded, &amp; Robert missing. You recollect <abbr
                        expan="Cousin">Cos.</abbr> David a noble generous hearted man. He has given
                    his life that we may have liberty for ourselves &amp; children. From what
                    Mary said he was ready to die. To give an account for the deeds done in the body
                    by having accepted salvation by Jesus Christ as offered in the Gospel. We should
                    all see to it that our calling &amp; election is sure for we do not know
                    when the angel of death may summon any of us away from this earth. Uncle John
                    &amp; Aunt Jane will be in trouble, whereas Robert will be their constant
                    care &amp; will James recover to come back to them will be a great deal of
                    anxiety to them. We expect from all indications to stay here for some time. For
                    how long it is not known, but the mud will for some time hold the
                    <unclear>army</unclear> level. Our paymaster has not come yet but like the good
                    time coming will be here after a while. Cynthia I am delighted with your
                    present. The butter is not so coarse on hard crackers &amp; as the air today
                    is frosty the socks are bully. I have nothing else to write today but to leave
                    us all in the care of our Heavenly Father that he may protect you from all
                    dangers seen &amp; unseen</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
