<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0029"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0029">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    February 12, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 12 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0029</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501204</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, February 12,
                            1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, february 12 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-02-12">1864-02-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Desertion/Leave </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0029T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter asks about the family and discusses the possibility of receiving a
                    furlough.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-02-12">Feb 12<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16th Pa Cav, Near Warrenton, Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The post master has just now handed me two letters from you &amp; if you were
                    anxious because mine were delayed you may well imagine my anxiety not hearing
                    from since the last day of January.</p>

                <p>Will Potters box came all right &amp; so did my cake &amp; can of apples
                    &amp; I tell you they were good, but I looked for a letter at the same time
                    &amp; got none until today. These two make me all right again. </p>

                <p>We have nothing new. The papers will give you an account of what part of the army
                    has been doing. Our Division (2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> Cavalry Corps) was not
                    out. We are still quiet. The <orig reg="rebels">rebs</orig>
                    <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> bother us of any account. Though we are ordered to
                    saddle up now and then nothing has been done yet.</p>

                <p>Some of the regiments of our brigade have gone home &amp; others will go
                    after a while on 30 days furlough. If we had the chance I would be tempted to
                    reenlist for the sake of getting home again, but you need not be afraid we <orig
                        reg="won't">wont</orig> have the chance this winter. I <orig reg="don't"
                        >dont</orig> know whether I will get to Harrisburg in March or not. Dr. King
                    has assigned Dr. Francis LeMoyne as our Surgeon, leaving Dr. Herrmann still the
                    assistant &amp; no opening for me. I would like to help you to burn your
                    pile of wood this winter. Although we have plenty of wood here &amp; can
                    keep warm and comfortable it is not so nice or pleasant as a seat beside you
                    would be. Being entirely well &amp; hearty now you would not be bothered
                    making catnip tea for me &amp; then I could have some little folks to help
                    me eat those nice cakes you bake &amp; have them sing for me. It would sound
                    much better if one of them would call me to dinner or supper, than the sound of
                    our bugle making its different calls, as we are waked in the morning called to
                    breakfast called to breakfast, called to wait on the sick, called to feed our
                    horses &amp; then to water them, then dinner call comes, dress parade, guard
                    mounting &amp; stable call again, supper, retreat, tatoo &amp; lastly we
                    put out our lights &amp; go to bed at the call of the bugle. You may be sure
                    I would prefer the music of home in its different keys.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Don't">Dont</orig> let Josey be out after night about the mill race or
                    tan yard. He might get drowned. The pay master has not been here since my return
                    &amp; I have no chance of getting any more money until he comes, or I get a
                    furlough for Harrisburg, when I may get some in Washington City if our paymaster
                    will be at his office. When this will be I do not know. We have most delightful
                    weather yet &amp; while thinking of home so much I thought I could fill two
                    letters when writing to you, but now I feel so well contented I <orig
                        reg="can't">cant</orig> think of anything interesting. I can see you all
                    smiling &amp; happy at home &amp; that satisfies me.</p>

                <p>The boys generally are stout &amp; hearty. Will Carrol is getting fat as a
                    pig. Will Potter keeps stout as ever. George <sic corr="McDaid's" cert="no"
                        >McDairs</sic> health is tolerable. </p>

                <p>Our regiment has a great deal of guard and picket duty to do &amp; which
                    keeps the boys quite busy &amp; this fine weather is not hard on them. </p>

                <p>Our hospital duties are very light not very many on the sick list &amp; none
                    of them very bad. As no mail will go out this evening I will keep this open
                    until morning so that if anything new occurs I will let you know. </p>

                <p>Saturday morning bright sunshiny, all quiet. Would you send me some stamps or
                    envelopes. The one you sent saved me from borrowing. I have no chance of getting
                    any here. Josey cries when mother corrects Jimmy. Well Josey mother does it
                    because she loves him &amp; she wants him to be a good boy. I am glad that
                    my children are good to mother &amp; I am glad too Josey that you said your
                    questions so well when Mr. McKee was examining you. I am glad too that Lucy
                    could answer some &amp; Bell say her little prayer. It would have given me
                    great pleasure to be with you then to answer too. If all our friends at home
                    would be earnest in prayer for the soldiers &amp; our country, might we not
                    expect to have the blessing of God on our efforts. The reason my horse was shot
                    was, that he had something like glanders. I will get another in a few days. Our
                    surgeon has not arrived yet.</p>

                <p>The weather today is warm and pleasant the roads are dry &amp; I wish I was
                    at home to go up to church tomorrow having the whole family along. Will you have
                    an opportunity of going? At least Josey can go &amp; when he returns tell
                    you where Mr. McKee's text is. Can he remember the text yet? He could tell some
                    part of the sermon I suppose. Tomorrow we will have mounted inspection in the
                    forenoon &amp; in the afternoon inspection of camp &amp; the <orig
                        reg="men's">mens</orig> quarters. That will be our Sabbath's duties,
                    although the <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lt.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> is a Presbyterian yet he must live up to
                    regulations.</p>

                <p>Write soon Cynthia &amp; let me hear from you regularly.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your most affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
