<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0023"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0023">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    September 28, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, september 28 1863</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0023</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501198</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, September 28,
                            1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, september 28 1863</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-09-28">1863-09-28 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Desertion/Leave, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0023T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter describes the bleak conditions at his brigade's new camp at Bealton
                    Station, Virginia. He also talks of dedicating himself to God and of wanting to
                    return home on a furlough.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-09-28">September 28<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Bealton Station <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your welcome letter was received yesterday evening after I had gone to bed
                    &amp; I suppose the <orig reg="pleasant">plesent</orig> dreams of last night
                    are to be attributed to the fact. You will see by the above that we are not in
                    the front at present. Just as I had finished writing my last letter we got
                    orders to be ready to move in half an hour. I put your letter in my pocket
                    &amp; packed up ready for the march. We formed into column &amp; turned
                    our backs on the Rapidan passed through <sic corr="Culpeper">Culpepper</sic>
                    &amp; on to the <sic corr="Rappahannock">Rappohannock</sic> where we <orig
                        reg="stopped">stooped</orig> to get a few more hours sleep &amp; rest
                    our horses. In the morning we resumed our march our rest coming to Bealton while
                    Brigade Headquarters at <orig reg="Rappahannock">Rappohannock</orig> Station.
                    Our division is now guarding this railroad from <orig reg="Manassas"
                    >Manasses</orig> Junction to the Rappahannock Division Headquarters at Catletts
                    Station. We have very little to do here. One squadron being out on picket while
                    the rest are laying in camp. We <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> have many sick
                    now. There are a great many soldiers passing back &amp; forwards &amp;
                    at present the prospects of a battle here <orig reg="are">is</orig> quite
                    distant but we may be <orig reg="disappointed">dissapointed</orig>. I have not
                    heard of any stir in the front. The report here is that the rebs are falling
                    back. I think their energies are turning to defeat <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Rosecrans so the army of the Potomac will have some rest from
                    marching &amp; fighting. We <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> live here quite so
                    well here as we did in the front. The army has been here all summer &amp;
                    the whole of this once beautiful country is a continuous scene of desolation.
                    There are no cornfields nor potato patches, hogs or sheep munching over the
                    fields. What few citizens remain here have nothing to sell or trade for our
                    coffee or sugar but still we live well &amp; I have as good health as ever.
                    I suppose Josiah got home on a sick furlough. Is he getting better. You ask me
                    whether it would be a good plan to get Martin Danly to take Josiahs note for the
                    rent. I think it would do very well. It will save us paying so much money
                    &amp; you would be a long time getting it from Carrols. I suppose Mr. Burns
                    death will be a lesson for all of us to be ready for we know not the day nor the
                    day when the angel of death will take either of us from this earth. May we
                    strive for a home in heaven. We know our time will come to die &amp; so let
                    us be prepared to meet the author of our existence to give an account of the
                    deeds done here on earth &amp; oh that we may hear that welcome sentence.
                    Well done good &amp; faithful servant, enter thou in the joy of thy Lord.
                    What will become of us when we die. Will we have time &amp; <orig
                        reg="opportunity">oppurtunity</orig>. Dear Cynthia let us prepare, though
                    others do as they will. &amp; Bell said she would be a good girl if mother
                    would take her to meeting. Mothers heart plead for her little daughter &amp;
                    they all went to Church. God bless mother &amp; her little children. I know
                    they will all be good for mother. God is a prayer hearing &amp; prayer
                    answering God &amp; will keep her children if she takes them to a throne of
                    grace &amp; there gives herself &amp; them into his care. You wonder if
                    you will have to go alone to see your mother. Well this time I expect you will
                    as I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> expect to get a furlough for some time yet.
                    None are granted except to the sick &amp; wounded but if I am spared to get
                    home &amp; am able to go with you I expect to enjoy the pleasure of riding
                    with you. &amp; the children down to your mothers &amp; having a
                    pleasant visit if they are all well. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> want them
                    to think hard of my <orig reg="laziness">lasiness</orig> in not writing to them
                    for <orig reg="laziness">lasiness</orig> is a poor excuse. The only letters I
                    have written are to my wife &amp; fathers except on business. There are
                    quite a number of my friends that I am not treating well but when I go to write
                    I think of Cynthia, Josey. Lucy, Bell &amp; Jimmy &amp; they crowd
                    others out of my mind. All of my affections center there. There is the
                    attraction for me, if I were to get twenty letters a week &amp; none from my
                    wife. I would be as uneasy &amp; unsatisfied as if I got none. To tell the
                    truth you are that I am anxious to hear about &amp; yet at your mothers I
                    have enjoyed myself well &amp; if I was there I would enjoy myself again in
                    their company, but still when I sit down to write a letter Cynthia is the one I
                    am thinking of. You <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> want me to join the army. Well
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> be afraid. I would rather join my family now
                    than anything I can think of. You seem to think I could get a furlough yet as I
                    got one in July. That one was got under peculiar circumstances which I will
                    explain after I get home. The same excuse <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be
                    brought before the General now. Then it was not a furlough as none were granted
                    but my claimed were urged in such a manner that instead of breaking his rule to
                    give me one he issued a special order, ordering me to go &amp; report back
                    to the <abbr expan="regiment">regt.</abbr> in July &amp; as you are aware I
                    never got the order because John Milligan &amp; I were in a barn in Maryland
                    when the order came to the regiment in <abbr expan="Virginia">Vir.</abbr> The
                    Doctors thinking I would go to a Hospital in Baltimore sent the order to my
                    address in Baltimore but I never got it &amp; did not hear from the regiment
                    until I joined it in August when they told me about the matter but too late. The
                    time had run out. The same claims <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> be urged now
                    &amp; I will have to wait &amp; take my turn with the rest. If there is
                    any chance at all I will be glad to accept it for the purpose of seeing those I
                    am thinking about all the time. There is no person on this round ball that I
                    would rather see than my own dear wife &amp; children. Tell Josey that his
                    drum will not be forgotten nor Lucy Bell nor Jimmy. I think I can find something
                    for each of you. There were some <abbr expan="Secessionist">Secesh</abbr> papers
                    in camp a few days ago but none of the boys would sell theirs. They wanted to
                    send them home. You will get the first one I secure. You say Sam Danly wants me
                    to write to him well there is Joe Sutherland, Alex Harvey, &amp; a number of
                    others that I ought to write to some day when I <orig reg="haven't"
                    >havent</orig> much to do maybe I'll write. I have my monthly report of sick to
                    make out tomorrow which will keep me busy for a day. Give my love to your
                    mother, Dolly, Anne, &amp; Emme as that is all the family they have that I
                    know of. I hope you will find your sister Jane in better health. Give her my
                    love. The little girls too. Remember me to them. I hope your visit may be a
                    pleasant one. I wish I were with you to help you enjoy it. <orig reg="Won't"
                        >Wont</orig> you need wintry clothing for the children &amp; yourself.
                    When you write next let me know how you are getting along. Have you a good
                    garden &amp; will the folks keep the stock out of it while you are gone. You
                    had better keep an eye on Jimmy or he will run out some place &amp; you will
                    be uneasy until you find him. I reckon when I get home he can run down to the
                    gate to meet me but he <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> know me. You will have to
                    give me an introduction. <orig reg="Won't">Wont</orig> you. Mrs. Emerick has a
                    young son, <orig reg="wasn't">wasnt</orig> Hannah or James Roney the Doctor. The
                    2 pairs of socks will be very acceptable I tell you but I reckon you want me to
                    go for them so there you are. See how they fit. If they fit well I will wear
                    them. No more at present dear wife, </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>From your affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Give my love to Josey, Bell, Lucy &amp; Jimmy </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
