<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0026"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0026">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    January 26, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 26 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0026</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501201</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, January 26, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, january 26 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-01-26">1864-01-26 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Family, Medicine/Hospitals </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0026T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter explains why he has not written more often and tells about moving into new
                    quarters near Warrenton, Virginia.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-01-26"><abbr expan="January">Jan</abbr> 26<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp 16<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                            <abbr expan="Pennsylvania 
                                Cavalry">Pa Cav</abbr> Turkey Run Near Warrenton
                            <abbr expan="Virginia">Va</abbr>
                        </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Cynthia </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I suppose you will scold me for not writing sooner but I was busy yesterday
                    &amp; could not get time. We are in the old tracks again. In the morning we
                    have sick call, which lasts for an hour &amp; a half or so. Then I have to
                    visit those who are sick in the quarters, taking about an hour. Soon dinner
                    comes. As a matter of course that must be attended to too &amp; we do it
                    full justice. After noon we read or ride out but as my horse has been condemned
                    &amp; shot I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> indulge much in that exercise.
                    Now you will suppose that I have plenty of time in the afternoon to write
                    &amp; so might be more punctual. The fact is through the week after getting
                    your letter I feel very well contented &amp; <orig reg="don't">dont</orig>
                    think of writing. As the week draws to a close I begin to feel anxious for the
                    mail to come in, thinking I might get a letter. Well last week none came.
                    Sabbath I though certainly one would be here that day, so I waited all day
                    &amp; in the evening they said there was no letter for me. Well then I
                    thought surely I would write. Well before writing I thought I would lay down
                    &amp; shut my eyes &amp; see you all at home. Well I lay there &amp;
                    talked with you &amp; the children until nearly bedtime. The <abbr
                        expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr> had been reading he laid down his book &amp;
                    commenced talking so I thought to put off writing to you until Monday morning.
                    Monday morning came &amp; the <orig reg="Veterinary">Vetinary</orig> Surgeon
                    came in &amp; handed me a letter. The postmaster gave it to him &amp; he
                    forgot to give it to me. One <orig reg="man's">mans</orig> carelessness often
                    gives others a great deal of uneasiness. If he had handed me your letter when he
                    got it I could have <orig reg="written">writen</orig> three days sooner.</p>

                <p>Now the reason why I was so busy yesterday is the <abbr expan="Doctor">Dr.</abbr>
                    concluded to put up quarters in the Regiment as we were some little distance out
                    of camp. I took the day to superintend the putting up of shanties, which kept me
                    busy all day. Today we moved. I have a first rate shanty of logs built up a
                    fireplace &amp; chimney in it &amp; covered with shelter<del hand="h1"
                        >ed</del> tents. It will be very comfortable. I have the medicines all fixed
                    up writing desk &amp; so on.</p>

                <p>Your letter was very welcome as I was lonesome for one with news from my wife. I
                    got not only news but encouragement from your cheering letter. I will send your
                    portfolio the first <orig reg="opportunity">oppurtunity</orig>.</p>

                <p>The weather here has been most delightful for a few days. The mud has dried up
                    &amp; it is like Spring. We certainly will have winter weather to pay up for
                    this soft snap. </p>

                <p>I would like to make you spill another dish of molasses one of these days but
                        <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know when. Probably not until March as then I
                    will get a furlough to go to Harrisburg &amp; as a matter of course Good
                    Intent is on the road to Harrisburg &amp; I will have to pass through it
                    &amp; might stop over night if anyone would keep me. None of the girls have
                    been to see you yet. They told me one of them would go down in a day or two
                    after I was there. They probably heard that Bell was better &amp; did not
                    go. </p>

                <p>I wrote to them a day or two after my return to the Regiment &amp; have no
                    answer from them yet. My letter may have been miscarried or they may have been
                    slow in answering. We had one of the Richmond boys to see us. Their Regiment is
                    near Warrenton. They are all well.</p>

                <p>I wrote to David &amp; Eliza but have no answer from them as yet. This letter
                    will not reach you in the time you expect one &amp; I sympathize with you in
                    advance, promising after this to write <orig reg="whether">wether</orig> yours
                    come or not.</p>

                <p>You wrote saying my last had not been received but that you would write thinking
                    Pa would be lonesome for a letter. I was very lonesome for one &amp; am very
                    glad that you wrote &amp; such a pleasant one too, made it doubly welcome.
                    After this I will try &amp; be more punctual. Jimmy is beginning to talk. I
                    expect his attempts are <orig reg="awkward">awkard</orig> &amp; amusing
                    &amp; must be interesting. I would like to hear him. Write to me how Josey
                    Lucy &amp; Bell are getting along. What are they doing &amp; what do
                    they say. I have an idea what my wife would say if I was their with her
                    &amp; I will now say that I will pray for the <orig reg="choicest"
                    >choisest</orig> blessings upon her &amp; her family &amp; am still her
                    most affectionate husband </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>S.M. Potter </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
