<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0033"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0033">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter,
                    April 19, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 19 1864</title>
        <author>Potter, Samuel M. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0033</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501208</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This is transcribed from a typescript.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel M. Potter to Cynthia Potter, April 19, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel m potter to cynthia potter, april 19 1864</title>
            <author>Samuel M. Potter </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Editor </resp>
                            <name>Name of Editor </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Potter Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-19">1864-04-19 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 16th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0033T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Potter writes without much news except to reassure his wife that life in camp is
                    fine.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Cynthia Potter</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-19">April 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">Hospital Dept. 16th Pa. Cav. Turkey Run, Va.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Wife </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>There is a report this evening that after tomorrow our mail will be stopped for
                    60 days. I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know whether it is true or false. If
                    true this letter will do no harm although not to get a letter from you for so
                    long a time will seem like parting. I was contented while I heard from you once
                    a week it seemed you were near. Now how <orig reg="different">differant</orig>.
                    Your cheering loving letter will not come. </p>

                <p>Still no military orders can take your sweet beautiful picture from me nor
                    deprive me of the delicious dreams I have of a loving beautiful tender wife. My
                    object in writing is that you may not be <orig reg="disappointed"
                    >dissapointed</orig> if this order be true. I want you to write regularly once a
                    week. The order may not be true &amp; I will still get your ever welcome
                    letters. <orig reg="Don't">Dont</orig> forget write once a week. My health is as
                    goood as usual. We are still in the old comfortable <abbr expan="quarters"
                        >qrters</abbr>. <orig reg="Don't">Dont</orig> know how soon we may move. The
                    Brigade was on a scout yesterday but saw no rebels. All is quiet yet. Give my
                    love to the children. Tell Josey that I am looking for another letter from him.
                    When Dr. King will send for me to go to Harrisburg I <orig reg="don't"
                    >dont</orig> know. but I hope it will not be long. So that I can have the
                    pleasure of seeing you again. I would ask you to remember me at the throne of
                    Grace asking the blessing of the Almighty that I may not be led into temptation
                    but that I may be able to honor his name in my walk &amp; conversation
                    &amp; my petitions will be for you dear wife that you may be preserved in
                    this care, that his tender mercy may be over you keeping you from danger
                    &amp; temptation, that you may be sanctified &amp; be accepted holy for
                        <orig reg="Christ's">Christ'</orig> sake.</p>

                <p>Remember our vows to God in our baptism of our children, as you have all the
                    responsibilities now, watch over them, keep them out of bad company, teach them
                    the ways of Godliness &amp; may he bless you &amp; sustain you in your
                    labor of love. <orig reg="Don't">Dont</orig> forget to write whether the mail
                    will be stopped or not. A letter may chance to come through giving me pleasures
                    &amp; news from home. I promise to write all <orig reg="opportunities"
                        >oppurtunities</orig> I get, whether you hear from me or not still be
                    assured that you have the tenderest love of all </p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>of your most affectionate husband </salute>
                    <signed>S. M. Potter </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Morning this report may not be true. I hope not. I am
                        still hearty as usual.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
