<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0048"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0048">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Sam Taggart, June
                    24, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to sam taggart, june 24 1862</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">10</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0048</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501223</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Sam Taggart, June 24, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to sam taggart, june 24 1862</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-06-24">1862-06-24 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Camp Life, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0048T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart discusses the movement of Union troops around Richmond. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Sam Taggart</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-06-24">June 24<hi rend="super">th</hi>/62 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Richmond </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>
                        <hi rend="underline">Dear Sam</hi>
                    </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I will now commence to answer yours of the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi>, but it is
                    a hard matter to tell how long I may be permitted to write without being
                    interrupted by the sound of the "long roll," or the cry of "fall in." <del
                        hand="h1"/> usual thing here to form "line of battle" three or four times a
                    day. At the present moment the arms of our regiment are all "stacked," ready to
                    be grasped and used whenever on guard. </p>

                <p>On Tuesday the 17<hi rend="super">th</hi> we resigned the indolence of camp life
                    near Fredericksburg, and marched to a point on the River Rappahannock 7 miles
                    below the city, expecting to there <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and proceed to join the "Army before Richmond." It was Friday
                    however before we shipped and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on Saturday at 3 P.M. disembarked
                    at Whitehouse landing on the <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Parum">Parum</orig>
                    </unclear> bay. I enjoyed the trip down the Rapphannock down the bay, and up the
                    York, very much, the scenery along the banks of those <pb n="2"/> waters is
                    beautiful, but on entering the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> everything seemed to suddenly
                    change. The shore land, so low that it could be <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> distinguished,
                    covered with swamp weeds. Vegetation looks sickly. Swamps abound, and no signs
                    of improvement or civilization are visible as far as the eye could reach. Treked
                    out Charter's creek being a crooked stream, <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> as we were steaming up the Rapphannock over appeared at anchor
                    right before us I thought about 300 yards. Imagine my surprise when after more
                    than two hours sailing at the rate of ten <hi rend="underline">miles an hour we
                        found <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> schooner at anchor</hi>, and on looking back, could
                    see other schooners which we had <hi rend="underline">passed early in the
                        morning</hi>, apparently right behind us. I must have been <hi
                        rend="underline">twenty-five miles around</hi> this peninsula -- so I
                    understand from hands on the boat -- and only a <hi rend="underline">few hundred
                        yards across</hi>. Our regiment occupied the steamer "Georgia," having in
                    time two schooners <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> baggage &amp; train.</p>

                <p>Whitehouse station is a miserable look <pb n="2"/>ing place. The only thing to be
                    seen are "Government Hospitals" "<hi rend="underline">Undertaker's</hi>" shops,
                        <hi rend="underline">Embalmers</hi> of the dead, Suiters, &amp; niggers.
                    I felt no reluctance on Sunday morning -- the day after our arrival -- as we
                    packed up and started out the Richmond &amp; West Point <abbr
                        expan="Railroad">R.R.</abbr> Just as we were about leaving I met Dr. Gilmore
                    who looked well and reported the healthy condition of <orig reg="Woodville"
                        >Woodville</orig> and vicinity. On Sunday evening we bivouaced at <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Huntlett's">Huntlett's</orig>
                    </unclear> Station, getting our shelter up, just in time to protect us from a
                    heavy rain. On Monday, we marched to "Dispatch" Station 13 miles from Richmond.
                    Remained there until Wednesday morning and started out again after marching
                    above 9 miles <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> right in front of <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen.</abbr> Porter's division a little less than a mile from <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Black's Regiment. During our stay, Tom Douglass
                    &amp; <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> called on us. They both look well. Thursday morning we marched
                    out to this place. One mile from Mechanicsville, &amp; about 4 1/2 miles
                    from Richmond. Our first encampment here was on a field five or six hundred <pb
                        n="3"/> yards front of where we now are. We had to vacate it and an
                    encampment on account of its proximity to certain rebel fortifications on the
                    other side of the Chickahominy. We are now in a dense woods and concealed from
                    the view of the enemy, but still within range of their guns. </p>

                <p>Well, Sam, this looks, feels, and sounds like active service not a single half
                    hour in the day passes without the sound of musketry or artillery breaking upon
                    the Earth <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> the shots in such quick succession and awaken apprehensions of
                    a general engagement. Every morning before day break the different regiments are
                    arroused and made to put every thing in order for instant action, formed in line
                    of battle, marched to one point &amp; then to another <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and all conducted with the regularity and indifference of a
                    country <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> hearing recitations.</p>

                <p>Our <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and those of the enemy line the banks of the river, at some
                    places only few yards apart and stationed <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                </p>

                <p>Yesterday the enemy's pickets fired at some of our men. <abbr expan="General"
                    >Gen</abbr> Seymour ordered the Mt. Jackson boys, <unclear>
                        <orig reg="Swarton's">Swarton's</orig>
                    </unclear>, and a regular battery in position on the hiss this side the river.
                    The 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> was formed in their rear, ready to support.
                    Companies "C." &amp; "G." were sent out as skirmishers, with orders to
                    approach the bridge unobserved, make a dash across, and "<hi rend="underline"
                        >feel</hi><pb n="4"/>marked" by the enemy. there is a probability that we
                    may stay here longer than eight days and as there is only a chance occasion of
                    sending letter to Washington, you must not be disappointed if you don't hear
                    from me soon. I wish you would get and send me (directed as usual) some sort of
                    a <hi rend="underline">diary</hi> in which to "take notes." the article can't be
                    got here and I often find myself at a <pb n="5"/> loss for such a thing. I begin
                    to like the <orig reg="Gypsy">Gipsey</orig> life a little better than at first,
                    and don't care much if they do keep us here a little time longer. My health is
                    very good.</p>

                <p>My love to all the folks. Respect to <orig reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig>
                    friends. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
