<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0045"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0045">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John
                    Taggart, October 11, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, october 11 1861</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0045</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/ </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501220</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>The first page and a half of the original letter are too faded to read and
                        are omitted from this transcription.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to Captain John Taggart, October 11,
                            1861</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to captain john taggart, october 11 1861</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-10-11">1861-10-11 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0045T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart describes his regiment's movement into a new camp and tells about an
                    incident in which union soldiers stole a farmer's oats.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-10-11"><abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> 11<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 1861 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Pierpont <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                            <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Va. </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John </salute>
                </opener>
                <p><del rend="none" hand="h1"/><pb n="2"/>On Wednesday evening, when we arrived here, we were
                    marched into <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> field to encamp for the night. Taking a survey of the ground,
                    it was evident we were going to have very soft, though apparently, not very
                    comfortable beds. In one corner of the field stood a large stack of unthreshed
                    oats and you could see in a minute from the twinkling of eyes that the boys
                    intended to make themselves as much at home as possible. Before we were long on
                    the ground, the owner of the stack <add hand="h1" place="inline">came up,</add>
                    and requested of the Adjutant that he would <hi rend="underline">put a guard
                    on</hi> his property. That officer being a facetious and at the same time very
                    obliging individual responded "certainly Sir: I will <hi rend="underline">put
                        the regiment on it</hi>." And sure enough, no sooner were <hi
                        rend="underline">arms stacked</hi>, than the entire regiment was on the <hi
                        rend="underline">bay</hi>; But the <hi rend="underline">stack</hi><pb n="3"
                    /> was no where to be seen -- each fellow having taken his share and put it
                    under him, the better to perform guard duty over it, and enjoy a comfortable
                    sleep at the same time. In the morning we all awoke much refreshed, but a little
                    damp, from the affect of a heavy dew which fell during the night. Our teams had
                    not yet arrived, and the <hi rend="underline">sudden movement</hi> of the day
                    previous, preventing us from getting more than half a ration apiece, we found
                    ourselves in want of fresh meat. This want, however, was soon supplied by plenty
                    of <hi rend="underline">fresh pork</hi> being distributed. Its appearance was
                    rather mysterious, no one knowing where it came from or by when it was brought.
                    I have an idea though, if an investigation had been made into certain squealings
                    which were heard at intervals during the morning, in the adjoining woods, the
                    mystery might have been solved. </p>
                <p>Yesterday, the boys busied themselves scouring the neighborhood; and visiting
                    houses deserted by supposed secessionists. Many valuable and useful books and
                    articles of furniture were brought into Camp. Today, such operations have been
                    stopped. It is a real shame the way our soldiers destroy private property
                    whenver they can get a chance. If they happen to come across a deserted
                        dwelling,<pb n="2"/> in which according to rumor a secessionists once lived,
                    there is not a single article left undestroyed or unabused, and sometimes the
                    property of good union men is destroyed. Such conduct will continue, until the
                    participants are made to suffer the just penalty which is affixed to it. </p>
                <p>Since commencing this I have ascertained that our Camp is called "Pierpont." In
                    writing direct as usual except the name of Camp. Our letters I think will be
                    forwarded from Washington; but on account of the facilities for transmitting the
                    mail to this point being poor, and our movements uncertain, you must not be
                    uneasy, if you do not hear from me as often as heretofore. Will write as often
                    as possible. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>I received the diary. Just the thing I wanted, and am very much obliged.
                        Pierce received <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> and is also much obliged. He says he will
                        write to you. My health is very good, never was better. I don't see what
                        started that report about me being in the hospital. Have not yet been inside
                        of it either for medicine for anything else. My love to all the family. Best
                        Respects to all friends </salute>
                    <signed>Your Affectionate Brother </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Bob </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
