<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0052"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0052">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Bob Taggart to his sister Mary,
                    November 16, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to his sister mary, november 16 1862</title>
        <author>Taggart, Bob </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0052</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501227</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Bob Taggart to his sister Mary, November 16, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county bob taggart to his sister mary, november 16 1862</title>
            <author>Bob Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-11-16">1862-11-16 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Desertion/Leave, Family,
                        Medicine/Hospitals, Women </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 9th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0052T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart provides a general discussion of religion in camp. He also explains why
                    he will not be requesting a leave of absence to come home. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Mary </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-11-16">November 16<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Rappahannock Va </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Mary </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Yours of the 10<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> came to hand this morning, and I don't think
                    it will be any more harm to write you a few lines in answer than it would be to
                    be sitting around idle. There is very little going on in camp these days to
                    distinguish Sunday from any other day. The same routine of business is gone
                    through excepting, and in about six or eight weeks, the privilege of hearing a
                    sermon. Today I attended service in the 12<hi rend="super">th</hi>
                    <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr> and heard a very good discourse by Rev.
                    Miller, the Chaplain. Shortly after our chaplain resigned, a Rev. McFarland
                    volunteered to go with us and acted without an appointment of commission until
                    after the battle of "Bull Run," when he was taken<pb n="2"/> very ill and had to
                    be sent to the Hospital. He is now getting better and will be back soon, as I
                    hope with a commission. He appeared to be a very good man and made himself
                    useful, both in the field of battle, and in camp. Consequently both Officers and
                    got to like him and petitioned the Governor to commission him. </p>

                <p>I do not think there is any prospect of the army "being settled any place this
                    winter," consequently I would not advise you to come on. I would like very well
                    to get home a short time and if placed any way that I can get off I will make
                    the attempt; but so long as the <hi rend="underline">army is in the field</hi>
                    the idea of getting a "leave of absence" is out of the question unless in case
                    of sickness, where the Surgeon certifies it is necessary, "to save life, or
                    prevent permanent disability." Then there<pb n="3"/> is another reason why I do
                    not indulge in the hope very much. Every person that goes home from the army now
                    is almost sure to get married, and you know one might as well be out of the
                    world as out of the fashion and for me to conform to this fashion would require
                    some time to look around and enter into the <hi rend="underline">necessary</hi>
                    <hi rend="underline">negotiations</hi>.</p>

                <p>Holland says to tell Annie that he couldn't help it, and that it is all the fault
                    of the girls.</p>

                <p>I received a letter from Cunningham today. I wrote to him, day before yesterday.</p>

                <p>My love to all at home. Respects to friends.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <abbr expan="Affectionate">Affect</abbr> Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Bob </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
