<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0066"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0066">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Sam Taggart to Captain John
                    Taggart, April 22, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county sam taggart to captain john taggart, april 22 1864</title>
        <author>Taggart, Sam </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0066</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501241</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Sam Taggart to Captain John Taggart, April 22, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county sam taggart to captain john taggart, april 22 1864</title>
            <author>Sam Taggart</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Taggart Letters, Microfilm MG-132, Civil War
                            Material, Misc. Diaries and Letters, Pennsylvania Historical and Museum
                            Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-22">1864-04-22 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: none </term>
                    <term>Company: </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0066T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Taggart talks about regimental organization and the sighting of Confederate
                    pickets. </p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Captain John Taggart, 9th Penn. Reserve Infantry</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-22">April 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1864 </date>
                        <name type="place">On Picket near Mountain Run, </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear John, </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I wrote while in Washington, but neglected posting my letter till I arrived at
                    camp. I overtook <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Dale in Washington, and we
                    both went to Brandy Station together on Tuesday. Our camp is about four miles
                    from the station. The boys were rejoiced to see us, and the regiment begins to
                    assume the appearance of a complete organization. Recruits are arriving daily;
                    and I fear we will be compelled to move before we are quite ready. I remember
                    seeing the 116<hi rend="super">th</hi> at Chancellorsville. It was the regiment
                    that dropped their muskets there to save a battery, when nearly all its horses
                    had been killed. The boys dragged out the guns by ropes; and I remember how we
                    cheered them as they passed us. We have a jolly set of Irishmen in our brigade.
                        I<pb n="2"/> have a detachment of the 88<hi rend="super">th</hi> &amp;
                        69<hi rend="super">th</hi> N.Y. under my control on picket, and their
                    conversation is amusing. They are very friendly, and if any of them <hi
                        rend="underline">draws</hi> a canteen of milk, I must have my share of it.
                    Yesterday afternoon and last night Rebel pickets were seen a short distance in
                    front of our posts; but they have not attempted to molest us yet. We have had
                    most beautiful weather for the past few days; and so far as the condition of the
                    roads is concerned there is nothing to prevent an advance of the army at any
                    time. Bob is well and is getting along first rate. I haven't got my company
                    organized yet, I was only one day in camp before being ordered on picket; but I
                    will have things fixed as soon as we return. All my men have not yet joined the
                    regiment. I have distributed what postage stamps I had to others who needed
                    them, and want you to send me a supply. I promised Mary Jane to go out to Your
                    house before I left; but as my departure was sooner than I expected I couldn't
                    go...I looked for Bob as we passed Manassas junction but did not see him.</p>

                <p>Give my love to all at home </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Sam </signed>
                    <pb n="3"/>
                    <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="April">Apr.</abbr> 25<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> We returned from picket yesterday, and have been issuing ammunition
                        and making other preparations. All well so far. I wish you would get my
                        "Oriental Glee and Anthem Book" from Mr. Sherratt and send it by mail. Also
                        a copy of "Columbia's Guardian Angels." The latter you can get at Mellon's,
                        or if they haven't a supply yet Mr. Sherratt has a copy he doesn't use. Your
                        Affectionate brother, Sam </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
