<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0152"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0152">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: John J. Miller to George Miller, April 15, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county john j miller to george miller, april 15 1862</title>
        <author>Miller, John J. </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0152 </idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501275</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Transcription made from a photocopy.</p>
        </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: John J. Miller to George Miller April 15, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county john j miller to george miller april 15, 1862</title>
            <author>John J. Miller</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Source copy consulted: Miller Family Papers, Library and Archives, York County Heritage
       Trust, York, Pennsylvania. </p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from York County Heritage Trust, York, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-04-15">1862-04-15 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Battle Description, Troop Movement, Death/Casualties, Medicine/Hospitals </term>
          <term>Regiment: 76th Pa. </term>
          <term>Company: none </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0152T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>John J. Miller describes the Union shelling of Fort Pulaski from Tybee Island. He also talks
     about the incompetency of a regimental doctor.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">George Miller</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-04-15">April 15<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862</date>
      <name type="place">Tybee Isl Georgia</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Brother</salute>
    </opener>
    <p>I received yours of March 25<hi rend="super">th</hi> and was pleased to learn that friends
     were all well as i am enjoying the same blessing we had a <orig reg="pleasent">pleasant</orig>
     ride from Hilton Head we started on the 9<hi rend="super">th</hi> while there was the heaviest
     thunder gust i ever witnessed and arrived the same day we worked that night at the batteries
      <orig reg="until">untill</orig> about two <orig reg="o'lock">oclock</orig> in the morning and
     then took rest as the batteries were to open on Fort Pulaski at 9 <orig reg="o'clock"
     >oclock</orig> it was a grand sight to behold 7 or 8 batteries playing with the largest mortars
     that ever a bomb was shot out of and almost every bomb exploded<pb n="2"/> right over the fort
     there were 17 out of 25 - 240 pound bombs thrown into the fort from a battery that i was at the
     bombs that were shot from the fort sometimes fell very near to us causing us to squat there was
     only one man killed and one wounded at our batteries i dont know how many were killed in the
     fort. but we took 360 prisoners the cannonade was kept up for 32 hours before we made an
     opening in the walls of the fort there are only part of 8 <orig reg="companies">companys</orig>
     of our Reg't here our battalion was to lead the forlorn hope with two <orig reg="companies"
      >companys</orig> of the 46<hi rend="super">th</hi> New York Gen Hunter came to our Lieu't Col
     as the Col is not here and asked him if we would lead<pb n="3"/> the storming party if they
     would not surrender in 6 hours we gave him the Cheers Capt M<hi rend="super">c</hi> Intire was
     praying that they would hold out 6 hours longer so that we could charge on them the scaling
     ladders were all got ready but we were sadly disappointed at 3 <orig reg="o'clock"
     >oclock</orig> there was a white rag run up the flag staff and all was over we told the capt
     that Co. D. was the leading Co of our Reg't on a march he said he said he would not give a damn
     for us if we could not crowd through them and get into the fort first the first night of the
     bombardment we were marched through the greatest roads you ever seen through woods and
      swamps<pb n="4"/> we were muddy up to our middle we calculated that the rebels would leave the
     fort and try to escape and we were placed behind the fort to bring them to a halt if they tried
     to it but they did not towards morning our pickets were drove in we were ordered into line and
     our guns loaded but were not disturbed i think we will be in <orig reg="Savannah"
     >savanna</orig> when you receive this as we have Pulaski and fort Jackson now they only gave
     one broadside from the Wabash on Jackson the <orig reg="rebels">rebbels</orig> spiked <orig
      reg="their">there</orig> cannon and run like buggars give my respect to all <orig
      reg="inquiring">enquiring</orig> friends direct your letter Tybee Island Georgia 76<hi
      rend="super">th</hi> Reg't Co. I. <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penna</abbr> Vols in care of Capt
      M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Intire </p>
    <p>Your affectionate brother</p>
    <p>John J. Miller</p>
    <p>write soon </p>
    <pb n="5"/>
    <p>PS/ Thomas Stevens sends his respects to you he has done no duty Since we left Harrisburg he
     was on the sick list he has a running sore on his exterior parts which is hard to cure in this
     climate as we have nothing but a butcher for a doctor he knows nothing at all for here was a
     man went to him from <abbr expan="company">comp</abbr> F for medicine he told him he was fit
     for duty to go and drill all he wanted was exercise the next day he died that is the way he
     serves them most all i went to him one day just for fun i got lazy i wanted a day or two rest i
     told him i had awful pains in my head and neck he felt my pulse and looked at my<pb n="6"/>
     tongue he said i was not fit for duty and put my name on the sick list i told our orderly
     sergeant there was nothing wrong with me he told me i need not do any duty as long as my name
     is on the sick list all the <orig reg="doctor">docter</orig> gave me was three powders told me
     to take one in the morning one at dinner and one in the evening i threw them away i went to him
     the next morning and told him they done me no good. he said i was fit for duty. so i got two
     days rest</p>
    <closer>
     <salute>Your most affectionate brother </salute>
     <signed>John J Miller </signed>
     <seg type="postscript"> answer this if you please </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
