<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0385"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0385">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, July 31,
     1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, july 31 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Justin Hill </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
        <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0385</idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The University of Virginia.
      All rights reserved. </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1997">1997 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501284</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, July 31, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, july 31 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Division of Archives and Manuscripts,
       Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
          </seriesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1862-07-31">1862-07-31 </date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Camp Life, Prisons/Prisoners</term>
          <term>Regiment: 6th Pennsylvania Cavalry, Army of the Potomac </term>
          <term>Company: H </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="1997-06-15"> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name> </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item> </item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0385T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Geisel writes to his family about camp life.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>
  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel</name>
    </head>
    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1862-07-31">July 31<hi rend="super">st</hi> 1862 </date>
      <name type="place">Camp near Harrison Landing </name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister! </salute>
    </opener>
    <p>Your welcome letter of July 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> reached me in good health, and I was
     very happy to hear that you were well, and that you have not waited so long this time before
     you wrote to me for I am always anxious to hear from you, and how things are going on in the
     old neighbourhood. I wrote a letter to Sister Louisa before I wrote to you the last time, and I
     received one from Father which I have answered, but I have not received any answer from either
     of them yet. I have not yet wrote to Sister Anne nor Amanda, as I do not know where to direct
     their letters to. when you write to me again, please send me their address. I have not much
     news to tell you, but <pb n="1"/> as I have not much to do this afternoon I thought I might as
     well employ some of my time in writing to you. Those men of our regiment who were taken
     prisoners, on the 27<hi rend="super">th</hi> of June, have been released on parole of honor,
     and were <orig reg="sent">send</orig> home. Nathan Jones was along with them, they passed by
     this place last <orig reg="Wednesday">wensday</orig>, a week the 23<hi rend="super">rd</hi> but
     I did not get to see them. Last week I <orig reg="saw">seen</orig> Jonathan Harley, he looks
     well, and is hardy, but he says, it goes hard for him on long march. I have been to see the
      104<hi rend="super">th</hi> but they are never in camp when I get there. the first time i was
     there they were out on picketguard and I only <orig reg="saw">seen</orig> Levi Rosenberger and
     Bill Franks, and yesterday I was there again and they were out on a review; I <orig reg="saw"
      >seen</orig> Levi Markley, he had been down at the river to wash, and when he came back to
     camp the regiment had gone out and he was left behind pb n="2"/>he is well and so <orig
      reg="are">is</orig> all the rest of the boys. Levi told me that Bill Snyder has been
     discharged. last night a party of rebels came across the river in a small boat with the
     intention to set a vessel on fire, but our guards <orig reg="saw">seen</orig> them before they
     got near the vessel and fired into them. the rebels then tried to go back, but were taken
     prisoners before they could get away. I have not heard from Christian Lindauer since we came
     here. the last time I heard from him he was in Frankfurt yet and him and his sister were well.
     I would like to know how Polly Furhman is getting along with her young one, and what has become
     of Fyatty Miller. I never hear anything about them. I would like to know what has become of
     Charles Fackler. I will now close with my highest regards to all our family and friends, give
     my best respects to Levi Leidy and <pb n="3"/> his family; give my love to Sister Anne and
     Amanda if you see them, and tell them that I will write to them as soon as I get their <orig
      reg="address">adress</orig>, which would be easy for me to get if they would write to me
     first, and tell me where they live. I should be glad to hear from you soon again. </p>
    <closer>
     <salute>I remain your affectionate brother, </salute>
     <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
     <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> H. <abbr expan="Pennsylvania"
      >Penn.</abbr> Cavalry <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> R.H. Rush's Lancers Camp near
      Harrisons landing James River <abbr expan="Virginia">Vir.</abbr>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
