<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0384"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0384">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    June 18, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, june 18 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0384</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501283</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This letter was written in pencil. As a result of wear and tear and age, much
                        of the writing is so faded and smudged as to be illegible. Significant gaps
                        result.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, June 18, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, june 18 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp>Editor </resp>
                            <name>Name of Editor </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-06-19">1862-06-19 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Res. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0384T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel provides his family with an elaborate account of his maneuvers during the
                    Seven Days Battles near Richmond.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-06-19">June 19<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Cold Harbor </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister! </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Having some leisure moments today i thought i would spend them in writing you a
                    few lines to let you know that I am well and alive, and i hope that this letter
                    will find you all in as good health as i enjoy at present. I am obliged to write
                    this letter with a lead point for the bottle of ink i took with me from
                    Washington is used up, and <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> opportunity of getting any here, and
                    I hope you will therefore excuse me if my writing is not <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                </p>
                <p>I received a letter from Father a few weeks ago in which I <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> that
                    some of you had <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> i also received your letter of the 21<hi
                        rend="super">rst</hi> of <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, and I was very glad to hear from
                    you <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Father a letter since i received his last one on which i
                    suppose he has received his last one which i suppose he has received before this
                    time <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <pb n="1"/> that it was at Fort <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> on the James river near
                    Richmond. i heard that our men have taken the fort with a large number of
                    prisoners. i have not seen the official report of it yet for it takes several
                    days before we get the newspapers from Philadelphia and consequently you always
                    hear the particulars of the battles before we do. yesterday fighting was going
                    on at bottom Bridge on the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> but i have not heard the result of
                    it yet. there is fighting going on today somewhere near Richmond, but i cannot
                    tell exactly where it is. I see by the papers that a good many of the boys of
                    our neighbourhood have been wounded at the battle of Fair Oak. i also have three
                    from Whitemarsh in Davis's regiment who have been wounded. one of them, his name
                    is William Nicolous, was my messmate in the three month service. they must have
                    had a hot time of it, but i hope they may all get over it safe. A party of
                    rebels, who had been somewhere about Ashland since the fight at Hanover
                    Courthouse passed through this part of the county last Friday in our rear. we
                    got word of it at three o'clock in the afternoon and went in pursuit after them
                    right away; we followed them up all Friday night and until saturday afternoon to
                    the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> Creek which they had crossed just before we got there and
                    burned the bridge behind them.<pb n="2"/>they destroyed a train of Wagons near
                    Turnstall station on the Richmond Railroad. they went through there about twelve
                    o'clock on Friday night and we arrived there about four o'clock on Saturday
                    morning by what we could ascertain there was about three thousand of them, all
                    cavalry. Our regimental Quartermaster, Davis, Lieutenant Marro of <abbr
                        expan="Company">Co.</abbr> B, and one of our ambulance drivers were taken
                    prisoners of the rebels. they had been to the Whitehouse on Friday with some
                    sick men and were on the road back when they met the first party of rebels. We
                    have been on picketguard since last monday. we were relieved yesterday; we were
                    encamped near Mechanicsville when we started on picket, but when we came back to
                    the camp yesterday we found that our regiment had moved to Cold Harbor. we
                    followed them <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> at our new Camp about one o'clock last night. It
                    is very warm today. There are plenty <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> about here, which are
                    about getting ripe and we help ourselves to them, whenever we have time. I have
                    not received any letters from Sister Hannah since the first one she wrote to me
                    and i should be glad to hear from her. I must now close my letter with my
                    kindest regards to you all, give my best respects to all inquiring friends. i
                    should be glad to hear from you soon again. tell me all the news about the
                    neighbourhood. do you how Renchlers are getting along; if you get to
                    Philadelphia give them my kindest regards. is Polly Furhman married yet or have
                    you put her down on the <orig reg="Bachelors">Batchelors</orig> list. tell her
                    that i am well and alive yet. If we gain the battle at Richmond, the time of
                    which is nor far off i think this war will soon come to a close, when i hope
                    that it we all may see each other again. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>You affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript"><abbr expan="Company">Co.</abbr> H. 6<hi rend="super"
                        >th</hi> regiment <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr> Cavalry <abbr
                            expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> Rush's Lancers Camp near Richmond <del
                            hand="h1"/>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
