<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0382"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F0382">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel,
                    April 22, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, april 22 1862</title>
        <author>Geisel, Christian </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Justin Hill </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0382</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/personal.html </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501281</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow Project </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Christian Geisel to Louisa Geisel, April 22, 1862</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county christian geisel to louisa geisel, april 22 1862</title>
            <author>Christian Geisel</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Division of Archives and
                            Manuscripts, Christian Geisel Collection, Microfilm, MG 226 </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-04-22">1862-04-22 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 6th Pa. Cav. </term>
                    <term>Company: H </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""> </date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name> </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item> </item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0382T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Geisel writes to his sister about the final days of the Peninsula campaign.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Louisa Geisel </name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-04-22">April 22<hi rend="super">nd</hi> 1862 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Hampton </name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister! </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>With pleasure i write to you these few lines and hope that they may find you in
                    as good health as they leave me in at present. I received a letter from William
                    after we arrived at Hampton in which i <unclear>
                        <orig reg="saw">seen</orig>
                    </unclear> that you were all well and i was very glad to hear from you. i
                    answered his letter right away and i hope he has received it. I also received a
                    letter from Hannah just as we went on board of the vessel which i answered
                    before we started down the river. If William received his letter, i suppose you
                    have seen in it that we then <pb n="1"/> were at Hampton Virginia. when i wrote
                    it, we <orig reg="lay">layed</orig> there until monday the 14th <del hand="h1"
                    />. then we went about three miles out towards Yorktown where we are now
                    encamped near the James river. While we <orig reg="lay">layed</orig> at Hampton
                    i <orig reg="saw">seen</orig> a scrimmage between the rebel steamer <sic
                        corr="Merrimack">marrimac</sic> and two of our gunboats. they <orig
                        reg="threw">throwed</orig> shells at each other, but neither of them was
                    injured. I was sick for about a week after we came down here, but i am perfectly
                    well again at present. The neighbourhood we are in at present is quite level.
                    there is hardly a hill to be seen. there is a great many fruit trees around here
                    of all kinds, which are mostly all in blossom now.<pb n="2"/>the woods are
                    mostly pine; we had our horses out several times to <unclear>
                        <orig reg="pasture">paster</orig>
                    </unclear> on a farm along the James river, about two miles from our camp; it
                    must have been a splendid place at one time, but it is now deserted and the
                    buildings are all burnt down. We hear <orig reg="cannonading">canonading</orig>
                    most every day in the direction of Yorktown, but no general battle has taken
                    place yet, but i suppose they will begin before long. there are now about
                    250,000 men concentrated around Yorktown on both sides, and i expect there will
                    be a hard fight there. I did not hear anything from Levi Markley since they left
                    Washington. they are somewhere in this vicinity, but i <unclear>
                        <orig reg="don't">dondt</orig>
                    </unclear><pb n="3"/>know in what direction. the weather has been very pleasant
                    since we came down here. we had several thunder showers here. we had one today
                    which prevented us from drilling, and i thought i would take this opportunity to
                    write you a few lines; I received William's love letter which you sent me in his
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>. i think it is very well got up. has he found it out yet? i
                    believe i did not mention anything about it in his letter! you better be careful
                    or he might play the same trick on you; tell Anny that Nathan Jones is in our
                    company and is well. the young man that used to come with Harry Bernhard to see
                    Widow Kinder dine; give my best respects to all the family and all inquiring
                    friends. </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>your affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Christian Geisel </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
