<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0660"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0660">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel W. North to [unknown
                    recipient], [date unknown]</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to unknown recipient, date unknown</title>
        <author>North, Samuel W. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">6</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0660</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501322</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Letterhead: The first page of this letter is printed at the top with a
                        patriotic engraving of an eagle standing on a shield of the stars and
                        stripes, with olive branches beneath that, an American flag on each side of
                        the eagle, and stars and stripes above it.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel W. North to [recipient unknown], [date
                            unknown]</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel w north to recipient unknown, date unknown</title>
            <author> </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Samuel W. North Letters, Company C, 126th
                            Pennsylvania Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of
                            the U.S. Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania.
                        </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 126th Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: C </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0660T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>North describes where his regiment is camped and praises his Lieutenant
                Trout.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">unknown</name>
                </head>
                

                <p>This is a very desolate looking country. no fences of any account some of the
                    houses are torn down and others are not disturbed. there are two very fine
                    residences one on each side of our camp we get water at either. the one is a
                    union family and they have a fine orchard &amp; flowers garden, and yards.
                    it is a grand old residence and nothing is disturbed. the inmates of the other
                    have left. part of the house has been used for a stable part for head quarters.
                    the windows are broken and the <unclear>fluid</unclear> is the common property
                    of the men. the fields all<pb n="2"/>over the part of the country we are in are
                    all open and look as if they had never been fenced here and there you may see a
                    small patch of corn but I have seen but two fenced fields you seldom see any one
                    but soldiers. we are passing over the same ground which M<hi rend="super"
                    >c</hi>Clellans grand army passed over last winter. Camp life is very pleasant
                    so far there is so much variety and so much company that a person can not help
                    being cheerful. I wish you were here to eat with us we can cook as good a dinner
                    as any man need want we take pride in having <orig reg="everything">every
                    thing</orig> nice. Tell the girls there is no<pb n="3"/> use in trying to scare
                    us with the idea of bachelors hall for we have tried it and get along very well
                    the worst part is washing dishes we often sleep in the middle of the day for one
                    half hour or an hour. we only drill in the morning and evening. Maj. Hershbarger
                    is here drilling the officers. I expect you <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> read
                    this writing, but I am writing with my paper in one hand and pen in the other
                    and the boys are talking all the time so you will have to make some <orig
                        reg="allowance">allowanse</orig>. Cook sends his best respects to you and
                    says you must write all the news the rest of our family Liz Boyd Bruce<pb n="4"
                    /> Parkers boys M<hi rend="super">c</hi>Cune (cake bakers son) are all well and
                    hearty I think I will stop till I see whether I get any news from home <orig
                        reg="tonight">to night</orig>. Aug 26 I have not got a letter yet. <del
                        hand="h1">there is</del>I got a Valley Star from
                    <unclear>Neuville</unclear>. Capt has not received his trunk yet but I think he
                    will get it soon. Jacob is well and doing well he is drilling a squad sometimes
                    cooking &amp; so on <del hand="h1">Dr</del>Lieutenant Trout is the kindest
                    officer we have. the mail man is coming I must stop.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>Sam </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
