<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0679"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F0679">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Alvin H. Alexander to Lizzie,
                    February 12, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county alvin h alexander to lizzie, february 12 1863</title>
        <author>Alexander, Alvin H. </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Sally Henninger </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">F0679</idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1997">1997 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501338</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note> </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Alvin H. Alexander to Lizzie, February 12, 1863</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county alvin h alexander to lizzie, february 12 1863</title>
            <author>Alvin H. Alexander</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: Alvin H. Alexander Records, 103rd Pennsylvania
                            Infantry, Civil War Miscellaneous Collection, Archives of the U.S.
                            Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania. </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-02-12">1863-02-12 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 103rd Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: A </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="F0679T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Alexander describes to his sister the comforts of camp life and comments on his
                    like and dislike of various officers around him.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Lizzie</name>
                </head>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-02-12"><abbr expan="February">Feb.</abbr> 12<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi> 1863 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near New Bern N.C.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Sister Lizzie </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yours of the 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi> inst. was <abbr expan="received">rec<hi
                            rend="super">d</hi></abbr> yesterday afternoon And I was very glad to
                    hear that you were all well at home I wrote to Sister Mollie and sent it with
                    the Captain. I suppose you have received it by this time. I was Sorry to See the
                    Captain go home after being So long <orig reg="together">togeather</orig>. But
                    he is getting old and I think he has done Enough for his Country. I suppose he
                    has had a busy time talking<pb n="2"/> Since he got home. There is nothing of
                    importance going on here. The expedition that left here under <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Foster has not returned yet. We have moved into
                    Barracks and live very nice. My quarters are got up very nice. I have one room
                    to <orig reg="myself">my Self</orig> about a large as mothers room <orig
                        reg="upstairs">up Stairs</orig>, with a Stove in it, and a Small lumber
                    room. And we are playing soldier in Style now. I am Regimental Officer of the
                    day <orig reg="today">to day</orig> and have an orderly to do my Errands. I got
                    white gloves for all company A. the other day and they came out in Style. The
                    weather is warm and we are having a pleasant time. I wish you all could be here
                    and see how nice we live. I would like to See you all<pb n="3"/> at home. But I
                    think that that I will not be able to do for Some time. I would like to See this
                    war at an End but I am afraid that it will be Some time before it is over. We
                    received two months pay on the last day of January. I did not Send any home this
                    time as my Expenses were pretty large Since we were paid in October. We expect
                    to get two months more in a few days. We presented <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col.</abbr> Maxwell with a Sword on Sunday Evening which cost $150.<hi
                        rend="super">00</hi> dollars. It was a very nice one, he is very much
                    pleased with it. We are expecting Colonel <unclear>Lehman</unclear> back <orig
                        reg="today">to day</orig>. But I am not very anxious to See him. If he
                    remains in Command I think I will go home for I will not Serve under a tyrant
                    and a Coward like him. And there is not an<pb n="4"/> Officer in the Regiment
                    that will Serve under him. I <orig reg="believe">beleive</orig> that I have
                    nothing more to write at present. Remember me to <abbr expan="Captain"
                    >Capt.</abbr> Laughlin and tell him that I am anxiously looking for a letter
                    from him. Much love to you all Uncle &amp; Aunt &amp; Mrs. McCoy
                    &amp; family. Write soon and often.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Affectionate Brother </salute>
                    <signed>Alvy </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I will write to Father &amp; Mollie next time. I had
                        a letter from Levi yesterday. They are both well. I am much obliged for the
                        stamps. Alvy </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
