<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0689"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F0689">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: James A. Harman to Martin W.
                    Carman, July 18, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county james a harman to martin w carman, july 18 1862</title>
        <author>Carman, James</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amanda Mushal</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Amanda Mushal</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0689</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501342</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: James A. Harman to Martin W. Carman, July 18, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county james a harman to martin w carman, july 18 1862</title>
            <author>James A. Harman</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: James A. Carman to Martin W.
                            Carman, 18 July 1862, James Carman Papers, United States Military
                            History Institute</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-07-18">1862-07-18</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>African Americans, Agriculture, Church/Religious Activity,
                        Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Military Authority, Military Strategy,
                        Patriotism, Race Relations, Slavery</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0689T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lt. James A. Carman writes to his father, Martin W. Carman, regarding
                    expectations of an upcoming approach to Richmond, the conduct of the war, his
                    recent illness, his decision not to resign from the army, changes in furlough
                    application procedures, the alcohol-related death of Colonel Zeigle of York,
                    Pennsylvania, the agricultural difficulties of Virginia, buying food from local
                    citizens, and differences in attitudes toward the war between urban and rural
                    Virginians.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Martin W. Carman, Graham Ville, York County, <orig reg="Pennsylvania"
                        >Penna</orig>
                    <name type="recipient"/>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-07-18">wJuly 18<hi rend="super">th</hi>" 1862</date>
                        <name type="place"><orig reg="Headquarters">Head Quarters</orig> 107<hi
                            rend="super">th</hi>" <abbr expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Pennsylvania Volunteers">P.V.</abbr>, Camp At Warrenton <abbr
                                expan="Virginia">Va</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear <orig reg="Father">Farther</orig></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received Your letter I expected it the <orig reg="very">verry</orig> day I
                    received it, at least it was about the time if You was prompt in answering my
                    letter, I was glad to know You were all well. I received a letter from Frank
                    Since his return to his Regiment. I wrote to Margaret Yesterday She told Frank
                    that She wanted me to write, I was not aware of her husband <orig reg="running"
                        >runing</orig> on the road so near me last Spring we guarded that part of
                    the <orig reg="railroad">rail road</orig>. now we have gone 26 miles further
                    down. the road is now being repaired to Gordonsville which is about 50 miles
                    from here, then from there to Richmond the road is good, a distance 46 miles but
                    I think if the rebels have the <orig reg="knowledge">Knowlledge</orig> of our
                    army coming they will destroy the road.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Father">Farther</orig> there is an army in this valley 80 thousand
                    Strong good troops <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Pope at their head. we fear
                    nothing if <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr>
                    <orig reg="McClellan">McClelan</orig> watches his time as we approach to
                    richmond. he will be able to whip them and go into Richmond. he will be able to
                    whip them and go into Richmond. as you See they will have to Send out of the
                    city a large force to watch us on the north Side while <orig reg="McClellan"
                        >McClelan</orig> can go right into the city.</p>

                <p>This war must be conducted on different principals than what it has been or our
                    cause will be in danger, the abolitionists must be put down <orig
                        reg="Slaveholders">Slave holders</orig> must not look for their property or
                    negroes to be protected they must either be for us or against us, that is they
                    who are loyal must come out. and them who are rebels must Swear Allegiance to
                    the country or be taken as prisoners of war. Such I believe<pb n="2"/>is the
                    orders that has been issued lately. We cannot Succeed if we <orig reg="allow"
                        >alow</orig> rebels to run loose carry all information to the enemy they
                    can, we must Stop this thing, and Start out on the new. I fear <orig reg="very"
                        >verry</orig> much <orig reg="whether">wether</orig>
                    <orig reg="Pennsylvania">pennsylvania</orig> can make up her quota of troops
                    without drafting I only hope She can for her own credit. if things are as dull
                    as Reid Says they are in his Section, the State will have to draft the men.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Father">Farther</orig> You Speak of the great loss at Richmond. Yes it
                    was dreadful, I had heard nothing of <abbr expan="Captain">Capt</abbr> Hess or
                    the Regiment he was in I could See nothing in the papers about the first
                    reserves. I thought <orig reg="perhaps">prehaps</orig> they were not in the
                    fight.</p>

                <p>You also Say if You was in my place You would resign and come home, well <orig
                        reg="Father">Farther</orig> it is not that I have not been tempted to resign
                    before this when I look and See how things are going but, I have taken an oath
                    to Support the Constitution of the <abbr expan="United">U.</abbr> States and
                    obey the President and assist him in carrying out and <orig reg="administering"
                        >admistrating</orig> the laws.</p>

                <p>I do not like the idea of resigning when I am well in <orig reg="fact"
                    >facts</orig> there is, according to late orders a difficulty in a Officer
                    resigning without a good reason Such as bad health or Severe illness.</p>

                <p>I would be Satisfied now with even a furlough for ten days or two weeks. but all
                    applications for furloughs now must be made to the war department instead of the
                        <abbr expan="Brigadier">Brig</abbr> General.</p>

                <p><orig reg="Father">Farther</orig> we have met with a severe loss in our Regiment,
                    this week in the Sudden Death of our <abbr expan="Colonel">Col</abbr> (Thomas A.
                    Zeigle) of York Pennsylvania. he was a fine man a good <abbr expan="Colonel"
                    >Col</abbr> and a brave Officer. but he fell a victim to that one vice which men
                    in the army get into that is drinking too much <hi rend="underline">Whiskey</hi>
                    he died with "<hi rend="underline">
                        <orig reg="delirium tremens">delyrium Tremens</orig>
                    </hi>" His body was embalmed here in camp taken up to Washington from thence to
                    York to be <orig reg="buried">burried</orig> "<hi rend="underline">Peace to his
                        Ashes</hi>"</p>
                <pb n="3"/>

                <p>I have been unwell Since I wrote to You but only Slightly I have had the Yellow
                    Gaunders they made me right Sick for a day or two. <orig reg="Today">To
                    day</orig> is a wet day it has rained all last night all day <orig reg="today"
                        >to day</orig> with the prospects of a wet time generally, the weather has
                    been <orig reg="very">verry</orig> hot down here <orig reg="very">verry</orig>
                    heavy gusts, come up.</p>

                <p>I am pleased to hear of Such excellent crops this Season, down here in Virginia
                    where there is corn Potatoes beans peas <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig>
                    planted they all look well there is fine land in this <orig reg="neighborhood"
                        >neighbourhood</orig> but it needs tillers What Wheat has been Sown last
                    fall is harvested but never gathered in there being no horses <orig reg="owned"
                        >own</orig> by the farmers they all being in the rebel army. it Serves most
                    of them right had no <hi rend="underline">business to <orig reg="secede"
                        >seceed</orig></hi>. </p>

                <p>Us Officers have to find our own rations, in the city <add hand="h1"
                        place="inline">near</add> where we are encamped the white citizens will not
                    sell us <orig reg="anything">enything</orig> the <orig reg="colored"
                    >collored</orig> population Sell us <orig reg="vegetables">vegitables</orig>,
                    pies milk cakes <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig> When we first came here the
                    men in business did not want to take our money for <orig reg="groceries"
                        >Grocerys</orig>
                    <orig reg="etc">&amp;c</orig> but that was soon <orig reg="stopped"
                    >stoped</orig> they were all arrested and brought before the Provost <orig
                        reg="Marshall">Marshal</orig> who ordered them to take the oath of
                    allegiance or they would be taken as prisoners of war and all their Stores taken
                    they came down to the "<hi rend="underline">dots</hi>" Preachers was Served the
                    Same way, the Citizens of the town are big bugs with plenty of negroes and were
                    strong <abbr expan="secessionists">secessh</abbr>, but the people living in the
                    country are different Some are <orig reg="very">verry</orig> Strong Union and
                    voted against <orig reg="seceding">Seceeding</orig>.</p>

                <p>I will now Stop tell Cornelius to write my love to all the family write soon
                    again direct as before. no more now</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>From Your Son</salute>
                    <signed>J. A. Carman, <abbr expan="Lieutenant">Lieut</abbr>, <abbr
                            expan="Company">Co.</abbr> E. 107<hi rend="super">th</hi>" <abbr
                            expan="Regiment">Regt</abbr>, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania Volunteers">P.
                            V.</abbr></signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
