<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0703"?>
<?dlps page-images="color" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;



 <!ENTITY BitCre4a SYSTEM "uva-lib:502942" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre4b SYSTEM "uva-lib:502943" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre4c SYSTEM "uva-lib:502944" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
 <!ENTITY BitCre4d SYSTEM "uva-lib:502945" NDATA uvaHighRes> 
   
   
   
 ]>  
<TEI.2 id="F0703">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Alex Cressler to Henry A. Bitner, June 18, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county alex cressler to henry a bitner, june 18 1861</title>
        <author>Cressler, Alex</author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Anne Rubin, Valley of the Shadow project, Institute for Advanced Technology in the
      Humanities, University of Virginia </name>
          <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp>
          <name>Anne Rubin, Valley of the Shadow project, Institute for Advanced Technology in the
      Humanities, University of Virginia </name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup: </resp>
          <name>University of Virginia Library Electronic Text Center. </name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">13</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>University of Virginia Library </publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>
        <idno type="VCDH">F0703 </idno>
        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly-accessible </p>
     <p>URL: http://etext.lib.virginia.edu/modeng/modengB.browse.html </p>
     <p>Publicly-accessible </p>
     <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.Virginia.EDU/vshadow2/</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="1998">1998 </date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501347</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p> </p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>
          <p>Images of the manuscript have been included. This electronic text is a faithful
      transcription of the original manuscript; note that the last manuscript pages of this letter
      are missing. We have included SGML tags which allow the reader to view a modernized version of
      the text in which the punctuation and the spelling have been regularized.</p>
        </note>
        <note> </note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Alex Cressler to Henry A. Bitner, June 18, 1861</title>
            <title level="u"> </title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county alex cressler to henry a bitner, june 18 1861</title>
            <author>Alex Cressler</author>
            <respStmt>
              <resp> </resp>
              <name> </name>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent> </extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher> </publisher>
            <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
            <date value=""> </date>
            <idno type="callno">Manuscript copy consulted: University of Virginia, Alderman Library,
       Special Collections MSS 11395 </idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p> </p>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note> </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Prepared for the University of Virginia Library Electronic Text Center. </p>
        <p>Used with permission from Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Original lineation has been maintained. </p>
        <p>The images exist as archived TIFF images, one or more JPEG versions for general use, and
     thumbnail GIFs. </p>
        <p>Some keywords in the header are a local Electronic Text Center scheme to aid in establishing
     analytical groupings. </p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <refsDecl>
        <p> </p>
      </refsDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy>
          <bibl> </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-06-18">1861-06-18 </date>
      </creation>

      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng">English </language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>nonfiction </term>
          <term>prose </term>
          <term>masculine </term>
          <term>American Civil War; Special Collections </term>
          <term>Regiment: none </term>
          <term>Franklin County </term>
          <term>Troop Movement </term>
          <term>Chambersburg </term>
          <term>Home Front </term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
        <keywords>
          <term>LCSH </term>
        </keywords>
        <keywords>
          <term> </term>
          <term> </term>
          <term type="format">72 dpi; 24-bit color </term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="1998-05">May 1998 </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>corrector </resp>
          <name>Carolyn Fay and Lisa Spiro </name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Added TEI header and tags, corrected transcription errors, and standardized punctuation
     and spelling for the modernized version. </item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text id="F0703T">
  <body id="d2">
   <!-- <page n=1><ID>BitCre41</ID> -->
   <div1 type="letter" n="1861-06-18" id="d3">
    <opener>


     <pb n="1" entity="BitCre4a" pid="uva-lib:502942"/>


     <dateline> Chambersburg,<lb/>
      <date value="1861-06-18">June 18th 1861.</date>
     </dateline>

     <salute>Dear <name type="person">Henry</name>:-</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>Yours of the 16th was<lb/> received in due time, which found <add hand="h1"
      place="supralinear">me</add> wa<del rend="none" hand="h1"/><add hand="h1" place="inline">iting</add><lb/>
     and also well and hearty with a good<lb/> appetite. The troops have all left<lb/> here but one
     Regiment <add hand="h1" place="supralinear"> and that had left too</add> so that our town is
     coming<lb/> back to its former <orig reg="quietness,">quietness.</orig> but false reports
     and<lb/> rumors are in great abundance, and correct reports<lb/> are very scarce. <orig
      reg="But">but</orig> as I enjoyed Saturday<lb/> evening with its scenes and a mess of
     strawberries<lb/> I will commence a description, if I should not<lb/> get it finished in this
     letter, look for the balance<lb/> in the <orig reg="next,">next.</orig> so here goes. </p>
    <p> The boisterous winds of noonday had died away and given<lb/> place to the gentler zephyrs of
     a delightful June<lb/> evening. The intervening clouds, which had emerged in<lb/> mountain like
     masses, from the Western horizon had<lb/> dispelled the scorching rays of that luminary,
     which<lb/> was gently sinking in the western sky and all was calm<lb/> and serene, save the
     evening notes of a few joyous <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=2><ID>BitCre42</ID> -->
     <pb n="2" entity="BitCre4b" pid="uva-lib:502943"/> birds whose <orig reg="carols">carrolls</orig> seemed sweetened
     by the quiet &amp;<lb/> beauty of the surrounding landscape. <orig reg="Indeed"
     >indeed</orig> nature was<lb/> gently wrapping herself in her most gorgeous robes<lb/> of
     beauty, while the odors of a thousand flowers had<lb/> filled the air with their sweet perfume.
      <orig reg="And">and</orig> thus<lb/> while my mind was straying in unknown channels <orig
      reg="contemplating"> contempla<lb/>
      <del hand="h1">pleting</del>-ting</orig> the magnificence and glory of surrounding<lb/>
     nature, a sound from the distance fell upon my ears<lb/> which by its unrivaled powers for
     engulfing the mind in<lb/> paroxyms of unconsciousness, had so enlarged my former <orig
      reg="conception"> concep-<lb/> tion</orig> of instrumental music, that the perpendicular of
      <orig reg="astonishment">astonish-<lb/> ment</orig> fell outside the base of consciousness and
      <orig reg="consequently">conse-<lb/> quently</orig> submerged my powers of reason in a "ker
     splash," how<lb/> I extricated myself from the strong embrace of that fit<lb/> of <orig
      reg="ecstasies">ecstacies</orig>, could only be told by a scrutinizing observer,<lb/> however,
     when reason again returned I found myself<lb/> journeying towards that place from whence
     proceeded those <orig reg="bewitching">be-<lb/> witching</orig> strains of music, soon I was
     standing in the <orig reg="suburbs">su-<lb/> burbs</orig> of a very splendid little city, the
     appearance of which<lb/> was quite picturesque of itself, and grotesque when compared<lb/> with
     the cities of the country. This modern city is about<lb/> one-half of a mile in length and
     about one-eighth of a<lb/> mile in breadth having a population of about 3,000 <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=3><ID>BitCre43</ID> -->
     <pb n="3" entity="BitCre4c" pid="uva-lib:502944"/> inhabitants; the dwellings were of uniform size, the<lb/> largest
     being a little more <orig reg="spacious">spaceous</orig> than the smallest<lb/> and the
     smallest being somewhat less in dimensions than<lb/> the largest, with streets leading along
     every side of the <orig reg="dwellings">dwell-<lb/> ings</orig>; and running either straight or
     crooked from <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">the</add> one end<lb/> to the other side so
     that strangers could amuse themselves by<lb/> turning as many times as there is differences of
     direction. </p>
    <p> The architecture was of the latest style being neither<lb/> Grecian nor Gothic but a style
     of necessity. The <orig reg="roofs">rooves</orig><lb/> of <del hand="h1">which</del><add
      hand="h1" place="supralinear">the houses</add> were shingled with canvas, and the end of
     those<lb/> that were not round were neatly lapboarded with canvas<lb/> the <orig reg="roofs"
      >rooves</orig> of some reached so near the ground that the ground<lb/> came in contact with
     the <orig reg="roofs">rooves</orig>, while with others the <orig reg="roofs">rooves</orig><lb/>
     came in close conjunction with the earth, but others had a<lb/> partition wall of about 3 feet
     in height, this wall being of<lb/> solid masonry, the material of which was <orig reg="canvas"
      >canvass</orig>, served to<lb/> point out the dimensions of the edifice by plainly <orig
      reg="distinguishing">distin-<lb/> guishing</orig> the outside from the inside of the
     structure, but I<lb/> would have you also remember that where the eve of the roof<lb/> reached
     the ground, there was no such wall, but in all<lb/> such cases the roof separated the inside
     from the outside<lb/> so that there still remained <orig reg="an">and</orig> inside and outside
     to<lb/> every temple. These buildings for convenience could not be <!-- </page> -->
     <!-- <page n=4><ID>BitCre44</ID> -->
     <pb n="4" entity="BitCre4d" pid="uva-lib:502945"/> surpassed the door being just at the place of entrance and<lb/>
     after becoming <del hand="h1">iniated</del>initiated into the presence of the<lb/> occupants of
     the building and wishing to leave, you will<lb/> always find the door just at the place where
     you <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">come out</add>
     <del hand="h1">entered</del>,<lb/> and if your company has been burthensome to the inmates<lb/>
     of the house, you'll find no difficulty in <orig reg="leaving."> leaving,</orig><lb/> Among all
     the Ancient and Modern <add hand="h1" place="supralinear">cities</add> of the world
     perhaps<lb/> none were so well adapted <del hand="h1">to the</del>in a point of <orig
      reg="convenience">con-<lb/> venience</orig>, to the wants of the aged and infirm, there
     being<lb/> but one apartment in each dwelling in which were<lb/> found all the necessaries for
     house cookery, with the couch<lb/> on which to rest the weary head, which was usually
     placed<lb/> upon the soft earth, and in the left corner of the<lb/> room was the clerk's desk
     at which all the business<lb/> of the family is transacted, these halls are large and<lb/>
     <orig reg="spacious">spaceous</orig> while one person is occupying them, and<lb/> small and
     precious while six or seven, the usual<lb/> number in a family, <orig reg="were">where</orig>
     enjoying the luxuries of<lb/> their table. </p>
    <p>Fashion was carried to a state of perfection among<lb/> the inhabitants of this place, our
     eastern cities may<lb/> boast of their fashionable ladies and gents, but must<lb/> not attempt
     to compete with this city of these latter </p>

    
     <p>[Note: The last manuscript pages of this letter are missing.]</p>
    


   </div1>
  </body>

  <!-- </page> -->
 </text>
</TEI.2>
