<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0902"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]> 
  
<TEI.2 id="F0902">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Sylvester McElheney to Harriet
                    McElheney, December 14, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county sylvester mcelheney to harriet mcelheney, december 14 1864</title>
        <author>McElheney, Sylvester</author>
        <editor> </editor>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Amy Murrell</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">12</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F0902</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>copyright 1998, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1998 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501369</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>This transcription was taken from a typescript and a photocopy of the
                        original.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>


            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Sylvester McElheney to Harriet McElheney, December
                            14, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county sylvester mcelheney to harriet mcelheney, december 14 1864</title>
            <author>Sylvester McElheney</author>
            <editor> </editor>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p> </p>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Sylvester McElheney Papers,
                            Archives of the U.S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks,
                            Pennsylvania. </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from U. S. Army Military History Institute, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-12-14">1864-12-14</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave, Prisons/Prisoners, Troop
                        Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>

    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F0902T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McElheney describes the grisly execution of two deserters from his regiment. He
                    also tells about the burning of houses in Virginia in retaliation for the
                    burning of Chambersburg.</p>
            </div1>


        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <opener>
                    Letterhead: U.S. Christian Commission<lb/> sends this as the Soldier's messenger
                    to his Home. Let it hasten to those who<lb/> wait for tidings.<lb/> "Behold! now
                    is the accepted time: behold, now is the day of salvation."<lb/> Central Office:
                    11 Bank Street, Philadelphia, Branch Office: No. 500 H. Street, Washington
                    <name type="recipient">Harriet McElheney</name>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-12-14"><orig reg="Wednesday">Wenesday</orig> December the
                                14<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp in front of PetersBurg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Kind and respected Wife</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I take the <orig reg="opportunity">oppertunity</orig> this evening of <orig
                        reg="informing">in forming</orig> you that I am well at <orig reg="present"
                        >presant</orig>. I <orig reg="received">receved</orig> your letter on <orig
                        reg="Saturday">Satterday</orig> the tenth and was glad to <orig reg="hear"
                        >heare</orig> from you and that you <orig reg="were">was</orig> all well. I
                    would have answered your letter sooner but we have not been in camp since Friday
                    evening about six <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> only a little while on
                    Monday morning and last night we came in to camp again about Eight <orig
                        reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> but we <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know how
                    long we will stay We have been out on a <orig reg="raid">rade</orig>. We started
                    on friday evening at about six <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> and marched
                    about two miles<pb n="2"/> and encamped for that night and the next day it <orig
                        reg="commenced">comenced</orig> to sleet and rain when we was putting up our
                    tents and it sleeted the whole night and rained part of the next day. I tell you
                    that we had a rough time of it we was encamped in a field and it was nothing but
                    mud. Well now before I go any further about our <orig reg="raid">rade</orig> I
                    must let you know what I seen that day. It was <orig reg="Saturday"
                    >satterday</orig> the day I received your letter. There was two men had deserted
                    our Army and went to the <orig reg="rebels">rebles</orig> and took up arms
                    against us and they were <orig reg="captured">captuer</orig> sometime ago and on
                        <orig reg="Saturday">satterday</orig> they were both hung between one and
                    two <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig>. They were marched in <del hand="h1"
                    >in</del> front a regiment and a <orig reg="brass">bras</orig> band and <del
                        hand="h1"/>
                    <unclear>their <orig reg="coffins">cofins</orig> carried alongside of
                        them.</unclear><pb n="3"/> There <orig reg="coffins">cofins</orig> was set
                    down along side of the <orig reg="gallows">gallos</orig> and they were marched
                    up on the platform with two officers and a preacher. The officers talked to
                        <orig reg="them">theme</orig> awhile and then the preacher prayed for them
                    and then the officers put the bandage on <orig reg="their">there</orig> eyes and
                    the rope around <orig reg="their">there</orig> neck. I tell you that it was not
                    many seconds to they were dead. You had better <orig reg="believe"
                    >beleave</orig> it was a pretty hard sit<orig reg="sight">e</orig>. Well now I
                    will leave that subject and go on with our <orig reg="raid">rade</orig>. So we
                    started that evening about four o'clock and marched the whole night through the
                    mud halfway up our boot legs and after we got through our picket line our
                    Regiment was ahead and then we was halted and ordered to load our guns and then
                    the two front <orig reg="Companies">Companys</orig> was ordered to go ahead that
                    was <abbr expan="Company">Co</abbr> A and <abbr expan="Company">Co</abbr> F <pb
                        n="4"/> and we marched on to five <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> on
                    Sunday morning and then we encamped on the bank of the
                    <unclear>Nottoway</unclear> river. We did not cross the river but the sixth
                        <orig reg="Corps">corpse</orig> had crossed the river sometime before and
                    that day about 10 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> they commenced coming back.
                    The first that come was the pioneers on the <orig reg="wagons">waggons</orig>
                    with the pontoon bridges and then a lot of cattle that they had captured and
                    then the <orig reg="cavalry">cavelry</orig>. There was a pretty long string of
                    them. I was standing on the bank of the river and I seen John Boggs and he said
                    that your brother got wounded. He did not say that he was bad or not. I seen
                        <orig reg="several">severall</orig> of the boys that I <orig reg="knew"
                    >new</orig>. They were all well and in good spirits. There was some of them had
                    geese and chickens tied to their <orig reg="saddles">sadles</orig>. They had a
                    little of everything with them.<pb n="5"/> Well now I will give you the balance
                    of our trip. We did not capture anything but some sheep. There was a flock in a
                    field with them in it. You may know that our two <orig reg="companies"
                    >companys</orig> went into them. We got all of them. Bill Sibert got one hind
                        <orig reg="quarter">quartre</orig> and Phillip got the other one and then
                    Jacob Shearer got at and cooked some of it for that was all we had to eat that
                    and a little perched corn. We <orig reg="ate">eat</orig> some of it and then we
                    started back. It was about 3 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> and then I only
                    seen part of <orig reg="their">ther</orig> army. We could not see anything but
                    horses and men. There was some of the <orig reg="Cavalry">Cavelry</orig> in
                    front of us and they did put<pb n="6"/> fire to all the buildings along the road
                    and some of them was most splendid houses but they are paying them for burning
                    Chambersburg. We came into our camp that night. It was about 2 <orig
                        reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> when we landed in camp. There was some of the
                    boys did not get in that night at all. Phillip was one of them that did not get
                    in and there was a good many others that did not make it in to camp that night
                    but I made out to get in and night watch at that for my feet was most awful sore
                    and the <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> in my <orig reg="shoulder">shouldier</orig> but them
                    that did not get in to camp that night had it better than we had for we had to
                    march right back in the morning again about 2 miles and they<pb n="7"/> saved
                    saved that and we encamped in the woods that morning and stayed there until
                    yesterday evening to about 6 <orig reg="o'clock">oclock</orig> and then we
                    marched back to our camp. You had better believe that we slept good after we got
                    our supper. There was some of the boys feet got that sore and some of them froze
                    that they could not put on their shoes. My feet did get a little sore but I
                        <orig reg="made">maid</orig> it to camp.</p>

                <p>Well now if we stay here I will try and hunt him up and see how he is now. I have
                    wrote once a week to you since I <orig reg="came">cam</orig> out and I want you
                    to do the same and then I will know if you get them all or not. You sent me your
                    likeness and little <orig reg="Annie's">Annys</orig>. I did not get <orig
                        reg="Mary's">Marys</orig> I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know if you sent
                    it or not.<pb n="8"/> So I think that I will bring letter to a close for this
                    time and when you get this letter and reads it you may give it to Father and let
                    him read it. So nothing more at <orig reg="present">presant</orig> but remains,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>Sylvester McElheney</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Write as soon as this comes to hand.<lb/> Direct to
                        Company F, 208<hi rend="super">th</hi> Regiment PV<lb/> In care of Capt.
                        Palm,<lb/> Washington<lb/> D.C.<lb/> So Good Bye. <name type="recipient">To
                            Mrs. Harriet McElheney</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
