<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F0932"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F0932">

    <teiHeader type="migrated">



        <fileDesc>

            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: C. S. Eyster to Thaddeus Stevens,
                    January [1865?]</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county c s eyster to thaddeus stevens, january 1865</title>
        <author>Eyster, C. S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>

                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>

                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>

                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>

                    <name>Susanna Michele Lee</name>

                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>



            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>

            <publicationStmt>

                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>

                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>



                <idno type="VCDH">F0932</idno>



        <!--
                <availability>

                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>

                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>

                    <p>copyright 1999, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>

                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1999 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>

                <date value="1999">1999</date>

            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501388</idno>
      </publicationStmt>

            <seriesStmt>
                <p>Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>

            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>



            <sourceDesc>

                <biblFull>

                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: C. S. Eyster to Thaddeus Stevens, January [1865?]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county c s eyster to thaddeus stevens, january 1865</title>
            <author>C. S. Eyster</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Thaddeus Stevens Papers,
                            Microfilm reel 2, Manuscripts Division, Library of Congress, Washington,
                            D.C. </idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>

            <creation>
                <date value="1865-01">1865-01-00</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>

            <textClass>

                <keywords>

                    <term>Home front, National Government, State Government</term>

                </keywords>

            </textClass>

        </profileDesc>



        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>

    </teiHeader>



    <text id="F0932T">

        <front id="d2">

            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">

                <p>Proposes a bill for the "relief of our people" with future tax exemption and past
                    tax repayment.</p>

            </div1>

        </front>

        <body id="d4">

            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Thaddeus Stevens</name>
                </head>
                <opener>

                    <dateline>

                        <date value="1865-01">January</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>

                    </dateline>

                    <salute>Hon Thadeus Stevens<lb/> D Sir</salute>

                </opener>



                <p>with this I send you the form of a bill for the relief of our people. It provides
                    first to exempt from tax income of 1863. This is the tax of 5 per ct on income
                    imposed by joint resolution of <orig reg="Congress">Congrefs</orig> "special
                    tax." This tax has been <orig reg="assessed">asfesfed</orig> in our last but
                    will not be due and collectable until in February or March. It is on the income
                    of 1863.-- It will amount to five thousand dollars.- The next proposition is to
                    repay to the people of Chambersburg the tax and duty already paid by them for
                    the year AD 1863. This tax was collected in October AD 1864 and was three per
                    cent on the income also of 1863, the regular tax, also the tax on licenses
                    expiring May 1st 1865. This was also paid in October 1864 and the tax on
                    manufactures for the year AD 1863 up to July 30th 1864-- you remarked to me when
                    I was in Washington that it would be hard to have a tax refunded, much easier to
                    exempt from it:--<pb n="2"/>This is so as a general proposition: and at the time
                    of the calamity I asked Judge Lewis to exempt them from the payment of the tax:
                    he would have done so but had no power. He refered me to <orig reg="Congress"
                        >Congrefs</orig> with the <orig reg="assurance">asfurance</orig> that he
                    would cheerfully carry out any power they would give him for that purpose. On
                    the faith that the <orig reg="Congress">Congrefs</orig> would relieve them they
                    all paid except seven who were utterly unable, many of them paid this tax with
                    the small pittance of public relief money that was sent to them under the full
                    belief that it would be refunded. The collector could not have enforced it for
                    many of them had nothing, but they all paid it willingly-- This bill if <orig
                        reg="passed">pafsed</orig> will enable the <orig reg="commissioner"
                        >commisfioner</orig> to repay to those who were burned out the amount of tax
                    on manufactures of 1863, and up to July 1864- some of them had manufactured
                    goods on hand to a considerable value on which they had paid duty. If this is
                    thought to be too much it can be stricken out. If admitted it will help some of
                    them more than you can imagine and not take much from the Government.<pb n="3"/>
                    When I was in Washington last I talked with Judge Lewis and he <orig
                        reg="expressed">exprefsed</orig> himself as though if you would <orig
                        reg="address">addrefs</orig> any inquiry to him on the subject he would give
                    it a a favorable reply: with this view I have enclosed what I suppose <del
                        hand="h1">what</del> would be a proper letter to him from you. If it meets
                    your view please sign it and send it to him. I did it with a view to save you
                    labor not to dictate.-</p>
                <p>By the next mail I will send you a certificate from the Collector of Chambg
                    showing that the mass of the people paid their tax_</p>



                <p>If you deem it at all advisable I will come to Washington at a moments notice and
                    appear before the committee If you think it proper - please telegraph to me to
                    be paid here, or write me and I will come at once - excuse me for giving you so
                    much trouble and believe me</p>



                <closer>

                    <salute>your friend</salute>

                    <signed>C. S. Eyster</signed>

                    <seg type="postscript">Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives
                        of the United States of American in Congrefs asfembled That the Commisfioner
                        of Internal Revenue of the United States be and hereby authorized to exempt
                        the people of Chambersburg from the payment of the special income tax of
                        five per cent asfesfed for the year AD1863 or to repay it if paid and to
                        repay out of any money in his hands not otherwise appropriated to the people
                        of said Borough and those adjacent the amount of who have lost property by
                        Rebel incursions the amount of duty, tax, income tax <del hand="h1">and
                            licence mon</del> due and paid for the year AD1863 and up to the 30<hi
                            rend="underline">th</hi> day of July AD 1864 and the amount of Licence
                        tax paid on their Licences expiring May 1<hi rend="underline">st</hi>
                        AD1864. </seg>

                </closer>






            </div1>

        </body>

    </text>

</TEI.2>
