<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1117"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1117">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father) and probably Mary Jane Snider (stepmother), December 28, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father and probably mary jane snider stepmother , december 28 1863</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1117</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501413</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father) and probably probably Mary Jane Snider (stepmother), December
                            28, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father and probably probably mary jane snider stepmother , december 28 1863</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-28">1863-12-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Military
                        Authority, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1117T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery responds to news from home, explains that his faith in God allows him
                    to get through army life, and describes in detail a soldier's food rations. He
                    observes that the veteran soldiers receive provisions in the mail, in addition
                    to their rations. Rosenbery sees the rations as part of his pay from "Uncle
                    Sam."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-28">December 28 <abbr expan="anno Domini">A. D.</abbr>
                        1863</date>
                        
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensville, Virginia</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father and Step Mother---</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This morning I seat myself to inform you that I received your letter of 23rd.
                    Yesterday the postage stamp and letter paper came safe to hand. This is some of
                    the paper.</p>
                <p>Well, I am glad and thankful to the Lord that Father is getting better and sorry
                    to hear that William is sick. I hope and trust to God that he will get well
                    again.</p>
                <p>I, this morning, do thank God that through His Goodness and mercy that I am still
                    enjoying good health both in soul and body. Hoping that through the goodness and
                    mercies of God that these few imperfect lines may find you all enjoying the same
                    blessings.</p>
                <p>No doubt you think I am a hard hearted chap that I can be so contented away from
                    home. It is not the good living-it is not the comfortable place of writing-it is
                    not the comfort of standing on post when it is raining or snowing-2 hours on-and
                    4 hours off. It is not the soft bed that is made of white oak poles, but it is
                    simply this having a hope in God that reaches <orig reg="beyond">beyound</orig>
                    the grave, it is said in the words of God, that if we have no hope in this life
                    we are of all men most miserable-so as long as I enjoy that Love of God which I
                    profess.</p>
                <p>Thanks be to God, my <orig reg="soul">soule</orig> shall be fed with Heavenly
                    Food. <orig reg="Then">Than</orig> I am satisfied with a few <orig
                        reg="hardtack">hard tack</orig> and cold water. We have more than that. This
                    is our rations-for a day but it does not satisfy my appetite.</p>
                <p>Now, this day's ration for one man-ten <orig reg="hardtack">hard tack</orig>-1
                    1/2 pound beef-3 tablespoons of coffee and about 3 tablespoons of sugar. Then we
                    have a change sometimes. We draw 2 potatoes-2 onions-a few beans-a small portion
                    of rice and then a portion of pork.</p>
                <p>We do not get this all in one day. This is a change. Then we get a small loaf of
                    bread. The first I mentioned is a days rations. They say it will be plenty after
                    awhile. But I can't see the point.</p>
                <p>Now, to give you an idea the size of the <orig reg="hardtack">hard tack</orig>
                    and bread. Sometimes we have a chance to buy something at the Brigade <orig
                        reg="Commissary">Comesary</orig> or at the settlers by paying a good price
                    for it. Butter is 60 cents per <abbr expan="pound">lb.</abbr> Cheese 40 cents
                    per <abbr expan="pound">lb.</abbr> Eggs 60 cents per dozen. Onions -3 cents for
                    one.</p>
                <p>Well, as I mentioned above I will tell you what I consumed at one meal. But I was
                    hungry and I was hungry and I was determined to have a dinner. I ate 3 hard
                    tack-1 loaf of bread-12 sweet cakes-1/2 <abbr expan="pound">lb.</abbr> of cheese
                    and a few apples. That time I felt as though I had my dinner. I do not mention
                    these things. Some complains of our rations.</p>
                <p>This is a truth a man is always hungry but hunger is a good cook. But the old
                    soldiers say that we conscripts will get used to it.</p>
                <p>Well, I don't want this to cause you any uneasiness as I think no man ever
                    starved in the Army yet. The Old Soldiers-since we are in winter quarters-get
                    boxes of provisions sent to them.</p>
                <p>But I shant have anything sent to me <orig reg="until">untill</orig> I need it.
                    Uncle Sam owes me a living and I will try and have it. No doubt there is a great
                    many people that complains: But why should a living complains. Well, I must soon
                    close for this time.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute/>
                    <signed><abbr expan="Franklin">F.</abbr> Rosenbery</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
