<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1115"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1115">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father), December 25, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , december 25 1863</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1115</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501411</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father), December 25, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , december 25 1863</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical
                        Society</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-25">1863-12-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave,
                        Family, Home Front, Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1115T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>As in earlier letters, Rosenbery writes that he does the will of God. He also
                    hopes for peace, and he wishes that northerners would further devote themselves
                    to the nation's cause. He then goes onto discuss religion as well as the value
                    of tobacco in the soldiers' camp. Finally, he discusses Christmas dinner, the
                    weather, the possibility of a furlough, his prospects for survival, the war's
                    duration, and correspondence.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">John Rosenbery</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-25">December 25, 1863</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute/>
                </opener>

                <p>I am doing the will of God by Crying Freedom: Freedom. As much as if I was at
                    home crying repentance.</p>
                <p>Oh, that all the people of the north would be as active in the engagement of This
                    Cause as they are in <orig reg="trying to">tryingto</orig> get exemited. I am
                    persuaded that this <orig reg="rebellion">rebelion</orig> would soon be crushed.
                    And peace, freedom and liberty again prevail in our land.</p>
                <p>I have <abbr expan="received">Rec.d</abbr> 3 letters from you since I left home.
                    I have written over a dozen letters to you.</p>
                <p>I have <abbr expan="received">Rec.d</abbr> 3 letters from Rachel since I left
                    home. I have written about as many to her as I did to you.</p>
                <p>I write as often to you as I can. <orig reg="Oft times">Oftimes</orig> I have not
                    the privilege to write.</p>
                <p>I would be glad if Brother John would try and write some to me as he has a better
                    chance to write than I have.</p>
                <p>I <abbr expan="received">re.d.</abbr> that <orig reg="tobacco">tabaco</orig> that
                    you sent to me. I sold it nearly all for 25<abbr expan="cents">
                        <del hand="h1">c</del>
                    </abbr>; per plug but now we have a settler here that spoils the sale of <orig
                        reg="tobacco">tobaco</orig>. I can buy it here for a 1 dollar a pound.</p>
                <p>While I think of it you may get a good key for my watch when you send it to me.
                    If Rineman's has not got it fixed yet. Get it fixed by some person else and
                        <orig reg="send">sende</orig> it as soon as you can. As I need it bad.</p>
                <p>Keep account of what you lay out for me and for the family and I will try and
                    repay you.</p>
                <p>It may be that we will get home soon and it may be we will not get home for 3
                    years and it may be we will never get home.</p>
                <p>I am satisfied here as long as I <orig reg="feel">fee</orig> that I am doing the
                    Will of God. I have family worship in our tent. I have prayer meeting in my tent
                    and when the <orig reg="weather">wether</orig> is fit on Sunday we have
                    preaching. And on Thursday Evening we have prayer meetings.</p>
                <p>So if the Army is a hard place and a <orig reg="Soldier's">Soldiers</orig> Life
                    is a hard life. There is none that need be lost. If they are lost it is their
                    own fault. It is not God's for in His Word He saith as I live saith The Lord, I
                    have no pleasure in the death of the wicked. But rather all would be born and
                    live. Turn, ye, Turn, ye, for why will ye die?</p>
                <p>This is <orig reg="Christmas">Christmast</orig>. Now, I must tell what I had for
                    dinner. I had some soup beans boiled with beef and some pork and some of Aunt
                    Sally Lincoln's <orig reg="biscuits">buisquits</orig>-all boiled together. I
                    call the <orig reg="hardtack">hard tack</orig> Aunt Sally Lincoln's <orig
                        reg="biscuits">buisquits</orig>.</p>
                <p>The <orig reg="weather">wether</orig> is very cold. It has been cloudy nearly all
                    day with the appearance of snow. I think that it will snow before morning.</p>
                <p>I have a <orig reg="middling">medling</orig> comfortable place to stay in but
                    people at home would not think so.</p>
                <p>If I hear where <abbr expan="Abraham">A.</abbr> Rosenbery and Ashway is I will go
                    and see them if I can get a pass. As long as I am in Winter Quarters, I will
                    write to you as often as I can. Do not fret yourself about me and if you don't
                    get all the letters that I write do not think that I am forgetting you for I
                    will ever remember you as a Father as long as I live.</p>
                <p>You will soon hear from me if I live and the letters go safe.</p>
                <p>No more at present. Give my best <abbr expan="respects">respts.</abbr> to all
                        <orig reg="Inquiring">Enquiring</orig> friends.</p>


                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours Truly,</salute>
                    <signed>Franklin Rosenbery</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Farewell for the present. <name type="recipient">To his
                            father, John Rosenbery</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
