<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1116"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1116">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father) and probably Mary Jane Snider (stepmother), December 25, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father and probably mary jane snider stepmother , december 25 1863</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1116</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501412</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father) and probably Mary Jane Snider (stepmother), December 25, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father and probably mary jane snider stepmother , december 25 1863</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-12-25">1863-12-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home
                        Front, Patriotism, Slavery, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1116T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery discusses his duties as soldiers and goes on to offer his prayers and
                    proclamations of his Christian faith. He says that heaven waits after death,
                    noting that it will contain no war and no slavery. Rosenbery also mentions his
                    duty to fight for his country.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-12-25">December 25th <abbr expan="anno Domini">A. D.</abbr> 1863</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near, Stephensville, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father and Step-Mother:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Your letter of the 17th of this month came to hand on the 22nd of this month and
                    in the letter you requested me to answer it immediately.</p>
                <p>I had written you a letter on the 22nd but no answer as I did not <orig
                        reg="receive">receave</orig> your letter until evening. Yesterday I intended
                    to answer it but was detailed to help to build <orig reg="corduroy"
                    >cordury</orig> roads so that we can have our <orig reg="supplies"
                    >suplies</orig> brought from Brandy Station. If it <orig reg="should"
                    >shoud</orig> be wet - or as it appears-winter the <orig reg="roads">rods</orig>
                    soon get miserable bad in these Virginia swamps.</p>
                <p>Now, about Ashway not mentioning Abraham's name when he wrote, it is this way-the
                    soldier very seldom mentions one individual's name without there is something
                    wrong for all appear like brothers. When one is well all is right. I shall make
                    an inquiry of their <orig reg="whereabouts">wheabout</orig> as soon as I can.</p>
                <p>I am well. I thank God that I enjoy good health-both in soul and body.</p>
                <p>I hope you all enjoy the same as it is a very necessary thing as life is
                    incertain and death is sure.</p>
                <p>We are taught in the word of God that it is an awful thing to fall into the hands
                    of an angry God. Lord, prepare our Soul and meet thee at that great day with joy
                    and not with grief..it is no vain thing to wait upon the <orig reg="Lord"
                    >Lorde</orig>. Although we have trials, troubles and difficulty deep and
                    high-loses and crosses to contend with in this world but everything works for
                    good to them that love God.</p>
                <p>I am sorry to hear that you must suffer so much with pains in your back.</p>
                <p>But I should say to you-place your trust in God-then our light afflictions which
                    are <orig reg="for">fore</orig> a moment will work out for us. A far more <orig
                        reg="exceeding">exceedin</orig> and eternal weight of Glory. Lord help us
                    sinful worms of the dust to be faithful so that may be well with us when we
                    exchange time for eternity or when we are called to cross the cold Jordan of
                    death. It may be that we will never see each other here but if we live right to
                    do the will of God as we should, we will meet in Heaven to part no more. There
                    will be no war there and there will be no slavery. There all will be freedom.
                    All will be peace.</p>
                <p>As the poet says-when we've been there ten thousand years-bright <orig
                        reg="Shining">Shinning</orig> as the sun- we have no less days to sing God's
                    Praise than when we first begun. Glory to God for the hope of Eternal life and
                    the glorious enjoyment of <orig reg="Heaven">Haven</orig>, forever and ever.
                    White Christians enjoy this enjoy this, sinners will be sunk beneath the ice of
                    God's wrath forever and ever.</p>
                <p>This is an awful thought for a soul's so precious as to cost the blood of Christ.
                    To be lost and lost eternally without the hope of Eternal life.</p>
                <p>Lord, Lord, saved by the purchase of thy blood. As I believe that the great
                    judgement day will reveal some wonderful strange things to the children of men.
                    Therefore we should work while it is called today. For when the night of death
                    cometh no one can work. O May a Saviour's love be shed abroad in these cold
                    hearts of ours. Then we can obey thy commands and love our neighbors as
                    ourselves. Then we can realize that Love worked no ill to his neighbors. Lord,
                    bind our hearts together in one bundle of Love that we may pray continually for
                    one another and at last land our souls on the Sunny Banks of Eternal
                    deliverance.</p>
                <p>My prayer to God is that he will save us all in His Kingdom where we can praise
                    him while eternity remains.</p>
                <p>Dear Father, I am thankful to God that you take in the interest in the welfare of
                    my little babes. I am sorry that Rachel can't content herself enough to stay at
                    home. But I feel it is my duty to be here as my country is at stake.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Farewell Father. God Bless you all.</salute>
                    <signed>Franklin <orig reg="Rosenbery">Roenbery</orig></signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Please meet me in Heaven. Write down. Live in hope if God
                        spares us we will soon meet again.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
