<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1127"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F1127">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father), March 1, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 1 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1127</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501423</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father), March 1, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 1 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-01">1864-03-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Family, Military Authority, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1127T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery indicates his affection for his father and his country, and he also
                    mentions the soldiers' payday. Rosenbery expresses optimism that the rebellion
                    will be crushed, and he prays for peace. Rosenbery also mentions that his father
                    need no longer send his repaired watch.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-01">March 1, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This morning I sent with pen in hand to inform you that I am well. Hoping that
                    these few lines may find you enjoying good health.</p>
                <p>I was sorry to read in Rachel's letter that you were beginning to think that I
                    was forgetting you. No, No, father, I will never forget you...by the way of
                    writing or in any other way so long as I live.</p>
                <p>I think that you have had too much trouble in raising me to forget you and and in
                    caring for my family while I am engaged in my country's call.</p>
                <p>Since the 14th I have written 4 letters with a letter in 2 of them. I enclose 5
                    dollars in each or rather the 2 letters containing 10 dollars. Yesterday we were
                    mustered again for pay. I look for 26 dollars again in a few days. Then, I will
                        <orig reg="send">sende</orig> some more to you.</p>
                <p>Dear Father, when I do not think of home it appears not time since I am in the
                    Service. We were <orig reg="paid">paide</orig> from the 28th of August so, if I
                    think, the time will be recorded from that time and if so, the year will be up
                    at August and the 9 months will be up the 28th of May. These few months will
                    soon roll around so keep in good heart and I further think that till that time
                    this <orig reg="rebellion">rebelion</orig> will be crushed; No doubt it will
                    cost a great many lives.</p>
                <p>We all have our risk to run but thanks to God He is able to provide and protect
                    all those that place their trust in Him.</p>
                <p>We have been under marching orders since Sunday Morning at 1 o'clock. General
                        <orig reg="Kilpatrick">Killpaterick</orig> is out on a <orig reg="raid"
                        >radie</orig> feeling the strength of the enemy.</p>
                <p>The 6th Corps is advancing to Gordonsville while we are kept in readiness. We
                        <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> tell how soon we must march.</p>
                <p>A few days ago one of the General Lee's orderly came through the picket lines. He
                    informed our General of the numbers of Lee's Army. He said their number was
                    about 25,000 and further stated that there was a great number went home to <orig
                        reg="reenlist">re-inlist</orig>. If this is so, Now is the time for us. If
                    the weather was only favorable we might knock out some of his props for I think
                    that the <orig reg="rebellion">rebelion</orig> is like some old house <orig
                        reg="propped">proped</orig> up and I think we will soon knock out some of
                    the main props</p>
                <p>May God speed the day that peace may again be declared and we can all return
                    home.</p>
                <p>Well, I must close for the present.</p>
                <p>If you have not sent my watch yet, you need not send it and if you have sent it,
                    it is alright.</p>
                <p>Well, I must close for the present and if I have the chance I will write soon
                    again.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>From your son. So farewell, for the present.</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="Franklin">F.</abbr> Rosenbery</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
