<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1130"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1130">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham
                    Rosenbery (father), March 28, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 28 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1130</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501426</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to John Abraham Rosenbery
                            (father), March 28, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to john abraham rosenbery father , march 28 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-03-28">1864-03-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave,
                        Family, Military Authority, National Government, Patriotism, Troop Movement</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1130T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery ponders how much longer he will have to serve in the army. He
                    anticipates troop movement and action, and he is willing to remain in service
                    until war's end, if he must. As in earlier letters, Rosenbery vows to meet his
                    family in heaven if he does not survive the war.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-03-28">March 28, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This morning I seat myself to inform you that I am well at this time. Hoping that
                    these few lines may find you all enjoying the same blessings of health.</p>
                <p>It is <orig reg="middling">midling</orig> pleasant here this morning. The snow
                    that had fell on the 22nd is all gone. It was about 1 foot in depth.</p>
                <p>Everything appears quiet at present-not <orig reg="knowing">knowning</orig> how
                    long it will remain so it is reported that The Army of the Potomac will only
                    have 3 Corps in it-that will be 2nd-5th-6th. The 1st and 5th Corps to be broken
                    up and put into 3 Corps. Then it will be called 3 Grand Divisions. Our Regiment
                    will be taken out of the 3rd Brigade to put into the 4th Brigade but we will
                    still be in the 1st Division of the 2nd Corps.</p>
                <p>Now this is the talk and the preparation is made to that effect. You may direct
                    your letters to the 1st Division 2nd Corps. As I should have said, direct them
                    as you did before only leave out the Brigade till further orders.</p>
                <p>You may my subscription to John A. Horn. He can tell you how much it is. I think
                    it is 2 dollars.</p>
                <p>About me getting home in 9 months. Looks very doubtful. But according to the
                    Amendments of the Conscription Act they <orig reg="cannot">can not</orig> hold
                    us any longer than 9 months in the field and 3 month to do state duty. Now, look
                    at it, a substitute is only good for one year. How can they compel us to stay
                    longer <orig reg="than">then</orig> 1 year? It is against the Constitution to
                    make a draft for 3 years and then the trouble is this. There is no sign of us
                    getting bounty yet. Well, they may just do as they please. If I must stay 3
                    years or during the war, I can do that if I live. I have learnt how to make
                    myself contented. The time will soon roll around and time will reveal all
                    things.</p>
                <p>I have not heard anything from Abraham and Ashway since I got the letter from
                    them that I sent to you but I hope that they are all well.</p>
                <p>Now, I will say that I can't promise about writing very regular as we will soon
                    begin to move about some but I write as often as I can <orig reg="conveniently"
                        >conventiently</orig>.</p>
                <p>I have not particulars to write at this time more than I am still trying by The
                    Grace of God to follow the meek and lowly Lamb. Let come what will, trusting
                    that if I never meet any of you on earth, I will <orig reg="meet">meeet</orig>
                    you at the right hand of God in Heaven.</p>
                <p>Write soon. Take good care of your health. No more at present but remain your son
                    till death.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>So farewell for this time.</salute>
                    <signed>Franklin Rosenbery</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">We expect to be paid soon. Then I will <orig reg="send"
                            >sende</orig> you all the money that I will have to spare. You need not
                        send my watch till I write to that <orig reg="effect">affect</orig>. I am
                        still living in hope of seeing you all again e're long.<lb/> Give my <abbr
                            expan="respects">respt.</abbr> to all <orig reg="inquiring"
                        >enquiring</orig> friends.<lb/>
                        <abbr expan="Franklin">F.</abbr> Rosenbery</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
