<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F1132"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F1132">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to Rosenbery,
                    John Abraham (father) and probably Elemina (mother)), April 9, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to rosenbery, john abraham father and probably elemina mother april 9 1864</title>
        <author>Rosenbery, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Matt Speiser</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F1132</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501428</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Rosenbery to Rosenbery, John Abraham
                            (father) and probably Elemina (mother)), April 9, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin rosenbery to rosenbery, john abraham father and probably elemina mother april 9 1864</title>
            <author>Franklin Rosenbery</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent> pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kittochtinney Historical Society,
                            Chambersburg, PA</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinney Historical Society, Chambersburg, PA</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-04-09">1864-04-09</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Desertion/Leave,
                        Family, Military Authority, Military Strategy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005-07">July, 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Kid W.</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F1132T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Rosenbery anticipates the summer campaign. Later in the letter, he writes that he
                    continues to be in good health. As in earlier letters, he ponders the duration
                    of his remaining service, and he both professes his desire to perform his duty
                    as well as his longing for home and family. Facing the possibility of death,
                    Rosenbery finds comfort in his Christian faith.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-04-09">April 9, 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Near Stephensburg, <abbr expan="Virginia">Va.</abbr></name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Father and Mother:-</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>This morning I seat myself down to inform you that your letter of 27th March came
                    to hand a few days ago and also yesterday a letter dated 3 April.</p>
                <p>I was glad to hear from you that you were well. I am well at present hoping that
                    these few lines may find you all enjoying the same blessings of health.</p>
                <p>I have just came off of Camp Guard. We are kept pretty busy drilling. This
                    morning it is raining.</p>
                <p>The Summer Campaign will soon commence. We are engaged digging up the Earth,
                    making breast works. This looks as though we will stand the <abbr expan="rebels"
                        >rebs</abbr> a fight here if they make an <orig reg="attack">attact</orig>.
                    We has a good <abbr expan="position">
                        <hi rend="underline">posish</hi>
                    </abbr>. There is height here that we can plant our <orig reg="artillery"
                        >artilery</orig> on that we can give them an introduction to some of the
                    Yanks shells.</p>
                <p>The time is coming that will tell if we conscripts must stay 9 months or three
                    years. The report is that we must report at Chambersburg on the 15th of May. I
                    can't tell but time will tell if it be correct.</p>
                <p>I must say that I am very well contented here but as long as I have parents, wife
                    and children, I would rather be at home. I am glad that I can make myself so
                    content. Time passes very fast with me. Although <orig reg="soldiering"
                        >soldering</orig> is no fun but I must say with all the hardships and
                    exposures that I have endured since I am in the Service, I have never had my
                    health better. I have never yet reported to the doctor, not knowing how soon I
                    might. I was pretty sick the time that we advance to the Rapidan but it only
                    lasted a few days.</p>
                <p>I think that the summer will end this <orig reg="rebellion">rebelion</orig>; and
                    it may end me for all that I know. If it should, blessed by God, I have a bright
                    hope that reaches <orig reg="beyond">beyound</orig> the grave.</p>
                <p>I am glad in days that are gone by that I sought the Lord and found him to the
                    joy and comfort of my heart this morning. My heart rejoices for the peace of a
                    horrible conscience, yes, the peace that nothing but the love of a <orig
                        reg="Savior">Saviour</orig> can bestow on all the inhabitants of the Earth
                    that ever was told that <orig reg="Christ">Christe</orig> died for mankind can
                    have his peace, if they will only <orig reg="accept">except</orig> of it.</p>
                <p>I thank God that the way of Salvation is so simple and so plain: repentance
                    become sorry for sin is repentance. Sorry because we have offended our best
                    friend. One that is able to save, faith simple taking Jesus at his word, <orig
                        reg="believing">beleaving</orig> that he will save us if we only <orig
                        reg="believe">beleave</orig> on his name-giving him our <orig reg="hearts"
                        >heats</orig> by prayer. We must take Him at His Word for He says -Him that
                    cometh to me I will never renounce-cast off. Jesus <orig reg="cannot">can
                    not</orig> lie and by putting of the Salvation of our Souls till a future day
                    will not make any fitter and life is uncertain. We can't count on the future.</p>
                <p>So today is the time. Lord, help us to <orig reg="accept">except</orig> Thy
                    Salvation now. I must close.</p>
                <p>If I never see you again-prepare to meet me in Heaven. Write now. I life in hope,
                    if God spares us we will soon meet again.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>So farewell. God bless you all.</salute>
                    <signed><abbr expan="Franklin">F.</abbr> Rosenbery</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
