<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F3055"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F3055">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Jacob Christy to Mary Jane Demus, July 2, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county jacob christy to mary jane demus, july 2 1864</title>
        <author>Christy, Jacob</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F3055</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501493</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Jacob Christy to Mary Jane Demus, July 2, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county jacob christy to mary jane demus, july 2 1864</title>
            <author>Jacob Christy</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>3 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Case File of Wesley Krunkleton, Approved Pension
       Applications of Veterans Who Served in the Army and Navy Mainly in the Civil War and the War
       with Spain, Record Group 15, National Archives and Records Administration, Washington,
      D.C.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edwin W. Redkey, Lagrangeville, New York, for bringing these
        letters to our attention.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from National Archives and Records Administration, Washington, D.C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1864-07-02">1864-07-02</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>African Americans, Battle Description, Family, Military Authority</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value="2001-07">July 2001</date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name>Amy Murrell</name>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F3055T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>Christy updates his sister on the welfare of her brothers and her husband. He also expresses
     frustration that his regiment has not been paid, especially given how hard he and his comrades
     have fought.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    <head>
     <name type="recipient">Mary Jane Demus</name>
    </head>

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1864-07-02">July the 2 1864</date>
      <name type="place">Morris Island South Carolina</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I take this <orig reg="present">preasant</orig>
     <orig reg="Opportunity">Opertunity</orig> to inform a few lines to you that I am well At
     present <orig reg="hoping">hopeing</orig> these few lines may find you all well I receive your
     Letter and was <orig reg="very">verry</orig> glad to hear from you all once more Again that you
     was all well and was <orig reg="getting">geting</orig> Along so well I hope that you all may
     get Along well for I can not <orig reg="do">due</orig> anything for you for we will not get any
     money as long as we are in the surfers But <orig reg="they">thay</orig> Say that they <orig
      reg="Won't">Wont</orig> pay us and we <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> fight no more
      <unclear>thay</unclear> are great fighting going on At <orig reg="Richmond">Richmon</orig> and
      <unclear>thay</unclear> had last night on James Island and are still fighting there now And
     has been fighting all day and are going To fight <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig> But our
      <orig reg="Company">Compy</orig> will not be in it I <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> know <orig
      reg="whether">wither</orig> the <orig reg="Company">compy</orig> that David and George is in
     will be there or not for we are on another Island I <orig reg="haven't">haveant</orig> saw them
     two or three weeks But David will not <orig reg="be">bee</orig> in the fight for he Butchering
     now Samuel and Joseph is well and are <orig reg="getting">geting</orig> along <orig reg="very"
      >verry</orig> well we have <orig reg="very">verry</orig> easy times now We are on <orig
      reg="detach">detatch</orig> duty and have nothing to <orig reg="do">due</orig> But Picket duty
     we drill a little some times I <orig reg="can't">cant</orig> say when we may get home But We
     may get home sooner then what we <orig reg="expect">expecte</orig> for all <orig reg="colored"
      >colard</orig> troops fights well But still <orig reg="they">thay</orig> are <orig
      reg="getting">geting</orig> nothing for it and we Will stop our fighting now <orig reg="until"
      >on tell</orig> we know and See what we are fighting for We <unclear>shant</unclear> run <orig
      reg="ourselves">ourselfs</orig>
     <orig reg="into">in to</orig>
     <orig reg="places">placers</orig>
     <orig reg="where">were</orig> we well be slaughter up we have <orig reg="done">dun</orig>
     enough of it to know how it <orig reg="goes">gose</orig>
     <unclear>thay</unclear> was a many a man die this day And will be a many a one more before the
     4th of July is over I am <orig reg="sitting">seting</orig> out on a Picket post <orig
      reg="writing">righting</orig> this letter and the big cannon is roaring in a mile <orig
      reg="distant">disent</orig> from me And every <orig reg="time">thine</orig> I raise up my head
     I can see the smoke raising from the big guns our camp is not more <orig reg="than">then</orig>
     two miles of I am seting now not more <orig reg="than">then</orig> a mile of from the rebels
     forts and Battery we can see Them But <orig reg="they">thay</orig> are <orig reg="water"
     >watter</orig> between us I am Looking <orig reg="right">rite</orig> at rebels now walking
     around All the Mercersburg boys are well except Jeff <unclear>teat</unclear> I am <orig
      reg="very">verry</orig> sorry that I <orig reg="haven't">haveant</orig> got my likeness taken
     to <orig reg="send">cend</orig> you I would have <orig reg="written">riten</orig> to you sooner
     but I have been <orig reg="waiting">waiteing</orig>
     <orig reg="until">tell</orig> I would get my <orig reg="likeness">liknes</orig> taken But I
      <orig reg="haven't">haveant</orig>
     <orig reg="got">gut</orig> it taken yet but the <unclear>nix</unclear> time I <orig reg="write"
      >rite</orig> I think that I will be able to <orig reg="send">cend</orig> it I <orig
      reg="don't">dont</orig> know how <unclear>tikeovers</unclear> that was I Judge that you all
     will have good time in the fourth of July But that the day When poor soldiers are fighting as
     hard as <orig reg="they">thay</orig> can it is <orig reg="very">verry</orig>
     <orig reg="warm">worm</orig> here and dry give my love to father and Elizeberth and All the
      <orig reg="inquiring">inquireing</orig> friends we can <orig reg="sit">set</orig> and Think
     about a many a thing to see <orig reg="a woman">awoman</orig> or a girls is a show to us to see
     now All the boys <orig reg="send">cend</orig> their to you all and all the friends <orig
      reg="very">verry</orig> likely I may be taken to A fight <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>
     myself But I <orig reg="won't">wont</orig> fight any my love to you all Remember me while part
     we be</p>

    <p>Nothing More At <orig reg="Present">Preasant</orig> But still Remain</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>your Dear Brother</salute>
     <signed>Jacob Elliot Christy</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">
      <orig reg="Please">Pleas</orig> to <orig reg="Write">Rite</orig> Soon And Direct Your Letter
      To <abbr expan="Company">Compy</abbr> J 54<lb/><orig reg="Massachusetts">Massachuetts</orig>
      <orig reg="Volunteers">Volentears</orig><lb/> Morris Island South Carolina<lb/> Via of Hilton
      Head<lb/><lb/> Jacob Elliot Christy to Mary Jane Demes </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
