<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4025"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4025">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Alexander K. McClure to Eli Slifer,
                    February 27, 1851</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county alexander k mcclure to eli slifer, february 27 1851</title>
        <author>McClure, Alexander K.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4025</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501577</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Alexander K. McClure to Eli Slifer, February 27,
                            1851</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county alexander k mcclure to eli slifer, february 27 1851</title>
            <author>Alexander K. McClure</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Eli Slifer Papers, 1850-1891, Mss
                            Slifer-Dill, Special Collections, Waidner-Spahr Library, Dickenson
                            College, Carlisle, Pa.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Waidner-Spahr Library, Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pa.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1851-02-27">1851-02-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4025T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McClure's lengthy letter speaks in detail about passing a licensing regulation
                    bill, but also metions a developing split in the Whig party.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    Sentinel Office
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1851-02-27"><orig reg="February">Feb</orig> 27th, 1851</date>
                        <name type="place">Mifflintown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear <orig reg="Colonel">Col</orig></salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Mr. Cooper informed me that <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> have some apprehensions relative to
                    the propriety of legislating on the License question, without a formal
                    expression of the popular will by petition or otherwise.</p>

                <p>The reasons that induced the repeal of the general law <unclear/> as it related
                    to this county. I have before stated, and that statement is substantially true.
                    It was not done because there was any popular manifestation against it.</p>

                <p>If petitions are necessary, they can be furnished by the <unclear>cads</unclear>,
                    but the short time allowed if we wish to get the law in operation this spring,
                    would prevent anything like a general expression of the people. Rest assured it
                    was not because we feared to put petitions among the people.</p>

                <p>To make the law operative when Licenses are granted at the <unclear>may</unclear>
                    court, the bill should be passed by the first week, or the middle of March <pb
                        n="2"/>at the farthest; and the matter was not taken in hand until our
                    February court. A number of petitions were then presented for licenses and
                    several were illegal, but owing to the fact that but few of the citizens in the
                    respective <unclear/> knew that applications would then be made, and knew
                    nothing respecting who were the <unclear/> remonstrance was impossible. You are
                    not aware perhaps that both our February and May courts grant licenses and
                    applications may be made at one or the other of the towns, as petitioners may
                    choose. This can only be remedied by requiring <hi rend="underline">one</hi>
                    court to grant all licenses for the year, or by requiring the publication of the
                    petitions. Of the two you cannot be long in deciding which would best <unclear/>
                    the iterests of the <unclear>public</unclear> and afford the best check to
                    illegal licenses.</p>

                <p>I know also that both in Union and Mifflin counties the law we ask is in
                    operation, and infered that its practicality even necessity would be obvious to
                    both you and <unclear>friend</unclear> Cunningham.</p>

                <p>I trust that under the circumstances you will hasten the passage of the bill. By
                    so doing you will be almost universally sustained by the people, and will also
                    be heartily defended by both the Papers here.</p>

                <p>As I said before, out Court <pb n="3"/>meets in May, and the middle of the March
                    should find the bill passed to be carried into effect this Spring. Cooper and I
                    will have the landlords fully apprised of the matter, so that no complaints can
                    be made, and as to any division of sentiment in reference to it among the
                    people, I will agree to take the responsibility and <unclear>atter</unclear> all
                    damages.</p>

                <p>We have nothing special here, I see that Union has done the
                    <unclear>thing</unclear> all right, though I fear the resolution of conciliation
                    prepared by <unclear>Middlesworth</unclear> is hardly a fair representation of
                    the sentiments of the leaders of the two factions. I had a letter from Woods
                    containing a statement of the whole thing, from which I infer that there is a
                    serious split in the party. I hope it may be healed before the next campaign
                    opens.</p>

                <p>I have not heard from friend Cunningham lately. I hope he is enjoying himself. I
                    shall be sorry to leave so good a Whig out of our district next spring. I
                    believe he moves to Huntington. Remember me to him, and secure his efforts to
                    effect a speedy passage of the license bill.</p>

                <p>I will be down one of these days.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>thine,</salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">AK McClure</hi>
                    </signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient"><orig reg="Colonel">Col</orig> Eli Slifer</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
