<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4047"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4047">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Franklin Gaillard to "Sonny"
                    Gaillard, June 28, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county franklin gaillard to sonny gaillard, june 28 1863</title>
        <author>Gaillard, Franklin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Fred E. Gaillard</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4047</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501598</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Franklin Gaillard to "Sonny" Gaillard, June 28, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county franklin gaillard to sonny gaillard, june 28 1863</title>
            <author>Franklin Gaillard</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>1 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Franklin Gaillard Papers,
                            #3790-z, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina,
                            Chapel Hill.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>Letter transcribed by Fred E. Gaillard in 1941.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, Wilson Library, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-28">1863-06-28</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Military Authority, Military Strategy, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4047T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>In a letter to his son, Franklin Gaillard describes the troops' movement into
                    Pennsylvania and the reaction of the local population to the Confederate troops.
                    Gaillard also writes that he agrees with Lee's strict policy against
                looting.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-28">June 28th 1863.</date>
                        <name type="place">Camp near Chambersburg, Pa.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sonny</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I promised in my last letter to Aunt Ria that I would soon answer your letter. We
                    have been so constantly on the move since then that I really have not been able
                    to do it satisfactorily. When I received your letter we had just begun to move.
                    I had no idea that it was the beginning of so grand a movement as it has
                    resulted in here we are now in the great and powerful State of Pennsylvania
                    marching forward in the direction of her Capitol. I do not know, of course, what
                        <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee is going to do, for like a good
                    general he will keep his intentions to himself and his <abbr expan="Lieutenant"
                        >Lieut.</abbr> Generals. But it appears to me very much as if he is going to
                    strike a blow at Harrisburg and if he can succeed in taking it, it will be a
                    brilliant triumph of our arms. The enemy have nothing but raw troops in our
                    front. I think we can whip these three or four to one. Then we could march on
                    towards Philadelphia and <abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Hooker would have to
                    come to our front to save it and we would thus free Maryland and maybe take
                    Washington and Baltimore. Thus the summer is going to be filled with great
                    events and if Providence will favor our efforts I hope mighty things for our
                    country will be achieved. Our Army never was in better health and spirits. Since
                    we left Fredericksburg we have marched about one hundred and sixty miles. In our
                    march from Culpepper to Ashby's Gap we had a terrible march. The sun was very
                    hot and then so many men marching along together made it very dusty. Another
                    thing too, in the old settled country the farmers find great difficulty in
                    getting rails. Where we passed it was mountainous and stony and the people would
                    gather up large quantities and make stone walls which answer the purpose of a
                    fence and are very durable. When our troops would be down in a valley, so that
                    no wind could refresh them, with the sun coming down heavily upon their heads,
                    the heat increased by the reflection from the walls, and the dust stifling them
                    so that they could not breathe in pure air, the gallant fellows, many, very
                    many, would turn red in the face from blood rushing to their head and fall to
                    the ground with sun stroke. When we got to Ashby's Gap we stopped for two or
                    three days and then we had a very heavy rain and one or two days of cloudy and
                    wet weather. This revived them all like pouring water on wilted plants. Nearly
                    all came up. We stopped there to guard this Gap and it was well we did for the
                    enemy's Cavalry assisted by a small force of infantry drove our Cavalry several
                    miles before them and we all thought whipped them pretty badly. We had crossed
                    the Shenandoah River and had to recross it and go back three or four miles to
                    keep the Yankees from taking the Gap. Next day the Yankees went back and
                    Stuart's Cavalry went poking along at a very slow pace as if they were in no
                    great hurry to overtake them. They now claim in the papers that they drove them
                    back but we who were there and saw them know better. Our Cavalry is very little
                    account and have very little to boast of. There are more than half of them who
                    are with their horses lamed or sore backed with the wagons. I am glad to see
                    that the newspapers are speaking very severely about them and I hope it will
                    improve them. They have got so now that as soon as a fight begins they think
                    that they have nothing to do but to go to the rear and let the Infantry do the
                    fighting. Our boys ridicule them very much whenever they pass.</p>

                <p>I am afraid that our men will suffer for shoes. These long marches are very
                    trying on men's feet and shoes. You would be very much amused to see the men
                    crossing a river. A regiment is marched down to the banks and sometimes halted
                    long enough to allow them to pull of their pantaloons. If the water is over
                    waist deep they put bayonets on their guns and hang their cartridge boxes on
                    them - then right shoulder shift arms and wade across all in fine spirits as if
                    it was a frolic. The Yankees carry pontoon trains along with them but our boys
                    say that every man in General Lee's Army carries his own pontoons. It is very
                    funny to pass through these Yankee towns to see the long sour faces the people
                    put on. The girls some of them wear little United States flags. Others more
                    indecent hold their noses and make faces. Our men go on and pay no attention to
                    them. They only laugh at them when they make themselves ridiculous. Things are
                    very cheap here in their stores but they will not take our money and <abbr
                        expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee has issued very stringent orders about
                    private property. He is very right for our Army would soon become demoralized if
                    they were allowed to do as many of them would like to. Many of them think it
                    very hard that they should not be allowed to treat them as their soldiers
                    treated our people. But we must not imitate the Yankees in their mean acts.</p>

                <p>We are getting a large number of horses but this is being done by proper
                    authorities.</p>

                <p><abbr expan="General">Gen.</abbr> Lee is going to support his Army over here and
                    this will tax the people here and make them feel the war.</p>

                <p>You must give my love to all and kiss daughter for me. Give my love to Grand Ma,
                    Aunt Ria and all at Aunt Louisa's. It is getting so dark I can hardly see how to
                    write.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your very affectionate father</salute>
                    <signed>Franklin Gaillard</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
