<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F4055"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F4055">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: [G.?] C. Brown to his Sister and
                    Mother, June 25, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county g c brown to his sister and mother, june 25 1863</title>
        <author>Brown, [G.?] C.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F4055</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501606</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: [G.?] C. Brown to his Sister and Mother, June 25,
                            1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county g c brown to his sister and mother, june 25 1863</title>
            <author>[G.?] C. Brown</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Polk-Brown-Ewell Papers, #605,
                            Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel
                            Hill.</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1863-06-25">1863-06-25</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Military Authority, Patriotism, Troop Movement, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2005">Summer 2005</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Doug O'Reagan</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F4055T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Brown writes to his sister and mother about the goods he was able to purchase in
                    Chambersburg, and describes the general availability, quality, and price of
                    goods in the area. He also gives a brief account of the local population's
                    reaction to the Confederate troops.</p>
            </div1>
            <div1 type="note" id="d4">
                <p>Write to Henry Watterson, Chattanooga, to know what has become of your trunk. He
                    was to have sent it, may have failed to start it or kept it for W<hi
                        rend="super">m</hi> Stoddert to bring on.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d5">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d6">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1863-06-25">June 25<hi rend="underline">th</hi> 1863</date>
                        
                        <name type="place">Camp at Chambersburg, Pennsylvania</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sister &amp; Mother,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Yesterday I purchased a large lot of dry goods comprising three dresses for
                    H.S.B. &amp; two for Mother, or rather one of the girls' dresses is for
                    Lizzie. There are sundry other articles too numerous &amp; unfamiliar to me,
                    to mention, except that I send a piece of shirting cotton. The whole concern
                    cost me (4 lbs. tea at $3.00 included) $163.00-- It would cost you about $700 if
                    you could get it at all, I suppose I hope to be able to fill another box if we
                    get to Harrisburg or Carlisle, and will try to send the things included in your
                    list &amp; not sent now. There are no silk dresses in this town - all being
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> off or hidden. I bought for <abbr
                        expan="Confederate States">C.S.</abbr> money &amp; used no threats for
                    compulsion whatever.</p>

                <p>Chickens sell for 10 cents here, butter for 12 1/2, but we generally have to pay
                    in Yankee money for them as <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Ewell does not
                    allow us to force our own currency upon the people - a
                    <unclear>leniency</unclear> which I think utterly thrown away upon men who
                    behave as these have done, or at least as their troops have done. The people in
                    the towns seem to stir about as much as usual or more, and behave pretty well
                    except that now &amp; then women turn their backs on us, or bring up a
                    decided pout, which as they are naturally very much uglier &amp; coarser
                    than ours, doesn't improve them <pb n="2"/>in fact is a trial their faces are
                    not equal to.</p>

                <p>We have actually got again into the neighborhood where a five cent piece is worth
                    something. The dresses I send cost 50 cents a yard, but would have been about 25
                    in <abbr expan="Federal">Fedl</abbr> money, I think.</p>

                <p>I send you a New York Herald of June 22<hi rend="underline">
                        <hi rend="super">d</hi>
                    </hi> containing a pretty accurate map of the siege of Winchester to fair enough
                    Yankee account of it. As to our captures it rather exaggerates than diminishes
                    them.</p>

                <p>We are daily getting large supplies. All these little Dutch Yankee towns are full
                    of things we require, and we have clothing, shoes, provisions, letter paper even
                    in great quantities- less clothing &amp; shoes in proportion however, than
                    anything else. <abbr expan="General">Genl</abbr> Lee's orders prescribe that
                    requisitions be made on the towns <unclear>taken</unclear> for any articles
                    needed - if they fail to furnish it, then the town is to be searched &amp;
                    anything needed to be taken. We got a good deal by these two means in
                    Chambersburg.</p>

                <p>I hope you'll get the valise I send, packed, as a sort of "amende honorable" for
                    taking your carpet-bag supply, especially as the things are very valuable to
                    you. I will try next time to buy something for winter use. We are all well</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>
                        <abbr expan="Yours">Y<hi rend="underline">rs</hi></abbr>
                        <abbr expan="affectionately">affecy</abbr>
                    </salute>
                    <signed><unclear>G.</unclear> C. Brown</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">I hope the tea will be drinkable- It was the only article
                        in town above the degree of <hi rend="underline">abominable</hi>. </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
