<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6029"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6029">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Serena E.
                    Russell, [illegible] 2, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to serena e russell, illegible 2 1862</title>
        <author>Russell, Lauramann Howe</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagle</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Julie Beagle</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F6029</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2001">2001</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501608</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Lauramann Howe Russell to Serena E. Russell,
                            [illegible] 2, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county lauramann howe russell to serena e russell, illegible 2 1862</title>
            <author>Lauramann Howe Russell</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Lauramann Howe Russell Papers,
                            Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke
                            University, Durham, North Carolina</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>We have not included other letters in this collection written from
                                Williamsport, Maryland, Harpers Ferry, (West) Virginia, and
                                Alexandria, Virginia.</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Special Collections Department, William R. Perkins Library, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862">1862-00-02</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Church/Religion, Medicine/Hospitals, Family</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2001">Summer 2001</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against the original; transcription corrected.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F6029T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Lauramann Howe Russell writes from a hospital in Chambersburg to his daughter,
                    Serena, describing Sabbath School and entertainment at the hospital. He also
                    includes a description of quiet life in Chambersburg, mentioning the German
                    Reformed Church and the paper mill.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862"><del rend="none" hand="h1"/> 2<hi rend="super">nd</hi>
                        62</date>
                        <name type="place">
                            <orig reg="Academy">Acadamy</orig> Hospital <abbr expan="Pennsylvania"
                                >P.a.</abbr><lb/> Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <orig reg="Daughter">Dauter</orig> Serena</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Having just returned from the <orig reg="Sabbath">Sabbat</orig> School I am
                    thinking that I want to write to some of my <orig reg="folks">folkes</orig> and
                    as you have not written to me for some time as I to you now is a good time.</p>

                <p>As I was saying I have just returned from School. it is half past two o'clock
                        <orig reg="Though">Tho.</orig> you may think it rather late but it is not
                    so. the Sabbath School takes the place of the afternoon service the Church
                    meetings being in the morning and evening.<pb n="2"/> The Church is some five
                    minutes walk from the Hospital on the <orig reg="Main">Maine</orig>
                    <abbr expan="Street">St.</abbr> and a nice looking building. The
                    <unclear>vestry</unclear> is about the size of ours altogether but there is a
                    partition through the <orig reg="center">centre</orig> which makes two rooms for
                    the different departments of the School. The infant school is <orig
                        reg="upstairs">up stairs</orig>
                    <orig reg="where">whare</orig> the meetings <orig reg="are">ar</orig> held, The
                        <orig reg="room">roome</orig> that I was in was very nicely furnished with
                    pews &amp; I which was much more convenient than ours. The services were
                    nearly the same as I had been used to. Opened with Singing &amp; Prayer.
                    Closed with singing. I have not been to a Sabbath <abbr expan="School">S</abbr>
                    before since leaving home, It was at the <hi rend="underline">German Reform
                        Church</hi> I was conducted to a seat with a class of young men and had the
                    chance of<pb n="3"/> hearing this explanation of the Chapter that contained the
                    lesson. it did not differ from our version of the same texts.</p>

                <p>Some young ladies have come to the Hospital to sing for the entertainment of the
                    wounded inmates and while I am writing are performing in the hall, there is no
                        <orig reg="bass">base</orig> and it <orig reg="does">dose</orig> not
                    interest me much <orig reg="although">althoug</orig> they are very good singers,
                    Common tunes do not sound very well without the <orig reg="bass">base</orig> it
                    is different with a <orig reg="duet">duett</orig>.</p>

                <p>My hand is getting a little better, I think and will be well in a few weeks.</p>

                <p>Do you hear <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from <abbr expan="Benjamin"
                        >Benj</abbr> or John I have heard nothing in particular <orig reg="since"
                        >sence</orig> being here-- I had a few <orig reg="spare">spair</orig>
                    <orig reg="minutes">minuits</orig> yesterday and I went into a <hi
                        rend="underline">paper mill</hi>. it was <orig reg="where">whare</orig> they
                    made <del hand="h1">this</del> straw paper and it was a very curious <orig
                        reg="operation">opperation</orig>. the straw is first ground then mixed with
                    water and some other substance<pb n="4"/> and taken by <orig reg="machinery"
                        >machinary</orig> from the trough and <orig reg="run">rund</orig> between
                        <orig reg="rollers">rollars</orig> in thin sheets to press the water out. It
                    is then cut in <del hand="h1">sheets</del> squares about 22 x 30 and put up to
                    dry. The building was about one hundred feet long by sixty wide and four stories
                        <orig reg="high">heigh</orig> including the basement. the basement was used
                    for manufacturing the article the other three stories for drying it---- This is
                    the most quiet town I was ever in. there is nothing going on in <orig
                        reg="daytime">day time</orig> or evening excepting Church going other then
                    the <orig reg="ordinary">ordinery</orig> business of the week but it makes
                    little difference with me for I should not be the wiser for them.</p>

                <p>I <orig reg="cannot">canot</orig> write more this time. I hope to hear from you
                    in due time. Tell me all the news that you can think of---- Enclosed you will
                    find a little piece of change do with it as you think best only make a good use
                    of it.---I was thinking yesterday how you &amp; Ellen got along with your
                        <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, will you tell me when you write?--- - Remember me to all
                    the rest at home-- It is a very warm and pleasant day I hope it will continue so
                    for weeks yet to come. What is Williams Witherber &amp; Charley W. and the
                    Loring boy that were in the band doing these times-</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>yours From your </salute>
                    <signed>Father L</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
