<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6082"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F6082">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Benjamin S. Schneck to Margaretta
                    S. Keller, October 13, 1862</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin s schneck to margaretta s keller, october 13 1862</title>
        <author>Schneck, Benjamin S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F6082</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501625</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Benjamin S. Schneck to Margaretta S. Keller, October
                            13, 1862</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin s schneck to margaretta s keller, october 13 1862</title>
            <author>Benjamin S. Schneck</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Benjamin S. Schneck Papers,
                            Vertical File #77, Kittochtinny Historical Society, Chambersburg,
                            Pennsylvania</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinny Historical Society, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1862-10-13">1862-10-13</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Battle Description, Troop Movement, Home Front, Military Authority</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F6082T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Schneck writes his sister about a Confederate raid on their horses and supply
                    depot, as well as a false alarm that almost sent many civilians up in arms
                    agains their own Union forces.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
               

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1862-10-13">Oct. 13 1862</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sister --</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>To make you feel easy by exaggerated rumors which you will no doubt obtain of the
                    Cavalry Raid here on last Friday evening, I will merely say, that we are all
                    safe + feel like thanking God, that God deemed to have kept the hearts of these
                    1600 men in check not to eke out their vengeance, as one might have expected,
                    upon us. Such a surprise + such humiliation! We were helpless, and I am only
                    glad it was not possible even, for our Home Guard to be in readiness to meet
                    them, for they might have been fired on, and then their cannon, planted on the
                    hills above town, would doubtless have laid the place in ashes and no resistance
                    could, after all, have been effectively made. They brought two Batteries to town
                    + an officer called at the bank asking for money. But the cashier had slipped
                    all his notes into a Carpet Bag + sent it away an hour before, and the specie
                    had been sent to New York when Jackson threatened to invade us. The officer
                    might have threatened to burn down the house, + thus forced the cash from the
                    cashier, but after chatting for three hours, he complimented him on the
                    expertness of his financial abilities and politely bade him goodnight. -- They
                    had ransacked most of the stables, but broke none open, but asked to <hi
                        rend="underline">buy</hi> horses -- of course with <abbr expan="Confederate"
                        >Confed</abbr> money, and then took them. Many had their horses sent out of
                    town, and then lost them. Sometimes I left mine in the stable. She was not
                    called for; indeed, not one of the six ministers who have horses lost theirs.
                    Whether this was accidental or regard for our profession, I do not know.</p>

                <p>But I must close. I suppose our Synod will prove a failure, although our danger
                    is now over, for the Rebels are mostly safe in Virginia again, although our town
                    was all on fire with excitement today from rumors that a squad of <pb n="2"/>
                    them were -- first only two miles from town on their return -- then at
                    Fayetteville, (6 mi. from here) then over the mountains near Gettysburg, having,
                    it was said, been driven back by some of our forces at Emmetsburg. The stores
                    were all closed, every musket in use, and hundreds went out to <hi
                        rend="underline">meet the Rebels</hi>! We were all very brave, but alas! Our
                    bravery was not permitted to be put into requisition. This evening our men
                    returned <unclear>chopfallen</unclear>. The troops sent from Baltimore to
                    Gettysburg had come out of the mountain + the people mistook <hi
                        rend="underline">them</hi> for Rebels, + the Colonel tried to tell them who
                    he was, but they fled up the mountain and so the contagation spread until it
                    reached us. We can now laugh at the useless expenditure of Bravery, but the
                    Rebel cavalry will laugh the more heartily at their dashing, bold, successful
                    raid. They got probably 800 horses, plenty of our army clothing at the Depot,
                    sabres, pistols <orig reg="etc.">+c</orig> as much as they wanted, + are now <hi
                        rend="underline">nearly</hi> all at least, safe in Virginia. One must give
                    credit for two things: Gentlemanly conduct in their intercourse with our people,
                    and intrepidity and boldness. They had several men with them, formerly from this
                    county, hence they knew every nook + corner.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>In great haste, Your affect. Brother</salute>
                    <signed>B. S. Schneck</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">Please tell Mr. <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>, I wrote to Mr.
                        Dorworth. I did not understand from his first letter that he wished me to
                        send an order to Mr. D -- but merely to appraise me of the fact that Mr. D.
                        was to have it at some future time + that appreciation was to then be made
                        for it.</seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
