<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6084"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F6084">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Benjamin S. Schneck to Margaretta
                    S. Keller and her husband, August 3, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin s schneck to margaretta s keller and her husband, august 3 1864</title>
        <author>Schneck, Benjamin S.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F6084</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501627</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Benjamin S. Schneck to Margaretta S. Keller and her
                            husband, August 3, 1864</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin s schneck to margaretta s keller and her husband, august 3 1864</title>
            <author>Benjamin S. Schneck</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Benjamin S. Schneck Papers,
                            Vertical File #77, Kittochtinny Historical Society, Chambersburg,
                            Pennsylvania</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Kittochtinny Historical Society, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-08-03">1864-08-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Family, Home Front, State Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-01">January 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F6084T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Schneck's letter describes the Confederate invasion and burning of Chambersburg
                    of late-July 1864.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
              

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-08-03">Aug. 3 1864</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My dear Sister + Brother -</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>We are all safe, though homeless and with only some clothing left. Our stable is
                    unharmed. We saved by far the smallest part of our clothing -- I have a borrowed
                    shirt, one straw hat, + so-on. My Library, even my Papers + Manuscripts (except
                    my Deeds) all -- all gone. The good prospect I had for one hour: of saving our
                    house, kept us from saving furniture and clothing. Help there was none. I was on
                    the roof, Rebecca + the girl carrying water up 3 steps, for everybody had enough
                    to do for themselves for the firing began in different parts of town at one
                    time. Some houses in each square were fired, and then the others caught. In some
                    cases, money was offered to be taken (in out-of-the-way parts) by the men + the
                    properties then saved. Except one house (the Misses Dennys 8 doors above (and
                    where we are now), every house down on both sides for 7 Squares, is gone. So
                    with Main Street for nearly 1/2 mile, Queen Street, part of Washington, etc, Our
                        <unclear>Print</unclear>
                    <abbr expan="Establishment">Establ</abbr>, <hi rend="underline">with all</hi>
                    (except the stereotype plates + <abbr expan="Account">Acct.</abbr> Books) is in
                    ruins. The Bank, <hi rend="underline">all</hi> the stores, <hi rend="underline"
                        >all</hi> the hotels, every shoe, clothing, and other stores (except in the
                    outskirts some <pb n="2"/> small grocery etc. shops) are all consumed. In <hi
                        rend="underline">most</hi> instances, little -- in very many, <hi
                        rend="underline">nothing</hi> -- was saved, not even a single change of
                    clothing. But blessed be God, there are those who were spared, + their hearts +
                    houses are open to the rest. Help in the way of provisions + clothing is coming
                    in. None need to starve. But such a scene of Ruin! No imagination can conceive
                    it. <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Curtin came up last evening and said to
                    me: "The reality is fearfully beyond all my conceptions." He requested us to try
                    + keep the people in heart, for many have left, + more do not know what to do
                    here now. We have a little house out of town on one of my lots. The one half
                    will be vacant soon + I suppose we will go in it -- it has two little rooms
                    below + two in the attic for small bedrooms -- it is cottage style, 1 1/2
                    stories high. Further, I cannot say. But for the present, we must + will stay
                    here.</p>

                <p>I am hardly able to write. I thought I would write to you + the girls would be so
                    good as to write for me to sister Sophia, Mary, Louisa + the rest. To Benj<hi
                        rend="super">n</hi> I have just written. God bless you all, my dear ones.
                    Rebecca has kept up well. If only we are preserved from future invasions. But
                    this morning, there was news, that the <pb n="3"/>enemy is at Williamsport +
                    along the Potomac. Our force was repulsed there on Sunday. Petersburg has been
                    recaptured by them, so far as it was lost. It looks dark for our country.</p>

                <p>Some of the rebel officers + men that were here did not expect this vandalism, +
                    they showed a good spirit -- they did + would not fire any building + even
                    helped people to carry out things out of their houses. They denounced the whole
                    procedure as outrageous and wicked.</p>

                <p>But I can no more.<lb/> The Lord be with you all.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your Affectionate Brother + Uncle</salute>
                    <signed>B. S. Schneck</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
