<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6504"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6504">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Mary Polly, February 20,
     1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to mary polly, february 20 1863</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6504</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501632</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Mary Polly, February 20, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to mary polly, february 20 1863</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-02-20">1863-02-20</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6504T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to Mary Polly, Eliza Stouffer relates her views on religion and her sincere
     wish that Mary Polly share her views.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
 

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-02-20">February 20th 1863</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg, Pa.</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My dear friend Mary Polly</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>wishing unto you, the abundant grace of God, that he may strengthen and enlighten you still
     more and more according to your need, For he knows our wants, and has promised in his word that
     he will not cast off those that come unto him with an upright heart,</p>

    <p>I was much rejoiced when I received the letter, and found it was from you, we had not heard
      <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> from you for a long time, I often times wished myself in
     your company a while, Jacob and I had made up our minds if there would be sleighing roads we
     would go down to see you, but that time did not come, so we have concluded now to wait, <orig
      reg="until">untill</orig> the roads and weather gets better, I am rejoiced to hear through
     your letter, that you have not laid aside yet this one thing needful, and are desiring to Know
     the truth, and learn of Christ, For he says come unto me all ye that <orig reg="labor"
     >labour</orig>, and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest, and learn of me, for I am meek
     and lowly in heart, These are very encouraging words for a poor distressed soul, and much more,
     he says that he will draw nigh unto them, that draw nigh unto him, Oh what encouragement to
     all, we may be where we will, he is no respecter of person, all that live righteously are
     accepted, he has also promised that he will send us his spirit, and that shall lead us into all
     truth, is this not a comfort, that he will not leave us in the dark, but will teach us the way
     that he would have us go, but we must forsake our own will, make ourselves loose from every
     thing that is a hinderance to us in this pilgrimage here, for the time will come when we must
     leave all, and give an account of our stewardship here, let us try to make <pb n="2"/>good use
     of the talent that is given us, for we have to render an account of the same, and I would
     advise you dear friend, not to get weary in well doing, for I believe if the Lord has given you
     more light, there will be more required of you, do not get discouraged if you are opposed in
     your views of the scriptures, but search deep, and pray to God, for an enlightened spirit. you
     may be the means to bring others to more light For I think there is no danger, that we can be
     too careful on this point, for the way is <orig reg="described">discribed</orig> as a narrow
     one, and that many shall strive and not be able to enter in. Is not this enough to make us
     uneasy, for fear we might be found wanting, and live too light minded and careless, we should
     not rest <orig reg="until">untill</orig> we have found peace &amp; <orig reg="favor"
     >favour</orig> with God.</p>

    <p>I think I can feel for you, when I first began to get uneasy and think over these things more
     seriously and searched the scriptures, I soon found that I never lived up to the scriptures,
     and what is required of me. I had no rest. I spoke of it to my friends, they said, why if I
     believe thus, I condemn all my <orig reg="forefathers">fore fathers</orig>, I had to tell them,
     I believe the scriptures requires this and I must have them were they are, and try to obey the
     word of God, for it will be that word, that will Judge me at the last day, and if we let
     ourselves be Judged by the word, we will not come into Judgment. The word requires much of us,
     not alone going to church, or be a member of a church to receive baptism and the Lords supper.
     There are many other commands, that are so explicitly commanded, namely to love our enemies do
     good to those that hate us, and have peace with all men if possible</p>

    <p>Christ commanded many things that we cannot do, without having christs spirit, and if we have
     his spirit, he will teach us how we ought to live. we might be striving all the days of our
     lives about the mode of baptism, and forget the most <orig reg="important">impertant</orig>
     part of his teaching he tells us many things, which I Know you have often read, namely <pb
      n="3"/>to come out of the world, and separate ourselves from all <orig reg="ungodliness"
      >ungodlyness</orig> to live sober and <orig reg="righteously">rightiously</orig> in this
     present world, these few words are full of meaning. if we obey the same, take no part in <orig
      reg="unrighteousness">unrightousness</orig> but rather reprove them, and let our words that
     are yea, be yea, and nay, be nay, and in our whole walk and conduct, show, that we are born of
     God, and try to walk, as he walked, and follow the example he has set, This is worth striving
     for, And this is the guide, that he has given, which should be strictly observed, much more,
     than the mode of water baptism, that is only done once, but this is a daily work. <orig
      reg="everyday">every day</orig> we must try to bury this old Adam, and rise with Christ in
     newness of life, This takes a daily striving, for our nature is <orig reg="corrupt"
     >currupt</orig> and in our flesh, there is nothing good, and then we can only understand the
     Apostle Paul, when he says, in the flesh, there is nothing good, When I would do good, evil, is
     present, we learn to Know, that we cannot do it of ourselves, and that we have need of a
     saviour, and mediator, to intercede for us, and it is only then, that we can give God the <orig
      reg="honor">honour</orig>, and not take it to ourselves. Knowing that we cannot of ourselves,
     think a good thought, much less perform a good deed.</p>

    <p>With this will draw to a close, and commit you, to God and his protection, he Knows our
     wants, and will not turn a deaf ear unto them that <orig reg="diligently">deligenly</orig> seek
     him write soon again if you feel so. I could read your letter very well, and was very good, for
     so little as you say you write.</p>

    <pb n="4"/>

    <p>If you see Rebeckah Johnston, tell her that I often think of her too, and would be very glad
     to receive a letter from her too, and hear how she is getting along still,</p>

    <p>Let us all try to prepare, while we have yet time and <orig reg="opportunity"
     >oppertunity</orig>, for none of us Know, how long we may yet be permitted to be in the land of
     the living,</p>

    <p>I wish you could be here, again sunday we have meeting in the school house close by us. It is
     there every four weeks and also every four at the meeting house that makes every two weeks at
     one of the places </p>

    <closer>
     <salute>so with this will close, and remain your sincere friend and well wisher</salute>
     <signed>Eliza Stouffer</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">
      <name type="recipient">Mary Polly</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
