<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6505"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6505">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Jacob Stouffer to His Brother and Sister, March
     9, 1863</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county jacob stouffer to his brother and sister, march 9 1863</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Jacob</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6505</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501633</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Jacob Stouffer to His Brother and Sister, March 9, 1863</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county jacob stouffer to his brother and sister, march 9 1863</title>
            <author>Jacob Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1863-03-09">1863-03-09</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Agriculture, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Medicine/Hospitals</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6505T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter Jacob Stouffer discusses the health of family members and the upcoming sale of
     several neighbors' properties.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
   

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1863-03-09">March 9/63</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Beloved Brother &amp; Sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I Seat myself to write you a few lines for Satisfaction we received your letter of the 6<hi
      rend="super">th</hi> this evening and were pleased to hear from you-hope you may be all
     restored to health again-we too have been afflicted Some little Since you left us-Eliza had a
     bad cold with <orig reg="tightening">tighting</orig> in her breast-but is over it again-Emma
     has the mumps-is not much Sick- Amos complains this <orig reg="evening">evenig</orig>-is Sick
     on the Stomach-and pain in his Side-we do not know yet what it will be-Daniels are not So
     well-Daniel, David, <orig reg="Fannie">Fany</orig> Fry and H. Ryder's girl have the mumps and
     their little <orig reg="Johnny">Johny</orig> is also <orig reg="feverish">feeverish</orig> and
     Sick-Mary Cosgrove is <orig reg="perhaps">perhapse</orig> a little better-, Leah is also
     better-is able to go about again-the <orig reg="neighbors">neighbours</orig> and friends are
     generally well. Neither Immels, nor Eberlys have been here to <orig reg="inquire"
     >enquire</orig> for anything,-there will be offered at public Sale on <pb n="2"/>Friday March
      20<hi rend="super">th</hi> two Small properties in our <orig reg="neighborhood"
     >neighbourhood</orig>-that of P. Laufmen <abbr expan="Deceased">De<hi rend="super">c'd</hi>
     </abbr> and that of Littles, the first you are acquainted with-the other near the Alms house-is
     on the road from the pike to that institution-between John Bowmans and Mary Leydigs-Littles lot
     has an old log dwelling-a Small Stable and a new brick house not long finished-both are to be
     Sold on the afternoon of the 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>
     <abbr expan="instant">inst</abbr> -If you have a desire for any of them and could come and See
     them beforehand would be the most Satisfaction-or If you prefer it I will do what you may
     desire in the matter-the Laufman lot is far the most deSirable-and I fear will bring a big
     price. I learn there are a number waiting for it-I have heard nine to eleven hundred dollars
     Spoken of as a price for it-which is high for about 1 1/2 acres of rather poor land with <orig
      reg="very">verry</orig> poor buildings on it-how the feeling will run when it is up <pb n="3"
     />is hard to Say-the other property is too near the poor house for most people and does not
     border on the pike-I learn they want $1400 for it-If you have a desire for either and could
     come up to See them would be the most Satisfactory-having given you what is on my mind I will
     close wishing you the abundant Grace of God and the <orig reg="guidance">guideance</orig> and
     assistance of his holy Spirit to lead and direct you through this vale of troubles So that we
     may all meet and enjoy that rest which is in Store for those who love his <orig reg="appearing"
      >appearin</orig></p>

    <closer>
     <salute>From your friend and weak brother in the faith</salute>
     <signed>
      <hi rend="underline">Jacob Stouffer</hi>
     </signed>
     <seg type="postscript">Catharine Ryder and Adam come here Saturday-they were all well at
      Loudon-Adam went home yesterday after the meeting-he took a <orig reg="young">yound</orig> man
      along up-who came from mt. joy by the Cares and is going to live with him a while Catherine is
      here-intends to Stay part of this week.<pb n="4"/> Tuesday morning<lb/><lb/> Dear brother
      &amp; sister<lb/><lb/> I will yet add &amp; say. Amos came from the mill yesterday
      evening after dark, had a severe chill pain in the side, throw up several times we send for
      the D<hi rend="super">r</hi> He pronounced it Billious plurisy.<lb/><lb/> gave him powders
      applied mustard plaster to his side he was very sick all night still threw up. feels a little
      easier now<lb/><lb/> we will let you hear again should it not get better </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
