<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6500"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="F6500">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Anna Hoover, December 20,
     1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to anna hoover, december 20 1861</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Eliza R.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, Pennsylvania</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6500</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501628</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Eliza R. Stouffer to Anna Hoover, December 20, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county eliza r stouffer to anna hoover, december 20 1861</title>
            <author>Eliza R. Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>2 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, Pennsylvania, for bringing this
        letter to our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1861-12-20">1861-12-20</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6500T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter, Eliza R. Stouffer discusses a possible visit with Anna Hoover and recounts a
     recent conversation with Mr. and Mrs. Brechbill. In the postscript, Eliza includes a note for
     N. Hoover copying a letter from S. K. Snively to Jacob Stouffer. Snively expresses his
     gratitude that God has spared his life and vows to leave his sinful ways if he survives the
     war.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
    

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1861-12-20">December 20 1861</date>
      <name type="place">Chambersburg, <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pa.</abbr></name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>Dear sister</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>as I am writing to sister Catharine will drop you a few lines for your satisfaction we are
     all well. hope you are the same I would like to write you a long letter but have hardly time
     now, I would like to pay you a visit soon but I often do not feel well and feel best at home.
     my mind is often with you some three weeks ago perhaps longer, Brechbill was here said they had
     written to you <abbr expan="received">rec<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> no answer thought
     perhaps you had send something here for his wife brought one supporter here said she had Kept
     the first one found she could make it fit by altering it a little, said she was some better,
     wished to have some more drops, suppose you have heard from her ere this</p>

    <p>I will send the supporter down the first good <orig reg="opportunity">oppertuny</orig>
     perhaps you will be up soon</p>

    <p>My love to you and Brother George</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>Remember us in your prayers</salute>
     <signed><abbr expan="Eliza">E</abbr> Stouffer</signed>
     <seg type="postscript">please hand this over to N Hoover<lb/> Eliza Stouffer for Bregbiles<lb/>
      N Hoover<lb/><lb/> As this sheet is blank, I will tell you that Jacob <abbr expan="received"
        >re<hi rend="super">d</hi></abbr> a letter from S K Snively on 30th Nov. Benjamin wrote to
      him, then Jacob wrote a few lines and laid it in his letter he writes with great pleasure, did
      I read those lines you sent in Bs letter. I must feel very <orig reg="thankful"
      >thankfull</orig> that the Lord is so very merciful that he has spared my life to this present
      time. While many of my fellow soldiers and comrades, are every day hurried to a long and
      unending eternity I had to feel so in particular when those two men were struck with
      lightening near my tent. I had to feel that easily it might have been my lot, and what would
      have been the <orig reg="consequence">consequenc</orig>. I would have <abbr expan="received"
        >rec<hi rend="super">ed</hi></abbr> a fatal and <orig reg="irrevocable">irrivocable</orig>
      doom, Friend Jacob. I must often reflect of times past, How Satan led me from the narrow path
      to the broad and sinful <del hand="h1">way</del> one again and how happy and contented I was
      when I embraced religion, and now how miserable and <orig reg="wretched">reched</orig> I often
      now feel If it ever should be my luck to get home again I will give myself up to the Lord and
      try and serve him <del hand="h1">the remainder</del> faithfully the <orig reg="balance"
       >ballance</orig> of my days<lb/><lb/> These are his own words I thought perhaps you would
      like to hear from him <name type="recipient">N Hoover</name>
     </seg>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
