<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F6510"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="F6510">
 <teiHeader type="migrated">

    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Benjamin Stouffer to Emma V. Stouffer, April
     16, [1865]</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin stouffer to emma v stouffer, april 16 1865</title>
        <author>Stouffer, Benjamin</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
          <name>Edsel Burdge, Jr., Shippensburg, PA</name>
          <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
          <name>Jaime Henshaw</name>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

        <idno type="VCDH">F6510</idno>

        <!--
    <availability>
     <p>Publicly accessible </p>
     <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
     <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2001, by the Rector and Visitors of the University of
     Virginia</p>
    </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2001 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
        <date value="2001">2001</date>
        <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501638</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
      </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note/>
      </notesStmt>

      <sourceDesc>
        <biblFull>
          <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Benjamin Stouffer to Emma V. Stouffer, April 16, [1865]</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county benjamin stouffer to emma v stouffer, april 16 1865</title>
            <author>Benjamin Stouffer</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
              <resp/>
              <name/>
            </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
            <p/>
          </editionStmt>
          <extent>4 pages</extent>
          <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace/>
            <date value=""/>
            <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: From the private collection of Margaret Binkley
       DuVernet. Photocopies courtesy of the Reformed Mennonite Collection, Mennonite Historical
       Association of the Cumberland Valley, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania.</idno>
          </publicationStmt>
          <seriesStmt>
            <p/>
          </seriesStmt>
          <notesStmt>
            <note>
              <p>We would like to thank Edsel Burdge, Jr. of Shippensburg, PA, for bringing this letter to
        our attention and for sharing with us his transcription.</p>
            </note>
          </notesStmt>
        </biblFull>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from private collection</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date value="1865-04-16">1865-04-16</date>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <handList>
        <hand id="h1"/>
      </handList>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>Family, Home Front, Death/Casualties, National Government</term>
          <term>American Civil War</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>

    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date value=""> </date>
        <respStmt>
          <resp/>
          <name/>
        </respStmt>
        <item/>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
 </teiHeader>

 <text id="F6510T">
  <front id="d2">
   <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
    <p>In this letter to his family, Benjamin Stouffer discusses Lincoln's assassination and the
     subsequent reaction from the public in Poughkeepsie, New York.</p>
   </div1>
  </front>

  <body id="d4">
   <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
 

    <opener>
     <dateline>
      <date value="1865-04-16">16th April</date>
      <name type="place"><orig reg="Poughkeepsie">Pokeepsie</orig> NY</name>
     </dateline>
     <salute>My Dear Parents and Family</salute>
    </opener>

    <p>I now seat myself to answer Emmas very kind and welcome letter which I <abbr expan="received"
      >recd</abbr> yesterday. and as usual was very glad to hear from you. Oh, what sad news we have
     had of late. I suppose there is great excitement about it at home Here <orig reg="every"
     >evry</orig> one that is loyal wears a black and white badge and streets are all hung with
     crape flags are flying at half mast a <orig reg="trimmed">trimed</orig> with black. I never
     heard <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> that shocked me so much. some of the boys awoke me
     up early on <orig reg="Saturday">Saturdy</orig> morning and told me <hi rend="underline"
      >Lincoln had been shot</hi>. I scarcely knew what to do. <orig reg="Every">Evy</orig> one
     looked down and were sad the town was just<pb n="2"/> as Sunday. Our teachers told us to go
     home that <orig reg="they">thy</orig> could not teach school and about nine oclock all the
     bells in the city were tolled. speaking to plainly to sorrowful voice of our people. How true
     all flesh is as grass <orig reg="etc.">&amp;c</orig>. this passage of scripture came to my
     mind very often the past two day this evening I was to the congregational church had a good
     sermon, upon the uncertainty of life. But why should we mourn Lincoln was only a man and his
     time had come his God was ready to give him, and we must all follow. My dear Sisters only prove
     steadfast and hold out for we know not at what hour the son of man cometh. I know full well I
     am not competant to give you <orig reg="advice">advise</orig> but I know you often wonder how I
     feel toward you since you <unclear>chan</unclear>. I do<del hand="h1">n</del> not see and
     cannot feel to follow you know, but as a brother<pb n="3"/> I can only wish you well. You need
     not fear for me while here I have no temptations to do <orig reg="evil">evill</orig> other than
     when at home. I do not know any new that I think would interest you. this evening it is
     reported here that Booth has been caught and the Sewards are yet living. <orig reg="today">to
      day</orig> I was out in the county and collected some wild flowers, the first bloom of spring.
     I am getting along pretty well. I work pretty hard <orig reg="every">evy</orig> evening <orig
      reg="until">untill</orig> pretty late, but I feel very stout and a great deal better than when
     George left. I should like to correspond with SK Snively if you hear his adress "ie" his <abbr
      expan="Brigade">Brig</abbr>
     <abbr expan="Division">Div</abbr> and Corps let me know it. Abners little one has a hard time
     how much better off it would be if it could leave this world. I suppose the drafted boys feel
     pretty easy now since the late order from <orig reg="Staunton">Stanton</orig><pb n="4"/> I
     suppose Rush Senseny had a great party when he came home.<lb/> I am very glad to hear that
     Jennie has a colt I hope they can take good care of her. The lines you wrote me are very
     applicable and I often play some of the old songs we used to sing upon my flute for the boys
     here, and how attentive <orig reg="they">thy</orig> are <orig reg="they">thy</orig> to have
     friends at home and often sigh do they think of me at home. I must now conclude as it is very
     late give my love to the family and remember me to the enquiring friends tell Ella to be a good
     girl <orig reg="until">untill</orig> I come home. I suppose Uncle Hoovers will not feel very
     well at home if they go on <unclear>building</unclear> directly.</p>

    <closer>
     <salute>So good night to you all and I remain very truly yours absent Bro</salute>
     <signed>Ben</signed>
    </closer>
   </div1>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI.2>
