<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8035"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8035">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron,
                    January 5, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county i h mccauley to simon cameron, january 5 1861</title>
        <author>McCauley, I. H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8035</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501673</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron, January 5, 1861</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county i h mccauley to simon cameron, january 5 1861</title>
            <author>I. H. McCauley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron,
                            5 January 1861, Simon Cameron Papers, Dauphin County Historical Society,
                            Reel 6</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Historical Society of Dauphin County, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-01-05">1861-01-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>National Government, State Government, Economy</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8035T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McCauley congratulates Cameron on his appointment to Lincoln's cabinet, condemns
                    Alexander K. McClure, and seeks an appointment under Cameron.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <hi rend="underline">McCauley</hi><lb/>Clerkship<lb/><abbr expan="January"
                        >Jan</abbr> 1861
                    <name type="place">Chambersburg <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penna</abbr></name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-01-05">January 5" 1861</date>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> Simon Cameron</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>The papers of the day inform us that the President Elect has tendered to you a
                    position in his Cabinet, and that you have accepted. Permit me as one of your
                    many friends in this County, to offer my congratulations. We are not only
                    gratified because of your <hi rend="underline">personal</hi> success, but
                    because we hail the Act of the President as indicative of his policy in relation
                    to Pennsylvania's great interests, With you in the Cabinet we will feel certain
                    that all things possible will be done to foster and protect our suffering
                    manufacturing and industrial interests.</p>
                <p>The same papers which informed us of your appointment, stated that the Ajax of
                        <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Penna</abbr> politics, <abbr expan="Honorable"
                        >Hon</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Alexander ">A.</abbr>K. McClure of this place had been "called" to
                    Springfield by the President. Public rumor, and his fellow members say that he
                    "asked permission" to go. Now the fact is we know not--but his <hi
                        rend="underline">object</hi> we do know for he cannot keep his own counsil.
                    We are convinced that his purpose is to oppose you. We think that he should
                        have<pb n="2"/>had <hi rend="underline">enough</hi> of that by this time,
                    but some persons are so much puffed up with their own ideas of their own
                    importance, that they cannot see themselves as others see them. The <abbr
                        expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> thinks because he was Chairman of the last State
                    Committee, &amp; the party were successful that <hi rend="underline"
                    >all</hi> is owing to him and his <hi rend="underline">Herculian</hi>
                    ascertions. Why the veriest simpleton that lived last <abbr expan="October"
                    >Oct</abbr> &amp; <abbr expan="November">Nov</abbr>, must have been
                    convinced that Success would be ours had the indefatigable Chairman never lived.
                    Public Dinners and Gold Watches given by never so many expectants for Office,
                    will never elevate him any higher. We think here that he has reached the
                    top-most point on the ladder of Fame to which he was even destined to ascend.
                    The "Suspicions" of the "Valley Spirit" published in 1859 hang like a Mill Stone
                    around his neck--and the additional fact that after <unclear>indicting</unclear>
                    for <hi rend="underline">one and a half</hi> of them, he has now had <hi
                        rend="underline">Noble <unclear>Prosegrun's</unclear></hi> entered, can
                    never be gotten over by him.</p>
                <p>We therefore <hi rend="underline">rejoice</hi> over his defeat, for we cannot
                    think that President Lincoln will give any weight to his representations,
                    especially if he <hi rend="underline">knows</hi> the man. He is supremely
                    selfish, and where he cannot <hi rend="underline">rule</hi>, will <hi
                        rend="underline">ruin</hi>. In you he has found <hi rend="underline"
                    >more</hi> than his match. You<pb n="3"/>have your foot upon his neck--<hi
                        rend="underline">keep it there</hi>, and the number of your friends will
                    never decrease.</p>
                <p>Mark my prediction. If the Republican &amp; <orig reg="People's"
                    >Peoples</orig> party of Pennsylvania should soon again loose its present proud
                    &amp; triumphant position, <hi rend="underline">the result will be owing to
                        the conduct of him &amp; his "clique"</hi>, <hi rend="underline"
                    >more</hi> than to anything else.</p>
                <p>And now General permit me to say a word <hi rend="underline">personal</hi> to
                    myself. You have the reputation of <hi rend="underline">not forgetting your
                        friends</hi>. I claim to have been one of them in this County. Tis true that
                    I was not able to aid you much, and would have been greatly pleased to have seen
                    you nominated. You will recollect that I was at your house in Harrisburg whilst
                    our State Convention was in Session last Spring, and ready and willing to go to
                    Chicago to serve you, but the <abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr> controlled
                    matters so as to send his own partner Mr McLellan, who never once voted for you.</p>
                <p>When in power I wish you to remember this concerning the Republic. I shall then
                    ask you for some <hi rend="underline">good position</hi> in your own
                    Department--or your aid in obtaining one somewhere else. You will remember that
                    I was the Chief Clerk of the State Department of this State under <abbr
                        expan="Governor">Gov</abbr> Pollock &amp; to him I will then fully refer
                    you for <hi rend="underline">Character &amp; qualifications</hi>.<pb n="4"
                    />I am one of those who never drink, gamble, frolick or swear, and who think
                    that duty to God and our Country can be performed together. I think myself
                    qualified for any position to which I may aspire, and always make it the object
                    of my life to do promptly and faithfully whatever I undertake.</p>
                <p>I should like to get a Chief Clerkship in one of the Departments at
                    Washington--or some other position that would yield me a couple of thousand
                    dollars per year. One of the Assistant Collectorships or Deputy Naval Officer,
                    at Philadelphia, would suit me, and as those are connected with the Treasury
                    Department, perhaps when the times comes you will be able and disposed to aid me
                    in obtaining one of them, or some other position such as I seek, I trust that
                    you will do so, and whatever you may do will be <hi rend="underline">gratefully
                        remembered</hi>.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>I am<lb/>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>I.H.McCauley</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> Simon
                            Cameron<lb/>Washington City D. C.</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
