<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8036"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8036">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron,
                    July 20, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county i h mccauley to simon cameron, july 20 1859</title>
        <author>McCauley, I. H.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name/>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Andrew J. Torget</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8036</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501674</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron, July 20, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county i h mccauley to simon cameron, july 20 1859</title>
            <author>I. H. McCauley</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: I. H. McCauley to Simon Cameron,
                            20 July 1859, Simon Cameron Papers, Dauphin County Historical Society,
                            Reel 4</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note>
                            <p>Note at the top of the letter: "<hi rend="underline">Confidential</hi>"</p>
                        </note>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Historical Society of Dauphin County, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-07-20">1859-07-20</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>State Government, National Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value=""/>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name/>
                </respStmt>
                <item/>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8036T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>McCauley writes Cameron confidentially, seeking help in defeating Alexander K.
                    McClure's bid for the State Senate nomination.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>I. H. MCCAULEY,<lb/>ATTORNEY AT LAW<lb/>Chambersburg, Pa.,<lb/>Will attend
                    promptly to all<lb/>business entrusted to his care.<lb/>OFFICE AND
                    RESIDENCE<lb/>On East Market Street, near<lb/>the Court House<lb/>"Independent,"
                    Print. <name type="recipient"/>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-07-20">July 20/<abbr expan="1859">59</abbr></date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><abbr expan="Dear">Dr</abbr> Sir</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>You are no doubt aware that Franklin County is the present home of one of the <hi
                        rend="underline">great</hi> and <hi rend="underline">good</hi> men of the
                        Nation--<abbr expan="Colonel">Col.</abbr>
                    <abbr expan="Alexander">A.</abbr> K. McClure by name. I have every reason to
                    believe that you <hi rend="underline">know</hi> this <hi rend="underline">extra
                        honest</hi> individual, who stands a "head and shoulders" taller than his
                    fellows, equally as well as I do, and that you <hi rend="underline">like</hi>
                    him no better.</p>
                <p>I do not suppose however that you have been deceived as to his real popularity.
                    You hardly believe the story about offices being <hi rend="underline"
                    >forced</hi> upon him. That's <hi rend="underline">his</hi> way of talking. We
                        <hi rend="underline">know</hi> the <hi rend="underline">facts</hi> better.</p>
                <p>That he has been in the Legislature two Sessions you know. <hi rend="underline"
                        >What</hi> he did--<hi rend="underline">how</hi> he did it--and <hi
                        rend="underline">for what</hi> he did it, you know better than I. He now
                    aspires to a seat in the State Senate. He <hi rend="underline">wanted</hi> to go
                    to Congress, but McPherson licked him. He says he <hi rend="underline">does
                    not</hi> seek the Senatorial nomination- that he has not made up his mind to
                    take it even if offered &amp;c, &amp;c. This is all <hi rend="underline"
                        >bosh</hi>, we know he does want it, and that he has been
                        <unclear>endeavoring</unclear> to create the impression that <hi
                        rend="underline">he</hi> is the<pb n="2"/>only man who can carry the
                    district. To believe what his friends say would be to believe that he posesses
                    all the <hi rend="underline">honesty</hi>--all the <hi rend="underline"
                    >capacity</hi>--all the <hi rend="underline">statesmanship</hi>, and all the <hi
                        rend="underline">availability</hi> of the District.</p>
                <p>For the real opinion entertained of him by many, even of his own party here, I
                    would refer you to the "Valley Spirit" of this week. It will
                    <unclear>repay</unclear> perusal.</p>
                <p>Now I wish to see him beaten for the nomination, I care not who by, and my object
                    in addressing you is to see if you could not aid in accomplishing this result,
                    and thus pay the <hi rend="underline">second installment</hi> upon the
                    obligations of 1855. You have many friends in Fulton &amp; Adams Counties.
                    Neither county likes him very much. He has twice sacrificed his colleagues from
                    the former County for the Legislature--and the Americans of Adams do not love a
                    bone in his body. Could you not therefore array your friends against him. I know
                    he has been trying hard to get things smoothed away for his success with the
                    Connections of both counties by getting candidates to decline, by creating the
                    impression that <hi rend="underline">he</hi> alone can carry the District
                    &amp;c.</p>
                <p>I am not a candidate for the office. I did think of being a candidate last fall
                    at the solicitation of friends in this and Adams County.<pb n="3"/>The <hi
                        rend="underline">latter</hi> county, I was assured by the best men in it, I
                    could have gotten. In Fulton I know I could have done well--whilst here, at
                    home, my chances would have been as good as any other. But I knew the district
                    to be close, and I did not seek the office. McClure then said that he would not
                    under <hi rend="underline">any circumstances</hi> be a candidate. Thus you see I
                    would have had the field almost to myself. But I did not want to be away from
                    home and my family. I had been long enough from my profession, and I preferred,
                    and am now a Candidate for <hi rend="underline">District Attorney</hi> of this
                    County. What the result may be in this Contest I know not. I know McClure is not
                    my friend, and I am not his.</p>
                <p>I have written thus freely and openly, because I feel that what I say will be
                    kept Confidential, and so shall I keep any reply that you may make.</p>
                <p>Let me hear from you as soon as your convinience or inclination may allow</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours truly</salute>
                    <signed>I,H,McCauley</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> Simon
                        Cameron</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
