<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8509"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8509">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: L. Barnitz Bacon to Edward
                    McPherson, December 19, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county l barnitz bacon to edward mcpherson, december 19 1860</title>
        <author>Bacon, L. Barnitz</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8509</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501691</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: L. Barnitz Bacon to Edward McPherson, December 19,
                            1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county l barnitz bacon to edward mcpherson, december 19 1860</title>
            <author>L. Barnitz Bacon</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: L. Barnitz Bacon to Edward
                            McPherson, 19 December 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson
                            Papers, Box 47, Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-12-19">1860-12-19</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Enlistment, Family, Home Front, National Government,
                        Patriotism</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8509T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Bacon writes to McPherson about his views of the secession crisis, stating that
                    he would much rather settle the matter through compromise than bloodshed. Bacon
                    also discusses possible cabinet appointments and is view that Pennsylvania
                    deserves to be represented in the administration.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
         

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-12-19"><abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 19 - 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">1113 Broadway, New York,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr> Edward McPherson,<lb/>Sir,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have received your letter of <abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 8, &amp;
                    the General Report of the Alumni, for which I thank you. Upon reading your first
                    letter, I conceived it to refer to something in the future, relative to which
                    you wished to obtain my subject of address. You will remember that I knew of no
                    action taken by the Alumni, as to the past, such as is set forth in your Report,
                    I therefore viewed the tenor of your first letter from a stand point different
                    from <orig reg="your's">yours</orig>, who were fully posted.</p>

                <p>My address before the Alumni occurred in the Autumn of 1851, &amp; the
                    subject was "Physical Education."</p>

                <p>I perceive that the duties of the Committee, of which you are Chairman, include a
                    report of the pursuits, positions &amp; publications of the Graduates. I
                    have never received the Circular referred to, intended to obtain the information
                    for such a report. Without wishing to volunteer such information, I may say to
                    you, that my card will inform you of my position &amp; pursuits. I have been
                    employed as an Engineer for nearly a quarter of a century, with the exception of
                    some years when my wife's health demanded a permanent residence, <pb n="2"
                    />during which I was engaged in teaching. In 1837-8, it was my fortune to
                    advance the surveys &amp; construction of the first <orig reg="railroad"
                        >Rail Road</orig> west of the Ohio River, through a new country, now covered
                    with Railways.</p>

                <p>During the twenty years of my residence in and about New York, I have also been
                    more or less connected with the press, at first as the employment of leisure
                    hours; lately as a source of <unclear>involvement</unclear>. I send you a late
                    article of mine on the "<unclear>Dead</unclear> of St. Paul's"; and also the
                    latest list of contributors to Appleton's Cyclopedia, cited by Ripley &amp;
                    Dana of the Tribune, in which you will find my name.</p>

                <p>For the rest, a man who has been engaged in a long battle against secret
                    malevolence, powerful injustice, &amp; unscrupulous Knavery, does not wish
                    to report progress, until his victory is achieved. To that time, God's own good
                    time, I look forward.</p>

                <p>And now, Sir, permit me to add a word to you, as the representative of a region
                    &amp; a people, dear to my early memories.</p>

                <p>I am not now, nor have I been for some years, affiliated with any political
                    party. I always vote, sometimes for republicans, sometimes for democrats. I
                    therefore have no party nor sectional predilections.</p>

                <p>But I pray Heaven that some means may yet be suggested to our legislators, to
                    preserve the Union of our Federation. Let us have harmony, even if it be by
                    concession. But if that cannot be, <pb n="3"/>let us at least part in peace.</p>

                <p>My oldest son is an Officer in the Navy. My youngest is with my sister-in-law in
                    the South. It may be no remote contingency which may compel them to be in arms
                    against each other. Thousands here are now agitated by the same anxiety.</p>

                <p>My sons are dear to me. My father was dear to me. He sacrificed his life for the
                    amelioration of the colored race. I would not have my sons also sacrificed in an
                    unnecessary &amp; fratricidal war.</p>

                <p>Our homes here, your home in Pennsylvania, are surrounded by hidden dangers,
                    which would desolate them in such a war. I know well, the dark hand, reaching
                    from over the sea, &amp; moving its agents both in the North &amp;
                    South. If we must fight, let us rather unite as our fathers did, and beat back
                    our enemy of old.</p>

                <p>To turn to a more hopeful theme, I perceive that both James Cooper &amp;
                    Thaddeus Stevens have been named as probable Cabinet Officers of the coming
                    Administration. I have great faith in the patriotic character of all who have
                    been nurtured in that Keystone region of the Old Thirteen, around Mason
                    &amp; Dixon's Line. It is a region rich in all the memories which give
                    strength &amp; character to that national loyalty, upon which every
                    government must find its most enduring &amp; conservative basis. <pb n="4"/>
                    And it is a region, which has never properly asserted its position in the past,
                    nor pushed forward its claims for the future. Astute &amp; persistent New
                    England, &amp; the impulsive &amp; ardent South, have shoved it aside. I
                    should like to see it represented by either one or the other of those I have
                    named, in the new administration which is to preside over, I hope, a united,
                    peaceful, &amp; prosperous Republic.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Very Respectfully Your<lb/>
                        <abbr expan="Obedient">Obdt.</abbr>
                        <abbr expan="Servant">Servt.</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>L. Barnitz Bacon</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
