<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8517"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8517">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Edward McPherson to John B.
                    McPherson, July 27, 1854</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county edward mcpherson to john b mcpherson, july 27 1854</title>
        <author>McPherson, Edward</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">9</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8517</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501699</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Edward McPherson to John B. McPherson, July 27, 1854</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county edward mcpherson to john b mcpherson, july 27 1854</title>
            <author>Edward McPherson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Edward McPherson to John B.
                            McPherson, 27 July 1854, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers,
                            Box 47, Folder 1852-1854</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1854-07-27">1854-07-27</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Family, Home Front</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8517T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Edward McPherson writes to his father of being caught in a rain storm and of the
                    accomodations of the inn.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
             

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1854-07-27">Friday, July 27<hi rend="super">th</hi> 1854</date>
                        <name type="place">Buena Vista Springs,</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Father:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>As we had a storm yesterday I feared you might be anxious to know how I managed
                    to get through it. And I did get through very well. When at the Church it first
                    came upon me.-- There being no house near I had to trip on for some time in a
                    very heavy rain at a pace no faster than a walk. After some time I came near a
                    house. I observed a barn leading up to the house from the road. Into this I
                    intended driving: but was prepared on riding to the beginning of the lane to
                    find a barn there which prohibited entrance.-- The choice was left me either to
                    press my journey or get out &amp; take down the barn. I of course chose the
                    former &amp; continued on through the storm which abated when I reached a
                    house on the road with a "little better" barn a mile from Millerstown, as the
                    man told me.-- The storm was very heavy as I suppose you in <abbr
                        expan="Gettysburg">G--g</abbr> can testify. I put up the apron as high as I
                    could, but <unclear>could</unclear> not succeed in keeping off the rain entirely
                    from my face &amp; head.-- I arrived here, after tarrying almost 3/4s of an
                    hour in Millerstown, about six o'clock. By way of compliment to my writing I may
                    tell you that a boy who with very bad manners was looking at me when writing the
                    above gave up in despair, &amp; retired, remarking that I write a very <hi
                        rend="underline">fine</hi> hand.-- I have taken two meals &amp; a sleep
                    last night &amp; am able to form some idea of the house.-- And my opinion is
                    that it is the best house <pb n="2"/> I ever stopped at on the Mountain.- The
                    table is very good. Things are nice well cooked &amp; palatable.-- The <orig
                        reg="boarders">borders</orig> have a table to themselves &amp; are not
                    made to eat with the <orig reg="hosteller">hostler</orig> or not at all.-- They
                    are waited on attentively.-- W. F.s family <del rend="none" hand="h1"/>
                    <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> sit at table with the boarders. The beds are very nice. Mine
                    last night had on two as nice sheets as I <hi rend="underline">ever slept on or
                        could ever</hi> -- a nice coverlet and a blanket alongside to be used if
                    necessary.-- I am much surprised at the accomodations.-- Please give my
                    compliments to <abbr expan="George">Geo.</abbr> MClellan &amp; tell him for
                    me that if "Frank is not a decent man he keeps a very good house, his table <add
                        hand="h1" place="inline">&amp; beds</add>, being about as much superior
                    to Goodyear's or Buchman's his own, I believe is to Griswolds." The reason for
                    sending this message is he was trying to ridicule Frank &amp; his house
                    yesterday, I thought, in which he was assisted by others who tried their hand at
                    ridicule me <add hand="h1" place="inline">for offering to go there</add> too
                    until I gave them a cut or two which made them silent.-- The bathing
                    establishment - the building is not so good as Goodyear's but it is just enough
                    for all useful purposes. The warm baths fixture is something like this:--
                    Suppose this a little building:-- [hand drawn illustration of a bath fixture]
                    that inside fixture the bath tub, greatly larger, the outside mark a boiler
                    connecting with the tub by two tubes running though the side of the house into
                    the tub.-- The water in the cylinder when heated boils over &amp; flows
                    through the upper tube into the tub &amp; makes the crater in the tub of the
                    requisite temperature.-- The regular <orig reg="boarders">borders</orig> here
                    are people Aikers, of Mt. St. Mary College &amp; Maryland University
                    &amp; his family in all seven. A party of about ten came today from
                    Muttontown.-- About 12 couples are expected from there tomorrow, so these
                    report. The town is near Hagerstown.-- His terms are not more than $4.-- I
                    expect not so much from what he told me last evening.-- W. F. &amp; I went
                    up to the spring he <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> last summer about half a mile from this up
                    the mountain.-- It is indeed very large, the largest I ever saw.- It is larger
                    than our <pb n="3"/> pantry - and beautiful.- The house he erected last season
                    -- is unoccupied now. He expects to move it up to the road next spring &amp;
                    keep both going.-- Buchmans' is not making any progress. The foundation is up.
                    They are now burning the brick for it.-- I expect to be home some time next week
                    as I mentioned before I left.-- I may go from Hagerstown through <orig
                        reg="Waynesboro">Waynesboro'</orig> over to the <unclear>fham G.
                    Road</unclear> -- &amp; to the Springs near Fayetteville -- about two miles
                    from the place we come out on the road.-- I don't know that I will but I may. I
                    understood that the other day 120 for dinner there-- Quite a crowd.-- I have a
                    bad pen &amp; worse ink.-- Love to all.--I don't precisely when I go to
                    Hagerstown</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Your <del rend="none" hand="h1"/></salute>
                    <signed>
                        <hi rend="underline">Edward</hi>
                    </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
