<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8511"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8511">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Samuel G. Lane to Edward McPherson,
                    March 3, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county samuel g lane to edward mcpherson, march 3 1860</title>
        <author>Lane, Samuel G.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8511</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501693</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Samuel G. Lane to Edward McPherson, March 3, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county samuel g lane to edward mcpherson, march 3 1860</title>
            <author>Samuel G. Lane</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Samuel G. Lane to Edward
                            McPherson, 3 March 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers,
                            Box 47, Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-03-03">1860-03-03</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Economy, Family, Home Front, State Government</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8511T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Samuel G. Lane asks Edward McPherson to approach [Simon] Cameron in support of
                    the request for a loan by the proprietors of "The Times."</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
         

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-03-03">March 3<hi rend="super">d</hi>, 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Chambersburg</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir:</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>Messrs. Frey &amp; Foltz, proprietors of "The Times," have unexpectedly
                    become embarrassed financially by the sudden withdrawal of one of their backers,
                    who had engaged to supply them with their Spring payments. A very trivial Social
                    misunderstanding has excited the aforesaid gentleman's <abbr
                        expan="incorporated">inc</abbr>, and although he is a brother of one of the
                    firm, he refuses his promised aid just now when it most urgently needed. They
                    Know not where to look for assistance at so late a period, and it having been
                    suggested to them that <unclear>Mr.</unclear> Cameron is perfectly able to
                    render them timely help, they have requested me to <pb n="2"/> make the
                    application for a bona fide loan. They need $1,500 or $2,000, and will be able
                    to furnish good and ample security for that sum, and will pay whatever rate of
                    interest may be properly demanded. This is a simple business transaction, and is
                    just such an application as would be made to any man whom they thought had the
                    means; and as has already been made to persons here, who would have assisted
                    them had they been in possession of the funds. They are aware that a
                    misconstruction may be put upon this, but they earnestly declare that they apply
                    to <unclear>Mr.</unclear> Cameron only because they think that he may have it in
                    his power to accomodate them, and because he has often come to the rescue of
                    young men; and not at all with any false ideas of the matter, and because of Mr.
                    C's <pb n="3"/> present relations to the party. Unless they can procure such
                    security as would satisfy any money lender, they would not expect to be helped.
                    I have no personal interest in this affair, for although I am acting editor of
                    the paper, my salary is perfectly sound.</p>

                <p>I have taken the liberty of addressing you on this point, as I think you could
                    bring it before Mr. C in such way as to <orig reg="dissect">disect</orig> the
                    application of any seeming indelicacy, and present it, (as it is honestly) as a
                    purely business one. If you see it in another light, I wish you to decline it at
                    once, for we have too high a respect for you and your honorable position to wish
                    you to engage in anything questionable or indelicate. </p>

                <p>It is said to be a common <pb n="4"/> thing to ask Mr. Cameron for direct
                    donations, and of course at this time, many such solicitations are made; but
                    this has nothing of that character, being, as I have before said, only a simple
                    business transaction such as they would make with Bigler or <orig reg="anybody"
                        >any body</orig> else, who could afford the aid.</p>

                <p>In compliance with the request of the boys I have laid this matter before you.
                    They have no fear of the people of this vicinity not sustaining their paper, as
                    it is growing rapidly in public favor and is doing a fine business. You
                    understand why this can be so, &amp; <unclear>they</unclear> yet need help.</p>

                <p>Permit me to congratulate you upon your recent speech, which has given us the
                    greatest satisfaction, &amp; which I see so generally complimented. <del
                        hand="h1"/> all hope that you may long live to adorn this district in the
                    National <del rend="none" hand="h1"/> &amp; to reap higher deserved honors.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>
                        <abbr expan="Respectfully">Respy.</abbr>
                    </salute>
                    <signed>S. G. Lane</signed>
                    <seg type="postscript">
                        <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon.</abbr>
                            <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr> McPherson</name>
                    </seg>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
