<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8541"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8541">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to H. G. McPherson, December 29,
                    1858</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to h g mcpherson, december 29 1858</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8541</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501723</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to H. G. McPherson, December 29, 1858</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to h g mcpherson, december 29 1858</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to H. G. McPherson, 29
                            December 1858, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1858</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1858-12-29">1858-12-29</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8541T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. writes to her aunt, Edward McPherson's mother, about the death of Charles,
                    possibly a brother of McPherson. She also gives a general report of their circle
                    of friends including Lizzie Law, Nannie and Mr. Page, and the bad health of Dr.
                    Tyler.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
           

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1858-12-29"><abbr expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 29<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi>, 1858</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Aunt</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I received a letter from <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr>- last week dated <abbr
                        expan="December">Dec.</abbr> 13<hi rend="super">th</hi> &amp; it did not
                    reach me until the 20<hi rend="super">th</hi>-- where it was, all that time I
                    can't tell &amp; besides, it was marked "way". He stated you expected to go
                    to Hagerstown the next week if the weather permitted. Now as we have had many
                    rainy days &amp; a few clear, I have been at a loss to know where you are at
                    present &amp; consequently how to direct a letter, but concluded to send it
                    to Hagerstown. This will account for my not having written before, since
                    receiving <abbr expan="Edward's">Ed.'s</abbr> letter telling us of the recent
                    sorrow that had fallen upon you, in the death of Charles, so far away from home
                    &amp; friends -- yet from what <abbr expan="Edward">Edw<hi rend="underline">
                            <hi rend="super">d</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> says, you have much to comfort you <pb n="2"/> in the thought,
                    that he did not suffer for want of shelter &amp; kind attention during his
                    illness. As <abbr expan="Edward">Edw<hi rend="underline">
                            <hi rend="super">d</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> says, it would have been a great gratification to have seen
                    &amp; talked with him, but He, who ordereth all that concerns us, "doeth all
                    things well". "Be still &amp; know that I am God," is all we can do. We
                    regret very much it did not suit your plans to come to us first.- We hoped for
                    once, in our <orig reg="lifetime">life time</orig>, to have a relative with us
                    at this season of family reunions. I fear you will not want to leave <abbr
                        expan="Hagerstown">H--</abbr> after being there a while - you will become so
                    interested in the children. I do want to see them so much. Mr Tyler has not left
                    us yet-- he has not been able to wind up his business here yet &amp; that
                    prevented his being present at Mittie's wedding, which is a source of much
                    regret on all sides. If it had been any other time, it would have suited him. I
                    am very sorry too that circumstances prevented <abbr expan="Edward"
                        >Edw</abbr><hi rend="super">d</hi> going, for I know it would have gratified
                    Mittie &amp; all of them so much. <pb n="3"/> Lizzie mentioned Mittie had
                    recieved a very nice letter from him, with his regrets. We heard it was to be a
                    very grand affair. Bradley &amp; Maria Tyler with Jane
                    <unclear>Bungh</unclear> went down on Monday, Lizzie will be delighted to have
                    them with her. She &amp; the baby are well -- it seems to be the <hi
                        rend="underline">town pet</hi> especially among the young men &amp;
                        <unclear>receives</unclear> a great many presents from them. Dr. Bradley
                    Tyler is in very feeble health this winter - indeed, it is sometimes feared he
                    will not survive the winter, <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> he seems better now
                    &amp; his cough is not so troublesome. Mrs Tyler is very much better but
                    still in her room. Nelly has been sitting up some for two days past &amp; we
                    hope now, will soon be about again. I had a letter from Lizzie Law last week -
                    all were well &amp; full of the approaching event. I suppose all is quiet
                    again at Rose Hill. My love to them. Did Mary Emma go with the bridal party? I
                    was very sorry, to hear of the death of Mrs Harper's mother. She will <pb n="4"
                    /> feel it very much, especially under the circumstances. Nannie &amp; Mr
                    Page are still at the Dr.'s. He is a very gentlmanly clever man, but very
                    inefficient. He is about closing his present business &amp; then will have
                    nothing to do, &amp; at present, no prospect. I fear they will begin to feel
                    that the Dr. was right in his objections. I suppose they will return to the
                        "<unclear>Track</unclear>" in a few days. I am truly sorry to learn the
                    state of things in your church &amp; can see no earthly hope of a better so
                    long as Mr. Van <abbr expan="Wycke">W.</abbr> remains. I should think much more
                    of him, if he were to go, before it be too late to recover from all this tumult.
                    How sad it is! You must have some very quarrelsome spirits among you to keep up
                    such an unpleasant state of things. We have had two clear days &amp; now it
                    is snowing quite fast. Tell Ned I do hope he will get to see us soon. Much love
                    from us all for yourself, Kate &amp; the Dr. with the dear little children.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever yours <abbr expan="affectionately">affet</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E.</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
