<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8549"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8549">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, September
                    5, 1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, september 5 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8549</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501731</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, September 5, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, september 5 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 5
                            September 1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-09-05">1859-09-05</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8549T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. writes to Edward about a visit from the Mchaffeys, the death of Cousin Susan's
                    son, E.'s potential visit to Baltimore, doubts of whether the Pages will go to
                    Louisiana, and the state of the church.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
           

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-09-05"><abbr expan="September">Sep.</abbr> 5<hi
                                rend="super">th</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear <abbr expan="Edward">Edwd</abbr>--</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I am under the impression that you are in my debt- yet, as it is a rainy day, I
                    concluded to amuse myself, by telling you, that you might not forget it, for it
                    strikes me, you are not as good a correspondent as you were some time ago; you
                    must have some more agreeable occupation for mind &amp; body, to be found
                    ever in Gettysburg. Is it so? I received &amp; thank you for your Lecture
                    which I read with much pleasure. Mr T- has not had time to do so, as he has been
                    busily engaged, preparing an Article for the "Princeton Review--" on Sir <abbr
                        expan="William">Wm.</abbr> Hamilton-- Last week, we had a very short,
                    pleasant visit from Mr. Mchaffey &amp; <abbr expan="Elizabeth">Eliz<hi
                            rend="super">
                            <hi rend="underline">th</hi>
                        </hi></abbr> after their <pb n="2"/> return from Hagerstown. Mr. M. never
                    remained <orig reg="overnight">over night</orig> here before &amp; he thinks
                        <abbr expan="Frederick">
                        <hi rend="underline">Fred<hi rend="super">k</hi></hi>
                    </abbr> greatly before that place. We only regretted they could not remain
                    longer. E- received your letter, here. By this time I suppose they are in <abbr
                        expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>, as they left here
                    on Thursday last for Washington, intending to spend Friday there &amp; on
                    Saturday proceed to <abbr expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi rend="super"
                    >a</hi>.</abbr> to meet <unclear>Phersey</unclear>, who went there the week
                    before. They both look remarkably well &amp; were in fine spirits. I hope
                    you feel much better &amp; stronger after your visits to the different
                    watering places &amp; will be well prepared for the <orig reg="labors"
                        >labours</orig>, &amp; pleasures of the coming winter, not <hi
                        rend="underline">vain amusements</hi>, for I have ceased to class them under
                    the head of real pleasure for rational beings.</p>

                <p>Poor Cousin Susan has been again most severely afflicted in the death of her
                    youngest son, a very lovely &amp; promising youth, who died last week after
                    a few days illness. But they have much to comfort them in the belief that he had
                    the Christian's hope to sustain <pb n="3"/> him in a dying hour. About a year
                    ago he made a profession of religion, the <del hand="h1">third</del> fourth of
                    the sons at home, who have done so, since their father's death. We have been
                    looking for you, in vain, ever since last Spring, &amp; now I would not be
                    surprised if you make your appearance during my absence. I hope to go to
                    Thorndale the last of this, or beginning of next week -- if by Emmittsburg,
                    probably about Tuesday next - I expect to remain there until the marriage of Mr
                    Birnie's daughter early in <abbr expan="October">Oct.</abbr> immediately after
                    which, I hope to return home by Baltimore to see Cousin &amp; her family. I
                    could procure a driver &amp; carriage if a good &amp; safe horse could
                    be had, but I am afraid to trust the livery stable horses, especially with a
                    youth not greatly experienced in driving. The only alternative then is to go by
                    Emmittsburg which would be very pleasant, if I had company, but I suppose that
                    will have to be adopted or give it up altogether. Mr. Page &amp; Nannie
                    expect to start for Louisiana next Monday week, though none would be surprised,
                    should they <pb n="4"/>draw back, at the last. He is so inefficient. He is
                    expected to start the school &amp; build it up. We fear for the result,
                    unless he bestirs himself. The <abbr expan="Colonel's">Col's</abbr> family have
                    been in the country nearly all the summer, so that, I have not seen any of them.
                    From Lizzie's account I would scarcely know Gettysburg, the changes in every
                    way, are so great. The state of things in the Church would be my greatest grief-
                    How truly sad it is! I may be mistaken, but I cannot think Mr Van Wycke's
                    friends, who absent themselves from the church, do right - it will only widen
                    the breach &amp; most probably end in a division which would be deplorable -
                        <orig reg="though">tho'</orig> I do not know, but what, that would be
                    better, than a constant warfare. However my comfort is, "the Lord reigns". Let
                    us hear from you very soon-- Love to all friends. Mr T &amp; your Cousin C-
                    join me in much love to you.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours ever <abbr expan="affectionately">affect</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
