<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8545"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8545">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, April 1,
                    1859</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, april 1 1859</title>
        <author>E.</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8545</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501727</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: E. to Edward McPherson, April 1, 1859</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county e to edward mcpherson, april 1 1859</title>
            <author>E.</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: E. to Edward McPherson, 1 April,
                            1859, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47, Folder
                        1859</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1859-04-01">1859-04-01</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Church/Religious Activity, Death/Casualties, Economy, Family, Home Front,
                        National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8545T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>E. reports Jane Boggs's death to Edward McPherson and mentions good news about
                    Kate, Edward's sister. E. urges McPherson to become a practicing Christian, so
                    he can better serve his country. She also announces that Mr. Page is broke and
                    that Cousin C. is not better.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
        

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1859-04-01">April 1<hi rend="super">st</hi>, 1859</date>
                        <name type="place">Frederick</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Edward</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>After receiving your last letter, <hi rend="underline">I <unclear>felt</unclear>
                        <unclear>fine</unclear> writing very soon in return</hi>, but that very day
                    brought some sad news from Baltimore &amp; ever since, my letters have been
                    directed there; Jane declined very rapidly in the last two months yet she was
                    not confined <orig reg="upstairs">up stairs</orig> to her room or her bed until
                    two days before her death. She was down in the parlour last morning weak
                    &amp; the following (last Thursday) died, in great peace rejoicing in the
                    preciousness of the Lord Jesus, whom she loved. Being the household pet
                    &amp; much loved by all her relatives for her gentle confiding disposition
                    it is a sore affliction &amp; to her sister, it is like taking part of
                    herself, for they were very closely united to each other &amp; not only
                    sisters, but friends in all their intercourse. I longed to be with them, but it
                    was impossible for many reasons -- but they were not alone -- <pb n="2"/> they
                    have many devoted friends in the city &amp; Jane's most intimate friend
                        <abbr expan="Margaret">Margt</abbr> Breckenridge from Princeton
                    (granddaughter of old Dr. Miller) went on some weeks ago to make them visit,
                    &amp; as Jane declined so rapidly, she remained until all was over,
                    &amp; will be with them for two or three weeks yet. She has been a great
                    comfort to them all, in every way, as she is a very attractive girl &amp; of
                    great excellence of character. I cannot express, my Dear <abbr expan="Edward"
                        >Edwd</abbr> my delight &amp; gratitude, when I read the pleasing
                    tidings of Kate contained in your last. I cannot say I was much surprised, for I
                    had been hoping &amp; praying for it, encouraged too by the spirit &amp;
                    tone of her letter to me, soon after your dear Mother's death. However, my
                    impression two years ago was, that there was a preparation work going on, her
                    views &amp; feelings on the subject of religion were so much changed for the
                    better. Of Elizabeth I have not heard, though I wrote some time ago -- Lizzie
                    Howe expects her to make her a visit soon, of course, what impression sorrow has
                    made on her, I know not. I can only trust &amp; pray. As for yourself Dear
                        <abbr expan="Edward">Ed.</abbr> let me say, that before you enter upon the
                    public service of your country, I long to see you enlisted in the service of
                    Him, by "whom Kings reign &amp; princes rule". This is the best <pb n="3"
                    />preparation for such a trying, responsible work. A letter from Lizzie just
                    after yours, told us of your visit to them, &amp; how much gratified they
                    were. I am very sorry you had so much trouble to find them. Mr. Tyler is
                    preparing to go to the District very soon. Your cousin C- does not improve,
                    though she is about the house. All are in much trouble at the Dr's. Polly is
                    very ill &amp; what will surprise &amp; grieve you most, Mr. Page wrote
                    yesterday to the Dr. to say that he was entirely broken up, without a cent,
                    &amp; no place to take Nannie. Just exactly what the Dr. predicted, when he
                    made his objections to the marriage. They have been here nearly all the time,
                    have just left, &amp; of course will have to return. Do you not pity the Dr.
                    most truly. Mr. P- is totally inefficient, one of the <hi rend="underline"
                        >women-men</hi>, would rather sit <orig reg="upstairs">up stairs</orig> with
                    the ladies, in a rocking chair. Yet a gentleman, well educated &amp;
                    correct. What is to become of them? We hope to see you very soon now. Will you
                    not come this way to Hagerstown? I should think it would be most pleasant-- I
                    must stop-- All send love &amp; hope to see you as soon as you can leave
                    home. Love to Miss Polly &amp; all friends. Thanks for your good,
                    satisfactory letters-</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever yours <abbr expan="affectionately">affecty</abbr></salute>
                    <signed>E</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
