<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8557"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>


<TEI.2 id="F8557">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: James Wilson to Edward McPherson,
                    January 16, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county james wilson to edward mcpherson, january 16 1860</title>
        <author>Wilson, James</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8557</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501739</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: James Wilson to Edward McPherson, January 16, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county james wilson to edward mcpherson, january 16 1860</title>
            <author>James Wilson</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: James Wilson to Edward McPherson,
                            16 January 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-01-16">1860-01-16</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <handList>
                <hand id="h1"/>
            </handList>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Death/Casualties, Home Front, National Government, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8557T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Edward McPherson's eighty-one year old friend, James Wilson, writes about the
                    problem of electing the Speaker of the House. He includes a mocking discussion
                    of the Democrats and other politicians.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient"><abbr expan="Honorable">Hon</abbr> Edward McPherson</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-01-16">16<hi rend="super">th</hi> January 1860</date>
                        <name type="place">Fairfield Adams County</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>Dear Sir, </salute>
                </opener>

                <p>You have been exceeding <del hand="h1">in</del> kind in sending papers &amp;
                    documents since the commencement of the present Session of Congress. I should be
                    greatly wanting in common courteousness if I failed in making due
                    acknowledgments -- You have a <unclear>bousterous</unclear> time of it. Your
                    body can hardly be called a deliberative Assembly. I am greatly pleased with the
                    forbearance of our Republican friends. the vituperation of the Southern fire
                    eaters is uncalled for and beyond endurance and too much for human nature to
                    bear patiently with. Yet I think great good will result to the Republican cause
                    growing out of it. Iverson of Georgia <unclear>Vanlandinghouse</unclear> of
                    Ohio, and John B. Clark of <orig reg="Missouri">Misouri</orig> and some Northern
                    Democrats, will, if they continue in their violent course, do more to put down
                    modern Democracy than the Republicans can do of themselves -- I wonder some fun
                    Loving wag <orig reg="don't">dont</orig> take it into their head to get up a
                    caricature of Bigler and other Northern Democrats representing Iverson and some
                    other <orig reg="Southern">southern</orig> Democrats <orig reg="putting"
                    >puting</orig> coals of fire on their Backs like the Tarapins, to make them
                        <unclear>creep</unclear>. I say stick to Sherman, better by far to be beat,
                    than change at the period of the fight. your patience be like to fail you read
                    the Book of Job and persevere, your Constituents will see you out-- Without any
                    view to flatter, you have respectable talents for debate, do not attempt <del
                        hand="h1">and</del> to make share after small game, for no <del hand="h1"
                        >sacrifice</del> laurels can be won in this Negro fight let our enemies have
                    the glory, but let us have the Speaker; it is of immeasurable importance for us
                    to have the Speaker at this <hi rend="underline">juncture</hi>. I wish you and
                    all our Republican friends to be more than usually courteous to John Hickman, he
                    is worth his weight in Gold for his manly bearing in this contest, but all our
                    Delegation from <abbr expan="Pennsylvania">Pen<hi rend="super">a</hi></abbr>
                    have a hand ready <pb n="2"/> when they meet John Hickman. I had the honor of a
                    personal acquaintance &amp; would address him a letter to help to cheer him
                    on in his manly course.</p>

                <p>I should have written to you sooner, but for a severe spell of putrid sore
                    throat, and <orig reg="epidemic">epidemich</orig> that has afflicted our
                    neighbourhood much. this with a fast down hill life, being now 81 years old,
                    almost disables me from writing <orig reg="intelligibly">inteligibly</orig> the
                    mechanical part and you will perceive the mental part is alike deficient-- Your
                    generous nature will know how to excuse the imperfections of this epistle- You
                    are aware I lost the partner of my life in May last which nearly cost me my
                    life, this with my late spell of sickness has greatly shattered my nerves. I
                    feel now like a ship at sea without a rudder The Bark of my life is fast
                    drifting down the tide of time and will reach that Haven which a merciful God
                    has already indicated. I will naturally cast a lingering look upon the Country I
                    am about to leave to freedom and to the world.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Adieu Your old friend</salute>
                    <signed>James Wilson</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
