<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="F8563"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>

<TEI.2 id="F8563">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, May
                    15, 1860</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, may 15 1860</title>
        <author>Scott, Kate</author>
        <editor/>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>Virginia Center for Digital History Staff</name>
                    <resp>Conversion to TEI.2-conformant markup:</resp>
                    <name>Catherine S. Neale</name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">7</num>kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Virginia Center for Digital History</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Virginia </pubPlace>

                <idno type="VCDH">F8563</idno>

        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Publicly accessible </p>
                    <p n="public">URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2/</p>
                    <p>Text and images (c) copyright 2002, by the Rector and Visitors of the
                        University of Virginia</p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 2002 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="2002">2002</date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501745</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War</p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note/>
            </notesStmt>

            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson, May 15, 1860</title>
            <title level="m"/>
            <title type="sort">franklin county kate scott to edward mcpherson, may 15 1860</title>
            <author>Kate Scott</author>
            <editor/>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp/>
                            <name/>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <editionStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </editionStmt>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher/>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                        <idno type="callNo">Source copy consulted: Kate Scott to Edward McPherson,
                            15 May 1860, Library of Congress, Edward McPherson Papers, Box 47,
                            Folder 1860</idno>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p/>
                    </seriesStmt>
                    <notesStmt>
                        <note/>
                    </notesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Library of Congress, Washington, D. C.</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>

        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1860-05-15">1860-05-15</date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Arts/Leisure, Death/Casualties, Family, Home Front, Women</term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>

        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2003-07">July 2003</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Desi Hopkins</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Item proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text id="F8563T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Kate Scott fears that Edward McPherson is sick, because of a delay in his
                    letters. She updates him on news of friends and family.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>

        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
            

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1860-05-15">May 15<hi rend="super">th</hi>/60.</date>
                        <name type="place">Hagerstown</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute>My Dear Brother,</salute>
                </opener>

                <p>I have been anxiously looking for a letter from you for some time and feel uneasy
                    at your long silence fearing you are sick. I hope you will relieve my mind soon
                    by writing or letting me know how you are, it is so unusual for you to let so
                    long a time pass without writing I cannot account for it. I wrote you soon after
                        <orig reg="receiving">recieving</orig> your last. I had a letter from Lizzie
                    last week from <abbr expan="Baltimore">Balt.</abbr> telling me all about
                    Lizzie's going but she neglected to tell me how long she would be there or where
                    I should direct a letter. I want to write to her and am quite at a loss, if you
                        <pb n="2"/>know please let me know when you write, she mentioned you were
                    there a short time, what a trial it must have been to part with Lizzie, I feel
                    for her very much she will hardly know what to do without her so accustomed to
                    seeing her so often. I am afraid she never will have very good health, she
                    complains very much in her letter to me. she was anxious to go to Marietta. I
                    would like to have invited her up here from <abbr expan="Baltimore">B--.</abbr>
                    but we are in such dreadful confusion she could not be comfortable, we have
                    commenced improving our back building and it is quite a great undertaking, and
                    we are just living any way having been obliged to take the dining room for a
                    kitchen and the back <orig reg="parlor">parlour</orig> for a dining room, I hope
                    it will not be very long until we are fixed again, but I am afraid it will,
                    there is a great deal to be done, I have been very <pb n="3"/>busy home cleaning
                    and am just as tired as I can be <orig reg="tonight">to night</orig>. I have
                    worked more than I ought to have done to get the front part comfortable. Have
                    you been to <abbr expan="Gettysburg">G-</abbr> lately? the mirrors have not yet
                    arrived neither have I heard <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> of them. I
                    expected them before this. I hope they are safe, Mary Emma left this on Saturday
                    for Pittsburg first spending a week in <abbr expan="Philadelphia">Phil<hi
                            rend="super">a</hi>.</abbr> her Mother and Father will meet her in
                    Harrisburg next week and all go over, the bride and groom will take quite a trip
                    and visit Rose Hill on their return also Jinnie Berry's and Washington. Mary
                    Alvey is now on a visit to her Father's at the Agricultural College, I <orig
                        reg="don't">dont</orig> know if she will go to <abbr expan="Washington"
                    >W.</abbr> or not Mr &amp; Mrs <unclear>Isore</unclear> left this yesterday
                    to spend a few days in <abbr expan="Washington">W-.</abbr> and <abbr
                        expan="Baltimore">Balt-</abbr>. The children are very well. Lillie goes to
                    school and is making rapid progress. she is remarkably fond of her <pb n="4"
                    />book and is very apt Dr says she is smarter than both the boys put together
                    she is devoted to going to school. How long do you expect to be in Washington
                    yet? I think you must be getting tired of it and would enjoy a change. I hope
                    you will come to see us this summer. do be sure and write very soon and relieve
                    my mind, do excuse this writing. I can scarcely guide my pen. <orig reg="My"
                    >my</orig> hand trembles. Dr wishes to be remembered and in anxious to know if
                    there is <orig reg="anything">any thing</orig> the matter,</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours very truly</salute>
                    <signed>Kate --</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
