<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FN0001"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
<TEI.2 id="FN0001">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: R. S. E. to the Pennsylvania Daily
                    Telegraph, May 14, 1861</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county r s e to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, may 14 1861</title>
        <author>R.S.E </author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">8</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FN0001 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501766</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Transcription from a photocopy.</p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: R. S. E. to the Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph, May
                            14, 1861</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county r s e to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, may 14 1861</title>
            <author>R.S.E. </author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace> </pubPlace>
                        <date value=""> </date>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: R.S.E. Letter, published in the <hi rend="underline">Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</hi>, May 15, 1861, p.
                            2, under the headline "From Camp Scott." </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1861-05-14">1861-05-14 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Camp Life, Military Authority, Enlistment, Troop Movement, Patriotism,
                        Church/Religious Activity, State Government, National Government </term>
                    <term>Regiment: 2nd Pa </term>
                    <term>Company: I </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp> </resp>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees </name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FN0001T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>This letter by R.S.E. of Co. I, 2nd Pa., describes the good nature of his fellow
                    soldiers in camp. He also talks about the inefficiency of some of the officers
                    and expresses disapproval of the requirement that soldiers serve three months
                    rather than three years.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Editor, Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1861-05-14">May 14, 1861 </date>
                        <name type="place">Camp Scott, York, Pa.</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute> </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>To-day has been one of bustle and confusion. Early this morning orders were
                    issued to the First, Second and Third regiments to hold themselves in readiness
                    to move at an hour's notice. Spades, shovels, axes, and camp utensils of all
                    kinds, were gathered together ready for the march. The men in the 2d regiment
                    have not yet received their knap-sacks, and how they were to carry their things
                    was a matter that gave them a great deal of trouble. My attention was occupied
                    with our own company (I. 2d reg.) and the <orig reg="alacrity">alracity</orig>
                    with which the men bundled up their traps, with the expectation of a tramp
                    southward, was sufficient evidence to me that a speedy encounter with the rebels
                    was the uppermost thought in every man's mind, and all seemed anxious to
                    commence the journey toward "Dixie's Land."</p>

                <p>Since we have been encamped in this place nothing discreditable to the five
                    thousand men has transpired. No fighting nor street brawls have characterized
                    any of their proceedings. In fact I never saw so many men congregated in one
                    place that have behaved themselves with so much propriety. On last Sunday most
                    of the soldiers belonging the camp were in town, and all the churches were
                    crowded to suffocation. Delegations from some of the companies could not gain
                    admission, and at the request of the soldiers persons were sent outside of the
                    churches to speak to them. In the afternoon of Sunday there was a grand review
                    by <abbr expan="Governor">Gov.</abbr> Curtin, during which the strictest order
                    and decorum was preserved. This moral sentiment speaks well for the troops that
                    are quartered here, and it gives me pleasure to say that the citizens of York
                    duly appreciate it.</p>

                <p>It is now over three weeks since we have been quartered here, and during that
                    time the three first regiments, in the 2d brigade, should have acquired a
                    military skill sufficient to fit them to any action. I am pained to say that
                    through the <orig reg="inefficiency">inefficiancy</orig> of a number of the
                    company officers we have made but little progress. The First regiment, to which
                    the Cameron Guards are attched, is acknowledged to be the best drilled. The
                    reason of this is that their <orig reg="Captains">Captain's</orig> are all
                    military men and have had experience in the volunteer service. On the other hand
                    some of the companies of the Second and Third regiment are commanded by Captains
                    that never had a musket in their hands. The inefficiency of company commanders
                    is a matter that no delicacy should be allowed to be over looked, and I consider
                    that it is the duty of the Government to place men that know and have the nerve
                    to command on the forces in whose hands the destinies of our country are placed.
                    This defect must be remedied, or the thousands who have rushed to the defence of
                    their country from Pennsylvania will be as chaff before the wind to the well
                    disciplined forces of the traitors of the south. I say this in no harsh spirit
                    to any of the noble men of Pennsylvania who are unacquainted with military
                    tactics and have volunteered their services, but as a word of advice to officers
                    in command of regiments and brigades that the remedy may be applied.</p>

                <p>In closing this short epistle I am compelled to say a few words in refernce to
                    the two Harrisburg companies that gives me much <unclear>pain</unclear> to
                    write. Your readers are aware that it is the wish of Governor Curtin to have the
                    men of one regiment to enlist for three years, or the war; but to-day things
                    take a turn and one of the men told me that <hi rend="italic">not a single
                    man</hi> would go longer than three months. The cause of all that is owing to
                    the appointment of a non-commissioned officer obnoxious to the men in the
                    company. In the "State Capital Guards" <hi rend="italic">not a single man</hi>
                    is going for more than the three months. Rest assured that it is not for lack of
                    patriotism that these men refuse to enlist for the war, but for matters which I
                    decline at present to mention.</p>

                <p>The bustle and confusion in the camp incident to leaving here calls me away and
                    compels me to draw my letter to a close. You will hear from me again at the
                    first opportunity.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>R.S.E. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
