<?xml version="1.0"?>

<?dlps id="FN0008"?>
<?dlps page-images="none" figure-images="no"?>
<?dlps transcription="other"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/tei-p4/tei2.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % POSTKB "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % MANUSCRIPT "INCLUDE">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.ent SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.ent">
<!ENTITY % TEI.extensions.dtd SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/dtd/tei/uva-dl-tei/uva-dl-tei.dtd">
<!ENTITY % ISOpub SYSTEM "http://text.lib.virginia.edu/charent/iso-pub.ent"> %ISOpub;
]>
  
  
<TEI.2 id="FN0008">
    <teiHeader type="migrated">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
        <title type="main" id="VShadow">Franklin County: A.H. Baum to the Pennsylvania Daily
                    Telegraph, September 1, 1864</title>
        <title type="sort">franklin county a h baum to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, september 1 1864</title>
        <author>Baum, A. H.</author>
        <respStmt>
                    <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp>
                    <name>David Samuel Freed </name>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
            <extent>ca. <num type="kilobytes">11</num> kilobytes</extent>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities </publisher>
                <publisher>University of Virginia </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Charlottesville, Va. </pubPlace>
                <idno type="VCDH">FN0008 </idno>
        <!--
                <availability>
                    <p>Text and images (c) Copyright 1997 by The Rector and Visitors of The
                        University of Virginia. All rights reserved. </p>
                    <p>URL: http://jefferson.village.virginia.edu/vshadow2 </p>
                </availability>
-->
<availability status="public">
          <p n="copyright">Copyright &#xa9; 1997 by the Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</p>
          <p n="access">Publicly accessible</p>
        </availability>
                <date value="1998">1998 </date>
            <idno type="uva-pid">uva-lib:501773</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <p>The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War. </p>
            </seriesStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>University of Virginia Library, Valley of the Shadow collection</title>
        <idno type="uva-set">UVA-LIB-ValleyOfTheShadow</idno>
      </seriesStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Letter transcribed from a photocopy. </p>
                </note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
            <title>Franklin County: A.H. Baum to the Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph,
                            September 1, 1864</title>
            <title type="sort">franklin county a h baum to the pennsylvania daily telegraph, september 1 1864</title>
            <author>A.H. Baum</author>
            <respStmt>
                            <resp> </resp>
                            <name> </name>
                        </respStmt>
          </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher> </publisher>
                        <pubPlace/>
                        <date value=""/>
                    </publicationStmt>
                    <seriesStmt>
                        <p>Source copy consulted: A.H. Baum Letter, published in the <hi rend="underline">Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</hi>, September 3,
                            1864, p. 1, under the headline "From the 201st Regiment." </p>
                    </seriesStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Used with permission from Pennsylvania Daily Telegraph</p>
      </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date value="1864-09-01">1864-09-01 </date>
            </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language id="eng" usage="main">English</language>
      </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>Troop Movement, Camp Life, Arts/Leisure, Church/Religious Activity</term>
                    <term>Regiment: 201st Pa. </term>
                    <term>Company: I </term>
                    <term>American Civil War</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change>
                <date value="2000">Summer 2000</date>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp/>
                    <name>Amy Voorhees</name>
                </respStmt>
                <item>Proofread against original; corrections made.</item>
            </change>
        <change>
        <date value="2008-07">January - July 2008</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name id="scholarly_resources">Scholarly Resources migration staff, University of Virginia Library</name>
          <resp>Markup conversion</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>Converted markup (originally TEI Lite) to comply with the UVa Library TEI DTD (uva-dl-tei).</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text id="FN0008T">
        <front id="d2">
            <div1 type="summary" id="d3">
                <p>Baum describes his company's first nights at Camp Couch.</p>
            </div1>
        </front>
        <body id="d4">
            <div1 type="letter" id="d5">
                <head>
                    <name type="recipient">Editor Telegraph</name>
                </head>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <date value="1864-09-01">Sept. 1, 1864.</date>
                        <name type="place">CAMP COUCH, NEAR CHAMBERSBURG</name>
                    </dateline>
                    <salute><hi rend="italic">Editor Telegraph</hi>:-- </salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The 201st regiment P.V., Col. Awl, is now comfortably "fixed," and the men
                    composing it are being rapidly instructed in the various evolutions pertaining
                    to military tactics. Camp Couch is situated a little over four miles, due west
                    of Chambersburg, in Hamilton, township, Franklin county. The camp is located on
                    an eminence overlooking a vast tract of country. A fine mountain view is had
                    northward and westward, (the lofty range running in a semi-circle from due north
                    to west,) and very much reminds us Harrisburgers of the Blue Mountain Ridge
                    above our beautiful city, on the Susquehanna. Eastward and south the view is
                    insignificant; interspersed here and there with farm-houses or humble log
                    dwellings, then shut out abruptly by belts of timber. At the foot of the Slate
                    Hill on which we pitched our tents, runs a sluggish stream, the water (in which
                    we frequently plunge, like so many porpoise,) is icy cold. The pike or public
                    road running from Chambersburg to Bedford, passes in front of our quarters,
                    scarcely five minutes walk from camp. The rations dealt out three times a day,
                    consist of fresh beef, salt pork, rice or bean soup, sugar, coffee and hard
                    tack, and the men stow it away in "double quick" time, for camp life gives them
                    an appetite.</p>

                <p>When our regiment left Camp Curtin, on Tuesday, the men all seemed "gay and
                    happy" -- inspired with the idea that a soldier's life was one of pleasure and
                    excitement!</p>

                <p>We marched gaily along enlivened by the music of our fine Regimental Band, proud
                    of our respected young Colonel and the other officers of the regiment to which
                    so many of our friends and neighbors are attached. But when we paraded through
                    the principle streets of the city, and met the tearful gaze, the fond adieus and
                    the "God bless you, men" of our wives and little ones -- of our kind friends and
                    neighbors -- it was no small effort to restrain tears and choke down the anguish
                    that many of us felt in parting from those we hold most dear on earth. Once in
                    the old bridge the boys yelled with a hearty good will, and drove away all
                    traces of sorrow and despondency.</p>

                <p>All along the line of the Cumberland Valley railroad we were cheered and greeted
                    with demonstrations of joy; and the regiment, hurried over the rails by two
                    engines, reached Chambersburg at half-past five o'clock. -- From some cause or
                    other, we lay in this ruined place nearly two hours; and then, after a fatiguing
                    march of four miles - fatiguing became new to most of us. We reached our camp at
                    dark, partook of some food from our haversacks, spread our blankets on the bare
                    ground; and, with the dying soldier, many of us sang,</p>

                <p>"Let this knap-sack be my pillow,<lb/> And my mantle be the sky -- </p>

                <p>and so we passed the first night in our new quarters, enjoying a sound refreshing
                    sleep - feeling a little the worse on waking up in the morning, slightly stiff
                    in our limbs, the effect of hunting for the soft side of the ground on Slate
                    Hill?</p>

                <p>Morning in camp must be seen and <hi rend="italic">heard</hi>, to be realized.
                    The boys, all refreshed by sleep, of a sudden become lively as crickets
                    imitating the crowing of bantam or shanghai, the squealing of pigs, the braying
                    of donkeys, and the barking of a terrier, and a thousand-and-one other ideas of
                    deviltry, which would make a man laugh in spite of himself! Then comes the
                    reveille, the cooks are bust after that, and the soldiers are hurrying up to the
                    restaurant (as they term it) to get their hot coffee, meat and hard tack.</p>

                <p>After breakfast squads are detailed, guards are put out for the various duties
                    assigned them, the respective companies are then drilled for a few hours, and
                    then dismissed in time to go after fresh water, fruit, or whatever they choose
                    to purchase, and get back in time for dinner. </p>

                <p>There is something that is interesting and comes near to a "home-picture," to be
                    seen and heard in camp after nightfall. The men are all huddled together in
                    their tents, variously employed, Some singing good old fashioned hymns,
                    evidently preparing for the great "roll call at the judgement day -- some
                    humming over gay snatches of sentiment in the shape of</p>


                <p>"Do they miss me at home,<lb/> Do they miss me!"</p>


                <p>or -- </p>


                <p>"Home, home sweet home!<lb/> There is no place like home."</p>


                <p>Again you hear the strumming of the humble banjo, with a negro song as an
                    accompaniment while the others are exercising their lungs on "Hail Columbia,"
                    and</p>


                <p>"Rally round the flag, boys<lb/> Rally round the flag -<lb/> Shouting the battle
                    cry of Freedom!"</p>

                <p>But, owing to the industry, courtesy and perseverance of our worthy Chaplain,
                    REv. Mr. Rakestraw, there is a decided moral and religious improvement int he
                    regiment; as many of the soldiers are seen, when at leisure, to read over
                    religious matter, and can be heard to sing the hymns that John Wesley, and
                    Asbury, and the other great lights of the Methodist Church used to sing in years
                    gone by.</p>

                <p>Our regimental officers are,<lb/> Colonel - F. Asbury Awl.<lb/> Lieut.Colonel -
                    T. Wesley Awl.<lb/> Major - John T. Morgan<lb/> Adjutant - Reisinger.
                    Quartermaster - Benj. Stimmel. Chaplain - Rev. Mr. Rakestraw.</p>

                <p>Our officers are all men of good breeding and education, and men of the regiment
                    are greatly attached to them already. We anticipate a good time during our
                    enlistment. The the men are lavish in their praises of our courteous and
                    gentlemanly young colonel. One man in our mess remarked to-day "I say, boys, we
                    are a bully regiment -- nearly all Harrisburgers -- we have a splendid new <hi
                        rend="italic">Awl</hi> at our head, and if the Rebs give us a chance, we
                    will punch a hole clean through 'em!"</p>

                <p>Your correspondent is attached to the company I, Capt. Miles, and our position is
                    near the <orig reg="center">centre</orig> of the regiment, between companies C.
                    and D.</p>

                <p>To-day a copy of the TELEGRAPH, of Tuesday evening, came into camp and the boys
                    cheered loudly for that staunch Harrisburg daily, when they read the
                    complimentary notice of the appearance of our regiment, as we left Harrisburg.
                        <hi rend="italic">Viva la</hi> TELEGRAPH!</p>

                <p>Any of our friends writing to us (and we shall be glad to hear from home often)
                    will please address "201st regiment, Camp Couch, near Chambersburg, Pa," stating
                    the letter of the respective companies. The boys say, "tell our friends to send
                    us papers, by all means."</p>

                <p>Adieu for the present, and look out for more anon.</p>

                <closer>
                    <salute> </salute>
                    <signed>A.H.B.<lb/>High Private, Co. I. </signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI.2>
