<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.07.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/15/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-06">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.06.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We notice in the Episcopal Methodist, of June 27th, that a meeting of the
                        Trustees of Randolph Macon College will take place in Richmond on the 11th
                        inst., when the time and place of opening of the next session of that
                        Institution will be determined. The Editor, in a well timed editorial, calls
                        upon the Trustees to act promptly in the matter and select a suitable
                        location for this Institution. He calls their attention to the energy and
                        spirit shown by the sister Institutions of the State, which now bid fair to
                        flourish as they have never done before, and warns the Trustees that they
                        may lose the harvest-time for their College.. It seems almost a necessity
                        that the location of Randolph Macon shall be changed, and the editor sites
                        Staunton as one of the best points whither to remove this College. Without
                        any desire to disparage the claims of any other locality, we desire to call
                        the attention of the Trustees, and all others interested, to some of the
                        advantages of Staunton as a permanent location for an Institution of the
                        kind. Staunton is located in the midst of a highly productive, if not the
                        most productive, portion of the State, and could well and abundantly supply
                        all the wants of such an Institution. In locating a College it is important
                        that it shall be easy of access and the location healthy. This we think we
                        can claim, without denial from any source, for Staunton. So particularly is
                        it marked as a healthy location, that, in the summer seasons heretofore,
                        many, who set out from their homes to spend the summer at our famed watering
                        places, have stopped in Staunton and remained in preference.-As an
                        accessible point is in direct communication by railroad with almost every
                        locality, and this will be further increased by the completion of the
                        projected railway throughout the length of our beautiful Valley.</p>
                    <p>No people have suffered more during the long struggle through which all have
                        passed, long struggle through which all have passed, and none have shown a
                        more commendable energy in the recuperative process than the people of the
                        Valley. Not only do pecuniary interests excite their endeavors, but they
                        feel an earnest in education. Old schools, which during the war were
                        suspended, have been re-established, and new ones have sprung up with a
                        complement of pupils. Should this College be transferred to this point at
                        once, it would grow up with this section and be filled with students from
                        the Valley alone. There is a time in the life of Institutions as well as
                        men, which taken advantage of leads on to prosperity, and the present is the
                        auspicious moment for Randolph Macon College. If the Trustees determine upon
                        Staunton as the location, we think the day of prosperity is but dawning.</p>
                    <p>We think buildings could be secured here, that would answer until a site was
                        selected and buildings could be erected thereon, and we suggest to the
                        Trustees of Randolph Macon College, as worthy of their consideration to
                        investigate the advantages of Staunton as the future location of that
                        Institution, in regard to its accessibility, healthfulness, ability to
                        supply the wants of an Institution, and the morality of the people of this
                        locality and section.</p>
                    <p>We are satisfied that, should the Trustees investigate these subjects
                        Staunton would be selected and Randolph Macon would, ere long, be second to
                        no College in the State, either in standing or in point of numbers of her
                        students.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a the Trustees of Randolph Macon College will hold a meeting
                    on July 11 in Richmond and may soon move the college. The editor encourages the
                    Trustees to consider Staunton as a new location, noting its easy accessibility
                    and healthy climate. If the Trustees select Staunton, he argues, "we think the
                    day of its prosperity is but dawning."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The call for a National Convention at Philadelphia seems to be meeting with
                        more favor from Northern Democrats than was first supposed it would. Some of
                        our Southern exchanges favor the idea of sending Southern delegate to this
                        Convention, while others oppose it. It is a question whether Southern
                        delegates sent to this Convention would exhibit more plainly the sentiments
                        of the Southern people than they are known at present while, as our
                        cotemporary of the <emph rend="italic">Richmond Whig</emph> very justly
                        says, "in making their declaration of sentiments, some things would have to
                        be omitted in deference to the Southern delegates, that would weaken the
                        movement in the North, or if not omitted would compel such an expression of
                        dissent on the part of those delegates as would render it better if they had
                        not been present." </p>
                    <p>We think it a matter which should be left for the present with the Northern
                        Democrats and Conservatives, assuring them, as far as we can, that their
                        action tending to accomplish the objects set forth in the call will meet the
                        assent of all in the South, and that, as far as we can avail anything, our
                        support will not be wanting to aid in the defeat of the radicals.</p>
                    <p>We fear very much the cry might be raised, if Southern delegates were
                        present, that it was a coalition between the "Copperheads" and "Rebels"
                        which would deter many weak kneed conservatives from supporting its action,
                        and, perhaps, utterly destroy the object sought to be obtained by the
                        Convention.</p>
                    <p>We merely throw out these suggestions for the consideration of our people,
                        and if delegates are sent from the South we will hope for the best, and go
                        as far as any in our endeavors for the overthrow of radicalism, and the
                        restoration of the Union under the Constitution.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "the call for a National Convention at Philadelphia seems to
                    be meeting with more favor from Northern Democrats than was first supposed," but
                    recommends that the South not send delegates for fear that the cry of an
                    alliance between "'Copperheads'" and "'Rebels'" would undermine the
                    effectiveness of the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE Annual Examination of the pupils of the Deaf and Dumb, and Blind
                        Institution took place in the Chapel of the Institution, on Thursday evening
                        June 28th. The Hall was crowded with spectators who gazed with wonder and
                        admiration n the acquirements of the unfortunate pupils, as exhibited in the
                        examination. Difficult pieces of music were rendered with correctness and
                        pathos by the Blind, who likewise showed a remarkable aptness in every
                        branch taught in their department; one of them creating quite a sensation by
                        the demonstration of a problem in Analytical Geometry.</p>
                    <p>The Deaf-mutes exhibited a wonderful ability to acquire knowledge, some of
                        whom far surpass many of the same age who can both speak and hear.</p>
                    <p>When we consider the difficulty, of imparting instruction to those who can
                        not see, or hear, the patient and persistent zeal of the teachers in this
                        Institution can not be too highly praised. The worthy and competent
                        Principal, Maj. J. C. Covell, has devoted his whole time and energy to the
                        Institution and its pupils, and will be justly awarded a large degree of
                        praise for the success the Institution has met with under his
                    management.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Covell</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The annual examination of students at the Deaf and Dumb and Blind
                    Institution took place on June 28, where "the Hall was crowded with spectators
                    who gazed with wonder and admiration on the acquirements of the unfortunate
                    pupils."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Commencement exercises were held at the University of Virginia last week,
                    where A. H. H. Stuart delivered an address to the Literary Societies. Travers
                    Phillips and A. H. H. Stuart Jr. received degrees in Moral Philosophy and F. T.
                    Stribling and A. H. H. Stuart Jr. received degrees in French.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ayers</ln>
                        <fn>M. Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The closing exercises of the Virginia Female Institute were held last
                    Thursday. Among the graduates were M. Virginia Ayers of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For The Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:-- With several of the Masonic
                        Fraternity and citizens generally I paid a visit to the beautiful village of
                        Bridgewater, Rockingham county on the 23d inst., to witness and participate
                        in the festivities of the occasion connected with the celebration of the
                        birthday of St. John the Baptist. It was a cheering trip, reviving old
                        acquaintance and bygone days and making new friends. I write in part to
                        speak of the wheat crop, which far surpasses anything I expected. It is
                        wonderful to see the improvement for the last four weeks. There will be more
                        wheat in the upper end of Rockingham and the lower end of Augusta than there
                        was last year. The oats is the finest prospect I have seen for years-we all
                        croaked too soon.-Wheat, the good wheat lands have failed to a great extent
                        in some sections, the thin gray gravelly soils have more than an
                        average.-This is a just rebuke upon extortion and avarice. But to return to
                        the procession by the mystic tie. It was a grand affair, and of the speech
                        Mr. Editor, I wish you could have heard it. For eloquence, beauty, argument
                        and pathos, it exceeded anything I have ever heard on the subject of
                        Masonry, and was the clearest expose of the subject to which I have ever
                        listened. I trust it will be published as it was intended, in the main, for
                        the unitiated. I will not attempt a description for I can not do it justice.
                        More anon. </p>
                    <p>AUGUSTA.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Augusta" reports on his recent trip "with several of the Masonic
                    Fraternity" to Bridgewater to celebrate the birthday of John the Baptist. He
                    reports that the wheat crop in the upper end of Rockingham and the lower end of
                    Augusta "far surpasses anything I expected."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For The Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:-My attention having been called to
                        your issue of the 11th, I observed my name as one of the signers of a
                        petition praying Congress to send a Federal garrison to the county for the
                        purpose of protecting Union citizens in their rights. A petition was
                        presented to me totally different in character from the one published in
                        your paper which I signed. If the character of the petition had been truly
                        stated, I would never have signed it, not believing Federal troops to be
                        necessary for the protection either of the lives or property of Union
                        citizens. I signed it under false representations. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Respectfully</p>
                    <p>A. J. GRAHAM.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A. J. Graham</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Referring to the Dews-Todd petition which called for the return of Federal
                    troops to Staunton to protect loyal citizens, A. J. Graham explains that while
                    he did sign the petition, he "signed it under false representations."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Nathan H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jamison</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nathan Anderson and Maggie Jamison, both of Staunton, were married on June
                    28 by Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jas. Wilson and Agnes Long, both of Augusta, were married on June 28 by
                    Rev. Mr. Preston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.06.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
