<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.06.01">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/11/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-01">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>01</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.01.01">
            <div type="e">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>"Marching On."</head>
                <origin>Democratic Watchman, Bellefonte, Penn.</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">The columns of freedom march steadily on</emph>- </p>
                    <p>Yes, and in its wake is the graves of hundreds of thousands of our best
                        men-the bleaching bones of our brothers-a soil reddened with the blood of
                        our own kindred-solitary chimneys that mark the spots of desolated and
                        destroyed homes-outraged women -beggared children-a people robbed of their
                        liberty-plundered of their wealth-enslaved with debt and impoverished with
                        taxation.-A country shorn of its strength-despoiled of its glory-pilfered of
                        its greatness-its fields laid waste-its cities sacked-its towns
                        destroyed-its prosperity blighted-its flag disgraced-its Constitution
                        dishonored and its freedom made a mockery and its liberty a lie.-A race of
                        being torn from happy and contented homes and cast upon the highways and
                        by-ways of life to die. Yes, "the columns of freedom march steadily on," and
                        close upon its heels, grasping with cold, clammy hands, as if to stay its
                        onward progress, comes the corpses of the hundreds of thousands it has
                        murdered and trampled down; and all around and about it, with disheveled
                        locks, tattered garments and pleading looks, is the forms of outraged women,
                        begging with tearful eyes to be spared the horrors they have been subjected
                        to; yet it continues on, tramp, tramp, tramp--, crushing liberty, life and
                        justice-leaving nothing in its trail but blighted hopes, sorrowing hearts
                        and the blackness of despair. But it has about reached its end. A little
                        while longer, and with the "soul of John Brown," the columns of abolition
                        freedom will halt amid the smoke and flames of the infernal regions, at the
                        feet its father, the Devil.-<emph rend="italic">Democratic Watchman,
                            Bettefointe, Penn</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to the assertion that "the columns of freedom march steadily
                    on," the author responds that in the wake of freedom there is only devastation,
                    destruction and death and asserts that ultimately "the columns of abolition
                    freedom" will stop "at the feet of its father, the Devil."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.01.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Trumbull asked permission of the U S. Senate, on Thursday, May 24th, to
                        withdraw the original Dews-Todd petition presented by him, leaving a copy of
                        the same which was agreed to.</p>
                    <p>This strange course was pursued in consequence of a letter being written to
                        him by Dews, of which the following is an extract: <lb/></p>
                    <p>"The rebels of this place through A. H. H. Stuart, of Staunton and Joseph
                        Segar, as I learn, have gotten the names from Washington of the signers of
                        the petition of the Union citizens of this county praying for troops,
                        &amp;c., which you recently presented to Congress. It was done for the
                        purpose of injuring us in every possible manner, as events have proved. The
                        rebels have even intimidated some of the signers, some six or seven, until
                        they have actually signed cards in the rebel papers, denying that the signed
                        the petition. I therefore respectfully request that you will cause to be
                        forwarded to me immediately the original petition in order that those who
                        procured the names may be relieved of this infamous charge against us of
                        forgery." <lb/></p>
                    <p>Dews knew, when he was writing, that the object of obtaining the lists of
                        signers was not to "injure <emph rend="italic">us </emph> in every possible
                        manner," even if Dews and Todd alone are intended to be meant by the term
                            <emph rend="italic">us </emph>, and events have <emph rend="italic">not
                        </emph> proved that the object, though the result of the republication of
                        the names of signers has been to call forth charges against the circulators
                        of that petition, which, unless done away with, may injure them, but not in
                            <emph rend="italic">every possible manner</emph>. He knew that those who
                        made public their statements did so <emph rend="italic">voluntarily </emph>
                        and not from intimidation from any source. </p>
                    <p>The reason alleged for the withdrawal of the original petition is "to relieve
                        those, who procured the names, of the infamous charge of forgery." The
                        petition is again in the hands of Dews, and according to his letter, it is
                        incumbent on him to exhibit the petition and show that the signatures of
                        parties, who deny signing it at all, are genuine, and not forged by the
                        circulators of it. It seems there were four circulators of the petition,
                        each making affidavit to the list of signers obtained by himself, viz: W. J.
                        Dews, Jas. Todd, J. Frank Davis and John D. Sheets. Each one of these
                        parties swore that his respective list of signers were citizens of Augusta
                        and signed in his presence. Now some of these signers say they did not sign
                        this paper at all, and hence the necessity to show the petition and prove
                        the signatures to be genuine.</p>
                    <p>The exhibition of the petition may or may not prove the genuineness of the
                        signatures but we are at a loss to see how the charge of false swearing
                        against some of the circulators is to be done away with. They each make
                        affidavit to the list of signers obtained by themselves respectively, in
                        which it appears that they swear the names were signed in their presence and
                        the parties "<emph rend="italic">are citizens of Augusta County.</emph>" Now
                        we know that ten are citizens of Rockbridge, one or more of Rockingham, and
                        we learn that as many as six are citizens of Pendleton County, West
                        Virginia. Whether the charge made by some signers, that their names were
                        signed to the petition without authority, will be proved or disproved by the
                        exhibition of the petition remains to be seen, but we would like exceedingly
                        to see how the party or parties, who swore that the six citizens of West
                        Virginia, one or more citizens of Rockingham, and ten or more citizens of
                        Rockbridge, are citizens of Augusta, will relieve themselves of the dilemma
                        in which they are placed. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Segar</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Senator Trumbull has withdrawn the "Dews petition" from the
                    Senate floor after receiving a letter from W. J. Dews which claimed that the
                    signers of the petition were being pressured and intimidated into disclaiming
                    their affiliation with it. The editor disputes Dews' account, arguing that those
                    "who made public their statements did so voluntarily" and that Dews should
                    display the original petition to the community to see if any of the signatures
                    are forgeries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>News Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Avis</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. John Avis, who served as Provost Marshal at Staunton during the war,
                    was recently elected mayor of Charlestown, West Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Latest News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Senate passed the bill admitting Colorado into the Union
                    over President Johnson's veto and struck a provision from the Reconstruction
                    Bill that would have disfranchised Confederates until 1870. The House passed a
                    tax bill that levies an export duty of five cents per pound on cotton and passed
                    a bill to continue in force and amend the Freedmen's Bureau Bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.01.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items--Proceedings of County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Court appointed the following conductors for holding elections for
                        militia officers, viz: Captains and 1st and 2nd Lieutenants, under act
                        passed March 2nd 1866, reorganizing the militia:</p>
                    <p>J. Givens Fulton, R. Turk and F. F. Sterrett, for 160th Reg't; Jas. W.
                        Newton, M. W. D. Hogshead and Jas. Henry for the 93rd Regiment; and Samuel
                        McCune, Thos. W. McClung and Jas. W. Patrick for the 32nd Regiment.</p>
                    <p>Henry Woodson and Peter Ramsom (Freedmen) charged severally with felony,
                        examined and remanded to Circuit Court for trial.</p>
                    <p>Report of Commissioner J. M. Lilley, laying off Middle brook and Brownsburg
                        Turnpike into precincts, received and confirmed and the following Surveyors
                        appointed: Jno. Nunan, Wm. M. Bell, W. P. Cale, M. W. D. Hogshead, A. A.
                        Sproul and J. F. Hite.</p>
                    <p>John Miller charged with petit larcery was fined $50 and ordered to be
                        imprisoned for six months in county jail.</p>
                    <p>George W. Groiner and James W. Hudson, surveyors of road were ordered to
                        rebuild bridges on old Staunton and Scottsville Turnpike, over mill race at
                        Waynesboro' and Christians Creek, near Peck's Mill.</p>
                    <p>Leopold Loeb indicted for selling goods without license fined $20.</p>
                    <p>Nolle prosequis were entered in cases of Gabriel Hirsh, George Greaver, James
                        E. Carson, and Daniel Brown on indictments found at former Grand Juries.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>F. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsom</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nunan</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>W. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Groiner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loeb</ln>
                        <fn>Leopold</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hirsh</ln>
                        <fn>Gabriel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greaver</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes the recent proceedings of the County Court, including the
                    appointment of conductors to hold elections for militia officers and surveyors
                    for the Middlebrook and Brownsburg Turnpike.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Abingdon Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We copy, with pleasure the following extract from the Abingdon Virginian,
                        which shows the appreciation of that community for the Rev. Wm. A. Harris,
                        who has been for several years past a resident of that place, and will
                        shortly take charge of Wesleyan Female Institute in Staunton. We trust Mr.
                        Harris may be compensated for the change by the increased prosperity of the
                        Institute under his charge.</p>
                    <p>"The removal of Mr. Harris will be a great loss to this community, and
                        however his services may have been estimated heretofore, they will be more
                        fully appreciated after he shall have left us. As an instructor of young
                        ladies, and as a high-toned christian gentleman and scholar, and he has but
                        few superiors; and as the manager and master-spirit of a school of
                        comprehensive grade, he has fully established the reputation which preceded
                        him here. He took charge of Martha Washington at its opening the year before
                        the war, and when the enterprise was an uncertain and rather unpromising
                        experiment. It opened successfully, and before the war cloud burst upon us,
                        no college in the South had more brilliant prospects, nor has greater
                        satisfaction ever been given as to the proficiency of pupils. * * * * * *</p>
                    <p>"We congratulate the people of Staunton in securing his services, and if
                        unremitting industry, through scholarship, and a conscientious discharge of
                        duty can resuscitate and put in successful operation the Wesleyan Female
                        Institute, Mr. Harris will do that thing."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Abingdon paper praises Rev. William Harris, who is leaving Abingdon to
                    take charge of the Wesleyan Female Institute in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>AT the election held on Thursday, May 24th a very small vote was cast. Samuel
                        M. Paul was elected Sheriff.</p>
                    <p>The following gentlemen were elected Constables: Thomas Marshall, 1st
                        (Staunton) District; William Craig, 2nd (Staunton) District; William M.
                        Bush, Waynesboro' Dist.; G. M. Apple, Greenville Dist.; E. J. Bell, Mount
                        Solon District; A. Rumisel, Middle brook Dist.; H. G. McCausland, New Hope
                        District; A. J. Grooms, Mt. Sidney District; and John H. Heizer, Churchville
                        District.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>G. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>E. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCausland</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the results of elections held May 24 for constables and sheriff,
                    where Samuel Paul was elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>SUNDAY night last the Spring House of John B. Engleman, of this place, was
                        broken open and robbed of milk, butter, CROCKS, buckets, lot of soap and
                        half barrel of vinegar. Such thefts are getting too common in these times
                        and should be put a stop to, even if it is necessary to resort to
                    shooting.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Spring House of John Engleman was broken open and robbed
                    of various food items and opines that "such thefts are getting too common in
                    these times and should be put a stop to, even if it is necessary to resort to
                    shooting."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WE learn that the President of the Churchville Oil Company has returned from
                        the oil regions of West Virginia. His examination and conference with
                        experienced oil men there have tended to increase his confidence in the
                        success of the company. He has employed an experienced auger man, and bought
                        an engine and necessary tools. The Directors will meet in Staunton, Saturday
                        next, and desire to make arrangements to commence operations immediately.
                        About 20 shares of stock remain to be taken. The books will be closed June
                        5th. Those who desire to take stock in this promising enterprise can do so
                        by leaving their names at this or the "Spectator" office.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The president of the Churchville Oil Company has returned from the oil
                    regions of West Virginia and is confident in the success of the company. The
                    Directors will meet in Staunton next Saturday and hope begin operations
                    immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Hess, second son of William Hess, fell 35 feet from a tree last
                    Saturday, breaking his back. He is expected to recover.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Todd</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roher</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martin Roher denies ever signing the "Dews-Todd petition" that has caused a
                    local controversy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Henry P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mollie Bear, of Rockingham, and Henry Cease, of Staunton, were married on
                    May 17 by Rev. J. W. Howe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engleman</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Engleman and Peter Frenger, both of Augusta, were married on May
                    16 by Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickinson</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Julia A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>H. B. Dickinson, of Charlotte County, and Julia Crawford, of Augusta, were
                    married on May 29 by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Amanda Hunter, wife of W. L. Hunter, died on May 19. She was 37 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.06.01.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
