<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.05.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/04/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-05-11">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.11.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.11.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have never regarded President Johnson as the especial champion of the
                        South. It is true that he has stood as a bulwark against the surges of
                        fanatical hate which would have overwhelmed our sunny land but for his
                        timely and most determined opposition, but not especially on account of the
                        South did or does he oppose the huge attempts at a central despotism. To
                        suppose him influenced thus would deprive him of the title of patriot and
                        statesman which he has so justly earned since he came into position and
                        power. On his accession to the Presidency he found the country just emerging
                        from a vast civil war, with the antagonism of the past grown into seemingly
                        unconquerable hate from the contests of the past four years, which
                        overshadowed with a threatening cloud the prospects of a speedy and much
                        desired peace. Difficulties of a monstrous character loomed up to be
                        overcome, and his path was beset at every step by obstacles real and
                        imaginary, which would have chilled the heart of any but the most undaunted.
                        With fixed and patriotic purpose in view, the preservation of the Union, he
                        looked around for the means of accomplishing it and found ready to his hands
                        the Constitution of the United States, which had been rolled up during our
                        intestine struggle, and nearly lost sight of. He calmly unrolled it, and
                        found its bright face tarnished here and there by the mould of the last few
                        years, but enough of it left to preserve his native Country and its
                        government. Scarcely found, ere the desire for a new Constitution shows
                        itself in the insatiate mania for amendments, calculated to pervert its
                        primitive intent. Backing this desire is a large and powerful body of men,
                        whose representatives hold the next promineat places in the government and
                        whose front looks bold and threatening as did the Austrian Phalanxes to the
                        brave Swiss at the ever memorable Lempach.-With serried ranks and lances
                        drawn this reckless band of men moved forward for the destruction of the
                        charter of our country's liberty. What remained for the opponents of their
                        diabolical purposes? They must made to quaid before liberty's undaunted
                        array or all is lost. In this dire extremity, counseling calmness and
                        nerving his then small but trusty band of patriots by his brave example,
                        like Arnold Winkelried of old, with the cry "make way for liberty," he
                        hurled himself upon the destroyers of his country's Constitution, receiving
                        their thrusts in his own person and causing them to hesitate, waver and
                        retreat. His act receives the commendation of the great and good of the
                        land, who desire peace and prosperity, to secure which they have risen
                        superior to the passions of an hour.</p>
                    <p>Because the preservation of the, Constitution for which Andrew Johnson has so
                        earnestly striven, would secure directly their rights to the South, leads
                        many to believe him the especial defender of our oppressed section. We would
                        call the attention of all such to the fact that the Constitution, lost sight
                        of, perverted or destroyed would be equally burdensome to every State in the
                        Union, and would utterly deprive them every right, save what might be
                        vouchsafed by an unlicensed Central Government, or, more properly speaking,
                        Consolidated Despotism. To prevent this president Johnson has thrust himself
                        forward as the defender of the Constitution, and, knowing no North, no
                        South, no East, no West, is battling to preserve the liberties of the whole
                        country. That he will succeed, the patriotic masses of the north rallying to
                        his standard give every promise, and while counseling his sympathizers in
                        the North to persevere in their course, we of the South can only wish the
                        President, and his patriot followers, "God speed" in their noble efforts to
                        preserve the Constitution and the liberties of our entire people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Disputes the notion that President Johnson is "the especial champion of the
                    South," arguing instead that he is "the defender of the Constitution, and,
                    knowing no North, no South, no East, no West, is battling to preserve the
                    liberties of the whole country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We call the attention of our readers to the communication of "Teacher" in
                        another column. His suggestions are very good, and we commend them to the
                        consideration of the people, and especially to the Teachers of Virginia. A
                        system of text books by a convention of teachers of the State would
                        accomplish the end so much desired by "Teacher," preventing the necessity of
                        purchasing every new edition, gotten out with some pretended improvement
                        simply to sell, or other text books at every change of schools or teachers,
                        and also obviate the necessity of using books which contain such
                        objectionable features as those spoken of by 'Teacher.' Will not our
                        confreres of the Press in the State take this subject in hand, and urge upon
                        the teachers the calling of such convention as [UNCLEAR] at an early
                    day?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the letter from "Teacher" found in another column of the Vindicator
                    and echoes his call for a statewide conference of teachers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>03</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:-I desire through your medium of your
                        paper to call the attention of Teachers to some facts or rather evils, which
                        ought to be corrected, if remedies can be found. All who are engaged in
                        teaching have to a greater or less degree experienced much difficulty in
                        classifying their pupils from the following cause, the great difficulty in
                        obtaining suitable text books. Not that there is a want of variety from
                        which to make a selection, on the contrary, the variety is so numerous and
                        the number of editions so multiplied that to have uniformity is impossible,
                        unless teachers require new pupils to purchase new books and these books
                        must be changed every year, to keep up with the different editions. These
                        various changes are gotten up more for the purpose of giving sale to books,
                        than from a desire to improve them: in other words it is a scheme to make
                        money. So great is the mania on this subject, i. e., to make money, that we
                        may expect that the time is not far distant, when we shall have no pure
                        Latin or Greek unless it is just published by some New England
                        speculator.-How long will the people of this State, and especially the
                        teachers, suffer themselves to be thus imposed upon? Have they examined the
                        last edition of Goodrich's History of the U. S.? If so, they can longer use
                        it in their schools; for are not the chapters it contains in regard to the
                        late war offensive and insulting, besides being false and unfair? To prevent
                        these abuses, let the teachers of the State hold a meeting, composed of
                        delegates from different sections and adopt a system of text books for the
                        State of Virginia. Then we would have uniformity of action, and the pupil
                        when he changed teachers would not have to change his books, and in this way
                        much expense would be saved the patron.-Let these books be published in the
                        State, in fine let us be independent of all New England and New England
                        influence. Believing that all teachers will concur with me, that much good
                        could be accomplished by a convention of the teachers, I think a mere
                        suggestion for it sufficient. </p>
                    <p>TEACHER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Teacher</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Teacher" calls for a statewide conference of teachers to adopt a uniform
                    system of textbooks for the state. The author calls for all books to be
                    published in the state, so that both teachers and students will be "independent
                    of all New England and New England influence."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE Fire Company of Staunton made a grand turn out, by torch light, on
                        Saturday evening last, and paraded through our principal streets to the fine
                        strains of our "Stonewall" Band. They number about 100 members of whom about
                        80 turned out on the evening mentioned, and we do not hesitate, but take
                        pleasure in saying that no Fire Company anywhere surpasses ours in the
                        excellence of its material. As a citizen of Staunton we are proud-very proud
                        of this company, and we think they should be encouraged to the fullest
                        extent by our people. They need a uniform which will not only be a neat on a
                        parade, but also serviceable at a fire and as many of the members can not
                        easily spare the amount necessary to uniform themselves, and are not
                        property holders, but are willing to devote their services and labor for the
                        good of our people, we suggest to the ladies of Staunton to hold a fair for
                        the purpose of uniforming them, and, if there be a surplus, to laying the
                        foundation of a good library for the company. To the property holders, and
                        others interested, of Staunton, we propose, by a subscription of $5 each, to
                        purchase a <emph rend="italic">new </emph> and <emph rend="italic">good
                        </emph> engine for this company. The only draw back to the company is the
                        want of a <emph rend="italic">good </emph> engine for this company. The only
                        draw back to the company is the want of a <emph rend="italic">good </emph>
                        engine, for there is a full sufficiency of willing hands to work one and
                        render efficient service with it in an emergency. We are satisfied that
                        every property-holder in Staunton, or other person interested in the
                        protection of property here, will willingly subscribe, and we call upon the
                        company to appoint several parties to circulate a petition among them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Fire Company of Staunton paraded by torch light last Saturday evening
                    in Staunton and the editor praises their "services and labor" and urges "the
                    ladies of Staunton to hold a fair for the purpose of uniforming them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THROUGH the kindness of our friend, W. A. Burnett, County Clerk, we have been
                        furnished with the following list of county and Circuit Court Jurors, drawn
                        for the May and June terms respectively. <lb/></p>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">List of Jurors drawn for May term of County Court.</emph>
                        <lb/>
                    </p>
                    <p>Jerome H B Seller, D W Link, Jno Roudebush, Henry Crist, Jr., Benj Stuart,
                        Samuel Plecker, H M Loffland, Wm Armstrong, C W Baylor, Joseph Wright, Jos
                        Miller, Linden B Waller, W K Wallace, S. Taylor, Noah Miller, J M Brown, Geo
                        C Patterson, Washington Swink, Jno Seawright, Daniel Fall, Wm Lotts, A J
                        Hunter, Jno Layman, G C Hawpe, J C Cockran, Casper Koiner, Sr., Solomon
                        Wine, C W Burress. <lb/></p>
                    <p>List of Jurors drawn for June term of Circuit Court. <lb/></p>
                    <p>Wm Housemen, C T Palmer, Wm B Crawford, Jacob Swarzel, Jr., B F McNutt, H K
                        Eakle, W A Mann, Nicholas Croushorn, Benj Carricofe, J H Coiner, W J Larew,
                        W D Ewing, Henry Rader, J M Clarke, Andrew Yong, J W Hudson, Andrew
                        Crawford, G W Swoope, Jno Bumgardner, J N Hunter, Adam Stover, Jacob Hoover,
                        S F Miller, Henry Deffenbaugh, D S Bell, Jos Driver, William Phillips, E A
                        Fulcher.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seller</ln>
                        <fn>Jerome H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roudebush</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Loffland</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waller</ln>
                        <fn>Linden B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fall</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotts</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Layman</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cockran</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Casper</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wine</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burress</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houseman</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>C. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swartzel</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNutt</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>H. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croushorn</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carricofe</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rader</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deffenbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Driver</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulcher</ln>
                        <fn>E. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of jurors for the May and June terms of the county and circuit
                    courts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>IN our last issue we mentioned that a petition, purporting to be signed by a
                        number of citizens of Staunton, praying the return of troops, &amp;c.,
                        for the protection of loyal men, was presented by Senator Trumbull to the U.
                        S. Senate. We were furnished with a copy of the petition and its signers but
                        a short time before going to press and invert it for the information of our
                        readers and also as an act of justice to those Union men among us, who,
                        though solicited, declined to sign this petition, being unwilling to give
                        this monstrous falsehood the sanction of their names. We believe many of
                        these names have been signed without authority by second parties, as we find
                        several on the list who declared to us that they never signed or authorized
                        another to sign this petition for them. We now call on those parties who did
                        not sign the petition, but whose names are found appended thereto, to notify
                        us and we will take pleasure in giving publicity to the fact. For the
                        present we merely call attention to the petition and its signers.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">P. S.</emph> When the affidavit was made before W. A.
                        Burnett, it was simply to a list of names unaccompanied by any petition
                        whatever. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Referring to the petition from "loyal citizens of Staunton" recently
                    presented in the Senate by Senator Trumbull, the editor suggests that many of
                    the names were signed by second parties without authorization and urges those
                    whose names are on the petition to write the paper if they did not in fact sign
                    it. For the full text of the petition, see the Spectator, 5/15/66.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>SOME time during last month, an infant about two months old, was left in the
                        portico of the residence of Mr. GEO. K. Keiser, near Waynesboro', between 9
                        and 10 o'clock at night. The child was wrapped up in a cloak and beside it a
                        little willow basket, in which was found the following note:</p>
                    <p>To Mrs. C. G. MILLER:--Please receive this child and be kind to it. It was
                        born in Rockbridge county, of highly respectable parents. Her christen name
                        is Mary Barton. Be kind to her and you will receive your reward hereafter.</p>
                    <p>THE MOTHER.</p>
                    <p>Mrs. Sampson Pelter, Jr., who lives in Waynesboro', has kindly taken charge
                        of the infant and will no doubt take good care of it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>Sampson</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Last month an infant was left at the residence of George Keiser, near
                    Waynesboro, with a note asking them to care for the infant. The baby is now in
                    the care of Mrs. Sampson Pelter, Jr.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meredith</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werts</ln>
                        <fn>L. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jno. Sheets, of Mt. Sidney, reports that he helped bury a number of the
                    dead after the battle of Piedmont and will designate the graves to anyone
                    looking to recover the body of a friend killed in that engagement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE remains of our gallant young townsman, Thos. M. Garber, youngest son of
                        Albert J. Garber, Esq., color bearer of the 12th Virginia Cavalry, who fell
                        mortally wounded in a cavalry engagement near Upperville, Va., were brought
                        to Staunton on Tuesday week and re-interred in Thornrose Cemetery.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Albert J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The remains of Thomas Garber, color bearer for the 12th Virginia Calvary
                    were returned to Staunton last week and interred in Thornrose Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ISAAC CHANY, colored, who was tried by a military commission at this place
                        for the murder of a Mr. Geralds and wife, near the Natural Bridge,
                        Rockabridge county, and sentenced to be hung on Friday last, was reprieved
                        on Thursday last by order of the War Department.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chany</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Chany, who was tries by a military commission in Staunton and
                    transported to Richmond last week to be executed was reprieved by the War
                    Department the day before his execution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>ROBT. LEWIS, colored, charged with stealing several watches from the Adams
                        Express office, waved his right to an examination before the corporation
                        Court on Wednesday last, and was sent on to the Circuit Court for trial.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>Robt.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Lewis, charged with stealing watches from the Adams Express office,
                    will soon be tried by the Circuit Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>R. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. A. M. Fauntleroy, of Staunton, and Sallie Conrad, of Winchester, were
                    married on April 26 by Rev. J. R. Graham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.05.11.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
