<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.08.10">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/26/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-08-10">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.08.10.01">
            <div type="e">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>The Social Problem</head>
                <origin>Washington Republican</origin>
                <commentary>"The Washington Republican has a just perception of the enormous
                    practical difficulties of the problem in which emancipation has involved the
                    country; but which the Radicals fancy they can solve by an act of Congress or an
                    amendment to the Constitution, and require the South to settle at the drop of a
                    hat. It says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Washington Republican has a just perception of the enormous practical
                        difficulties of the problem in which emancipation has involved the country;
                        but which the Radicals fancy they can solve by an act of Congress or an
                        amendment to the Constitution and require the South to settle ast the drop
                        of a hat. It says:</p>
                    <p>The sudden abolition of slavery has suddenly forced the people of the South
                        where existed into the trial of an experiment which has never yet peacefully
                        succeeded, -- the experiment of so adjusting the laws and modifying the
                        temper, habits and bearings of Anglo-Saxons and free negroes dwelling
                        together upon terms of civil equality (social equality is out of the
                        question) in the some communities as to satisfy both and produce a condition
                        of mutual contentment. To zealots unadvised of the struggles which have
                        occurred heretofore under such or similar circumstances, it appears to be a
                        subject of no concern whatever.</p>
                    <p>To the Radicals in and out of the present Congress, judging from their
                        flippant method of treating it, it appears to be a n experiment which may be
                        resolved by the application of the dreams of Thaddeus Stevens -- an enforced
                        application of the equality doctrines of the Declaration of Independence.
                        But our best informed and most sagacious and considerate statesmen, whilst
                        impudent reformers push their notions upon and into the communities where
                        slavery has recently existed before their present wounds are [unclear], will
                        produce a war of races of a very terrible character. The reason for this
                        apprehension are too numerous for a newspaper article. They would fill a
                        volume.</p>
                    <p>The slaves of the ancients belonged to the same race s the masters. They were
                        trophies of war, and frequently, as the cases of Aesop and Terence, the
                        superiors of their masters in intellect and learning. Freedom was the only
                        distinction between them, and when this boon was conferred they came upon a
                        common level. And, although it was found that a prejudice against those who
                        had been enslaved lasted long after the period of the enfranchisement, the
                        freedmen bore so close a resemblance to the free born that it became after a
                        while impossible to distinguish one class from the other. Slavery in the
                        United States has been united with the visible badge of color. The negro has
                        been the subject of it. Doubly dishonored by color and the fact that his
                        race has been enslaved from time to time out of mind, the colored freedmen
                        is in a far worse condition for employing equal civil rights with his former
                        master than were the slaves of antiquity. This led De Tocqueville to remark
                        that "the law may abolish in form the institution of negro slavery, but God
                        alone can obliterate the traces of its existence."</p>
                    <p>In attempting to being our freedmen into harmony with the white men we have,
                        besides the fact of former servitude, three sorts of prejudices to contend
                        with -- the instinctive prejudice of color, the prejudice of the former
                        masters, and the prejudice of the race. These, separately or combined, have,
                        in all known instances of negro emancipation, been fruitful and never-ending
                        causes of discontentment and discord, so that whenever the whites have been
                        the most numerous they have found it necessary to their personal safety to
                        keep the blacks in a subordinate and servile position; and wherever the
                        negroes have been the strongest they either have, or have striven to destroy
                        the whites.</p>
                    <p>And when we remember how difficult and slow has been the process in every
                        country, inclusive of our own, of rooting out the distinctions of
                        aristocracy which we inherited from the old World, and of preventing the
                        growth of others, such as aristocracies of wealth and of sect, scarcely less
                        prejudicial to everything like equality and harmony, we are compelled to
                        acknowledge that it is not strange that no experiment of the kind we are now
                        trying has ever succeeded. There have been, and yet are, rightful we do not
                        say but actually nevertheless these intrinsic differences hitherto between
                        the two races, which statesmen, and particularly those in charge of our
                        Government, are not at liberty to disregard. It is the full knowledge of
                        these, and of the horrid massacres and wars they have heretofore produced,
                        which admonishes the President of the necessity of moving in the work of
                        reconstructing Southern society according to the altered condition of
                        things, with the utmost circumspection.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses concern that the course pursued by the Radical Congress may
                    "produce a war of races of a very terrible character" and urges leaders not to
                    ignore the "intrinsic differences" between the races when making policy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.08.10.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Before and during the war, the Southern master confided in hi slave and the
                        slave in turn relied upon his master for the sustenance of himself and
                        family, and protection from wrong at the hands of others. Nor need we say to
                        those who are familiar with that of which we write that this confidence on
                        the one hand and reliance on the other, was but rarely abused. Since the
                        emancipation of slaves, however, an influence has been at work to sever the
                        friendship which has so long existed between the whites and blacks of the
                        South. Those men in high places whose duty it was to have sided in restoring
                        amicable feelings between the lately hostile sections, with but few
                        exceptions, have rather endeavored to make the alienation more permanent and
                        lasting. To accomplish this more surely have their many acts of legislation
                        been passed, which, in no small degree, have tended to create distrust, want
                        of confidence, and even ill-feeling between Southern whites and blacks, who
                        are still, to a vast extent, dependent upon each other, and especially are
                        the blacks dependent upon the whites. Men have even been sent to, or are
                        found in certain communities, so depraved or lost to all principle, as to
                        instigate the colored people to deed which must redound to their future
                        disadvantage, if they do not, as in several instances already, result in the
                        death of many of them.</p>
                    <p>With the allurements held out shortly after the close of the war, it was not
                        to be wondered at that many negroes ceased to work and gave themselves up to
                        idle or vicious lives. Soon, however, their necessities or good sense,
                        together with the continued kindness of their former masters, induced the
                        vast majority to resume their work and they bid fair to become again useful
                        members of society. This did not suit those men who had arisen through
                        intestine struggle to the surface. They must needs to keep alive an internal
                        strife or sink forever. The various disturbances we hear of are the fruits
                        of their efforts, and, while advantaging neither party to the struggle,
                        serve to advance the interests of the instigators and their abettors. We
                        have not, and we are glad to see that others do not lay the blame to the
                        poor emancipated slave, who, without false tutoring, would have accommodated
                        himself to his changed condition and been useful as a laborer, as is
                        witnessed where the vile teachings of malicious agitators have not
                        insinuated themselves, and our treatment to those who conduct themselves
                        with the propriety should be just as kind as at any period of our past
                        lives.</p>
                    <p>But to those pretended friends of the poor African, who teach him to distrust
                        his early friends, the Southern whites, and incite him to open hostility
                        against them, in order that they may be advantaged thereby, too much of
                        culpability can no attach. All the blood that has been spilled by their
                        teachings in upon their heads and a fearful reckoning is in store, which
                        sooner or later must and will overtake them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes "those pretended friends of the poor African, who teach him to
                    distrust his early friends, the Southern whites, and incite him to open
                    rebellion against them," arguing that were it not for their "false tutoring" the
                    former slave "would have accommodated himself to his changed condition and been
                    useful as a laborer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Pass Him Around</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>About the 23d of July Col. Jas. H. Hardin, who claimed to be a Kentuckian by
                        birth, and to have served on the Staff of Gen. Breckenridge, presented a
                        check for $300 purporting to have been drawn by the "<emph rend="italic"
                            >Augusta National Bank of Georgia</emph>" on Colgate &amp; Stratton,
                        No 54 Exchange Place, New York, and made payable to Col. Jas. H. Hardin, to
                        the First national Bank of Staunton, where it was cashed, only after Col.
                        Hardin, who was a stranger was vouched for by a well known citizen of
                        Staunton. Upon the check being forwarded to Colgate &amp; Stratton it
                        was protested and returned without remark. Thereupon a telegram was sent to
                        Augusta, the check was ascertained to be a forgery and that a man calling
                        himself Col. Jas. H. Hardin has used similar forged drafts before. We learn
                        that the national Valley Bank of Staunton cashed a check for $50 for Col.
                        Hardin, purporting to be drawn by a Louisville firm on another house in New
                        York, and upon being forwarded, was also returned protested.--Col. H. is a
                        man of fine address, and as he is still at large it would be well for the
                        press to circulate these facts to prevent imposition on others. We learn
                        that he had lately married a lady in Monroe, Michigan.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardin</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that a man calling himself Col. Jas. H. Hardin recently cashed a
                    forged check at the First National Bank of Staunton and has done the same thing
                    elsewhere.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The citizens of Richmond and other places have been very much disturbed
                        lately by the parading and drilling of negroes at all hours of the night.
                        Gen. Terry has issued an order prohibiting in this military department,
                        during the existence of martial law, any organizations for the purpose of
                        drill or military instruction other than the militia organized by the
                        Governor of Virginia. This will put an end to the annoyances complained
                    of.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that "the citizens of Richmond and other places have been very much
                    disturbed lately by the parading and drilling of negroes at all hours of the
                    night," a practice that has just been prohibited by Gen. Terry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that cholera has reached epidemic proportions in New York, where
                    two hundred died from the disease last week alone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>The Southern States to Vote in the Presidential Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following pointed remarks occur in an editorial in the President's organ
                        of Wednesday:</p>
                    <p>It will be recollected by our reader who have kept the run of this paper,
                        that we intimated a suspicion several months ago that the Radical members of
                        Congress had entered into a conspiracy against the Constitution to shut out
                        the electoral vote n 1868 of certain southern States, and that about a month
                        ago we stated more clearly what it was. As no Senator, Representative, or
                        Radical newspaper has presumed to deny the allegation, we take it to have
                        been true.</p>
                    <p>It is a point that cannot be carried out with impunity. We do not believe it
                        can be consummated without bloodshed. At all events, if the electoral votes
                        of the States thus unlawfully excluded will elect a candidate for President
                        who shall not be elected without them, the people will find a way to have
                        them counted, by putting the proper President elect into the executive
                        office and maintaining him there, by force if necessary.</p>
                    <p>The exclusion of ten States from representation in Congress goes to the verge
                        of public forbearance. No further outrage can, in our opinion, be superadded
                        to it without breaking the public peace and exposing the country to the
                        horrors of another civil war, in which the people of the excluded States
                        would have the sympathy of the civilized world.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Southern states cannot be prevented from participating in
                    the 1868 presidential elections "without breaking the public peace and exposing
                    the country to the horrors of another civil war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.08.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seawright</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Among the most recent recipients of pardons are five residents of Augusta:
                    Jas. Guy, Chesley Kinney, John McClure, George Seawright and W. H. Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCraddock</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A "difficulty" occurred at Jno. Beck's Bar Room on Monday evening when John
                    White was "severely handled" by two patrons, John McCraddock and James Gallaher.
                    Gallaher and McCraddock were arrested Tuesday morning and will be tried in the
                    next session of the Hustings Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the charges against Peter Hanger Jr. for defrauding the
                    government by making false returns of distilled spirits have been found to be
                    groundless.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Loring</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turner</ln>
                        <fn>Job</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Loring Turner, the youngest son of Job Turner, recently fell from a
                    distance of 30 feet while climbing a tree. No bones were broken, and Loring is
                    "rapidly recovering from his bruises."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arthur</ln>
                        <fn>Dr.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The chimney of Dr. Arthur's residence caught fire last Thursday and spread
                    to the roof of the National Hotel. The fire was extinguished quickly with little
                    damage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLauglin</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Phillip McLauglin was arrested by Deputy Sargeant Kurtz last Tuesday and
                    brought before the Mayor, who fined him one dollar for firing a pistol within
                    the corporate limits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.08.10.04">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A slave ship was recently captured in Pensacola Bay with 150 freedmen on
                    board, bound for Cuba. Men from Mobile, New Orleans and New York have been
                    implicated in the kidnapping.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
