<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.07.27">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/26/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-07-27">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.27.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.27.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Raymond, Republican member of Congress and editor of the New York Times,
                        has in a late communication to his paper laid open the intention of the
                        Radicals, in a certain event, to inaugurate another civil war. A resolution
                        was recently passed by the House of Representatives calling on the States to
                        organize, equip and drill their militia, and directing the immediate
                        distribution of two-thirds of the arms, ordinance and ammunition in
                        possession of the General Government among the loyal States, but to be
                        postponed as to the States lately in rebellion, <emph rend="italic">until
                            further orders</emph>. This Mr. Raymond says is the first step towards
                        another civil war. The radicals believe if the fall elections result in the
                        choice of northern Democrats, enough, together with the Southern
                        Representatives, to constitute a majority of the House, they will claim to
                        be the Congress and will be recognized as such by the President, and will be
                        protected in their convening by military force. They assert on the other
                        hand that if the Union members returned from the loyal States constitute a
                        majority from those States, they will claim to be the only legal Congress,
                        and do not conceal their determination in this event to appeal to force, and
                        in the language of a leader, to "drive the rival Congress, the President and
                        his Cabinet and supporters into the Potomac." </p>
                    <p>They pretend to believe that the President intends to disperse the present
                        Congress, on its re-assembling in December, if it refuses to admit the
                        Southern members. Mr. Raymond says no such a purpose can be ascribed to
                        President Johnson, but that it serves the purpose intended-to arouse the
                        North and prepare for a resort to force upon the reassembling of the
                        Fortieth Congress, in extra or regular session, and that this determination
                        is avowed.</p>
                    <p>Taken in connection with the fact that leading Republicans have declared
                        their belief that an issue of <emph rend="italic">force </emph> was rapidly
                        approaching and that preparations must be made to meet it, it is possible,
                        and indeed not improbable, that this country is on the eve of another civil
                        strife. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that recent actions by the Radicals in Congress indicate that they
                    are prepared, "in a certain event, to inaugurate another civil war" in order to
                    maintain control of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Tennessee Legislature recently ratified the 14th Amendment
                    despite not having a quorum of their members present. Nevertheless, a joint
                    resolution for the readmission of Tennessee into the Union was immediately
                    offered in Congress and passed the House by a vote of 125 to 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The expectation of many, so often disappointed, with reference to the
                        Atlantic Cable is likely now to be realized. The greatest precautions have
                        been taken to render it a success, and vast strides made in the construction
                        of a trustworthy cable and the improvement of the instruments with which it
                        is to be successfully operated. The shore end of the cable was landed at
                        Valentia on the 6th inst., and the Wm. Corry proceeded to sea immediately,
                        paying out slowly. The work of laying the shore end, thirty miles of cable,
                        was accomplished in less than twelve hours and its insulation found to be
                        perfect. The main cable was to be spliced to the shore end on the 13th
                        inst., when the laying of it was to commence. By the time our next paper
                        goes to press, it may be possible that European news as late as that
                        received from the cities of this Continent, may be reported in the papers of
                        the day. The Atlantic cable successfully laid, what will be the next great
                        undertaking of the world?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the completion of the Atlantic Cable, which make news from Europe
                    as current as news from throughout the U. S., and asks "what will be the next
                    great undertaking of the world?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:-- On Saturday last the people of the
                        Greenville neighborhood gave a barbecue and extended a general invitation to
                        all participate with them. Among a number, we repaired to the appointed
                        place, where a large crowd of the good people of the neighborhood, and their
                        invited guests, were assembled to do honor to the occasion. How we arrived
                        there can only be realized by those who have jogged over a rough road in any
                        army ambulance with a heavy load. The monotonous journey of twelve [UNCLEAR]
                        lengthened out by the anxiety to get to the grounds, was relieved with an
                        occasional song-lively repartee or the frolicsome pranks of "Ready," who,
                        with hat full two sizes two large, played the drunkard, in the attempt to
                        light his Virginia weed from the unfired one of his neighbor, to the no
                        small delight of the party and the intense gratification of the small boys
                        along the road, and the flaxen haired maiden, whose disheveled tresses were
                        seen but for a moment, as the lumbering vehicle whirled along with its noisy
                        occupants. </p>
                    <p>With merry time we arrived at the selected spot. The old "Stonewall"
                        Band-noble fellows, who followed Stonewall Jackson in his wonderful marches
                        and brilliant campaigns, were also there and made the woods echo with the
                        sweet strains.</p>
                    <p>After the rendition of several pieces by the Band, Capt. Jas. Bumgardner in a
                        few appropriate remarks introduced in succession, Capt. Powell Harrison and
                        Maj. Howe Y. Peyton, who delivered very appropriate and well-conceived
                        addresses, which were received with tumultuous applause by the large
                        auditory. The speeches over, several excellent pieces were performed by the
                        Band whose sweet strains were the delight of all and who will ever be
                        welcomed to Greenville, when dinner was announced, which was well served and
                        ample, not only sufficing for the large crowd of whites in attendance, but
                        abundantly supplying the wants of the colored persons present, who were
                        invited to participate after the whites were served.</p>
                    <p>The Band continued to discourse sweet music until half-past three o'clock
                        when the crowd began to disperse-some to their homes, others to spend the
                        remainder of the evening in Greenville.</p>
                    <p>Greenville was in a state of hilarity that evening. Such a day could scarcely
                        pass by without exciting the bellicose passions of some as was the case on
                        this occasion. The Bully of South Bottom was there, and altho' he made a
                        Bull Run retreat from the grounds in the morning in full pursuit by "Johnny
                        Reb," yet on reaching Greenville he recovered himself, and arming with shot
                        gun and backshot boasted his determination to stand his ground and maintain
                        his "posish."-"Johnny," being aware that "Bull Run" with deadly firearm
                        awaited his approach, stole a march on and flanked him, and, ere he was
                        aware of it, made him prisoner at the mouth of death dealing Colt. After
                        sharp manoevreing, and loud entreaties, on the part of "Bull Run," "Johnny"
                        released him, minus shot gun and hat, and with a docility in marked contrast
                        with his former boastfulness. Several minor skirmishes took place thereafter
                        but we are gratified to state that "nobody was hurt."</p>
                    <p>Towards the dusky hours of evening we left for home again and merry was the
                        crowd over the events of the day. I would not have you understand, Mr.
                        Editor, that the merriment was superinduced by anything save the pleasures
                        of the day, although one of the party, tired with the jostling ambulance,
                        did call out to the driver very lustily "please make the darn thing pace."</p>
                    <p>Landed safely at home we can but revert with pleasure to the day spent with
                        our neighbors of Greenville and vicinity, and trust that many such occasions
                        may arise to call the good people of our county together in such pleasant
                        reunions.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">DIXI</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Dixi</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Powell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Dixi" offers an account of a grand barbeque given by the people of
                    Greenville, which included addresses, music, a near-gun battle, and a large
                    dinner in which "colored persons" were "invited to participate after the whites
                    were served."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:-- I noticed my name among the signers
                        to the Dews petition. I will take a solemn oath that I never signed that
                        petition, nor did I ever see it. I was a Southern man during the war, and am
                        the same yet.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Geo. Elliot</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elliot</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Elliot denies ever signing the Dews petition, claiming he "was a
                    Southern man during the war, and am the same yet."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Curious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have recently heard, from several sources, says the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Richmond Whig</emph>, that Northern men have approached late holders of
                        slaves with the offer of five dollars for each slave lost by emancipation.
                        What does this mean? </p>
                    <p>Why it means that the Yankees want to buy up all Southern claims for negroes
                        emancipated, and then make Congress pay them damages to the value of the
                        negroes! They will buy at five or ten dollars, and then ask Congress to give
                        them three or five hundred and tax us to get the money. Sharp set of
                        scoundrels, these Yankees.-<emph rend="italic">Lynchburg Republican</emph>.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Claims that some "Northern men" are offering five dollars to former
                    slaveholders for each slave in the hopes that Congress will offer compensation
                    at some future point.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.27.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A pic-nic came off at Dr Isaac Hall's Schoolhouse, on July 21st under the
                        management of the efficient Committee, Messrs M. R. Coalter, Wm. Hunter,
                        Capt. Clinton Hall, Capt B. M. Ellis, Alex Coiner, and John Lipscomb. It was
                        a pleasant affair. The day was delightful and prattling children and grey
                        haired parents, gay old bacholers and meek benedicts, happy lovers and
                        meddling rivals were there to give zest and variety to the gathering.</p>
                    <p>An eloquent address was delivered by the rev. Mr. Ball, after which a
                        sumptuous collation was spread upon the ground, which was greatly enjoyed by
                        the pic-nickians.</p>
                    <p>The remainder of the day was devoted to the usual pleasures incident to such
                        an occasion, and when the dusky shades of evening warned that the hour for
                        leave taking had arrived, the crowd dispersed, well satisfied with the
                        enjoyments of the day.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coalter</ln>
                        <fn>M. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>B. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lipscomb</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ball</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A picnic was recently held at Dr. Isaac Hall's Schoolhouse, and is reported
                    to have been "a pleasant affair."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items--Proceedings of the County Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Maj. Jno. B. Watts qualified as Notary Public.</p>
                    <p>The powers of Wm. J. Dews as Notary Public were revoked, he having failed to
                        furnish the required security.</p>
                    <p>Thos. S Hogshead qualified as road commissioner.</p>
                    <p>Rev. Harrison Getzendanner, of the German Reformed Church, gave bonds and was
                        authorized to celebrate the rights of matrimony</p>
                    <p>Nothing else of general interest was transacted.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dews</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getzendenner</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Summarizes the recent proceedings of the County Court, including the
                    revocation of William Dews' powers as a Notary Public.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A little daughter of Deputy Sheriff Towherman of this County swallowed a
                        grain of corn, some ten days since, which lodged in the wind-pipe.-On Sunday
                        last indications of suffocation being exhibited, Drs. Fauntleroy, Watson,
                        Churchman and Carter Berkely, were called in and successfully performed the
                        operation of opening the windpipe, and removed the grain of corn. The child
                        is at present doing well.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauntleroy</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkely</ln>
                        <fn>Carter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Four doctors recently removed a grain of corn lodged in the windpipe of a
                    daughter of Staunton Deputy Sheriff Towberman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>GEO. WHITEZELL, aged 13 years, son of Nelson Whitezell near Burke's Mill in
                        the County, was drowned on July 15th while in bathing with his cousin, who
                        was endeavoring to learn him to swim. He was an only child and an
                        interesting little fellow.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitezell</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitezell</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Whitezell recently drowned near Burke's Mill while his cousin was
                    attempting to teach him how to swim. He was 13 and "an interesting little
                    fellow."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gulley</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keblinger</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Keblinger and G. A. Gulley, both of Charlottesville, were married on
                    July 19 at the Virginia Hotel by Rev. George Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>George K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>Millie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Millie Bruce and George Harper, both of Staunton, were married on July 19
                    by Rev. W. E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Verner F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Verner Ferguson died on July 11 after an illness of twelve hours. He was
                    the only son of William and Sarah Ferguson and died three weeks before his fifth
                    birthday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.07.27.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
