<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.12.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/11</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-12-21">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.12.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Abolition of the Southern States Governments</head>
                <origin>Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With rumors swirling that Thad Sumner has introduced a bill to abolish all
                    southern state governments, the article suggests that such a law would abrogate
                    those states' debts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Negroes of Boston Supporting the Democratic Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blacks in two wards in Boston are supporting the Democratic ticket, relates
                    the article, causing considerable consternation among the city's Republicans.
                    The party's leadership had promised blacks representation on the City Council,
                    but failed to deliver on the pledge prompting "the wrath of the colored men."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Fort Wayne Democrat</origin>
                <commentary>"The Fort Wayne Democrat is responsible for the following:"</commentary>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a woman who "can plow, fish, nurse, and sing all at once," and
                    compares the "heroine" to the "sickly sentimentalists who can't sweep a room or
                    bring a bucket of water without being broke down."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.12.21.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>While we have no voice in the National Legislation, we, nevertheless, can not
                        fail to look with interest to the doings of Congress. Though noting the
                        sayings and doings in that body we are totally at a loss to tell what our
                        status is. Indeed we think it would puzzle a philosopher to disentangle the
                        mesh [unclear] into which radical fanaticism has gotten the condition of the
                        South. When the Constitutional Amendment was passed it was intended that it
                        should be ratified by all the States, in which category the most ferocious
                        radical classed our Southern communities.--Then it was contended that by
                        secession we had lost our status as States and were conquered provinces and
                        to be dealt with as such. Now a member of Congress openly declares that upon
                        the ratification of the Constitutional Amendment, we must, in all fairness,
                        be allowed representation and admitted to our old position of States in the
                        Union, but if we reject it the whole military and naval power of the country
                        is to be used to thrust it down our throats. He plainly takes as the basis
                        of our wrong-doing the failure to ratify the Constitutional Amendment and
                        thus relieves us of all the alleged culpability on account of our acts of
                        secession and consequent war.--Another, not seeing as far into the
                        mill-stone, would reduce the States of the South into a territorial
                        conditions, re-organize the governments by the tools of Congress,
                        disfranchise our citizens, &amp;c., while a third would re-construct the
                        "District formerly composing the State of North Carolina," which would be a
                        precedent for action in regard to other States.</p>
                    <p>Now for the life of us we can't tell whether we are to be re-organized as
                        "fish, flesh or fowl," whether the Southenr States "so-called" are to be
                        considered as <emph rend="italic">States, Territories, of Districts</emph>,
                        or when this long and much mooted questionis to be decided, so varied and
                        conflicting ar the opinions of those in power. This much we do know that
                        there is not enough of philosophic statesmanship in Congress to disposition
                        of the Southern States has gotten it. The only resort will be to cast aside
                        fanaticism and fanatical legislation, and fall back upon the Constitution
                        and common sense, and, as respect for the Constitution is but slightly
                        entertained in the Halls of Congress, and an approach to common sense is
                        vastly slower than a "snail's galley," we can reasonably expect that the
                        status of the Southern States will be the subject of declamation for
                        Congressmen yet unborn, and the youngest of us will die with the question
                        unsolved as to whether he was born in a <emph rend="italic">State, Territory
                            or District</emph>.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As Congress debates the future of the southern states, the editors assail
                    the various proposals promulgated thus far.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Labels the passage of the law granting suffrage rights to blacks in the
                    District of Columbia as the first step in the Radicals' program.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia House of Representatives unanimously passed a bill last
                    Monday, declaring its intention to recognize prewar debts and avoid all attempts
                    at repudiation. This position, suggests the article, reflects the view of the
                    "vast majority" of the people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the face of continuing difficulties arising from the split of the
                    Methodist Church into northern and southern wings, Col. Baldwin, reports the
                    article, has introduced a bill in the legislature to oversee the distribution of
                    church property. According to the terms of the bill, the majority of each
                    congregation will determine the fate of contested property.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Virginia House of Delegates unanimously approved a bill appropriating
                    $20,000 to purchase artificial limbs for the state's maimed Confederate
                    soldiers, states the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General Assembly Of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Among the subjects discussed by the legislature this past week, reports the
                    article, were measures affecting the administration of railroads, taxes, and a
                    bill to erect a monument to Confederate soldiers killed in the late war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.12.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that citizens living near Stribling Springs disinterred the bodies
                    of sixteen Confederate soldiers, who died in the hospital nearby, and brought
                    them to Staunton for reburial in the Soldiers' Cemetery. An additional
                    twenty-three bodies were brought from the Piedmont.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that a "brutal" murder took place in Rockingham County last
                    week. The victim, a "gallant" soldier in the Confederate army, was shot in the
                    head and his body mutilated. Local citizens intend to offer a $500 reward for
                    the apprehension of the murderer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the ladies of the Trinity Church will hold a fair and festival
                    on Thursday and Friday night.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>When members of the Staunton Lyceum met last Monday, relates the article,
                    they debated the question, Is Republicanism a Failure, which they "decided in
                    the affirmative." Next Monday, Jed Hotchkiss will deliver a lecture.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brackett</ln>
                        <fn>N. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn>St. F. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Lavinia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. N. C. Brackett, the Supervisor of the Freedmen's schools in the
                    Valley, recently rented a house west of Staunton, relates the article.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>P. H. Trout</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company met on December 14 at which time its members
                    passed a series of resolutions in memory of John Beck, the company's 4th
                    Engineer, recently deceased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Martha E. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>Reuben D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha E. B. Hill, Consort of Reuben D. Hill, died on December 4, in
                    Lebanon, Ohio, where she traveled to obtain medical treatment for her "delicate
                    health." Hill leaves a grieving husband and three young children. She was 35
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 19, Capt. C. G. Merritt and Lizzie Wilson were married by Rev. Dr.
                    McFarland.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuire</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latune</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 19, Joseph McGuire, of Washington City, and Anna, daughter of
                    Alfred Chapman, were married by Rev. James A. Latune.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuire</ln>
                        <fn>Hunter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 19, Dr. Hunter McGuire, of Richmond Medical College, and Mary
                    Stuart, daughter of A. H. H. Stuart, were married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grimm</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 29, Rev. George Huffman and Catherine Snyder were married by Rev.
                    J. W. Grimm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>Theresa M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 7, John C. Dunlap and Theresa M. McChesney were married by Rev. J.
                    I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Dec. 14, John Beck, 31, died in Staunton. Pneumonia was the cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitler</ln>
                        <fn>Mary V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 20, Mary V. Spitler died near Spring Hill after suffering several
                    weeks of illness. She was 14 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.12.21.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
