<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.sv.1866.01.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/23/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-01-26">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="00">26</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.sv.1866.01.26.sgml.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>05</column>
                <head>Heavy Penalty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two men were recently arrested in Lynchburg, "charged with distributing
                    obscene prints." Unable to pay their fines, the two men were "ordered to work on
                    the streets for a period not exceeding one year."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>The London Times on Grant's Report</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At an "early period of the rebellion," General Grant had divined the secret
                        of Southern strength and Northern weakness. The Federals were three to one,
                        at least, in numbers, and immeasurably superior in material resources, and
                        yet the Confederates maintained their ground and defended their territories
                        against all attacks. This, says Grant, was because the strength of the North
                        was never exerted on a good system or with sufficient resolution. The
                        Southern Generals held a position like the outline of a fan, extending from
                        east to west, and covering the country behind them. By means of the
                        railroads intersecting the interior they could bring up their forces to any
                        point of the circumference; and so long as it was necessary for them to be
                        strong at one point only, they could always contrive to be stronger at that
                        point than their adversaries. The first and most indispensable step,
                        therefore, was to deprive them of this favorable condition by attacking at a
                        variety of points at once, so as to retain every Southern army in its own
                        position and prevent it from reinforcing another. Hitherto the two main
                        armies of the Federals-one in Tennessee and the other in Virginia-had been
                        acting, as the General expresses it, "like a balky team." When one was
                        pulling the other was backing, and so the able Generals of the Confederacy,
                        could shift or concentrate or relieve their forces in such a way as either
                        to economise their strength or employ it to the greatest advantage. If Lee
                        was hard pressed, he could be reinforced by Beauregard; if Johnston was in
                        difficulty, he could be supported from Richmond or Petersburg. Attack on
                        both sides at once, and these tactics would be impracticable. But, besides
                        all this, General Grant took a harder and more terrible view of affairs. Man
                        for man, the Southerners were the best troops, partly, perhaps, from natural
                        aptitudes, but mainly, no doubt, from the great military ability of their
                        commanders. On a fair field, and in any one battle, the Federals could not
                        pretend to reckon confidently on winning; but there was one thing on which
                        they could reckon, and that was on killing a certain number of
                        Confederates.-Of course they must suffer equal, or even greater losses
                        themselves, but that they could well afford. If every battle cost the South
                        a certain proportion of men, a given number of battles must destroy the
                        Southern power, even if no battle was a decisive victory. So Grant
                        determined not only to fight, but to fight on, without stint or stay, come
                        what might. Hard knocks and incessant blows constituted his strategy and
                        tactics. If he were to fare as McClellan and Hooker had fared, he would not
                        do as McClellan and Hooker had done. He opened the new campaign, resolved to
                        go on fighting whether he won or lost, and, as he himself says, "to
                        [UNCLEAR] continuously against the armed force of the enemy and his
                        resources, until, by mere attrition, if in no other way, there should be
                        nothing left to him but submission." The literal execution of this policy is
                        expressed in every line of the report.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Credits Grant for recognizing at an early stage of the war that the Union
                    was not utilizing its vast superiority in manpower and material resources and
                    for ultimately adopting a policy of concerted attack "'until, by mere attrition,
                    there should be nothing left to him but submission.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>The South</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>That portion of the country known as "the South" embraces eight hundred and
                        fifty thousand square miles, and is as lare as Great Britain, France,
                        Austria, Prussia and Spain, with a most productive soil and genial climate;
                        with staple productions which none of those great countries can grow; with
                        three thousand miles of coast line, indented wit bays and crowded with
                        islands; and its vast centre watered by the Mississippi, into whose bosom
                        are poured thirty-six thousand miles of tributary streams.</p>
                    <p>The total agricultural productions of the United States for 1850 amounted to
                        1,164,000,000; of the sum of the North produced in round numgers, 6,400,000
                        and the South 5,600,000. Population of the North in 1860 was 13,527,220;
                        population of the South, 9,663,656. The North had a deficiency in 1850 of
                        agricultural productions to the value of $6,105,594; the South a surplus of
                        $124,855,712, or each person at the North censured thirty-eight cents more
                        than he produced; at the South each person produced twelve dollars and
                        ninety cents more than he consumed.</p>
                    <p>These facts are now referred to for the purpose of showing how idle it is to
                        despond of the future of a region which possesses such enormous elements of
                        natural wealth and whose exports at the period above mentioned were three
                        times as great as those of the whole United States ten years after the
                        Revolutionary war. The recuperative powers of such a region must be
                        perfectly incalculable. With the introduction of capital and immigration
                        from the North and from Europe, all traces of the late war will be
                        obliterated in five years. Every year that succeeds will witness such a
                        march of prosperity and population as even the Western States have never
                        equaled. With the removal of slavery the energies and enterprise of the
                        whole world will seek a field of action within our borders. If we will only
                        give up the barren pursuits of politics, and turn in to hard work, and the
                        end of the present century will see the South the most prosperous and
                        densely populated portion of the American Republic.-<emph rend="italic"
                            >Richmond Dispatch</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that it "idle to despond of the future" of the South because "with
                    the removal of slavery the energies and enetrprise of the whole world will seek
                    a field of action within our borders." If Southerners "give up the barren
                    pursuits of politics, and turn in to hard work," the author argues, the South by
                    1900 will be "the most prosperous and densely populated portion of the American
                    Republic."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>07</column>
                <head>Gems of Thought--Woman's Beauty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that "most women had rather have any of their good qualities
                    slighted than their beauty. Yet that is the most inconsiderable accomplishment
                    of a woman of real merit."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.sv.1866.01.26.sgml.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One of our Richmond cotemporaries copies our local, in reference to a
                        petition to the General Assembly for the charter of a Valley Railroad being
                        circulated and signed in the Valley Counties, under the caption of "<emph
                            rend="italic">Baltimore at work</emph>," while another speaks of the
                        notices in the Valley papers of meetings to be held to further the project
                        of securing the Valley Railroad, as being "<emph rend="italic">in the
                            interest of the city of Baltimore</emph>." While it may not be the
                        desire of our cotemporaries to throw cold water on the Valley Railroad
                        scheme, by creating a prejudice against the city of Baltimore, and
                        especially as one of them expressed his conviction that no reasonable
                        objection could be urged to granting a charter for said road if asked for,
                        yet such allusions and headings do tend to create a prejudice, not only
                        against Baltimore, but also against the Valley Railroad, and are decidedly
                        unjust to the Valley section. The petition spoken of was gotten up in the
                        Valley, and is being circulated and signed in the Valley Counties, not in
                        the interest of Baltimore, Richmond, or any other city, but <emph
                            rend="italic">in the interest of the Valley exclusively</emph>. </p>
                    <p>We have, by the operations of war, had our houses and crops destroyed, our
                        lands laid waste, fences burned, cattle and horses killed or driven off, and
                        are left without labor necessary to repair the damages we have sustained, or
                        render the production of the Valley equal to its former, and also without
                        means of procuring the necessary labor. Our lands, the richest and most
                        productive in the State, bring now but a nominal price compared with the
                        sale of lands elsewhere. We therefore cannot afford to sell, and are unable
                        to render them as productive as formerly.-Like our cotemporaries, in all
                        portions of the State, but few of which have suffered as did the Valley
                        section, we naturally look for aid away from home. We know that the price of
                        our lands would be greatly enhanced by rendering access to market easy, and
                        the only way in which this can be done is by a Valley Railroad. While it is
                        being constructed money will flow into this greatly impoverished section,
                        and when completed an impetus will be given to the development of our
                        resources such as we have never before felt. Immigration will flow in and
                        will take hold of our idle lands and the Valley will blossom as the rose.
                        With all this in our minds' eye, we have started, and are circulating and
                        signing this petition, believing that we, the people of the Valley, are the
                        parties directly interested. Whether Richmond or Baltimore will get more of
                        the trade of the Valley will depend, then, as it now does, upon which can
                        offer the greater inducements of that trade. There will be a competition
                        between Baltimore and Richmond, which will add life to both cities, and
                        either, as we have stated in a former article, will get more trade from the
                        Valley, due to this road, than the whole trade of the Valley now amounts to,
                        which, at present, is divided between them. No loss can be sustained by
                        Richmond on account of this road, unless she lags behind in efforts to build
                        up her trade, but she must be the gainer by it, and the Valley will be
                        greatly advantaged thereby. Even if the interests of Richmond did suffer,
                        must the whole valley section remain unproductive for years on that account?
                        We should opine not, and we trust that Richmond will see her interest
                        sufficiently clearly to assist us in this matter rather than throw
                        impediments in our way. But whether she does or not, we must push forward,
                        and we again say to all hunt up the petition and sign it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to arguments in the Baltimore papers that the construction of
                    the Valley Railroad will benefit Baltimore's trade at the expense of Richmond,
                    the editor contends that the local efforts to secure the rail line are being
                    taken "not in the interest of Baltimore, Richmond, or any other city, but in the
                    interest of the Valley exclusively" and that it is unlikely that Richmond's
                    trade will in fact suffer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.sv.1866.01.26.sgml.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WE notice in the last Rockingham Register that our old friend and
                        predecessor, Maj. S. M. Yost, has purchased an interest in that excellent
                        journal. Maj. Yost, long and ably filled the editorial chair of the
                        Vindicator, from which he was called by war's loud trump, when, closing his
                        office, he, with his hands, took the field in defence of his native Valley
                        and State. The war being over duty calls him again to the sanctum, to aid in
                        resuscitating the old Dominion and building up the prosperity of his native
                        Valley. We cordially welcome him once more into the editoral fraternity, and
                        hope that, as heretofore, his labors may be crowned with success.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>S. M. Yost, the former editor of The Vindicator, has recently resumed
                    editor duties at the Rockingham Refgister.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. WM. DOLD, Deputy Collector of U. S. Internal Revenue, is in Staunton, and
                        is proceeding with the collection of the taxes on Licenses, and incomes and
                        on such articles as Carriages, Watches, &amp;c., which were assessed by
                        the Assessor, during the months of August, September and October. Persons
                        assessed during these months are required to pay by the 31st inst., or ten
                        per cent will be added. Those assessed since October, are not required to
                        pay now. The Collector's office is in the Virginia Hotel.</p>
                    <p>Persons who have not been assessed with these taxes, should come forward at
                        once, as the Assessor informs us that the time is growing short.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dold</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Dold, Deputy Collector of U.S. Internal Revenue, has set up an
                    office at the Viginia Hotel, where he will be collecting taxes based on previous
                    assessments until January 31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>VERY little of importance transpired at the sitting of the County Court on
                        Monday last.</p>
                    <p>Sam'l Paul, W. L. Mowry, A. B. Lightner and Geo. Harian qualified as Deputy
                        Collectors for the County.</p>
                    <p>John Paris qualified as Deputy Clerk of County Court.</p>
                    <p>Kelinerly Craig qualified as Notary Public.</p>
                    <p>Robt. M. White and John Irvin qualified as Road Commissioners</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paul</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>W. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Kennerly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Robt. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irvin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists men who qualified for local positions at the most recent meeting of
                    the County Court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Richard H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Julia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Julia Grove and Richard Fisher were married on January 17 by Rev. George
                    Taylor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCall</ln>
                        <fn>Josephine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCall</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Josephine McCall, of Rockingham, and John Andrew, of Augusta, were married
                    in Pocahontas county, West Virginia, on January 7 by Rev. M. D. Dunlap.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Firebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Robt. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jennie Clemmer, of Augusta, and Robert Firebaugh, of Rockbridge, were
                    married at the home of the bride's father on January 2 by Rev. J. D. Shirey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maury</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Southard</ln>
                        <fn>Juliet F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Juliet Southard, of Fredericksburg, and J. W. Bryan, of Staunton, were
                    married on December 21 by Rev. Maury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.sv.1866.01.26.sgml.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
