<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1866/va.au.rv.1866.03.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>John Riedl</taggerName>
            <tagDate>05/01/01</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1866-03-09">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>09</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.09.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.09.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Wednesday, the 21st ult., the Valley Railroad bill was passed by the
                        Senate, (having previously passed the House,) with the following proviso:</p>
                    <p>"That it shall not be lawful to complete the said valley Railroad to a point
                        nearer than twenty miles of the Virginia and Tennessee railroad, earlier
                        than one year after the Covington and Ohio railroad shall be completed."</p>
                    <p>If this proviso was intended to damage the bill by preventing the stock being
                        taken, or retard the completion of the valley railroad, even to within
                        twenty miles of the Virginia and Tennessee railroad, it will miss its mark.
                        We of the Valley know that Richmond's interest in the speedy completion of
                        the Covington and Ohio railroad will not let that road stand long in its
                        uncompleted condition, and that, by the time the Valley railroad shall be
                        completed to the point designated in the proviso, the Covington and Ohio
                        road will have been completed more than one year, and the Valley railroad
                        will be pushed on to its junction with the Virginia and Tennessee railroad.
                        Other Legislatures will meet in the mean time, and the repealing of that
                        proviso is a fixed fact, if an undue dilatoriness be exhibited in the
                        completion of the Covington and Ohio railroad. We do not believe the proviso
                        will delay the construction of the Valley railroad a day, and this fact will
                        be exhibited to those who proclaim that the proviso takes the sting out of
                        the Valley railroad bill. Its completion to within twenty miles of the
                        Virginia and Tennessee railroad, will open up a section unsurpassed in
                        production and resources in the Union, and will benefit our whole State,
                        Richmond not excepted, whether she will or she won't. Let every energy be
                        exerted to put in construction this road, so important to the interests of
                        Virginia and particularly of this Valley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the Senate's passage of the Valley Railroad Bill, despite a proviso
                    that may impede the completion of the rail line, and urges that "every energy"
                    be exerted to construct the line.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Reconstruction Committee in Congress has reported a joint
                    resolution that recommends Tennessee be readmitted to the Union, provided the
                    people of Tennessee prevent former rebels from voting or holding office,
                    repudiate the Confederate debt and abandon claims for compensated emancipation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.09.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hiram F. Ely, hailing from New York was arrested here on Tuesday last for
                        passing a counterfeit $20 note, on the National Bank of Indianapolis, on Mr.
                        Jno Beard of Staunton. He was discharged, after an examination, on account
                        of the evidence being insufficient to prove that it was willingly and
                        knowingly passed.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hiram Ely, of New York, was arrested last Tuesday for passing a counterfeit
                    $20 note to Jno. Beard of Staunton. After examination, Ely was released with
                    insufficient evidence to prove he passed the note willingly and knowingly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchens</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Copeland</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Copeland, of England, and Mary Guthrie, of Augusta, were married by
                    Rev. Jno. Hutchens on February 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutcheson</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Anna Hutcheson and James Campbell, of Rockbridge, were married on March 1
                    at the home of the bride's father in Greenville by Rev. H. A. Gaver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Flory, of Iowa, and Sarah V., the daughter of William Wright of
                    Augusta, were married on February 23 by Rev. Daniel Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evy</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evy</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Wine, of Rockingham, and Mary Evy, of Augusta, were married on
                    February 25 by Rev. Daniel Thomas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaver</ln>
                        <fn>H. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Myers, of Waynesboro, and Maggie Palmer were married on March 1 at the
                    home of the bride's mother in Port Republic by Rev. H. A. Gaver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hale</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>E. Hale and J. H. Craun, both of Augusta, were married on March 1 by Rev.
                    C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Leander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kearney</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie Wright, wife of Leander Wright and daughter of M. L. Kearney, died
                    in Fishersville on December 16 after a long and painful illness, leaving behind
                    her husband and three small children. She was 35 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Louisa Bear, daughter of J. and C. Bear, died on February 24 "of
                    complicated disease" at her home in Churchville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1866.03.09.04">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
