<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.05.29">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/29</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-05-29">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.29.01">
            <pageNote>The page contains a variety of anecdotes and semi-comical
            vignettes.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.29.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Bankrupt Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One of the most important measures as affecting the commercial relations of
                        the country, passed by Congress during the last session, was the bankrupt
                        law. It seems strange, considering the fact that every commercial country
                        has some uniform system of laws regulating bankruptcy, that heretofore
                        legislation on that subject in this country should have failed as often as
                        attempted. The truth is, however, that the bankrupt laws heretofore passed
                        by Congress have been framed to meet special emergencies, and not being
                        adapted to the ordinary wants of the commercial public, have been repealed
                        as soon as the emergency that required them was passed. In 1800 a bankrupt
                        act was passed, but its object being simply to relieve creditors, it was
                        soon discovered to be unwise and was repealed with little or no opposition.
                        In 1841 another was passed to suit the necessities of debtors, but it was so
                        inefficient and objectionable in its parts that it was even more short-lived
                        than the former.</p>
                    <p>Since its repeal to the present time, we have been without a uniform system
                        of laws on the subject, each State regulating the matter as it preferred.
                        The necessity of a national bankrupt law that should operate uniformly
                        throughout the country, and give the needed relief to the unfortunate debtor
                        and at the same time afford protection to the creditor, has never been
                        questioned to any considerable extent. The great difficulty has been to
                        frame a law acceptable in all its parts to the different sections of the
                        country. The present law was not passed without serious opposition, but it
                        is such an improvement upon the former laws on the subject, and seems to be
                        so well adapted to the ordinary wants of the public, that it is likely to
                        remain in force. It has embodied in it all the improvements in English
                        legislation, and provides first for voluntary and compulsory bankruptcy. It
                        is impartial in its provisions and not more stringent than justice to the
                        creditor requires. It aims to relieve the hopeless bankrupt, and at the same
                        time to protect the creditor against dishonesty and fraud. The last section
                        of the act provides that the law shall go into effect on the first day of
                        June next, after which time all State laws on the subject will be
                    negatory.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial lauds the passage of the congressional bankruptcy bill, which
                    creates a uniform standard, as a key measure to facilitate transactions that
                    cross state lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Common Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors call attention to a provision contained within the school bill
                    passed by the last legislature requiring teachers to have sound knowledge of
                    "orthography, reading, writing, geography, English grammar, mental and written
                    arithmetic, history of the United States, and the theory of teaching" to qualify
                    to instruct children. An additional requirement mandates that teachers should
                    not be in the habit of imbibing intoxicating beverages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Letters From Mrs. Jane G. Swisshelm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Correspondence of the Franklin Repository.</p>
                    <p>NO. XXVII., Wilkinsburg, Pa., May 21, 1867.</p>
                    <p>The way of the transgressor is said to be hard, and the way of the
                        philanthropist is not always easy. This the eccentric philosopher of the New
                        York <emph rend="italic">Tribune</emph> will realize if censure is in any
                        way disagreeable. His late exploit in becoming first bondsman for the head
                        traitor, has done much to loosen, if it has not quite broken, his hold on
                        the confidence of loyal men, and yet the fault is not individually his. This
                        lies with those "Fathers" whose wisdom has been so lauded, as something
                        quite superhuman. The government organized by those Fathers, with whom
                        wisdom is supposed to have died, presented the curious anomaly of ranking
                        its own life as of far less value than that of the humblest citizen. Nay, so
                        worthless, and less than worthless is that government, as estimated by
                        itself, that while a man forfeits his own life, for taking that of another,
                        for any private enmity, he may take the lives of any number of men for the
                        avowed object of destroying that government. The end sanctifies the means,
                        and what, otherwise, would be murder most foul, is only a fineable, and so,
                        of course, a bailable offence, if committed in the hope of overthrowing this
                        government. Had Jefferson Davis induced any man, or set of men, to kill any
                        other man, or set of men, for any purpose less praiseworthy than that of
                        destroying this government, he could not have been admitted to bail under it
                        while awaiting trial, but the only penalty attached to treason is an
                        insignificant fine or imprisonment, and the emancipation of the slaves of
                        the offender. Mr. Davis' slaves having been emancipated, he has, already,
                        suffered the extreme penalty provided by law.</p>
                    <p>As the value of these slaves has been repaid to him a hundred fold, by the
                        voluntary contributions of his admirers, and he himself has become the
                        beheld of all beholders, the hero of the hour, there is no reason why he
                        should not get up another rebellion, except the one argument that he has had
                        glory enough to satisfy the most exorbitant ambition. Mr. Davis ought to bow
                        himself off the stage and persistently refuse all calls for encore. It is
                        not right that one man should have all the laurels of a century; and Brigham
                        Young's time comes next. When he gets ready to turn this government upside
                        down, inside out, or blow it to fragments, I, for one, will bid him God
                        speed. Next to slavery nothing has so crushed our people as our ridiculous
                        veneration for the wisdom of the men who organized this government; and it
                        does not appear we shall ever get rid of it, until the old cob house is
                        tumbled over. The present generation have saved it in spite of itself, and,
                        at every step of progress in that salvation, have been confronted by it as
                        its own worst enemy. It appears to have been constructed for the confusion
                        of its friends, and comfort of its enemies. Every vital measure for the
                        preservation of the Constitution, has necessarily been in violation of, or
                        without the sanction of the Constitution. Every interpretation authorizing,
                        or requiring its defence in the most dire extremity, is a strained
                        construction. It is an instrument dangerous principally to its friends; and
                        those who use it for its own preservation must take hold of the sharp end.
                        If the people have not before learned this fact, they have a good
                        opportunity in the release of Davis. That release is strictly in accordance
                        with the law of this boasted government, for whose preservation hundreds of
                        thousands of brave men have laid down their lives--it is Constitutional. Can
                        we wonder that the recreant sons of Puritan sires, who, at the bidding of
                        Infidel France, struck out the name, and all reference to the authority of
                        God of their fathers from the fundamental law they framed for themselves and
                        posterity, should have made a botch of their work? The men who, under the
                        teachings of Tom Paine, and kindred writers, struck from the oath of office
                        of their chief magistrate, all religious obligation, all reference to the
                        Searcher of Hearts, and a future state of rewards and punishments, certainly
                        paved the way for all the perjury which has characterized its officers.</p>
                    <p>The men who included slavery in the catalogue of wrongs forced upon them by
                        the mother country; who appealed to God and the world, in their war for
                        Freedom, and then turned around and outlawed men who fought side by side
                        with them, on many a bloody field, were either very muddle-headed or very
                        dishonest. In their war for Independence they laid a noble foundation of
                        Freedom! In their Constitution and laws, they built thereon, straw, stubble,
                        which will not endure the fire of trial. If we have learned nothing since
                        their day, it may be well for us to go on with the prospect before us, of
                        pouring out the best blood of the nation for the defence of the old pioneer
                        cabin which these fathers erected before stump machines were invented. If we
                        have learned anything we had better remove it, and build a more substantial
                        edifice, something that will defend its defenders, and not require them to
                        stand on the open field, while its enemies get such shelter as its walls
                        afford.</p>
                    <p>Let us have a constitution that shall require traitors to pay the expense of
                        every effort to overthrow it, and answer for the crime, not only with their
                        property but with their lives. Until we have such an one we really have no
                        Government worthy of the name. The thing called Government which releases
                        Davis, and leaves the torture and starvation of her brave defenders
                        unavenged, is unworthy of either respect or obedience. The people--the loyal
                        people saved this so-called Government in its extremity. Let that same
                        people see that they replace it with something not quite so hard to save.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Greeley may afford to be magnanimous. He lost no husband, or brother, or
                        father, or son in the war. He lost no limbs and carries no bullets, or the
                        scar of them, in his body. Neither he, nor his, shivered on Belle Isle, or
                        prayed for death at Andersonville. It is easy to forgive injuries committed
                        against other folks. The tax the war imposes on him, is a pittance to the
                        addition it made to his business. Of the $100,000 he made by writing a
                        record of the rebellion, he can afford to give $5,000 to the head of the
                        rebellion, for furnishing material, and still make a profit. But every one
                        was not so fortunate.<lb/> JANE G. SWISSHELM.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Jane G. Swisshelm</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In her article, Swisshelm rails against the decision to free Jefferson
                    Davis and questions the logic behind it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Horace</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Horace discusses the paradox of honoring past Indian chiefs at the same
                    time that settlers in the plains are being victimized by Sioux and Cheyenne
                    Indians. The Repository correspondent also recounts the current gossip making
                    the rounds: Rumors are circulating in the state capital and in Democratic
                    journals that several legislators brought their sons to Harrisburg during the
                    last session to work for them, which has provoked a considerable outcry among
                    those offended by the reported acts of nepotism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.29.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Odd Fellowship</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In Philadelphia last week, the Grand Lodge of Odd Fellows held its annual
                    session. Jacob Spangler, of Columbus Lodge No. 75 was elected District Deputy
                    for Franklin county for the ensuing year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece announces that Dr. Valentine, the "celebrated electropathist," is
                    now in Chambersburg and is "drawing great crowds of the sick and ailing."
                    Valentine cares for his patients "without the use of medicine or surgery by
                    laying on of hands." Some are "cured in a few minutes, others in few hours or
                    days," even those who have "diseases heretofore considered incurable."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--To School Directors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors admonish the district's School Directors to publish the account
                    of receipts and expenditures, as called for by the laws of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Recording Soldiers' Discharges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>From Henry Strickler, Register and Recorder for Franklin, it is learned
                    that, contrary to the report issued by the Repository, the law authorizing the
                    recording of soldiers' discharges did not pass Congress. The bill was approved
                    by the House, but was rejected by the Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Salaries of our Judges</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the last session of the legislature, reports the article, the salary for
                    President Judge of the district that includes Franklin county was fixed at
                    $3,500 for the present year; associate judges will receive $5 per day, not
                    exceeding $50.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Thief Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Duncan was arrested in Waynesboro last week, charged with robbing a
                    man in Scranton, Pa. Chief of Police, Barney Campbell, of Harrisburg, caught
                    Duncan while he was attending the circus; Campbell will bring Duncan back to
                    Harrisburg to stand trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin>Valley Spirit</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ashcom</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>C. W. Ashcom was appointed Collector of Internal Revenue for the district
                    that includes Chambersburg. Reportedly, Ashcom has indicated he will collect the
                    taxes personally and "will visit the county at stated times for that purpose."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Resigned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. W. A. Snively, formerly of Greencastle, has resigned his position at
                    St. Andrews Church in Pittsburg to accept the charge of Christ Church,
                    Cincinnati.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The New Liquor Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article is a copy of the new liquor law signed by Gov. Geary. Among the
                    provisions contained in the legislation are prohibitions against selling
                    intoxicating beverages to anyone below the age of 21, to all habitual drunkards,
                    and to those whose spouses do not approve of drinking. Those who transgress the
                    law are liable to a fine of up to $20 or five days imprisonment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Culbertson</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sturgeon</ln>
                        <fn>M. Burd</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 23rd, John P. Culbertson and M. Burd Sturgeon were married by Rev.
                    James Harper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuman</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 9th, Catharine Shuman died at the residence of her son-in-law in
                    Hamilton township. She was 68 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.05.29.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
