<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.02.27">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/04</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-02-27">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.02.27.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Across the Plains to Montana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. C.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter provides yet more details of the journey taken by men from
                    Franklin county as they travel to the gold fields of Montana.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.02.27.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Morn Breaks Brightly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We give elsewhere in to-day's paper the Reconstruction bill passed finally by
                        both branches of Congress last Wednesday, and now in the hands of the
                        President for his approval or veto. What he may do with it matters little,
                        save so far as his action may indicate his purpose to persist in Wrong or
                        yield gracefully to the inevitable triumph of Right. The bill passed the
                        Senate by the overwhelming vote of 35 to 7--Pennsylvania, as usual,
                        furnishing two votes to proclaim her shame,--and in the House by 125 to 46,
                        being a strict party vote. One of the most significant signs of the times is
                        the manly support given the bill by Hon. Reverdy Johnson, of Maryland, one
                        of the ablest and most earnest of the President's supporters. If the
                        President shall sign the bill, his action will indicate his acceptance of
                        the inexorable march of events under the guidance of a determined and loyal
                        people, and will hasten and smooth the way to complete restoration. If on
                        the contrary, as we anticipate, he shall interpose his veto, the bill will
                        become a law notwithstanding, by the largest vote ever given to any
                        contested measure in our national legislature, and will be enforced either
                            <emph rend="italic">by</emph> the President or <emph rend="italic"
                        >over</emph> the President. He takes his choice either to do right or see it
                        done without his aid, and in defiance of his persistent but now harmless
                        apostasy. Under existing laws, the President can hold the bill until the
                        meeting of the next Congress, (the 5th of March) as it was not sent to him
                        until within ten days of adjournment; but if he should smother the bill by a
                        "pocket veto," the next Congress will re-enact the bill into law within the
                        first fortnight of the session, by a stronger vote than that by which it
                        passed last week.</p>
                    <p>We invite the dispassionate consideration of men of all parties to the
                        details of the bill. It goes to the very root of the malady that has been
                        festering in the rebellious States since the war, now and again erupting in
                        the shape of the Memphis, New Orleans and other massacres, and making
                        loyalty a term of reproach throughout the whole country embraced in the
                        rebellion. Every effort has been made--even to criminal leniency on the part
                        of the Executive--to regain the controlling people of the South to fidelity,
                        order and law; but each concession and every step toward generous pardon,
                        has but nerved disloyal arms and made disloyal hearts mingle their
                        implacable hatred for free institutions with the intensest hate for every
                        loyal statesman, every loyal measure, and every loyal citizen who claimed
                        the South as his home. Our military commanders, from Grant down, none of
                        whom are charged with radicalism, give concurrent testimony that the
                        submission of the rebellious people is but a mockery and a lie, and that the
                        safety of loyal men and freedmen in those States is solely in the military
                        arm of the government. With one accord these heroic chieftains deprecate the
                        subordination of the civil to military rule, and have resolutely struggled
                        to restore the civil powers to supreme authority; but all have informed the
                        government that they utterly despair of even ultimate success, as long as
                        leading rebels fill every public position and dictate the policy and laws of
                        that section. There is not an Executive in one of the rebellious States who
                        did not give his best efforts to dismember the Union. None others could be
                        chosen, and to be even suspected of luke-warmness in the cause of treason
                        during the war, has thus far been fatal to the aspirations of every citizen,
                        however distinguished or useful he has been.</p>
                    <p>The act of Congress places the pretended governments of the rebellious States
                        in their proper position. As State governments, or as governments of States,
                        they are but colossal monuments of Executive usurpation; but Congress
                        pronounces them as provisional only, and subordinates them entirely to the
                        military authority, and provides for their early extinction. The practical
                        effect of the bill is to bring the rebel States under martial law, but it
                        wisely provides that the proper exercise of the duties and prerogatives of
                        the civil powers will restrain the interference of military authority, and
                        provides for their early extinction. The practical effect of the bill is to
                        bring the rebel States under martial law, but it wisely provides that the
                        proper exercise of the duties and prerogatives of the civil powers will
                        restrain the interference of military authority in any way whatever. It
                        provides for the faithful and impartial administration of justice--a feature
                        thus far entirely novel in the government of those States since the war; and
                        it sends to all--to traitors South and their impotent but still malignant
                        abetters in the North--the long needed admonition that henceforth there
                        shall be impartial justice and entire equality before the law in every
                        section of the Union.</p>
                    <p>Most wisely, we think, Congress has not stopped with merely providing for the
                        maintenance of justice in the rebellious States. Earnestly as some of the
                        truest men in Congress resisted the acceptance of the Blaine Amendment, (the
                        fifth section of the bill) it cannot be questioned that the principle
                        involved in it met the overwhelming approval of the Republicans throughout
                        the country, and its adoption will be hailed with the profoundest
                        satisfaction. While the action of the rebels warranted almost any degree of
                        harshness in the laws for their government, yet the nation has in every way
                        manifested its desire that some definite terms for the restoration of the
                        seceded States should be proposed in such shape that they could, by
                        voluntary acceptance, place themselves again within the folds of the Union,
                        and at the same time give ample power for the enforcement of the terms in
                        case they should be rejected. The only plausible complaint against the
                        proposed amendments to the constitution, was the want of any positive
                        assurance that their adoption would facilitate restoration. Willing to grasp
                        any pretext for refusing to accept them, under the advice of a perfidious
                        Executive, they refused to accept what was in fact the plighted faith of
                        Congress that the adoption of, and faithful conformance to, those amendments
                        would restore the States to representation and all their sovereign rights.
                        That refusal has quickened the nation to appreciate the great peril of rebel
                        rule, and now treason is about to crown its utter overthrow with manhood
                        suffrage--a fruition that the persistent malignity of treason only was
                        potent enough to achieve.</p>
                    <p>We hail this action of Congress as the bright morn of Peace and Union; and
                        breaking as it does amidst the gloom, with every attribute of justice in its
                        refulgence, it cannot fail to rally the whole nation to the fulfilment of
                        its just and highest duty to Freedom and Mankind. It may be delayed or
                        embarrassed for a time by those who hate free institutions and blindly
                        resist the inevitable; but we cannot doubt that the result must, sooner or
                        later, be the cordial restoration of every section to fraternity again, and
                        the great Republic of the world will go on, in discharge of its sacred
                        mission, to prove that the noblest and strongest government of the earth is
                        so because it is most just, and therefore most blessed by the Great Ruler of
                        all!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors celebrate the passage of the Military Reconstruction bill,
                    which they claim "cannot fail to rally the whole nation to the fulfillment of
                    its just and highest duty to Freedom and Mankind."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Retribution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors condemn the appointment process for public officers, as
                    conducted by the Johnson administration, as corrupt. To substantiate their
                    claims, they point to the removal of Scull and Harper, both "upright and
                    respected citizens," and replacement with Gen. Coffroth and Col. Swope, two men
                    of questionable character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Schuyler Colfax, the Speaker of the House, will come to
                    Chambersburg in a few weeks to speak about his journey to the West, which he
                    undertook during the summer of 1865.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having "felt the full measure of rebel barbarity," relates the article, the
                    faithful men of Tennessee have passed a military bill to provide state troops to
                    enforce the recently enacted suffrage law, which grants voting rights to "all
                    loyal men without regard to caste or color" and disfranchises former rebels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors alert readers to the fact that the spring election for officers
                    of election and township officers will take place on March 15th, and urges
                    Republicans to cast their ballot since they have been "shamefully remiss" in
                    recent years thus allowing the Democrats to "control the election boards in some
                    of the strongest Republican districts in the county."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Speech of Mr. McConaughy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Senator McConaughy, of this district, addressed the Senate last week on
                    the apostacy of Senator Cowan in the following appropriate and pungent terms:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his address, McConaughy criticizes Cowan, the former U. S. Senator, for
                    making derogatory remarks about the Republican party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Government of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following is the Military Government bill which having pssed both
                    houses of Congress, now awaits the signature or veto of President Johnson:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following is the Military Government bill which having passed both houses
                        of Congress, now awaits the signature or veto of President Johnson--</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, No legal State governments or adequate
                        protection for life or property now exists in the States of Virginia, North
                        Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Mississippi, Alabama, Louisiana, Florida,
                        Texas and Arkansas;</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">And, whereas</emph>, It is necessary that peace and good
                        order should be enforced in said States, and loyal and republican State
                        governments be legally established; therefore,</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Be it enacted, &amp;c.</emph>, That said Rebel States
                        shall be divided into military districts, and made subject to the military
                        authority of the United States, as hereinafter prescribed; and for that
                        purpose Virginia shall constitute the first district; North Carolina and
                        South Carolina the second district; Mississippi and Arkansas the fourth
                        district, and Louisiana and Texas the fifth district.</p>
                    <p>Section 2. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That it
                        shall be the duty of the President to assign to the command of each of said
                        districts an officer of the army not below the rank of brigadier general,
                        and to detail a sufficient military force to enable such officer to perform
                        his duties and enforce his authority within the district to which he is
                        assigned.</p>
                    <p>Section 3. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That it
                        shall be the duty of each officer assigned as aforesaid to protect all
                        persons in their rights of person and property, to suppress insurrection,
                        disorder, and violence, and to punish or cause to be punished all disturbers
                        of the public peace and criminals; and to this end he may allow local civil
                        tribunals to take jurisdiction of and to try offenders; or when, in his
                        judgment, it may be necessary for the trial of offenders, he shall have
                        power to organize military commissions or tribunals for that purpose, and
                        all interference, under color of State authority, with the exercise of
                        military authority under this act shall be null and void.</p>
                    <p>Section 4. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That no
                        persons put under military arrest by virtue of this act shall be tried
                        without unnecessary delay, and no cruel or unusual punishment shall be
                        inflicted; and no sentence of any military commission or tribunal hereby
                        authorized, affecting the life or liberty of any person, shall be executed
                        until it is approved by the officer in command of this district; and the
                        laws and regulations for the government of the army shall not be effected by
                        this act, except in so far as they conflict with its provisions; <emph
                            rend="italic">Provided</emph> that no sentence of death under the
                        provisions of this act shall be carried into effect without the approval of
                        the President of the United States.</p>
                    <p>Section 5. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That when
                        the people of any one of the said Rebel States shall have formed a
                        constitutional government, in conformity with the Constitution of the United
                        States in all respects, framed by a convention of delegates elected by the
                        male citizens of said State, twenty-one years old and upwards, of whatever
                        race, color, or previous condition, who have been residents in said State
                        for one year previous to the day of such election, except such as may be
                        disfranchised for participation in Rebellion or for felony at common law,
                        and when such Constitution shall provide that the elective franchise shall
                        be enjoyed by all such persons as have the qualifications herein stated for
                        election of delegates, and when such Constitution shall be adopted by a
                        majority of the persons voting on the question of ratification who are
                        qualified as electors for delegates, and when such Constitution shall have
                        been submitted to Congress for examination and approval, and Congress shall
                        have approved the same, and when said State, by a vote of its Legislature,
                        elected under said Constitution, shall have adopted the amendment to the
                        Constitution of the United States proposed by the Thirty-ninth Congress, and
                        known as article 14, and when said article shall have become a part of the
                        Constitution of the United States, shall be declared entitled to
                        representation in Congress, and Senators and Representatives shall be
                        admitted therefrom on their taking the oath prescribed by law; and
                        thereafter the preceding sections of this act shall not be in operation in
                        said State; <emph rend="italic">Provided</emph>, That no person excluded
                        from the privilege of holding office by the said proposed amendment to the
                        Constitution of the United States shall be eligible to election as a member
                        of a convention to frame a constitution for any said Rebel State, nor shall
                        any such person vote for a member of said convention.</p>
                    <p>Section 6. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That until
                        the people of said Rebel States shall be by law admitted to representation
                        in the Congress of the United States any civil government which may exist
                        therein shall be deemed provisional only, and in all respects subject to the
                        paramount authority of the United States at any time to abolish, modify,
                        control or supersede the same; and in all elections to any office under such
                        provisional government, all persons shall be entitled to vote, and none
                        other, who are entitled to vote under the provisions of the fifth section of
                        this act, and no person shall be eligible to any office under such
                        provisional government who would be disqualified from holding office under
                        the provisions of the third article of said Constitutional Amendment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a full copy of the Military Reconstruction Bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.02.27.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Telegraph Office in Waynesboro</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Mr. Shaw, General Superintendent of the Pacific and
                    Atlantic Telegraph Company, visited Waynesboro for the purpose of opening an
                    office there. To do so, $5,000 in subscriptions must be raised.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Application for Pardon</head>
                <origin>Valley Spirit</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berntisel</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Berntisel, now imprisoned for adultery, has applied to Governor
                    Geary for a pardon</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Post Master</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that President Johnson nominated Matthew P. Welsh as Post Master of
                    Chambersburg last Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bigham</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 21st, J. W. Heintzelman and Nancy Stouffer were married by Rev. S.
                    Bigham.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slouthour</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Anna Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 19th, George Slouthour and Anna Elizabeth Miller were married by
                    Rev. B. S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>Percilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dutt</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 19th, George W. Smith and Percilla Zimmerman were married by Rev.
                    E. Dutt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkleman</ln>
                        <fn>C. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 19th, Peter Stenger and C. L. Kunkleman were married by Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkelman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Florich</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 21st, Andrew S. Conrad and Ann Barbara Florich were married by Rev.
                    G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>P. Dock</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>Justina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 21st, P. Dock Frey and Justina Harmony were married by Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkelman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Lemuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>Rosanna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 19, 1866, Lemuel King and Rosanna Forney were married by Rev. H. Y.
                    Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>P. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peiffer</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 8th, P. W. Jacobs and A. M. Peiffer were married by Rev. H. Y.
                    Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 16th, Frederick Keller and Mollie J. Jacobs were married by Rev. H.
                    Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Cario Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Winger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Duffield</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 17th, Cario Amanda, infant daughter of Col. B. F. and Susan
                    Duffield Winger, died at Duffield Mansion. She was 5 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillen</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Feb. 18th, William Gillen died at his residence near Orrstown. He was
                    almost 70 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.02.27.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
