<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.01.23">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/21</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-01-23">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.01.23.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Inuaugural Address of Gov. John W. Geary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a transcript of Gov. Geary's inaugural message, as presented on
                    Jan. 15th, 1867. Among the topic discussed in his speech were education, the
                    late war, war orphans, and the state's finances.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Across The Plains To Montana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>From Virginia City, Montana, the Repository correspondent provides more
                    details from his westward journey. In this installment, he relates the physical
                    geography of the terrain, a region of rugged beauty with few signs of
                    "civilized" life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.01.23.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Legislative Reform--It Must Be Fundamental!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors issue a call to arms to root out and destroy the "hideous
                    cancer of legislative corruption" that has polluted the "entire body politic of
                    Pennsylvania." The only way to achieve this goal, they suggest, is to call a
                    Constitutional Convention so that the appropriate "radical" reforms can be
                    instituted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article repudiates the charge levelled in "certain journals" that Thad
                    Stevens appeared in Harrisburg during the Senate election to campaign for the
                    office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although they are not happy with the outcome of the Senatorial contest, the
                    editors have resigned themselves to Simon Cameron's election. As such, they
                    offer an olive branch to the Senator-elect, and profess their conditional
                    support to him. Yet, despite this overture, they maintain their conviction that
                    the "mercenary betrayers" of the Republican party must be unmasked and expelled,
                    and pledge their continued efforts to achieve this goal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Life in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A friend who is spending the winter in South Carolina for his health,
                    writes us as follows from Charleston, as to the condition of the Freedmen and
                    society generally among the chivalry. It is indeed a painful chapter of human
                    degredation, treason, brutality, and misery:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A friend who is spending the winter in South Carolina for his health, writes
                        us as follows from Charleston, as to the condition of the Freedmen and
                        society generally among the chivalry. It is indeed a painful chapter of
                        human degradation, treason, brutality and misery:</p>
                    <p>You know that any code of laws suited to a system of slavery must necessarily
                        be barbarous, suited to the 14th or 15th century, but not to the 19th. Civil
                        law here means power to the wealthy few to do as they please, but there is
                        no law for the "poor white," the Union man, or the Moke. Civil law whips for
                        theft, hangs for larceny and burglary, and as you may have seen from the
                        papers, they have a man now in Walterboro jail sentenced to death, for
                        highway robbery, in that, he took while in our army, and upon a foraging
                        expedition under orders, a wagon load of <emph rend="italic">bacon</emph>.
                        He was to have been hung on Jan. 4th or 7th, but an intimation having been
                        given from the headquarters here that most probably their amusement would be
                        interfered with, the Governor has respited him until Feb. 1st. A report of
                        the investigation has been forwarded to the President; what he will do, who
                        knows? The President has disapproved Gen. Howard's order "to establish
                        Bureau Courts where necessary," in accordance with the Bureau bill, and
                        consequently there is no protection of any kind for the Freedmen; they are
                        at the mercy of a set of wretches, as unprincipled as they are cruel. What
                        power the President has to set aside any provision of a law passed by
                        Congress, we don't know; [illeg] that as Commander in Chief of the Army, he
                        can render any law of Congress a farce, by refusing the power necessary to
                        enforce obedience, we do know, and we know also that this is just the
                        situation here. The only thing the U. S. forces here now are doing, is
                        aiding a half civilized people to reduce a defenseless herd to a worse
                        condition than slavery ever was. Should Moke object to being shot and
                        beaten, to being robbed, plundered and cheated, and exercise the right of
                        self defense, these cowardly wolves call at once on the military for aid, in
                        the name of civil law, and it is given; the President has ordered it. The
                        officers of the Bureau are now mere advisory protectors no more, and are
                        compelled to stand powerless and see, and listen, to acts and complaints
                        that make the blood boil.</p>
                    <p>We'll state a few instances of what is occurring all over the State. On
                        Christmas eve and day, four Freedmen were murdered on the streets of this
                        city, and a number more cut and stabbed. In Edgefield, on Friday, one of
                        these kind, gentle massas, a high-toned chivalry, chopped the head off a
                        Freedman with an axe.</p>
                    <p>Over near Lawtonville they work the Moke under the lash, as of yore, in the
                        cotton field and at the port, and extend to him all the other kindnesses of
                        the old system. One high bred Southern gentleman, brim full of the milk of
                        human kindness, boasts that he has shot <emph rend="italic">eighteen</emph>
                        niggers. That dozens of these poor creatures are murdered and left to rot in
                        the woods, of whom nothing is known, is true. While out shooting last winter
                        within three miles of this town, we saw where a Moke had just been found
                        with a rifle bullet through his head. When they cannot treat them with
                        cruelty, they cheat and plunder them in every conceivable way. Any thing
                        meaner than a S. C. planter, is impossible to imagine. What redress has
                        Moke? None. If he dislikes this style of thing and complains, we can only
                        say "go to a magistrate and make a complaint." If he does so, he must give
                        security in $200 or $300, to prosecute, or his complaint is not heard. This
                        is the redress he has, and the satisfaction he gets, unless the certainty of
                        feeling that he'll be shot the first good opportunity, can be called
                        satisfaction, a fact we don't see in that light. There are a few localities
                        in which the Justices(?) have some little humanity and regard for justice,
                        but they dare not act. Should they <emph rend="italic">act</emph>, and even
                        express a desire to do justice to a Moke, any life insurance company would
                        be warranted in cancelling their policy instanter. Another insuperable
                        obstacle to anything like justice being done is the extensive ramification
                        of the family relation. Suppose the whole of Franklin Co., divided into some
                        hundred plantations and owned in one family connection; all the Mokes and
                        poor whites ("tresh buccra") under the old system would have been owned by
                        that family connection. Now supposing all the property owners, actuated
                        first by a deadly hatred to the government, second by a hatred to the Moke
                        because he is free, and you see at once, that all the magistrates being
                        members of that family, Moke or "tresh buccra" would have little to show. If
                        they let him live, and shoot and beat him now and then, he ought to be
                        satisfied. The last dodge in North Carolina is this: No one in N. C. who has
                        ever been whipped can vote; therefore they are arresting all Mokes, for
                        anything or nothing,--perjury is, you know, no crime in the South--and
                        whipping them; and have announced their determination to whip every nigger
                        in N. C., so as to disqualify him from voting for members of that
                        convention. The N. C. delegation <emph rend="italic">forgot</emph> to
                        mention this amiable resolve in Washington, and so we had to send it on.</p>
                    <p>The last dodge in S. C. is this: A man sees a "likely nigger," and preferring
                        to have his services for nothing, swears out a warrant and has him arrested.
                        Having let him lie in a S. C. jail for a few days, he goes to him, and
                        offers to get him out, if he'll agree to work for him six months or a year
                        for nothing; of course Moke will do anything to get out, and we, from the
                        moral obliquity of our vision, perhaps fail to see much difference between
                        his former and his present condition. During the past week, the humane son
                        of the jailor in this town, has with a club killed one and abused several
                        freedmen in the jail. Suit will be brought against him to-morrow. High
                        toned, honorable men, these moral church going community. Speaking of
                        morals, you asked me what effect the female population of mixed blood was
                        going to have on society here. I have looked somewhat into the matter since
                        my return, from what I can learn, I believe there is hardly a young man here
                        of Southern birth, who can afford the expense, who does not <emph
                            rend="italic">protect</emph> one of these girls, and few married men who
                        have not two families. Miscegenation is practiced here. I know of nearly a
                        dozen cases where the parties are married. These girls are many of them
                        beautiful, many almost pure white, with blue eyes and light hair, of fine
                        figures and lady-like appearance. Many of them are much whiter than the
                        majority of pure whites, who seem to belong to the order of women known as
                        scraggy, and are the color of a liver colored pointer, having tan colored
                        paws and faces. But few children are born where these girls are protected by
                        single men, while some of the old men have larger colored families. Nothing
                        can be done to rectify this evil, as these girls will not on any account
                        marry a man with a drop of "nigger blood" in his veins.</p>
                    <p>Thousands of the freed people here desire to quit the State. Many are going
                        to Florida, some to Mississippi, and a large number to Texas. Northern men
                        have purchased land in Florida, and are here now getting hands.</p>
                    <p>The people of Orangeburg rose and attempted to drive out the guard there, but
                        the boys in blue having met Johnny before, formed, opened fire and cleared
                        the streets in short order. There is a band there calling themselves "Dead
                        Heads," who have sworn to kill and drive out all freedmen from that section,
                        and they have murdered four within a week. The cavalry, a detachment of
                        Capt. William Brown's Anotemicals, are after them.</p>
                    <p>That these people are slowly emerging from the darkness in which they have
                        lived so long, is evinced by the passage of an act by the Legislature of
                        this State, taxing all books, periodicals and papers coming from other
                        States, twenty-five per cent. on their first cost, and by Georgia passing an
                        act prohibiting all <emph rend="italic">foreigners</emph> from holding real
                        estate in that State--foreigners meaning all others than Georgians--which
                        has since been reconsidered. Truly life among such a people is mere
                        existence. Here in Charleston is the only spot where one can live with even
                        a semblance of decency and comfort, and why? Because they know, that the
                        troops once withdrawn, the freedmen would take this town and burn it in less
                        than twenty-four hours. There is but one way to deal with this people, and
                        that is the Irishman's way with his wife. Appeal to them by the hair,
                        expostulate with them by the shoulders, plead with them over the head. Add
                        to this a sufficient quantity of moral suasion in the shape of bayonets and
                        argumentative bullets, and something may be made of them in time. I would
                        not have you understand that there is no leaven in this lump of the
                        commonest humanity. There are among the young men, the soldiers, and to
                        their credit be it said, they are heartily ashamed of the State, and will
                        one and all quit it as soon as they can command the means. But the power,
                        and the press and pulpit, are in the hands of an old, effete race, and young
                        blood has no opportunity to make itself felt or heard.</p>
                    <p>That the colored race is doomed to extinction any observant man can see, and
                        but few will be left to trouble the people of 1900. This fact that time will
                        remove the cause of trouble, makes the trouble no less now. Time will cure
                        the toothache, but it hurts at the time for all that. That the race is
                        doomed is evident, and from these and other causes. They are incapable, or
                        too careless to care for each other when sick. I have known them when sick
                        of small-pox or pneumonia rise from their bed and go out into a cold,
                        drizzling rain, yet feel it an outrage if compelled to do so. "We take care
                        of she, we's free as a frog, hab to take care of she, dats not bein free as
                        a frog." They care little for their children, and but few are being reared
                        outside of the towns. They will leave their own sick and go any distance to
                        nurse whites, and sit up with them night after night.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The report provides a bleak assessment of life in post-war South Carolina,
                    particularly for union men and blacks who "are at the mercy of a set of
                    wretches, as unprincipled as they are cruel." The war may have brought about the
                    destruction of the Confederacy, relates the piece, but the outcome has had
                    little impact on everyday life; the antebellum elite continues to rule over
                    society and the ex-slaves are virtually powerless to defend themselves from
                    violence perpetrated by whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.01.23.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Ladies Skating</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, the propriety of permitting young ladies to ice
                    skate is being vigorously debated; in fact, many physicians have advised parents
                    not to allow their daughters to engage in the activity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Game Laws</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the hunting season for quail and pheasants has expired, as
                    decreed by the amended law passed last April.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Railway Extension</head>
                <origin>Shepherdstown Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the proposal to extend the railway line from Hagerstown
                    to Martinsburg has been approved. The line will be an extension of the
                    Cumberland Valley road, and will provide direct service from Martinsburg to
                    Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--A Good Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article endorses the law recently passed by the legislature that
                    mandates a fine of up to $500 and a prison sentence of up to one year for anyone
                    who buys or receives scrap iron, brass, lead, or metal from a minor. The law
                    "removes the temptation to pilfer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Bank Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Amberson</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jacobs</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Good</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mickley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the annual meeting of the stockholders of the First National Bank of
                    Waynesboro, the following men were named Directors for the ensuing year: W. S.
                    Amberson, Alex Hamilton, George Besore, George Jacobs, John Price, Henry Good,
                    Daniel Mickley, Joseph Price, and James H. Clayton. W. S. Amberson was
                    re-elected President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Col. Daniel O. Gehr, of Chambersburg, was elected Vice
                    President of the State Agricultural Society at its meeting in Harrisburg on Jan.
                    16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickey</ln>
                        <fn>Seth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 15th, Seth Dickey and Annie E., daughter of Matthew Smith, were
                    married by Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Agnew</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritchey</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>R. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 15th, N. S. Agnew and Mary E. Ritchey were married by Rev. R. G.
                    Ferguson, assisted by Rev. T. Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swanger</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 17th, Henry Swanger and Lizzie Shoemaker, daughter of William
                    Shoemaker, of Roxbury, Pa., were married by Rev. J. G. Moore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emery</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCouley</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 10th, James W. Emery and Mary McCouley were married by Rev. J. B.
                    Jones.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maxwell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 17th, James A. Davison and Maggie C., daughter of Dr. Maxwell, were
                    married by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eshelman</ln>
                        <fn>Peter L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Royer</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 3rd, Peter L. Eshelman and Susan Royer were married by Rev. John
                    Shank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Matilda L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Jan. 12th, Matilda L., wife of Andrew Wilson, died near Dry Run. She was
                    61 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.01.23.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
