<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.08.28">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/7</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-08-28">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.08.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Letters From Mrs. Jane G. Swisshelm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In her column, Mrs. Swisshelm discusses the results of the recent elections
                    in Tennessee and Kentucky, contending that they demonstrate that blacks can be
                    trusted to vote their true interests, rather than according to what their
                    masters tell them. That this occurred, she avows, should not come as a surprise
                    since blacks "are the shrewdest people I have ever met, and have thoroughly
                    learned the art of bending before a storm." Their cunning "has, for centuries,
                    been their only defense against savage ferocity and despotic power."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.08.28.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The County Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The ticket which the Republican Convention offered to the voters of Franklin
                        county for their support at the election before us, will command general
                        respect. The gentlemen who compose it are widely and favorably known, are
                        entirely worthy, and deserve the honors they will receive. It is inspiring
                        to go into a campaign with such names inscribed upon our standards. They are
                        of themselves the earnest of success. Placed in nomination fairly and
                        honorably, bearing good records politically and morally, representing a
                        party known to be the only hope of the country which it saved, it is
                        scarcely borrowing too much of the future to predict that their election is
                        fore-fixed. The nominees are so well known, that we have no call to
                        introduce them to the people; but we desire to say a word or two in regard
                        to each of them.</p>
                    <p>FOR THE ASSEMBLY.</p>
                    <p>Col. Theodore McGowan, of Fayetteville, received the nomination. A more
                        fitting selection could not have been made. Col. McGowan belongs to one of
                        the oldest families in the country, his father and grandfather having lived
                        and died in the neighborhood in which he resides. The Colonel is thoroughly
                        identified with the county, and would represent her with filial pride, as
                        well as with great ability, in the Legislature. He is a gentleman of
                        excellent qualifications. To a high classical education, he adds good,
                        plain, practical, every day common sense, a grace of nature above the gift
                        of schools. He is industrious, energetic, steady in purpose, true. Of a kind
                        and friendly disposition, he is still rather modest in his demeanor, and
                        lacks the self confidence that some people call impudence in us older
                        politicians. Although yet a young man, he has had much experience in
                        business life, for from the time he bore off the honors of his college to
                        the present moment, he has not had an idle day. The outburst of the
                        Rebellion found him occupying a prominent position as a professor in an
                        institution of learning in South Carolina. He left his situation as soon as
                        he could get away, and sought admission into our army. He entered the
                        service as Asst. Adj't General, in June, 1862, was on the Peninsula with
                        Gen. Howe, in Keyes corps; subsequently served under Gen. Sedgewick, in the
                        6th corps, and was at the battles of 2d Mannassas, and at Fredericksburg. He
                        was then transferred by special order from the War Department as chief of
                        staff to Gen. Martindale, Military Governor of Washington, and afterwards
                        continued with Gen. Augur. His duties at Washington were of the most
                        laborious nature, and were fulfilled with a fidelity that won him
                        distinction.</p>
                    <p>TREASURER.</p>
                    <p>Our fellow townsman, Samuel F. Greenawalt, will be assigned charge of the
                        public funds, for the next two years. Mr. Greenawalt is one of the most
                        popular young men amongst us, and one of our most influential business men.
                        He is engaged in the mercantile line in this place. It is likely that every
                        male adult in the county is acquainted with him, and we doubt very much if
                        any of his acquaintances will be willing to vote against him. No member of
                        the party has done more hard work for it than he, and none is more deserving
                        of its compliments. He will receive a strong vote.</p>
                    <p>ASSOCIATE JUDGE.</p>
                    <p>W. W. Paxton, Esq., the present incumbent, has discharged his duties so
                        satisfactorily, that it is the purpose of his constituents to continue him
                        on the bench. The Judge is admirably adapted to his post. He is discreet and
                        just, of pure moral character, and endowed with a wise discernment of human
                        nature. Calm, patient and intellectual, Judge Paxton is fitted by
                        temperment, experience, and training for the position he fills, and to which
                        he will be undoubtedly re-elected by a handsome majority.</p>
                    <p>COMMISSIONER.</p>
                    <p>Mr. A. H. Etter, of Green township, a practical farmer, is more than
                        qualified for the office he is selected to fill. The interests of the public
                        will be well subserved in his hands. He is pleasant and affable in
                        deportment, of unblemished reputation, and strict business habits. He will
                        make a very popular officer.</p>
                    <p>DIRECTOR OF THE POOR.</p>
                    <p>This, in our opinion, is one of the most important offices in the county. The
                        proper management of Alms House, is a subject which is beginning to attract
                        the earnest attention of the public, which had been too long indifferent to
                        the prominent christian duty of taking care of the poor. To provide a
                        comfortable home for our unfortunate fellow-beings upon whom poverty and
                        disease have laid their heavy burdens, is a high moral obligation imposed
                        upon communities. The institutions established for this purpose should be
                        managed with a spirit of benevolence. It is not enough to furnish food and
                        shelter for their inmates; these should be made comfortable, and, as far as
                        practicable, contented and happy. At the same time, extravagance should be
                        avoided, as prodigality is not beneficence.</p>
                    <p>John E. Maclay, of Lurgan, possesses in an eminent degree, the qualifications
                        needed for the Directorship. He is well suited both in heart and mind. A man
                        of excellent judgment, substantial business parts, and kind heart, he will
                        look well to the wants of the poor, and the interest of the public. The
                        choice of him as our candidate was most happy. He, also, is a practical
                        farmer, which is an additional recommendation of a Director.</p>
                    <p>JURY COMMISSIONER.</p>
                    <p>Addison Imbrie, of Antrim, formerly of Mercersburg, is fitted for the duty,
                        which he will be called upon to perform, by his general acquaintance with
                        the people of the county, by his discretion and good sense. He has long
                        enjoyed the reputation of being a consistent, and earnest member of our
                        party, and his name upon our ticket will add to its strength.</p>
                    <p>AUDITOR.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Witherow, of Metal, is at present a farmer; but for may years was a
                        prominent teacher. His education qualifies him in an especial manner for
                        Auditor. He is a gentleman of marked firmness and honesty; and any paper
                        that bears his signature presents a guarantee of its correctness. The favor
                        with which his name was received in the convention, betokened the reception
                        it will meet at the polls.</p>
                    <p>Such a ticket should secure the active support of the party, and commend
                        itself to the favor of those who have hitherto not been with us.</p>
                    <p>We want a full vote this fall. We owe to these gentlemen, who have sustained
                        us so often, that we now do some work for them.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maclay</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imbrie</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherow</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editorial endorses the ticket selected at the Republican County
                    Convention, describing it as commanding "general respect," and gives a brief
                    biographical sketch of each candidate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Convention: Its Harmony an Example</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors gleefully describe the proceedings at the Republican County
                    Convention as the most "harmonious" ever held in Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>D. Watson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The brief piece praises Col. D. Watson's performance during the convention,
                    which he presided over.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that President Johnson issued an order, calling on Gen.
                    Grant to rotate the generals in charge of the military departments in the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Tour Through The Rocky Mountains</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. K. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>McClure discusses his time in Montana in this installment of his journal to
                    the West. McClure focuses on the efforts of vigilantes to maintain order in an
                    area virtually devoid of the presence of law authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Salary of the County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Justice</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>P. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In his letter, "Justice" says the effort to raise the salary of the County
                    Superintendent of the Common Schools has been met "with an almost unanimous
                    disapprobation," and should therefore be abandoned. Opposition to the increase,
                    Justice explains, has nothing to do with P. M. Shoemaker, the current
                    Superintendent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.08.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Delegates Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nixon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that W. S. Everett and J. S. Nixon, T. B. Kennedy were selected by
                    the Farmers' and Mechanics' Industrial Association to represent the organization
                    at a meeting of Pennsylvania's agricultural societies that will take place at
                    the Agricultural College on Sept. 4th. The purpose of the meeting is to elect
                    Trustees of the College, make changes to the curriculum, and to select two
                    experimental and model farms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Barn Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Abraham Carbaugh's barn and its contents, including his crop
                    and farming utensils, were destroyed in fire on August 16th. The loss is
                    estimated to be $4,000, though Carbaugh did not have insurance. Carbaugh was the
                    only one to suffer injuries in the blaze; his injury was sustained when he tried
                    to rescue a prized horse. The fire is believed to be the work of an incendiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fun-Ahead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the Hope Fire Company will hold a picnic at Brown's Mill on Sept.
                    11th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Temperance Pic Nic</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Falling Spring Division, No. 122, S. of T., held their
                    picnic yesterday; the event had initially been scheduled for last Thursday, but
                    was postponed due to inclement weather.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Correction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors offer a correction for a mistake that appeared in the last
                    issue of the Repository. The correct number of votes received by S. F.
                    Greenawalt in the first ballot at the Republican County Convention amounted to
                    28, not 23, as the erroneous piece claimed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Political</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shilito</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the meeting of the Republican County Committee last Tuesday, J. W.
                    Fletcher and S. M. Shilito were elected Chairman and Secretary respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Appointment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>Will F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duffield</ln>
                        <fn>S. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Will F. Duffield, son of Dr. S. E. Duffield, was appointed Stenographic
                    Reporter to the Courts in Franklin county by Judge King.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Died at the Almshouse</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Brown has died from complications from his throat wound. Brown cut his
                    throat several weeks ago and had been recuperating in the Almshouse since.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Republican County Resolutions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article includes the ten resolutions passed by the delegates at the
                    Republican County Convention. Among the issues addressed: support of Congress's
                    Reconstruction plans; praise for Edwin Stanton; and endorsement of greater
                    protections for American industry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 16th, Catherine Hoke died suddenly at her home in Stoufferstown.
                    She was 61 years old</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 19th, William W. Skinner died at his residence in Fannettsburg.
                    He was 58 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, David Brand died in Chambersburg. He was 27 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Laura Alice</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 13th, Laura Alice, daughter of Christian and Mary Weaver, died at
                    Marion. She was 6 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 23rd, Ellen C., daughter of Andrew Detrich died in St. Thomas.
                    She as 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.08.28.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
