<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.11.06">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/14</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-11-06">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day>06</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.06.01">
            <pageNote>Page contains advertisements, a variety of anecdotes, and a story about
                sailing in the sewers of Paris.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.06.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Democracy and Mr. Stevens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Ill temper in a disputant is evidence of weakness. Whether the cause be bad
                        or the advocate poorly prepared to defend it, want of success is apt to
                        inspire malice and prompt abuse. Accordingly, the present course of
                        Democratic journals, the columns of which teem, North and South, with
                        frantic exclamations and the coarsest invective, must be regarded as the
                        natural result of the circumstances in which their editors find themselves
                        placed. For, we take it, difficulties similar to and equal to theirs have
                        seldom afflicted any class of men. Committed to a cause so inherently
                        weak--so absolutely indefensible on grounds of reason or humanity--conscious
                        to a degree men seldom attain of their want of means and ability to even
                        cover its defects from eyes sharpened by common sense, oppressed by a weight
                        of odium justly incurred for their betrayal of human rights in the interest
                        of a clique, and weighed down by a long, uniform, course of disasters, their
                        perplexities drive them to the employment of the weapons of malignity and
                        despair.</p>
                    <p>Once before, perhaps, in our brief history as a people has the indecency of
                        our opposition prints been rivaled. After the memorable contest waged and
                        won on the floor of the Constitutional Convention of 1787, by neither party,
                        and after the opening of the first administration under the Constitution,
                        when the workings of the government were plainly seen to be in the direction
                        of the party of stability and order, it speedily became the habit of the Red
                        Republicans of that day to load their columns with the bitterest
                        maledictions and the vilest calumniations of the characters, private and
                        public, of their opponents, and the most odious misrepresentations of their
                        actions. The name of Freneau has descended to our times as that of the most
                        malevolent and foul of those detractors. Though impotently, the scoundrel,
                        persistently, sought to stab the character of Washington. His spirit has
                        been revived and animates the body of more than one of his lineal party
                        descendants. For, if we scan the so-called principles of the Democratic
                        party, to day, it is easy to identify them as in soul the same as those of
                        the men who vexed the beginnings of our constitutional course, after having
                        nearly made impossible any harmonious union at all. The Democrats of to-day
                        are the Red Republicans--the transplanted sans-culottes of the eighteenth
                        century, animated by their impatience of restraint and their contempt for
                        whatever is stable and enduring. How bitterly they resisted the turnings of
                        the colonies towards a union which would make harvestable the fruits of the
                        Revolution; how zealously they strove, when settling the foundations of
                        government, to restrict it from enclosing all of privilege within its
                        limits; how successfully, operating through colonial jealousies, natural
                        dread of monarchical oppression, and vested interests, did they emasculate
                        the powers of government and providently protect class interests and
                        privileges!</p>
                    <p>We are not of the number of those who are profoundly penetrated with a sense
                        of the general or average superiority of our ancestors over ourselves, in
                        the matter even of statesmanship and sacrificing devotion to an idea. In the
                        light of the flames of our own civil war, whose illumination serves as well
                        to relume [unclear] the periods of past struggles, as to bring into relief
                        and comparison the figures of old time and present leaders, we can, and do,
                        judge intelligent, and possibly severely, of integrity, capacity, dignity
                        and purity. We assert, consequently, that our so much lauded ancestors were
                        very much as we--capable of rising, under the spur of an imminent necessity
                        to the height of the sublimest self-abnegation, as to many of their number,
                        for a brief period and in the matter of a particular and cherished interest,
                        but capable of furnishing, and actually furnishing, side by side with their
                        types of nobility and single-heartedness the representatives, zealous and
                        fierce, of the basest and meanest, or the weakest and most pusillanimous, of
                        half-hearted cowards and traitors. And of all they exhibited for the delight
                        or the reproach of humanity, we can, and do, under similar circumstances,
                        furnish counterparts. the rebel may well match the Tory and surpass him in
                        infamy, as the Copperhead rivals and outshames the cowboy. But we may also
                        proudly place the loyalist of Tennessee as a companion patriot to the
                        barefooted soldier of Trenton of Entaw [unclear] Springs. Such as men were
                        in '76, good and bad, such are they with whom we deal in this generation--no
                        better, perhaps no worse.</p>
                    <p>Accepting this judgment while it, upon the whole, will repress any undue
                        complacency with which we may be filled, who have toiled and suffered for a
                        great cud, and have now the happiness of beholding it partly accomplished
                        and with reach of consummation, it will serve to moderate our surprise that
                        party rancor should assume even its present vindictive phase. Yet, it is
                        true, that the Democratic sheets of yesterday and last week are only to be
                        approached in transcendent dirtiness by those the same Editors will issue
                        to-morrow, and from Brick Pomeroy down, by steps of varying height, to the
                        Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Age</emph> and the Memphis <emph
                            rend="italic">Avalanche</emph>, it will go hard with even the man who
                        vilified the Father of his country "as a pickpocket," but that they will win
                        the palm of vituperation. Even our country sheets, uttered for the
                        information and guidance of a rural and placid people catch the evil
                        inspiration. Our neighbor of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> takes to
                        calling names with the earnestness and vigor of a drab. It opens a studied
                        leader with a wanton characterizing of Pennsylvania's most cherished
                        statesman as a "villain," and ascribes to him, in the compass of an article,
                        every attribute, which, in a free country, unfits a man to be either the
                        peer of the representative of his fellows. Why does it do this? Its ill
                        temper is certainly due to either the repugnance, which, in its virtuous
                        rage at wrong doing, it feels towards Mr. Stevens' actions, or it springs
                        from its consciousness of the party's past misfortunes being attributable to
                        the badness of their cause or their own want of ability to support and
                        defend it.</p>
                    <p>Who, that knows the history of the Democratic party, will, even in charity,
                        deems its anger to arise from outraged public virtue? The party which, for
                        forty years, debased itself at the feet of an ebony god and joyfully obeyed
                        biddings of its priesthood for the sake of a share of the offerings at its
                        shrine, as those calculating priests might deign to bestow them, and who did
                        this not only without the pretence that their fathers were idolaters and
                        they knew no better, but with blatant professions of their hatred of any
                        idolatry, can have no claim to manliness or sincerity. Since 1820, when
                        Missouri opened to slavery and Whitney invented the cotton-gin, the
                        Democracy have been the willing slaves of slavery. Thrift followed their
                        fawning. For its aid they sold their manhood; in its behalf they surrendered
                        their truth; and when they vent their spleen on hostile pens and thinkers,
                        the motive must be sought for in chagrin occasioned by other reasons than
                        excited virtue. It is noticeable, in nature, that bane and antidote usually
                        grow in the same forest, that the victim of the one may find relief in the
                        other, and it happens that as ink and type give forth to the world the venom
                        of the disappointed and hence slanderous politicians, that the alembic of
                        thought distills the stimulus of truth which will counteract it. Hence the
                        timeous [unclear] publication of the calm reflections of the sage of
                        Lancaster. They set at rest the minds disturbed by the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Spirit's</emph> loud outcry of "villain." Few will believe, after they
                        read and ponder over the old man's faithful portraiture of things as they
                        were, of things as they are, and as they may and must be, and who feel, as
                        they read, that the imagination, which guided the pencil in these
                        depictings, is that of genius inspired by the love of humanity, that the
                        artist is obnoxious to censure of his work to condemnation. He sees, with,
                        the breadth of vision which an election-jobbing politician's eyes cannot
                        compass, how that again, as to our founders, it is given to us and under
                        better auspices to widen and extend the foundations of constitutional
                        liberty; how it is possible, profiting by the experience of peace and the
                        blunders and dangers of war, to rectify the mistakes and make up the
                        shortcomings of our ancestors. We are rid of the great evil of our life
                        freed from the only incubus which disturbed our repose Unhampered by any
                        restrictions it haply our perverseness we do not create them we are freer to
                        build than our fathers of '87, freer to act than in the good times of
                        Monroe. And why shall we not? Why shall not the lessons of ninety years--the
                        lessons of an ideal mutilated by interest and passion; of growing greed and
                        extortion fostered by opportunity and natural depravity; of perverted policy
                        crippling or stifling the general weal in behalf of a sectional institution;
                        of rapidly rising danger to the general freedom from the debauching of a
                        partial wrong; of a horrid, baleful, war spitefully waged to turn back the
                        advancing power of truth, of a bitter, vengeful, resolve to undo the work
                        which sacrifice alone was able to achieve why shall not these lessons be
                        incorporated in sculptured stone in the temple of freedom which, as
                        architects, we are constrained to alter and improve? There seems to be no
                        reason save the opposition of them who occupying it hitherto only to defile
                        and desecrate it, clamor for the retention of the gloomy crypts in which,
                        save from observation, they practised their juggleries, rehearsed their
                        ceremonies and perpetrated their crimes. The Constitution of the past is
                        inadequate to the necessities of the present, and we must either amend it at
                        the suggestions of prudence or at the biddings of a future necessity.
                        Democrats may rave, but new articles must grow as columns to the temple. Let
                        them, indeed, be added with care and with understanding, but, where wisdom
                        points, let them be added. The result will vindicate the skill of the
                        framers. If well done, if incorporated in accordance with the law of the
                        work, with the grand conception of its original framers and the plan of our
                        Michael Angelo, the restorer, we will have, as our boast, a temple whose
                        dome will be co-extensive with the land, whose pillars will last while time
                        endures, and, blessing with a pure worship the nation which assembles in its
                        courts, will dwarf into littleness and shame into silence the bigots or
                        zealots who resisted its completion and maligned its builders.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors rebuke their Democratic counterparts for lowering the threshold
                    of acceptable journalism by publishing venomous diatribes against Thad Stevens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Italy Reconstructed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article recounts recent events in Italy, where Garibaldi and his
                    "'party of action'" are close to defeating the Pope's forces and establishing
                    control over the peninsula, and welcomes the changes as a step "in the right
                    direction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Golden Age</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a tendency in these of the "living present" to look back with fond
                        regret to the "good old times." The early Romans mourned the prosperous
                        reign of Anens Martius [unclear], and wished that they might see their like
                        again; a century later they panegyrized the classic age of Augustus.
                        Frenchmen love to remember the gallantry and popular sympathies which
                        characterized the age of their Fourth Henry, and Englishmen sing of the days
                        of "good Queen Bess." Old men talk of the better times in their youthful
                        days, and moral essays are written upon the growing depravity of these
                        latter days. How stands the matter? Does the age of gold belong to the dead
                        past, the present, or shall we expect it in the time to come? What period of
                        time has produced fruit more golden than that in which we live? In the arts
                        and sciences we have made rapid strides; true religion and morality are not
                        less generally practised, and political liberty has greatly progressed. Six
                        years ago many millions of human beings that are now free suffered in
                        bondage. Four millions in the United States; nine or ten millions of serfs
                        in Russia, and millions of slaves in Brazil are clothed with many in the
                        United States with all the rights belonging to citizenship. This itself
                        gives the period a golden tinge that no former age has equalled. But this is
                        not all, for this was but the result of a purer religion and a better public
                        sentiment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors decry the tendency to romanticize the past and disparage the
                    present; no period of time, they contend, "has produced fruit more golden than
                    that in which we live."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Killing Negroes For Fun</head>
                <origin>Memphis Post</origin>
                <commentary>"The Memphis Post chronicles the doings of a scoundrel in Tipton county,
                    Tenn., named Poindexter, who has been amusing himself by killing negroes
                    whenever he had a chance, without any other motive than a desire to murder black
                    men. His last crime is thus described:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article recounts the details surrounding the murder of a black man
                    named Jake Thompson, who was killed by a white man named Poindexter, for no
                    other reason than his race. In the past, Poindexter had apparently articulated
                    his desire to kill all the blacks he could, and had acted on this sentiment
                    several months prior, though his actions had not resulted in any type of serious
                    investigation by the authorities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Woman Marries A Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece reports on the marriage of two women in Syracuse, one of whom is
                    a cross-dresser who, after arriving from England, apparently drew the interest
                    of several local young women. Three weeks after the marriage ceremony was
                    performed, the subterfuge was discovered by the bride's father and the English
                    woman arrested. Despite that the "bride still clings to her woman husband, and
                    claims that the arrest is a conspiracy against them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Reconstruction of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One result of the elections at the South is clear. Conventions will be held
                        in most or all of the States, and an overwhelming majority of the delegates
                        thereto will be advocates of the Congressional plan of reconstruction. This
                        is the great lesson of the hour. Local politics at the North, party
                        machinations, impeachment, agrarianism, gains here and loses there--all
                        petty partisan phenomena are but the surface ripples, at best the chopwaves,
                        on the political sea, while the great ground-swell is to be found in that
                        steady and resistless flood-tide of public sentiment at the South which
                        flows on to reconstruction.</p>
                    <p>We at the North have been liable to forget, of late, that the political
                        squabbles, which are as common to the most stagnant peace times as to
                        revolutionary epochs in history like that of to-day, can have little to do
                        with the fate of the South. Northern State elections, though much in every
                        way to us, are of very little import or interest to the South. When the
                        Jackson <emph rend="italic">Clarion</emph> tells us that only half a dozen
                        out of the sixty-one delegates to the Anti-Congressional Convention so
                        imposingly advertised for weeks in every county, and this after the
                        "Conservative triumphs" at the North, we may divine that the South does not
                        propose to reject the Congressional plan. Question of impeachment, of
                        repudiation, of prohibitory liquor codes, of protective tariffs, of revenue,
                        of <emph rend="italic">Alabama</emph> claims--of whatever else it likes, can
                        be discussed by the North with furious fervor; but to the South, the first
                        and sole question is that of reconstruction. What, therefore, the <emph
                            rend="italic">Clarion</emph> says of Mississippi is probably true of the
                        people of South in general--that "the attempt to organize a party in
                        opposition to reconstruction meets no response whatever in their hearts, and
                        is emphatically a failure."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As a result of the outcome of the late elections in the South, says the
                    article, constitutional conventions will be held across the region and the
                    overwhelming majority of the delegates will be "advocates of the Congressional
                    plan of reconstruction."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.06.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bricker</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallach</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Leonard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cauffman</ln>
                        <fn>Isaiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayhew</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Noah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Justice</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kean</ln>
                        <fn>Jesse</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hovis</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horner</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skipp</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hisey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGeehen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booth</ln>
                        <fn>Jane L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heisy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Talhelm</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>Obed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deihl</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plasterer</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herrenlahen</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Godfrey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spielman</ln>
                        <fn>Melchior</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fourthman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langhorn</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morten</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Jamesx</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports on the cases adjudicated last week in Court. The
                    session was presided over by Judge King and Associates Paxton and King. Quarter
                    Sessions: Com. vs. Frank Jones--Assault and Battery, on oath of John Ferry. A
                    true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty, verdict guilty of assault. Sentenced to
                    pay a fine of $5 and cost of prosecution. Com. vs. John McGeehen--Assault and
                    Battery, on oath of Jane L. Booth. A true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty,
                    verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine of one cent and costs of prosecution.
                    Com. vs. Joseph Wallach--Surety of the Peace, on oath of Jacob Heisy. The court
                    after hearing the case dismissed it, each party paying half the costs. Com. vs.
                    John Powell--Assault on oath of Simon Talhelm. Not a true bill and prosecutor to
                    pay costs. Com. vs. Obed Gsell--Assault and Battery on oath of Elizabeth
                    Thompson. Not a true bill and prosecutor to pay costs. Com. vs. Jacob
                    Diehl--Malicious Mischief, on oath of C. Plasterer. Defendant pleaded guilty,
                    whereupon the court sentenced him to pay a fine of one cent, costs of
                    prosecution, and be imprisoned in county jail one month. Com. vs. Margaret
                    Bricker. Assault and Battery. Catherine E. McKee, Prosecutrix. A true bill.
                    Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict not guilty--costs equally divided between
                    Prosecutrix and Defendant. Com. vs. Susan Spidle--Larceny, on oath of Elizabeth
                    Lesher. A true bill. Defendant pleaded guilty whereupon the court sentenced her
                    to pay a fine of one cent, costs of prosecution, and be imprisoned in county
                    jail two months. Com. vs. Theodore Myers--Desertion of his wife, on oath of Mary
                    Myers. Upon hearing the case, the court directed the defendant to pay the
                    prosecutor the sum of $5 per month, and be committed to jail until he comply
                    with the order, or give security for compliance therewith. Com. vs. Mary Hays
                    and Bettie Johnson--Disturbing meeting of Sumner League, on oath Moses Taylor.
                    Defendants pleaded guilty, and sentenced to pay fine of one cent and costs of
                    prosecution. Com. vs. Leonard Cauffman and Isaiah Cauffman--Assault and Battery,
                    on oath of J. R. Smith. Not a true bill and prosecutor to pay costs. Com. vs.
                    Branton Williams--Assault and Battery, on oath of Obed Gsell. Not a true bill
                    and prosecutor to pay costs. Com. vs. Dr. John E. McKee. Assault and battery. A
                    true bill. Defendant pleaded not guilty. Verdict guilty. Sentenced to pay a fine
                    of five dollars and costs of prosecution. Com. vs. Mary Hays--Charge assault and
                    battery, on oath of Bettie Johnson. Defendants pleaded guilty and were sentenced
                    to pay costs. Common Pleas: Ann C. Funk and James Hovis vs. David Miller and
                    William F. Horner. Summons in trespass. Defendants confessed judgment for $30
                    and costs. James Shipp vs. Jacob Hisey. Appeal from judgment for John Kauffman,
                    Esq., Justice of the Peace. Defendant confessed judgment for $20 and costs.
                    Jesse Kean, Administrator of James W. Palmer, dec'd, vs. Daniel Palmer. This was
                    an action to recover $475, which Plaintiff alleged that the Defendant had
                    received from the Bounty Fund Committee, of Southampton township, as the local
                    bounty of Plaintiff's intestate, James W. Palmer--The Defendant admitted the
                    receipt of the money but pleaded payment. Verdict for Defendant. Daniel
                    Hawbecker, Administrator of Noah Myers, dec'd, vs. Frederick Foreman. This was
                    an appeal by Defendant from the judgment of justice John A. Hyssong--The claim
                    of Plaintiff was for $98.68 for hogs sold to Defendant at the sale of the
                    property of Noah Myers, dec'd. The defendant claimed to have paid the claim in
                    full. Verdict for the Plaintiff for $98.68. James Shipp vs. Jacob Hisey. Appeal
                    from judgment for John Kauffman, Esq., Justice of the Peace. Defendant confessed
                    judgment for $20 and costs. Sarah Mayhew vs. Ephraim S. Shank. Summons case in
                    assumpsit. This was an action brought by the Plaintiff, Sarah Mayhew, for money
                    claimed to be due her for services tendered the Defendant in the capacity of a
                    servant. Verdict for the Plaintiff for $54.87. Licenses: Licenses for
                    restaurants were granted to Catharine Herrenlahen, George Rodgers, and Godfrey
                    Greenawalt, Chambersburg, and Melchior Spielman, Waynesboro: for ale houses to
                    Michael Miller, Chambersburg, and George Fourthman, Waynesboro: for wine store
                    to Dr. H. Langhorn, Chambersburg. Licenses for restaurants were refused to Maria
                    Morton, Greencastle, and James Snider, Mercersburg. The applicant of David
                    Harper, for a restaurant in Greencastle, was withdrawn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Franklin Lyceum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamborn</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oelig</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Irwin</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamborn</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gsell</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witherspoon</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that a literary organization named the Franklin Lyceum was
                    recently established in Montgomery township. Since its founding, the Lyceum has
                    hosted debates on two topics: the utility of capital punishment and a discussion
                    on whether a republic is the best form of government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Improvements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>George K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanamaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulmer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Early</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beatty</ln>
                        <fn>Walter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article notes the various internal improvements undertaken by local
                    residents lately. Apparently, Chambersburg is experiencing a building revival.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Centenary Celebration</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Presbyterian congregation of Upper Path Valley will
                    celebrate their centenary in Spring Run on November 19th and 20th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Promoted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLeod</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that Lieut. A. McLeod, of Franklin county, was promoted to First
                    Lieutenancy in the Regular Army, and assigned to the 38th Infantry Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Arrested</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Chief</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ackerman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece informs readers that Chief Houser has returned from Illinois with
                    his prisoner, William Ackerman. Ackerman, a young man from Chambersburg, is
                    wanted for "obtaining money under false pretence." Ackerman was arrested a year
                    ago, but escaped from prison and managed to elude detection until recently when
                    Chief Houser received information that the escapee was living in Illinois, and
                    immediately took steps to return him to Franklin county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Supreme Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Supreme Court of Pennsylvania has rendered decisions in four cases from
                    Franklin county: the case of Dixon et al. vs. Gilian et al. was affirmed at
                    Applicants' costs; Best vs. Hammond was reversed and venerie de noxo awarded;
                    Gillen's Administration vs. Gillen et al was affirmed; Guilford township School
                    District vs. Zumbro was reversed and judgement for defendants below on case
                    stated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--I. O. G. T.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyter</ln>
                        <fn>Wilber</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloh</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilber</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tolbert</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>Edward C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roney</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keagy</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahon</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKroy</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sloan</ln>
                        <fn>R. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespie</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoke</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forbes</ln>
                        <fn>Cordelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wanamaker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kirby</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officers were selected to represent the McMurray Lodge, No. 119, I. O. G.
                    T., in a meeting held last Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Hoops Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article disparages the return of the hoop skirt, which is once again in
                    vogue in Paris. "That inexorable Fashion should compel our women to be street
                    sweepers is a deplorable plague of social tyranny, but there is no escape from
                    what the French call le despotisme de la mode," the piece relates. "The time
                    will come, we hope, when our ladies will not go to the French Court but to
                    common sense for their styles."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Counterfeits Afloat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that counterfeits of "the fifty dollar Compound Interest Notes,
                    issued under the act of February 1862," have appeared for a second time. The
                    counterfeits are such a "good imitation of the genuine" that some have been
                    redeemed unknowingly by the Treasury Department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Admitted to Practice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph McClure was admitted to practice law in the county's courts last
                    Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Sorghum Factory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zook</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Samuel Zook's Sorghum Factory, located near Orrstown, burned
                    down in a fire on October 25th. The fire destroyed "a large quantity of cane"
                    stored in the mill as well. The blaze was touched off by a spark that fell from
                    the chimney onto a pile of crushed sorghum.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Street Extension</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Town Council has approved an ordinance extending King
                    Street from the Franklin Railroad to a new street to be opened running north
                    from Market St.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local Items--Sworn In</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shenafield</ln>
                        <fn>Wiliam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Shenafield assumed his place as a member of the board last week.
                    Elected Commissioner in the late election, Shenafield replaces John Armstrong,
                    who is retiring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtzworth</ln>
                        <fn>William D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>Evaline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindsay</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 22nd, William D. Holtzworth and Evaline, eldest daughter of John
                    Lindsay, were married by Rev. W. Howe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>Martin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 31st, Martin V. West and Sophia Yost were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moulder</ln>
                        <fn>Wilmer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Clarinda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 30th, Wilmer Moulder and Clarinda A. Harrison were married by Rev.
                    William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zollinger</ln>
                        <fn>F. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rigner</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 24th, F. L. Zollinger, of Strasburg, and Sarah P. Rigner were
                    married by Rev. J. Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Walker</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fraker</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 26th, Martha, 11, died; on Oct. 4th, Walker, 5, died; on Oct.
                    25th, Sarah, 21, died; and on Nov. 1st, Daniel, 18, died: The children,
                    belonging to Elias and Mary Fraker, died of diphtheria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaldson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 24th, Elizabeth Donaldson died in Greencastle. She was 67 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crouse</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 23rd, Ann, wife of Solomon Crouse, died near Spring Run. She was 39
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas Bruce</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 13th, Thomas Bruce, son of William and Mary Ferguson, died in
                    Guilford township.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 1st, Samuel Shaffer died. He was 64 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jane Ann Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jenings</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 2nd, Jane Ann Maria, daughter of Jenings and Elizabeth Jones, died.
                    She was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.11.06.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
