<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.06.05">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/30</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-06-05">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day>05</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.06.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>WE clip the following from one of our exchanges, which we give for the
                        benefit of the "fair sex," showing the material used to make a fashionable
                        "waterfall." Here it is:</p>
                    <p>A WATERFALL.</p>
                    <p>Take four ponds of rags and a bunch of shavings,<lb/> An old tin pan, and a
                        bunch of straw;<lb/> Then steal an old hat of somebody's leavings,<lb/> And
                        swear it's your own to get clear of the law;<lb/> Next get an old stocking
                        and stuff it with paper,<lb/> And if it is possible, put in a mole;<lb/>
                        Then get some old china, and a nutmeg grater;<lb/> And make them all up in a
                        nice little roll;<lb/> Put all these things in a net of red,<lb/> And
                        glistening beads must cover them all;<lb/> Then fasten it on the back of
                        your head,<lb/> And you will have--a waterfall.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The brief piece provides mock instructions for fashioning the latest vogue
                    in women's hairstyles--the "Waterfall."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The page contains advertisements, several anecdotes, and a short story
                entitled "The Left Slipper."</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.06.05.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>How It Will Result</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defending their belief that the legislative process in Pennsylvania needs
                    reform, the editors lampoon their rivals at the Patriot and Union for failing to
                    comprehend the urgent need for substantive procedural changes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To The Humane</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In farcical terms, the editorial urges the public to have pity on state law
                    makers who are forced to endure long hours of intensive labor while legislating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Address of Penna. State Equal Rights League</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Moses Anderson, who speaks of himself a "an humble citizen of prescribed
                        race," sends us "An address to Leagues and other Associations auxiliary to
                        the Pennsylvania State Equal Rights League, and to the colored people of the
                        State of Pennsylvania, signed by William Nesbit, President of Pennsylvania
                        State Equal Rights League, and he asks us to give place to his address, or
                        at least to a synopsis of it. He anticipates that "the day is not far
                        distant when the colored man will enjoy all the rights that belong to
                        American citizens," and deems it important that the race is prepared for
                        their coming privileges. The aforementioned League is said to be a thorough
                        organization of the colored people, looking to this end.</p>
                    <p>The address opens by announcing that it is fitting and proper that the
                        persons to whom it is directed should take note of their progress, and
                        counsel together as to their condition and prospects; and, it congratulates
                        them that they have more to encourage them now, than they had in all the
                        long years since their race has inhabited this continent. The true
                        principles of the government, as enunciated in the Declaration of
                        Independence, are asserted to be for the first time understood and
                        practiced, and the policy everywhere recognized that it is not safe to
                        trample on human rights. Their brethren in the rebel States, being invested
                        with their God-given rights, it is assumed that they will be a judicious use
                        of their power reflect back power upon the colored residents of the North.
                        The lively hope is expressed that the National Congress will secure their
                        rights, or that the Supreme Court will decide against discriminations on
                        account of race or color. But if no shorter or juster course be possible,
                        the question of enfranchisement will be before the people at the general
                        election in 1869. It is therefore proposed to secure the tribunal of the
                        people in their favor. To effect this purpose, the address counsels a
                        combination of effort.</p>
                    <p>The objects of the League are "to unite the entire colored people of our
                        State into one common brotherhood, for the promotion of morality, education,
                        temperance, frugality, industry and the encouragement of everything that
                        pertains to a well ordered and dignified life, and to obtain by appeals to
                        the minds and consciences of the American people, or by legal process, a
                        recognition of the rights of the colored people of the United States," and
                        to arouse these people to labor until they have arrived at the full stature
                        of enfranchised manhood. The address denies that they are, under all
                        circumstances, especially lax in morals, intelligence or understanding.
                        Outraged and oppressed as they have been, it is a wonder that they have
                        preserved even a show of regard for law and order. It points proudly to the
                        fact that they have kept pace with the spirit of the age in the amenities
                        and refinements of civilization, and that they present an unbroken front of
                        loyalty to the government.</p>
                    <p>Each one can do something to raise their standard still higher; and by
                        uniting their energies in a common cause will reap the reward that comes to
                        a just cause guided by intelligent combination of efforts. If they suffer
                        themselves to be distracted and divided, they will show themselves a race of
                        idiots, of whom their friends now, and their children hereafter, will be
                        ashamed. They have already realized the blessings of union. They did all
                        possible to influence Congress in the direction it has taken, have poured in
                        petitions; sent their agents to Washington; have personally solicited the
                        champions of their cause, and know their organization is approved. The
                        victory most satisfactory and practical which they have achieved, is in
                        removing the discrimination against them in public conveyances. The address
                        claims that the committee of the League, Messrs. Foster, Catto and Bowser,
                        prepared, word for word, as it now stands on the statute books, the act
                        passed by the legislature of Pennsylvania forbidding discrimination against
                        passengers by railroad and railway corporations, and then ably assisted in
                        securing its passage and approval. It appeals to the colored people to rise
                        above their surroundings, and, by their own merits, close defamation and
                        detraction. They must not depend solely on the philanthropist or statesman.
                        They must plead their own cause. As they are now American citizens, they
                        must cultivate such virtues as will not shame that honored title. Education
                        is their surest passport to respectability, and industry and frugality will
                        silence their enemies. Their plain duties are organization, education,
                        industry and frugality. The League is the only organization universally
                        adapted to their needs, and the colored person who opposes it is false to
                        his interests. The next annual meeting sits at Reading, Pa., on the second
                        Wednesday of August. The address closes with a glowing appeal to the colored
                        men of Pennsylvania to unite, organize, do their full duty, and rely upon
                        God, who has brought them through the wilderness of slavery, almost within
                        view of the promised land of equality before the law.</p>
                    <p>We have condensed the address, nearly in its own words. It is written
                        skilfully, earnestly, and forcibly. All good citizens, of whatever race or
                        party, will rejoice at any effective efforts to promote the personal welfare
                        of the race; and intelligence, sobriety, frugality and industry are powers
                        that will elevate any people, however degraded by oppression and wrong. The
                        colored people have now inducements to progress, morally and intellectually,
                        before them, and it is wonderful how they are pressing forward in
                        self-improvement. We bid them God speed in their "longings, strivings,
                        yearnings," and we have enough faith in "God and Nature" to believe that
                        they will be "lifted up and strengthened."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial endorses the Pennsylvania State Equal Rights League, a
                    "colored" organization promoting racial uplift. Its goal, the piece relates, is
                    to "'unite the entire colored people of our State into one common brotherhood.'"
                    To achieve this goal, the group promotes the importance of "morality, education,
                    temperance, frugality industry, and everything that pertains to a well ordered
                    and dignified life."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Penna. Reserve Corps Association</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article recounts the events from the first annual convention of the
                    organization, which was held in Harrisburg last Thursday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Indian Troubles</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE INDIAN TROUBLES.--The intelligence from Montana indicates that the people
                        of that Territory are making extensive preparations for a general Indian
                        war, which they evince a determination to push to the point of
                        extermination. Acting Governor Meagher is reported to have issued a
                        proclamation calling for six hundred mounted men for immediate service,
                        which was being eagerly responded to, several companies having been
                        organized in a few hours. Indian outrages upon the white settlers in the
                        Gallatin Valley seem to be the provocation for this movement. The Indians
                        are also said to be threatening the destruction of Virginia City and Helena.</p>
                    <p>Reports from Fort Kearney represent the Indian war fairly commenced on the
                        Platte river, the savages burning ranches, stealing stock and murdering
                        settlers daily. Gen. Smith is <emph rend="italic">en route</emph> for Fort
                        Kearney. Detachments of troops, encamped opposite Fort Sedgwick, were
                        expected to leave the former post about the 1st of June. Gen. Custer is
                        reported, with his cavalry, at Fort McPherson. The Indians appear to
                        entertain no desire for peace, and can only be brought to terms by the
                        bayonet.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a war with the Indians in the Montana Territory is
                    imminent. The governor has issued a call for "six hundred mountain men" to seek
                    revenge for "Indian outrages upon the white settlers of the Gallatin Valley." So
                    deep is the enmity, the settlers "evince a determination" to exterminate their
                    foes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Far Off Chats With Old Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>McClure discusses his stay in Denver in this week's correspondence. He
                    reveals that the chief topic of discussion there is the Indian question, which
                    settlers believe can only be solved by "prompt and merciless extermination."
                    Though not fully in accord with the extreme nature of this conclusion, McClure
                    does exhibit a certain sympathy for the position.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Letters From Jane G. Swisshelm</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Jane G. Swisshelm</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuing her assault on Gen. Grant, Swisshelm assaults his character and
                    argues that he cares for no one but himself and his cigars. And for that reason,
                    he is unfit for the presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.06.05.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--District Temperance Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eberly</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rowe</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>R. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oaks</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>Morrow R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ziegler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Small</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Upton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClintock</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Linn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barr</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article reports that the State Pennsylvania Temperance Union met in
                    Chambersburg last Tuesday during which time several resolutions were passed
                    outlining the organization's plans to promote abstinence from intoxicating
                    beverages. The convention continued the next day with addresses given by Rev.
                    George D.Chenoweth, the Correspondent Secretary of the Union, Rev. J. A.
                    Kunkelman, and Rev. S. H. C. Smith, and in the evening an auxiliary group--the
                    Franklin County Temperance Union--was formed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--I. O. O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ebright</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schlessman</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kendig</ln>
                        <fn>D. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisely</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powders</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keefer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golden</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zearfoss</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicklas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dehart</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mehler</ln>
                        <fn>F. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article notes that officers were selected at the organizational meeting
                    of the new I. O. O. F. lodge in Orrstown last Saturday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Meeting of Classis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>Walter E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Mercersburg Classis of the German Reformed Church, which convened in
                    Bedford county on May 17th, Rev. Walter E. Krebs was elected President, reports
                    the piece.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Baggage Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In its last session, says the article, the legislature passed a law
                    limiting to one the number of trunks a passenger can bring on board trains; the
                    trunks must not exceed one hundred pounds and, if lost, damages exceeding three
                    hundred dollars will not be allowed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Shooting Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blues</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Little</ln>
                        <fn>Titus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Officer</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that William Montgomery was shot by David Stoner last Saturday
                    afternoon. The shooting occurred several hours after the two men had been
                    involved in an altercation, which resulted in Montgomery knocking Stoner out.
                    Stoner took his revenge later after he procured a gun; he went to Montgomery's
                    house in Wolfstown and shot him, inflicting a painful, but not fatal wound.
                    Stoner fled the scene and is still at large, though two men, George Blue and
                    Titus Little, were arrested by Officer Houser and charged with acting as
                    accomplices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Sudden Death</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The piece notes the startled reaction of the town to the news that Nannie
                    E., daughter of W. W. Paxton, had died. Nannie had only recently recovered from
                    a long illness when she suffered a hemorrhage while walking with friends and
                    later expired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Our Woolen Factory</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary>"The editor of the Waynesboro Record, W. Blair, Esq., having visited our
                    Woolen Factory, speaks of it as follows in the last issue of his paper:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article praises the Chambersburg Woolen Factory, and calls on readers
                    to patronize the entrepreneurial endeavor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Death of Mrs. Baker</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassler</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that Mrs. Harriet Baker, wife of Samuel Baker, died at her home in
                    Ohio several weeks ago from the effects of the injury she suffered in
                    McConnellsburg last fall. Baker and Laura Hassler were hurt in an accident that
                    occurred when the horse pulling their wagon dashed off suddenly; unlike Baker,
                    Hassler died immediately following the incident.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Called</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Agnew</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. Agnew will take charge of the Chambersburg Presbyterian
                    congregation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhamer</ln>
                        <fn>George O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Informs readers that George O. Seilhamer, formerly local editor of the
                    Repository and "now on the editorial corps for the New York Tribune," is in town
                    for a short visit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gehr</ln>
                        <fn>Hastings</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hastings Gehr, member of the Chambersburg bar, has been appointed Register
                    of Bankruptcy for Franklin's congressional district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Mr. Stevens on Confiscation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Hon. Thaddeus Stevens has written the following letter in vindication of his
                        proposed policy of confiscation.</p>
                    <p>LANCASTER, PA., May 28, 1867.</p>
                    <p>DEAR SIR: Short as your letter is, I fear I cannot answer it without
                        violating an injunction of my medical adviser not to become excited. You
                        live in a region which was two or three times invaded by the armies of
                        Jefferson Davis. In the Counties of Bedford, Fulton, Franklin, Cumberland,
                        Adams and York they visited almost every farmer and other inhabitant, and
                        plundered them of their horses, cattle, provisions, wagons, and money, when
                        found. Beside some detached cases, they laid in ashes one thriving village
                        of 6,000 people, and turned the inhabitants houseless into the streets to
                        seek shelter in fence corners. No provision has ever been made, or is now
                        making, to reimburse the plundered citizens. By the law of nations a
                        government makes no compensation for damages done by an invading army,
                        unless such government be victorious, when it always provides by treaty for
                        the payment by the vanquished enemy. A government which neglects to make
                        such provision on behalf of its plundered citizens is basely negligent of
                        its duty. A <emph rend="italic">quasi</emph> peace exists between the late
                        belligerents, the terms of which are dictated wholly by Congress, which is
                        under the control of the Republican party. Nothing but the proceeds of the
                        confiscation of a small portion of the property of the wealthy Rebels can be
                        applied to pay the damages inflicted by the marauders, unless it be paid out
                        by the Treasury of the United States. A few Republican meteors, always
                        erratic in their course, are flitting through and exploding in the
                        Republican atmosphere. They attract sufficient public attention to enable
                        them to assure the amiable Rebels who inflicted this injury that they need
                        fear no confiscation; that nobody of any note in the North is in favor of
                        imposing such punishment for the sake of remuneration, or of justice. They
                        assure them that nothing shall be taken from Aiken's estate of millions,
                        from Hampton, Davis, Orr, Faulkner, or from a thousand others who are still
                        worth their hundreds of thousands, to reimburse the loyal men, North and
                        South, who were plundered of their estates, and to aid your post neighbors
                        to rebuild their humble tenements. It is scarcely to be endured that
                        Congress for two sessions should sit indifferent to these sufferers, and
                        take no steps to enforce these rights. These remarks apply to large portions
                        of Maryland, of West Virginia, Ohio, Indiana, and Missouri, as well as to
                        the Slave States. He who can patiently listen to that patent humanity which
                        we now see propagated, has more command of himself than I have. Indeed it
                        looks as if we are still to add to the burden of our taxation to defray the
                        expenses of transportation, and the ovation of triumphant traitors. But I
                        must stop, or I shall commit the fault against which I have been warned.
                        With great respect, your obedient servant, Thaddeus Stevens.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his letter, Stevens spells out his reasons for supporting the
                    confiscation of rebel property, and expresses his belief that northern border
                    counties, like Franklin county, that suffered damages as a result of raids
                    should be compensated from funds derived from the sale of Confederate estates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brubaker</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Creigh</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 30th, Daniel Etter and Rebecca, daughter of Peter Brubaker, were
                    married by Rev. Thomas Creigh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Appleby</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 23rd, John A. Skinner and Rachael Annie Appleby were married by Rev.
                    William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilhelm</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 22nd, Rev. J. Smith Gordon, of Pastor of Lower Path Valley and Burnt
                    Cabins Presbyterian Churches, and Maggie B. Kyle were married by Rev. John C.
                    Wilhelm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shartzer</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christ</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 28th, Emanuel Shartzer and Mary Christ were married by Rev. Dr.
                    Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 1st, Nannie, daughter of W. W. and Mary C. Paxton, died in
                    Chambersburg. She was 30 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reisher</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 18th, Mary, wife of Samuel Reisher, died in Chambersburg. She was 64
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crooks</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 19th, Robert Crooks, formerly proprietor of the Greencastle Pilot,
                    died in Petroleum Centre, Venango county. He was 27 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>Lisle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speer</ln>
                        <fn>Lisle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 29th, Nellie, daughter of James and Lisle Speer, died in
                    Chambersburg. She was 6 days old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On May 28th, Jacob Stover died in Mercersburg. He was 57 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.06.05.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
