<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1867/pa.fr.fr.1867.09.04">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/08</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1867-09-04">
            <year>1867</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>04</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sheridan.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains an ode to Gen. Sheridan, who was recently relieved of his command
                    and placed in charge of the military department of the Missouri.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Tour Through the Rocky Mountains</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. K. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>McClure's journey has brought him to Montana for this installment in the
                    series. The focus of the article is the mining industry, which is more
                    successful than its counterpart in Colorado. McClure claims the mines "teem with
                    boundless and available wealth," thus, he argues, the failure of mining
                    companies here can only be blamed on the ineptitude of their managers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.04.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Coming Contest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial argues that the Democrats have nothing of substance to offer
                    the voters in the upcoming election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that, contrary to popular perceptions, the reconstruction
                    bill does not confer upon the General-in-Chief the power to direct the district
                    commanders. Thus Gen. Grant had to follow the President's order to remove Gen.
                    Sheridan from his post.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>As tension builds between the President and Gen. Grant, the question has
                    arisen, "Does the President have the power to remove Grant?," to which the
                    article responds with an unequivocal no.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Johnson has replaced another district commander, Gen. Sickles, with an
                    appointee more to his liking, says the article. The President selected Gen. E.
                    R. Canby to take command of the Second (Charleston) District, and mustered out
                    Gen. Sickles and "reduced his rank to Colonel in the Regular Army."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Far Off Chats With Old Friends</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A. K. M.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his piece this week, McClure discusses daily life in the mining
                    districts of the Montana Territory.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Colored Celebration at Greencastle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>On Saturday week the colored men of the county had a great celebration at
                        Moss Spring, near Greencastle, in which they were joined by many of their
                        brethren from a distance. Hagerstown had many representatives, and furnished
                        a brass band. Mercersburg, with its colored military company, in black and
                        red, was prominent. Chambersburg sent quite a delegation. New York and
                        Philadelphia furnished the speakers. Greencastle, of course, provided
                        eatables for all in great variety and profusion, and also gave to the
                        occasion a military company, uniformed in white and blue. From early morn
                        till high noon, the dark faces came from every direction to the pic-nic--men
                        and women, youth and babies, and not a few old white-haired uncles, some of
                        whom were beat and bowed with three score years of slavery. All were dressed
                        for a gala day; garments in high colors, countenances in smiles. The blue
                        sashes of the Marshals were prodigious. In short, every thing gave color to
                        the anticipations of a high day.</p>
                    <p>Towards eleven o'clock there was a parade of the military through the
                        streets, and then the procession--band, speakers, guests, drum corps,
                        military companies, colored league, &amp;c., in due order, marched to
                        the grove at Moss Spring. After a capital speech by Rev. Henry Highland
                        Garnett, a colored man of great prominence among his people, dinner was
                        called for the children of Ham, and, an hour after, Wm. Forten, of
                        Philadelphia, a colored man of education and intelligence, was introduced to
                        the audience, and spoke for two hours. These, with music, fun and frolic in
                        plenty, finished out the programme and closed the pic-nic with the day.</p>
                    <p>It was a joyous occasion for them all, but never, under the sun, were mortals
                        happier than the old Virginia slaves who, at the pic-nic, looked and heard
                        with countenances where a broad grin but partially concealed an expression
                        of doubt and admiration. At night Garnett and Forten addressed the people of
                        the town, on the public square, in behalf of their race, oppressed and
                        wronged for two hundred and fifty years. On Sunday afternoon the former, a
                        Presbyterian preacher, delivered a sermon in the grove at the spring, to a
                        large audience, on the queer text, "Run and speak to that young man." The
                        same evening he preached, by invitation, in the German Reformed Church, to a
                        full house.</p>
                    <p>The noticeable feature about this demonstration, from beginning to end, was
                        the course of the Democrats. If they did not, Saturday and Sunday, day and
                        night, compose a majority of the whites present, they were, at least,
                        present in very respectable numbers, to their credit be it said. Nor did I
                        hear any of them that were present, find fault with anything said or done;
                        for indeed the conduct of the blacks was exemplary and the speakers were
                        careful in their utterances and modest in their behavior, and no one could
                        reasonably be offended. And besides all seemed to agree that it was both
                        natural and proper for a people that had been for so long a time groaning in
                        chains, to express their emotions of joy and gratitude at their deliverance
                        in some such public way, nor was there any question of the propriety of a
                        colored man (however it might be with a white) standing up to plead for the
                        rights of the colored race.</p>
                    <p>You will not be surprised then, that the Democracy of Antrim were not at all
                        obliged to the <emph rend="italic">Valley Spirit</emph> for its perverted
                        and jaundiced account of this affair; that on the contrary, they were very
                        much mortified at it. In fact, they manifested their displeasure at the
                        conduct of the ardent young man who hastened to head-quarter at Chambersburg
                        with a wild exaggerated story about it, in a very marked and disagreeable
                        way at the late delegate elections. The story as told in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph>, though palpably false in some particulars
                        only, gives as a while such a distorted and perverted view of what took
                        place as to be a sort of compound lie; which being perceived by all the
                        Democrats of the township, it was to be feared their belief in the veracity
                        of their organ's statements generally and in other more important matters
                        might be shaken. And then the particulars wholly false and unfounded were so
                        unfortunate and cutting, that they could not forgive the goose that inserted
                        them to the injury of his own friends. Thus, when he said the Chief Marshal,
                        "an exalted darkey on horseback, wore a Lieutenant Colonel's uniform,
                        borrowed from the President of the late Union County Convention," when it
                        was a notorious fact that the said exalted darkey was clothed in a black
                        dress, and the Union men laughing, said: "It is a pardonable mistake, these
                        Democrats knew little and cared less for the blue uniform of the Union
                        soldier, but had a sharp eye for rebel grey," they felt it keenly. It was
                        still worse to charge Mr. A. B. Wingerd, a Republican, with having invited
                        Mr. Garnett into the German Reformed pulpit, whereas the responsibility for
                        that rests with Mr. Augustus Shirey, a life-long Democrat until the breaking
                        out of the rebellion, who then joined himself to the supporters of the
                        war--sent his two sons to the front, one of whom fills a soldier's grave on
                        the heights of Fredericksburg; then, the war ended, exercising a patriotic,
                        at least, if any one should think an erroneous judgment, united himself
                        again with the Democratic party and remains there, voting their ticket. And
                        this was perfectly well known to everybody, for Mr. Shirey, has not at any
                        time since attempted to shift the responsibility, and does not now (I speak
                        by authority) desire to do so. It was very unfortunate for the <emph
                            rend="italic">Spirit</emph> to broad this subject. It is a sore one to
                        the Democrats. For they are not all of one mind about it. Some of the best
                        of them surmising that good pious colored ministers may be invited by God
                        into Heaven itself--than which hardly any pulpit or place is more sacred.</p>
                    <p>Lastly, a large portion of the audience at all times, as I said before, were
                        Democrats, yet the <emph rend="italic">Spirit</emph> speaks of the audience
                        as a whole as composed of "black and white niggers," which is excruciatingly
                        painful to those of its friends who were present--in short and not to put
                        too fine a whole matter is, that the colored folks had a jolly old time, and
                        the Democrats who went out for wool came home shorn.</p>
                    <p>W.</p>
                    <p>P. S.--If the <emph rend="italic">Spirit's</emph> man seems to cast ridicule
                        on the colored military, it is to be noted that almost all of them had been
                        in the Union army and <emph rend="italic">fought</emph> there."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>W.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>In his letter, "W." gives a glowing account of the celebration held by
                    blacks in Greencastle. He reports that there were delegations from the
                    surrounding communities present for the festivities, which included a speech by
                    Rev. Henry Highland, "a colored man of great prominence among his people."
                    Indeed, says W., Highland was so impressive that he was asked to preach at the
                    German Reformed Church the following day. And contrary to the "exaggerated"
                    reports in the Valley Spirit, his sermon was well-received by the white
                    audience, even by Democrats in the flock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Salary of the County Superintendent of Common Schools</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Friend of Common Schools</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The letter challenges the assumptions underlying a letter that appeared in
                    the last issue of the Repository demanding a freeze in the Superintendent's
                    salary. "A Friend" notes that the superintendent earns less than his
                    counterparts in the surrounding counties, a fact that prompted "the enlightened
                    progressive portion" to take a stand in favor of boosting his pay to achieve a
                    semblance of parity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Address of the Union Republican State Central Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article contains a copy of the speech delivered by F. Jordan, the
                    Chairman of the Republican State Committee. The subject of the address: the
                    weaknesses of the Democrats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.04.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article notes that A. K. McClure has accepted an invitation to speak
                    before the people of the Montana Territorial, and says he and his family will
                    probably not return until next spring because the Missouri River is too low to
                    sail and he refuses to make the trip overland because of the continued
                    hostilities with the Indians.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Kremer, of Cumberland county, was killed in an accident last week at
                    Foreman's mill. Kremer suffered a fatal wound to the head when he was struck by
                    a piece of the threshing machine, which burst while he was using it. Kremer, 29,
                    was a veteran who served "faithfully and gallantly" with the cavalry regiments
                    from the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Delegates to Synod</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fouse</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmer</ln>
                        <fn>A. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higbee</ln>
                        <fn>E. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krebs</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gast</ln>
                        <fn>F. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deatrick</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunn</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingerd</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyle</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aurandt</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weisel</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eisenburg</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fink</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walter</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article contains a list of the delegates from the Mercersburg Chassis
                    of the German Reformed Church who were selected to attend the Synod, which
                    convenes in Baltimore on October 16th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Odd Fellows</head>
                <origin>Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Daugherty</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the scheduled Odd Fellows' picnic did not come off because of
                    the weather; consequently, the much-anticipated address by Dr. Daugherty, of
                    Carlisle, was presented in the Hall.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--The Greencastle Pilot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the Greencastle Pilot will henceforth be known as the Valley
                    Echo and will contain an additional four columns of print.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wigner</ln>
                        <fn>B. Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the Democratic County Convention held yesterday, Capt. George W. Skinner
                    was named the party's candidate for Treasurer, Col. B. Frank Wigner for
                    Assembly, and Jon Armstrong for Associate Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Meeting of Synod</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the West Pennsylvania Synod of the Evan. Lutheran Church will
                    be held at the Lutheran Church in Chambersburg on September 12th. The event is
                    expected to draw over one hundred attendees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Off on a Tramp</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Silver Cornet Band has left for Antietam, says the
                    article, where they will participate in a dedicatory ceremony on the 17th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Broke Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Joseph Spindle, Gotlieb Miller, and Jacob Davis reportedly broke out of the
                    jail in Hagerstown last Wednesday. A reward of $75 is offered for their arrest.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Camp Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes that a camp meeting, "under the control of the Church of God," will
                    be held on land owned by John Kohler, near Monterey Springs, next Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Change of Proprietor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article relates that ownership of the rival newspaper, the Valley
                    Spirit, has changed hands. Messrs. Cooper, Stenger, and Duncan took possession
                    of the Democratic journal on the 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Anna</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coble</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 28th, Anna Coble, consort of Daniel Coble, died at the residence
                    of Samuel Coble. She was 81 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGowan</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 5th, Annie McGowan, daughter of Dr. D. S. McGowan, dec'd, died in
                    Fayetteville. She was 24 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1867.09.04.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
