<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.04.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01.21.96</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-04-14">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote>02</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.04.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Plant Corn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another article admonishing farmers to plant food crops, particularly corn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Murdering Women</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article alleges that exchanged prisoners collaborate stories of women
                    killed in New Orleans while cheering Confederate prisoners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Darkies in Council</head>
                <origin>Boston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Parody of blacks in an imaginary meeting to increase Negro enlistments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Col. 1 - 5 ads. Col. 6 poetry. Col. 6 and 7 Congressional records.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.04.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Human Nature Consistently Frail.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article condemns speculators and exhtortionists who attempt to amass
                    fortunes during the Southern struggle. Article points out examples of
                    speculation in the Revolution and quotes Washington on the subject.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>For Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article reports that communications in the Rockingham Reigister, the
                    Vindicator, and the Lexington Gazette urge Gov. Letcher and Col. Harman to
                    present themselves as candidates for Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The 25th and 31st Regiments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This ought to be sufficient warning to the citizens to have every drinking
                    establishment broken up."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Saturday evening and night last, the 25th and 31st Va. Regiments arrived
                        at this place on their way to-----where they will render gallant service.
                        These regiments have seen hard service, and never failed to admit themselves
                        in a gallant manner in the heat and trial of battle. Many of these men have
                        sealed their devotion to their country with their hearts' blood. These
                        regiments are composed chiefly of soldiers whose homes are in the possession
                        of the enemy. We hope they will soon be redeemed, that these gallant men may
                        again enjoy the comforts of home, by their own blazing and cheerful
                        firesides. In the disaster of Rich mountain, in July, 1861, the 25th
                        Regiment lost by capture 381 men--22 officers and 359 privates.</p>
                    <p>In this place on Sunday last, some of these soldiers imbibed too freely of
                        the "liquid fire," and becoming rather exuberant, were arrested by the Guard
                        of the Provost Marshal and placed in the Guard House. Some were arrested who
                        were not in that condition. For some time there was considerable excitement,
                        and a conflict between the soldiers of these regiments and the Guard seemed
                        imminent. The Colonel of the 25th happened to be in town, and he succeeded
                        in having his men released and their sympathizers and friends sent to their
                        regiment. This ought to be a sufficient warning to the citizens to have
                        every drinking establishment broken up. Will the newly elected Council do
                        their duty in this respect, or will they aggravate the evil by throwing open
                        the floodgates of crime?</p>
                    <p>Have we so soon forgotten the sad fate of Mr. Snider, or shall another human
                        sacrifice be offered on the altar of this devouring Molock? Shall the peace
                        and order of the town, and the safety of the lives of our citizens be
                        weighed in the balance with the paltry considerations of the revenue. God
                        forbid!</p>
                    <p>We would invoke the Council to pause and reflect, and to reflect seriously
                        before they consent to bring upon themselves the awful responsibility of
                        such consequences as may result from their action.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Mr.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that the 25th and 31st passed through Staunton. Some soldiers
                    got drunk and rowdy and were subsequently placed in the guardhouse. A scrap
                    between the soldiers and the Guard of the Provost Marshall was narrowly averted.</summary>
                <note>Article makes reference to a Mr. Snider, who was killed at the beginning of
                    the war by a drunken soldier, who was released as the shooting was deemed
                    accidental.</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNeill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports success of Capt. McNeill in capturing 16 more Yankees.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Isaac W. Airy</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Airy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac Airy refutes the charge of desertion made in the Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>William R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of William Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Anna L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Anna Clayton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Melvin Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Melvina Bell Summers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column/>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Anna L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Mary Ann Summers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Howe Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Items announce that Baldwin is standing for re-election to Congress and
                    that Howe Peyton and James Walker are standing for election to the House of
                    Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports, including a naval engagement at Charleston.
                Bottom illegible. Col. 4 Telegraphic Dispatches. Col. 7 ads and notices including
                list of letters left at the Post Office.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
