<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.09.29">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/29/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/12/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-09-29">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.09.29.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5, 6, 7</column>
                <head>General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details a series of actions taken by the Virginia Legislature, including
                    War Resolutions, Resolutions of Inquiry, Joint Resolutions, and Bills read and
                    passed. These included measures to prevent the issuance of small notes; a
                    resolution to inquire into the expediency of prohibiting speculators from
                    purchasing real estate; authorization of a sale of free black convicts in the
                    penitentiary; an act prohibiting citizens from going within the enemy boundaries
                    with intent to return again; a measure to require all justices of the peace and
                    constables to report to the nearest military post all deserters, or military
                    absentees; an act re-organizing the militia; a resolution on "Stonewall
                    Jackson;" an inquiry as to the best means of encouraging the production and
                    manufacture of powder and lead; and a resolution inquiring of the expediency of
                    reporting a bill fixing the prices of prime necessities.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.09.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Bragg's Victory Over Rosecrans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It has pleased Almighty God to reward the valor and endurance of our
                    troops by giving our arms a complete victory over the enemy's superior numbers."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After mentioning the fact that a major battle had been fought and won on
                    the Chickamauga River, in the northern part of Georgia, the article reprints a
                    series of dispatches from General Braxton Bragg detailing the particulars.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In addition to noting the occurrence of a series of skirmishes between Gen.
                    Lee and Gen. Meade, the article reports that there are indications the Northern
                    forces are planning an attack along the Rapidan River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Daring Act</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Pat Channing</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smoot</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An account of a raid by a small group of C.S.A. scouts, members of the
                    Black horse Cavalry, Fourth Virginia Regiment, upon a "Yankee" brigade
                    headquarters that resulted in the capture of a United States flag. The flag was
                    later presented to the Confederate War Department by Private Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Exchange of Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During a recent meeting between Col. Ould, the Confederate commissioner for
                    the exchange of prisoners, and his Northern counterpart Col. Meridith, Col. Ould
                    put forth a number of recommendations for expediting the release of officers and
                    men of both sides. While Col. Meridith seemed receptive to these
                    recommendations, he needed to refer the particulars to his government for
                    official approval.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Home Defense</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robertson</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2nd Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Preston</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt. Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoope</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2nd Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report on the organization of companies for home defense at the New Hope,
                    West View, and Mt. Solon districts, including, where available, the names of the
                    officers elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Socks For The Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The mere mention of this fact, we are sure, is all that is needed to have
                    this yarn in the fair hands of the ladies to be wrought in the form of good
                    comfortable socks for the suffering soldiers."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Members of the Soldiers Aid Societies are notified that there is a large
                    quantity of yarn available at the manufactory to be made into socks for the
                    soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Good News If True</head>
                <origin>The Columbus Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the private correspondence between Mrs. Maury and her husband,
                    Lieut. Maury of the Confederate Navy, there are three iron clads currently at
                    the Nassau port and four more are anticipated at any time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Yankees are making poisoned bullets at their arsenals. The Devil has a
                    just claim to the Yankees."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short filler piece that alleges the Northern troops are being supplied
                    with poisonous bullets.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Power of Endurance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is a notable fact that many of the men who were the most zealous advocates
                        of secession are now the least to be relied upon and have been almost,--some
                        of them quite,--brought to the point of grounding arms and making terms with
                        the enemy. This may result in great part from the fact that they did not
                        first count the cost of secession, and were not prepared for the
                        consequences which,--it is not arrogating too much to say,--more sagacious
                        men foresaw. Those who wanted secession, for its own sake, believed that
                        that great result would be accomplished by purely peaceful means; and, once
                        accomplished, the Southern Confederacy would soon attain a rank that would
                        place it amongst the foremost nations of the earth. We do not include in
                        this class those who, from considerations wholly selfish, labored to effect
                        the secession, rather than by compromise and conciliation to perpetuate the
                        Union. They may have had the q to comprehend in part, the nature of the
                        issue they were attempting to force upon the country, but labored
                        nevertheless to deceive the people. And they did deceive them. If the truth
                        can ever be ascertained, we believe that it will appear that both sections
                        were deceived; the North not anticipating the obstinancy [sic] with which
                        the South has fought to make good the act of secession; nor the South
                        expecting such an example of tenacity of purpose as the North has evinced in
                        its war for the Union. We say, therefore, that if both sections had foreseen
                        the terrible struggle that has ensued, the Union would have been preserved
                        by compromise, or a peaceable separation been effected.</p>
                    <p>The fact that this war has been changed in its character, and objects avowed
                        now which even Lincoln's Congress, directly after the battle of Manassas
                        positively disavowed does not effect the question in the slightest degree.
                        The progress of the war has served to develop the fact that many of the men
                        in the South who were least inclined to dissolve the Union, have now the
                        most decided repugnance to its restoration; whilst many in the North who
                        were originally hostile to the war, and would have condemned the Abolition
                        policy of the Administration, now support both. Such are some of the lessons
                        of the war.--<emph rend="italic">Lynch. Virginian.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that many of those who were most vocal in their call for secession
                    are now the most faint-hearted about carrying on the struggle, while others who
                    were reluctant to take this extreme measure are most committed to seeing the
                    struggle through to the end. The author opines that "[s]uch are some of the
                    lessons of the war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Fight In Madison On Tuesday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Based on reports offered by recent arrivals from Gordonsville, it appears
                    that Northern forces have crossed the Rapidan, burned Liberty Mills, and retired
                    back across the Rapidan River.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Outrage By A Yankee Brute Of A Colonel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A searing account of an alleged incident in which a Col. Murphy, now
                    stationed near Union Mills, attempted to force himself upon a number of women by
                    threatening them with drawn pistols and threats of death. He was only prevented
                    from carrying out his design by the intercession of others who were drawn to the
                    scene by the cries of the victims.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Public Speaking</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a large and enthusiastic meeting of the people of Augusta county, held on
                        Monday, 28th September, 1863 (being Court day,) on motion of J. Marshall
                        McCue, Hon. A. H. H. Stuart was appointed Chairman, and A. F. KINNEY,
                        Secretary.</p>
                    <p>The Chairman, in a brief speech, having explained the object of the meeting,
                        on motion of N. K. TROUT, Thomas J. Michie, Maj. S. L. Lewis, Jacob Baylor,
                        Samuel B. Finley, Wm. P. Tate, J. Marshall McCue, Dr. John McCheeney, A.
                        Koiner and John S. Ellis, were appointed a Committee to draft resolutions
                        expressive of the sense of this meeting.</p>
                    <p>On motion of J. MARSHALL MCCUE, Thomas J. Michie, Benjamin Crawford and
                        Matthew Podson, were appointed a Committee to wait on the Hon. LEWIS T.
                        WIGFALL, of Texas, and Hon. WM. SMITH, Governor elect of Virginia, and
                        request them to address the meeting, with which they complied in two
                        powerful and patriotic speeches, at the conclusion of which the Committee on
                        resolutions reported he following, which were unanimously adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we, the citizens of Augusta county,
                        will promptly deliver to the Government the tenth of our produce as required
                        by law. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we pledge ourselves to sell to the
                        Government and families of soldiers and other consumers all our surplus
                        products at the prices established by Government, and we further pledge
                        ourselves when any citizen refuses to sell his surplus at Government prices,
                        to report him to the Government Agent that his surplus may be impressed. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we will discountenance the sale of
                        anything to speculators and will not, under any circumstance, sell our
                        surplus grain to distillers. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we will discourage in every way we
                        can the desertion of our soldiers and extend all the facilities in our
                        power, to the authorities on their speedy arrest and restitution to their
                        commands. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That the people of Augusta co. have
                        perfect confidence in the ability and determination of our government and
                        people to pay the debt of the Confederacy, whatever it may be, incurred in
                        the holy cause of Liberty and Independence, and they will, therefore, invest
                        all they can and induce others to invest in the purchase of Confederate
                        bonds from the government. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we hail with pleasure the
                        brightening prospect before us of our ability to defend ourselves and that
                        we appeal to our people to let no momentary reverse chill their patriotism,
                        but do all in their power to encourage our Government in prosecuting the
                        war. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we feel our indebtedness to the
                        invaluable and we have derived from our mothers, wives and daughters during
                        the war, and we have a guarantee for the future in their indomitable zeal,
                        by a retrospect of the past and hereby extend to them our cordial thanks for
                        gracing this meeting with their presence. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That we most cheerfully accord to the
                        distinguished gentlemen who have so ably and eloquently addressed us to day,
                        our cordial thanks, and urge them to go forward in the good work they are so
                        ably sustaining. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That a Committee of _____ be appointed
                        to circulate these resolutions in the several Magisterial Districts of this
                        county, and obtain to them the signatures of the people. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That the proceedings of this meeting by
                        published in the papers of this place, and the city of Richmond. </p>
                    <p>On motion of S. B. Finley, the meeting adjourned <emph rend="italic">sine
                        die</emph></p>
                    <p>A. F. KINNEY, <lb/>Secretary. </p>
                    <p>A. H. H. STUART, <lb/>Chairman </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the various resolutions agreed to at a recent meeting of the people
                    of Augusta County. These resolutions were agreed to after two powerful speeches
                    offered by the Hon. Lewis T. Wigfall of Texas and the Hon. Wm. Smith,
                    Governor-elect of Virginia. These resolutions include pledges to send a tenth of
                    their produce to the government, as required by law; to sell their surplus goods
                    at the prices established by the government; to discontinue the sale of goods to
                    speculators and grain to distillers; to discourage deserters and help
                    authorities to apprehend any deserters; to invest in Confederate bonds; and to
                    avoid disillusionment in the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To The Valley And Its Ladies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There are a certain class of men in Virginia, remaining at home, who look
                    upon the progress of this war with careless indifference--they have folded their
                    arms and said 'Let the confederacy slide.' Can you not reclaim them? Let me ask
                    you to wield your influence, which is powerful, over them, and, by your winning
                    smiles, earnest solicitations, and patriotism, and send them forth to assist in
                    gaining our liberties--the sweetest BOON of life. Your patriotism, so far, has
                    no parallel in history, and we feel confident that you will not be found wanting
                    in this instance."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>CHURCHVILLE, <lb/>Augusta Co., Va., <lb/>September 17th, 1863 </p>
                    <p>If there is one section of country more deserving than any other of the
                        grateful respect of the Southern soldier, or more endeared to him by the
                        remembrance of the kindness and hospitality which he has received at the
                        hands of its people, that section is the VALLEY OF VIRGINIA.--Though it has
                        frequently been overrun by a merciless foe, its pleasant villages sacked and
                        robbed of all their wealth and grandeur, its fields laid waste, its
                        beautiful residence demolished, and its families driven away from their
                        homes--exiled by the hand of tyranny and oppression--yet it has NEVER failed
                        in its kindness to the poor, sick, wounded or hungry soldier. Though its
                        plains have been drenched in fraternal blood, and its vales "made" to
                        re-echo the sound of the thundering cannon--though its brave, noble and
                        patriotic sons have bled and died in the defence of their liberties, their
                        homes, their wives and children, their friends and sweet-hearts, yet it has
                        never faltered, never SHRUNK from the duty and obligations it owed to the
                        Commonwealth and to the Confederacy.</p>
                    <p>I would not cast the slightest shade of disrespect or dishonor upon any
                        portion of this glorious old State, the Mother of States and Statesmen.
                        Neither would I detract from the honor of the LADIES of any portion of this
                        State. Their generosity and kindness towards our soldiers have never been
                        surpassed by any people. Their conduct has rendered them worthy of being
                        called the daughters of the "OLD DOMINION," and should command for them the
                        respect of every enlightened nation.</p>
                    <p>But yet, with all due deference to the feelings of the "fair sex" in other
                        sections of Virginia, I must confess that in no part of the State have I
                        ever seen soldiers treated with the same kindness and attention that they
                        have been in the Valley. I am proud to say (though I am not from the Valley
                        myself, being an exile from the Northwest) that I have never seen a soldier
                        turned from the door of any residence without his wants having been supplied
                        and his sufferings administered to. And, in regard to myself, I have never
                        been treated with the slightest degree of disrespect in all of my travelings
                        through this beautiful and fertile section of country--this EDEN of
                        Virginia. But, on the contrary, have frequently been invited to their homes,
                        to "remember that I would always be welcome to share their hospitality, and
                        should I ever be weary, sick or wounded, they would take care of me,
                        &amp;c." Cold must be the heart of him who could speak of such a people
                        with levity; and false to his country and to the cause of humanity must he
                        be who could remain at home and "see them overrun by a set of Yankee vandals
                        and cut-throats. Such a man is unworthy the name of a VIRGINIAN, or the
                        attention of her ladies. He should not be allowed to associate with them
                        unless he is willing to shoulder his gun and aid in dealing our enemies a
                        blow that would hurl them back to the granite hills of New England, content
                        to live in peace with a people whom they CANNOT CONQUER, and secure for them
                        a lasting and glorious independence, as a reward for their gladness,
                        hospitality and patrollers.</p>
                    <p>How many a sick soldier have the ladies of the Valley taken to their homes,
                        and cared for them and nursed them as kindly as if they had been a brother.
                        After the hard fought battles of Winchester, Port Republic, Sharpsburg; and,
                        more recently of Gettysburg, how many a wounded man has had his wounds
                        dressed by the tender hand of some fair lady--perhaps the one who is to
                        become his future companion through life. Her kind attentions, gentle
                        caresses, and words of sympathy soothed his pain, and caused him for a while
                        to forget his sufferings.</p>
                    <p>Ladies:--There are a certain class of men in Virginia, remaining at home, who
                        look upon the progress of this war with careless indifference--they have
                        folded their arms and said, "Let the Confederacy slide." Can you not reclaim
                        them? Let me ask you to wield your influence, which is powerful, over them;
                        and, by your winning smiles, earnest solicitations, and patriotism, and send
                        them forth to assist in gaining our liberties--the sweetest FOOD of life.
                        Your patriotism, so far, has no parallel in history, and we feel confident
                        that you will not be found wanting in this instance.</p>
                    <p>As I am leaving the Department of the Valley, I bid you an adieu, hoping that
                        the tread of the invading foe may never again disturb your midnight
                        dreaming, that your freedom may soon be achieved, and that the sun of
                        INDEPENDENCE may never again cease to shine upon your happy homes.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully, &amp;c., <lb/>J. G. R., Capt. P. A. C. S. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a letter dated September 17, 1863, a correspondent only identified as J.
                    G. R., Capt. P.A.C.S., offers a flowery tribute to the patriotism and sacrifice
                    exemplified by the women of the Shenandoah Valley during the current conflict.
                    He also calls upon women both to use their influence on backsliders and to
                    bolster the spirit of the populace in the continuation of the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For The Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Light, in very many of its manifestations, is often guilty of leading
                    people into mysterious surmising about the will of Providence and the
                    interpretations to be put upon what are, in truth, very strange and uncommon
                    appearances, but, at the same time, the results of physical natural laws."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--The very remarkable phenomenon noticed in your last noticed in
                        your last issue, seems to have attracted some attention, and the pains taken
                        by your correspondent to substantiate the credibility of the witnesses to
                        the fact, fully attests the infrequency of such phenomenons. Light, in very
                        many of its manifestations, is often guilty of leading people into
                        mysterious surmisings about the will of Providence and the interpretations
                        to be put upon what are, in truth, very strange and uncommon appearances,
                        but, at the same time, the results of physical natural laws. Nevertheless,
                        Providence works by means, and whether we regard the cotton bales seen
                        drifting North as representing the trade in that staple northward after we
                        gain our independence, and the serial army moving in the same direction
                            <emph rend="italic">en deshabille</emph>, as the Yankees retreating from
                        the sunny South in a "double quick" bequeathing their unmentionables to the
                        sable contrabands on the wayside, who show their ivories and hop into the
                        blue breeches, is of little importance. Such things are somewhat like
                        certain passages in scripture which we can interpret <emph rend="italic"
                            >according to our own creed.</emph> No doubt, according to Yankee
                        exegesis the cotton bales would represent the first fruits of General Banks'
                        labor system, and the army of <emph rend="italic">images</emph> the
                        apotheosis of the saints of abolitionism constituting the army of invasion.
                        But we propose simply to state a few recorded facts to show that similar
                        phenomena have, at various times, been witnessed, and are well attested by
                        competent and credible witnesses. There are two laws by which light is
                        governed, or rather there are two constant manifestations of light under
                        certain peculiar conditions--the term law as applied to nature not being a
                        principle of energy of power, but simply a constant recurrence of the same
                        phenomena under similar conditions.--We say, however, in common patience,
                        that light obeys two laws, the law of refraction and the law of reflection,
                        by either of which it is possible to depict images in the air to an observer
                        who may be placed in a proper position to receive the light. By the
                        refraction of light is meant the bending of a ray of light from its original
                        rectilinear direction, when it is made to pass from one medium into another
                        of different density, as for instance, when it passes from air into glass or
                        water, or <emph rend="italic">vice versa</emph>. Many of the ordinary
                        phenomena of nature are due to the operation of this law, as the apparent
                        bending of a stick when plunged obliquely into water, the elevation of the
                        bottom of a clear stream so that it appears of less depth than it is in
                        reality, the apparent steepness of a hill as we approach it, and the
                        undulatory surface sometimes given to a level plane when viewed through a
                        common window pane. But the different strata of the atmosphere also
                        constitute media of different density, and a ray of light passing through it
                        from above toward the earth in an oblique direction from any object will,
                        from the manner in which it is refracted, cause the object to appear at a
                        greater altitude above the horizon than its real position. Thus objects on
                        the earth's surface under peculiar conditions of the atmosphere in certain
                        localities by which its refractive power is highly increased, might
                        apparently be elevated to positions much above their real positions in
                        nature. We have said that an image in the air might be produced under the
                        laws of refraction. The refracting telescope is constructed with direct
                        reference to this principle, the observer viewing the image of the celestial
                        body formed by the rays of light form the body being made to converge and
                        cross each other by means of the refracting power of a double convex lens.
                        It is probable, however, that any very striking phenomena, as that recently
                        witnessed in the mountains, are not generally produced by the principle of
                        refraction alone, though, as we have said above, it is not impossible under
                        certain conditions of the atmosphere, which may be supposed to exist. But
                        recurring to the law of reflection, images are produced, first, by plane
                        mirrors at a distance as far behind the mirror as the object is in front,
                        and secondly, by concave mirrors in front of the mirror in the air, when the
                        object is at a greater distance from it than the principal focus. It may be
                        thought improbable that a medium so transparent as the atmosphere, under
                        ordinary circumstances, would, under any circumstances, constitute a mirror
                        for the reflection of natural objects. But glass is also very transparent,
                        and yet we often see the image of a candle or a fire, or of a scene in
                        nature by simply looking at a window-pane. Water is also translucent, but
                        all the beauties of the rainbow are produced by the reflection of light from
                        the [sic] surface of the rain-drop. In fact, there is a strong indisposition
                        in light to pass from a dense into a rare medium, being very liable to be
                        reflected from the inner surface of the denser medium. Thus, a ray of light
                        will not pass out of glass into air if the angle of incidence exceed about
                        40 degrees, nor out of glass into water if it exceed 50 degrees.--It is not
                        improbable, therefore, that under peculiar conditions of the atmosphere at
                        certain times it may be made to constitute a mirror for the reflection of
                        the light proceeding from objects on the Earth's surface, and the rays of
                        light thus reflected downward from above would undergo a retraction tending
                        to elevate the image of the object from which the light emanated. Should the
                        atmosphere constitute a plain mirror, the images would be at a greater
                        distance than if its peculiar conformation constituted a concave mirror. In
                        the latter case, the image would lie between the observer and the
                        atmospheric region rendering it, and would be visible only to observers in
                        the particular locality, into which the reflected rays, after crossing each
                        other, diverge. It is evident that such mirrors from their was of perfection
                        and symmetry of form might produce both a multiplication and distortion in
                        the images of objects and perhaps, also, if the mirror condition of the
                        atmosphere be supposed to move, motion of the whole scene. It will be
                        observed that what is here written is based on the hypothesis that, in the
                        particular phenomenon to which we allude, the images produced had a real
                        objective counterpart in nature, though the distance to anybody of troops
                        may have been very considerable. The following remarkable cases of like
                        character to the phenomenon in question, which are well authenticated, will
                        serve not only to show the capacity of the atmosphere for rendering images,
                        but also the fact of the great distance at which the objects producing the
                        images may be from the observer. </p>
                    <p>1st. On July 26th, 1797, about 5 P. M., at Hastings, on the south coast of
                        England, a large portion of the coast of France appeared to a number of
                        observers so distinctly that sailors who were spectators of the scene
                        pointed out to the narrator and witness of the phenomenon a number of places
                        easily recognized with the naked eye, but further increased in distinctness
                        by the use of the telescope. Places known as the Bay, the Old Head, and
                        Dover Cliffs, even the French fishing boats, and portions of the French
                        coast at a distance of from 80 to 90 miles, all appearing as near as if they
                        were sailing at a small distance from the coast.</p>
                    <p>2d. In the Highlands of Scotland in 1774, Mr. Wren and others observed upon a
                        extremely precipitous hills, the figure of a man, with a dog pursuing
                        several horses, all running at a most rapid rate until they finally
                        disappeared, all of which proved to be a mere scene similar to others of the
                        kind. Some time afterward, in the same locality as observed by the
                        inhabitants for miles around, there was seen a troop of horsemen advancing
                        in close ranks and at a brisk pace. The various evolutions through which the
                        troops passed, were distinctly visible and observed by all. These
                        appearances wee supposed to be the images of a body of rebels drilling
                        themselves previous to the rebellion of 1745.</p>
                    <p>3d. The "Spectre of the Brocken" in the Hartz Mountains in Germany, which is
                        of frequent occurrence, representing oftentimes a magnified image of the
                        observer, and obeying all of his motions, is too well known to allude to
                        more definitely.</p>
                    <p>4th. On Sunday the 17th December, 1826, the clergy in the vicinity of
                        Poictiers in France were engaged in the exercises of the Jubilee which
                        preceded the festival of Christmas. Three thousand spectators wee present.
                        They had planted, as part of the ceremony, a large cross 25 feet high and
                        painted red, in the open air before the church. About 5 in the afternoon, a
                        similar celestial cross suddenly, appeared in the heavens about 200 feet
                        above the horizon and apparently about 140 feet in length, of a bright
                        silver color tinged with red.</p>
                    <p>The causes of certain phenomena, similar to those above mentioned, have been
                        illustrated in an interesting manner by the experiments of Dr. Wollaston
                        upon different refracting media.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a learned discussion of the recent apparition noted in the last issue of
                    the Spectator, the correspondent, recorded only as "K," lists a number of
                    historical precedents for the phenomenon described.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the Ladies of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Try to enlist them in the army of religion and right,/Try to give them
                    courage to 'fight the good fight,'/Tell them to take the Bible for their colors,
                    to the cross make it fast,/And with Christ, as their battle cry, fight to the
                    last."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wilfred, American Hospital, Sept. 14, 1863</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A poem to the ladies of Staunton that urges them to visit soldiers in the
                    hospital and shore up their faith in God and country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. John W. Bare married Miss Lizzie M. Cease, both from Staunton, on
                    September 10 at the residence of the bride's mother.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bert</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. S. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. Bert (7th Regt. S. C. Volunteers) of the Abbeville District of South
                    Carolina married Miss Bettie J. Baskin of Staunton on September 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous advertisements and announcements, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
