<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.10.27">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/30/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/18/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-10-27">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>27</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.10.27.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details a series of actions taken by the Virginia Legislature, including a
                    long discussion of the debate about the desirability of regulating prices, which
                    appears to have been defeated in the Senate. In addition, the legislature passed
                    a joint resolution in favor of raising the pay of soldiers and continued its
                    debate on the militia bill.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The English Press On The Battle of Chickamauga</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The London Times thinks that General Rosencrans was defeated by the
                    superior strategy of the Confederates rather than mere fighting. It says it is
                    evident that the federal troops contested the field obstinately, rallied when
                    broken, formed again and renewed their engagement repeatedly. They seem to have
                    done all that bravery and determination could effect, but the greater skill of
                    the Confederate generals in combining the force which made the attack insured
                    them the victory."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After noting the positive effect on the Confederate bond rating in London,
                    this article goes on to sample the various editorial opinions of English
                    newspapers on the implications to be drawn from the recent Confederate victory
                    at Chickamauga.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Revolution In Ladies Fashion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The fashionable writers from the great fashionable countries of Europe
                    announce that no lady of taste will dare to promenade with trailing dresses or
                    long petticoats. Short dresses are now the style."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A detailed description of the latest in women's fashion from Europe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Means And Resources</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Only let the currency be saved from suffocation and the ability of the
                    Confederate States to supply means for carrying on the war is well nigh
                    inexhaustible."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Basing his assessment of the potential taxable property in the Confederate
                    States on the 1860 census and taking into consideration the loss of property and
                    the inflated prices of the day, the author argues that there is a sufficient tax
                    base to meet all foreseeable needs of the war effort, as long as the currency is
                    protected from "suffocation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>"Monsieur Tonsin Come Again"</head>
                <origin>Cincinnati Commercial</origin>
                <commentary>"The Immortal Parson Brownlow has turned up again--this time in a letter
                    to the Cincinnati Commercial, breathing fire and destruction upon the 'rebels.'
                    He says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"...and let there be no armistice, on sea or land, until all the rebels,
                    front and rear, North and South, are subjugated or exterminated. And then let
                    divine punishment be speedily meted out to the surviving leaders in this unholy
                    crusade against civilization."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of a particularly hostile letter sent to the Cincinnati
                    Commercial newspaper by a Parson Brownlow advocating the complete "subjugation
                    or extermination" of all "rebels."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Reason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The reason why every other article of consumption has been run up to ten,
                    fifty, or a hundred prices, is because some crazy people are always found to buy
                    them, and others in consequence are compelled to do so."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The men who are making the money don't stand on price.--They pay whatever
                        price is asked for any article they may want, and the man who has plenty of
                        money want a great many things. This is one reason--the principal one, we
                        imagine--why prices are so inflated. The reason why every other article of
                        consumption has been run up to ten, fifty, or an hundred prices, is because
                        some crazy people are always found to buy them, and others in consequence
                        [sic] are compelled to do so.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Attributes the inflated prices of consumer goods to the desire of wealthy
                    individuals to possess merchandise regardless of the price requested.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The "Pierpont Government"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The Northern papers say 'the formation of the State Government of
                    Virginia is now complete.' The following are the names of the 'State officers:'"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pierpont</ln>
                        <fn>F. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Governor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowper</ln>
                        <fn>P. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant-Governor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hagass</ln>
                        <fn>L. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Secretary of State</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Treasurer</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>L. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Auditor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adjutant General</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowden</ln>
                        <fn>P. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Attorney-General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the officials in the pro-Union government of West Virginia, which
                    claims to be the true government of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page contains various advertisements and is partly illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.10.27.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Exorbitant Prices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[T]he policy of our Government should be directed to stimulate productions
                    and to diminish consumption. But by some strange infatuation, our officials act
                    as if they were influenced by an opposite purpose."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We were surprised to learn that flour had suddenly risen in Staunton to $50.
                        per barrel. There certainly can be no sufficient reason for this rapid
                        increase. Although the last wheat crop was not a large one, it was not much
                        below the average, and there ought to be a considerable surplus in Augusta.
                        Bad as our currency is, it would not, of itself, warrant so great a
                        rise--other causes must have contributed to it.</p>
                    <p>In this crisis of our affairs the policy of our Government should be directed
                        to stimulate productions, and to diminish consumption. But by some strange
                        infatuation, our official act as if they were influenced by an opposite
                        purpose.</p>
                    <p>The administration of the impressment law tends directly to repress
                        production. No man knows when he sows his crop, whether he will be allowed
                        to reap and market it. The act regulating impressment seemed to be very fair
                        on its face. It provides, while property might be taken at schedule prices,
                        in the hands of <emph rend="italic">speculators</emph>, it could only be
                        taken at a fair impressment value in the hands of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >producer</emph>. This was fair and right, and farmers were content with
                        it. The discrimination was formed in sound policy. But by a system of
                        indirection, the law is practically set aside. When a farmer's grain or
                        cattle is taken now, and valued by disinterested parties, if the valuations
                        be higher than the schedule, an appeal is taken by the Government agent to
                        the Commissioners, and they cut down the price to the schedule [illegible].
                        The speculator thus fares better than the farmer, for he gets his pay
                        promptly, while the producer gets the same pay after a long delay, and some
                        [illegible] heavy expense, in trying [illegible] his rights. </p>
                    <p>[illegible] system of mal-administration dis- [illegible] the farmer, and
                        tends directly to diminish productions.</p>
                    <p>There is another matter connected with the food question which merits
                        attention. A great parade was made two years ago, about suppressing the
                        distillation of grain. Crude laws were passed, by which most of the
                        distilleries were stopped; and a monopoly given to the favored few. We doubt
                        not that whiskey was necessary for the medical bureau, but we are not
                        satisfied that the law was sufficiently guarded in reference to the quantity
                        to be made, or the grain to be used. We are of the opinion that the
                        distillation of wheat should have been prohibited altogether. Wheat is the
                        staff of life, and should be kept for the sustenance of the people. If
                        whiskey must be made, it should be made of the coaser [sic] grains. This is
                        a more serious matter than may be at first supposed.--We have one distillery
                        in our suburbs which is reported to consume 100 bushels of wheat per day. If
                        this be true, it is equivalent to abstracting from the food of the people,
                        20 barrels of flour per day, and about 50 bushels of offal.--In a year this
                        would be over 7,000 barrels. It is a fair estimate to say, that 10 barrels
                        per year, will supply a family of seven persons, and consequently that
                        amount distilled here would supply bread to about five thousand
                        people.--There are other distilleries in the county, which, in the
                        aggregate, probably use as much as the larger one here.--Thus wheat enough
                        to supply ten thousand people, near half the population of this county, is
                        annually consumed in the distilleries.</p>
                    <p>If corn and rye were used, the damage would be much less, for these grains
                        are not so important for bread, and the swill serves to fatten hogs.</p>
                    <p>Should not the Legislature take this matter in hand?</p>
                    <p>But there are other measures tending to discourage production. The practice
                        of withdrawing, every now and then, hundreds of our stoutest and most
                        athletic negroes from farming operations, to work on the fortifications near
                        Richmond, is a serious evil. These negroes are our best farm hands, and for
                        every one so withdrawn, the production of grain is diminished several
                        hundred bushels. Why cannot the deserters, and other wrong-doers, be taken
                        from Castle Thunder, and put to work on the fortifications? Where too, are
                        the idlers about Richmond, and the conscripts of Camp Lee? We think this
                        system of employing negroes ought to be stopped.</p>
                    <p>Finally, the militia bill, we fear, is to be one of the most unfortunate
                        measures yet adopted, for the agriculture of the State--every boy over 16,
                        and every old man under 55, is liable to be called into the field. If you
                        take all who can plow, and sow and reap, how is grain enough o be raised for
                        consumption of the people? We have men enough, between 18 and 45, to fight
                        our battles.--The fear is not of a deficiency of men, but of provisions.</p>
                    <p>We throw out these suggestions for the consideration of the public. But we do
                        so with little hope of their having any good effect. When the popular fervor
                        is up, reason is unheeded.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator criticizes the government's policy of impressment, which has
                    the unintended effect of repressing production. The paper believes that this
                    policy has caused prices to rise rapidly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>From Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The current positions of Gen. Lee's and Gen. Meade's forces is such that
                    any attempt to dislodge either side would result in losses disproportionate to
                    any advantage gained. As a result, there is little activity to note.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Legislative Tinkering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We earnestly hope the legislators will have common sense enough to reject
                    these demagogue ideas. Let them strike at the root of the evil. Reduce the
                    currency. Put that on a secure foundation, and prices will soon adjust
                    themselves."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We perceive that some of those members of the Legislature who are
                        particularly wise in their own conceit, but in the estimation of nobody
                        else, are tinkering with the question of prices. They would be better
                        employed in seeking to regulate by law, the drift of the clouds, or the flow
                        of the tides. In the latter case, they would, at least do no mischief. But
                        we fear, that in the former, they may do great harm.</p>
                    <p>The idea of regulating prices by act of Legislature, is not only absurd, but
                        is positively mischievous. These quack legislators, ignore the teachings of
                        history, as well as the deductions of reason. This same experiment has been
                        tried, over and over again, in other countries, and always failed. Our
                        fathers attempted it in the revolutionary struggle, and Washington
                        admonished them, if they did not stop it, they would starve the army.</p>
                    <p>We say that the whole thing is simply absurd. Prices depend on the condition
                        of the currency, and the rates of supply and demand.</p>
                    <p>What is the <emph rend="italic">price</emph> of anything? It depends on its
                        relation to the currency for the time being. When gold and silver are the
                        circulating medium, it means the amount of gold and silver for which the
                        whole can be exchanged. So when gold and silver are abandoned, and paper
                        substituted as a currency, it means the amount of paper for which it can be
                        exchanged. If the render money plenty, prices will be high--if you render it
                        scarce, they will be low. Here is the whole matter in a nutshell. Before the
                        war, gold was the standard of value, and wheat would bring one dollar, and
                        corn half a dollar per bushel.--Since the war, we have adopted paper as the
                        currency, and we have ten times as much paper as we had gold. As a matter of
                        course, prices have risen to ten times their old rates, and wheat now brings
                        near ten dollars and corn five.--The only practical way of bringing down
                        prices, is by reducing the amount of currency. Retire half the currency, and
                        you will reduce prices one half.--Double the currency, and you will double
                        the prices. </p>
                    <p>But to talk of leaving the currency as it is, and then, arbitrarily requiring
                        certain classes of people to sell their commodities for one-half the present
                        rates, is so preposterous, that we wonder how sane men can entertain the
                        proposition for an instant.</p>
                    <p>Let us look at it for a moment. Shoes are now worth $35. Suppose Legislature
                        provides that no man shall sell shoes for more than $12.50, under a heavy
                        penalty; what will be the result? Will it cheapen shoes? Unquestionably not,
                        for no man can afford to make and sell them for that price. He will
                        therefore not sell at a loss, but close up his shop. So with the blacksmith,
                        the tailor, and the weaver. The moment that they find they are required to
                        sell at a loss they will stop work. Instead of high priced goods, we will
                        have none.</p>
                    <p>How will it be with the farmer? It formerly cost a farmer about $300 to hire
                        and maintain a hand. He could then afford to sell flour at $5. Now his
                        expenses, in the depreciated currency, are ten times as great, and of course
                        he must have ten times as great, and of course he must have ten times as
                        much for his flour. When you say to him by law you must not sell your flour
                        for more than five dollars, and if you do, you must go to jail, he will say,
                        "very well! I shall not violate your law by selling at more than $5--I will
                        not sell at all--I will keep what I have for my own use, and in future, I
                        will raise no more than is necessary for my family consumption." What will
                        be the effect? Production will stop and starvation will follow. Instead of
                        high priced grain, we will have none!</p>
                    <p>These silly legislators are very innocently, but very ignorantly, striving to
                        aggravate the very evil of which they complain. They will shut up all the
                        workshops and stop all production of agricultural productions, and what
                        they? Scenes of unparalleled distress will ensue, followed by mobs, anarchy
                        and bloodshed! People will take by force, if they cannot buy for money. They
                        will not see their wives and children starve.</p>
                    <p>We earnestly hope the legislators will have common sense enough to reject
                        these demagogue ideas. Let them strike at the root of the evil. Reduce the
                        currency. Put that on a secure foundation, and prices will soon adjust
                        themselves.</p>
                    <p>But, if in spite of all warnings, they are determined to plunge the community
                        into the vortex of anarchy and suffering, we beg our readers to remember,
                        that we entered our earnest protest against it; and if violence follows, we
                        hope it will be directed against the authors of the mischief--the solid
                        legislators, who from stupidity or a selfish desire to gain notoriety, have
                        brought these calamities on the country. If any are to be roughly handled,
                        let it be the guilty, and not the innocent.</p>
                    <p>P. S.--Since the above was put in type, we are pleased to see that the
                        Senate, upon the matter being brought to a test vote, has had the good sense
                        to defeat the bill by a considerable majority.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator disparages the idea of the legislature attempting to regulate
                    prices. Rather than pursing this wrongheaded approach to lowering elevated
                    prices, the paper urges the legislature to reduce the amount of currency in
                    circulation which, it is believed, is the real reason for the inflation of
                    prices. A "P. S." added at the end of the column adds that after the article was
                    set in type, the paper was notified that the legislature had defeated the
                    proposal to regulate prices by a large majority.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Union forces continue to strengthen their fortifications at Charleston
                    to the degree that according to the Charleston Mercury "the Yankees may be
                    looked on as a 'permanent institution,' at least so far as any efforts on our
                    part to dislodge them." At the time, however, the situation remains calm,
                    although the article adds the ominous note that "stormy times may be looked for
                    soon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Heavy Cavalry Victory In Tenn.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During a recent cavalry raid outside Philadelphia, Tennessee, the Southern
                    forces successfully captured a large cache of supplies, over one hundred
                    prisoners, and numerous horses and mules, all without any loss to their forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Imboden's Recent Capture</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We have received from a correspondent, the following graphic account of
                    the recent brilliant exploit of Gen. Imboden in the capture of a Yankee regiment
                    at Charlestown, with their arms, ammunition train, &amp;c. The prisoners
                    arrived here Saturday, and have been sent to Richmond:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>The men captured "are principally from Baltimore and six months' men,
                    having two months yet to serve, and freely express the determination never to
                    enter the service again, saying they entered for six months to avoid a draft for
                    three years."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a detailed description of a recent military clash in Charlestown,
                    West Virginia. According to an eyewitness, Gen. Imboden arrived to find the town
                    controlled by members of the 9th Md. Infantry and a battalion of cavalry and
                    demanded their surrender. Upon their refusal he initiated a bombardment of the
                    town, which resulted in the Union forces attempting to escape by horse and foot.
                    This attempt was frustrated and resulted in the capture of a large number of
                    prisoners and munitions.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Latest Northern News--Removal Of Rosencrans</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Northern newspapers have reported that Gen. Rosencrans has been removed
                    from command in the west as a result of charges that "he had fled from the field
                    in the crisis of the battle." Other reports indicate that Gen. Meade may also
                    have been removed from command.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Based on dispatches from the western theater, it appears that General
                    Wheeler has been successful in his cavalry actions behind the enemy lines in
                    disrupting the supply of goods to the Union troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Kanawha Valley</head>
                <origin>Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It appears that there is only a token Union presence in the Kanawha Valley,
                    West Virginia, as most of the Union troops have been transferred to Tennessee.
                    The article expresses the hope that the Confederate forces in the Kanawha Valley
                    will soon completely clear the area of enemy troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Exchange of Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notice is given that, as a result of a recent exchange agreement, all
                    soldiers, except those captured at Vicksburg, are now expected to return to
                    duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>From East Tennessee</head>
                <origin>The Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Union retreat towards Knoxville is continuing and mentions
                    the continuing apprehension on the part of the Union troops that a large
                    engagement is imminent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Another Cavalry Victory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Stuart is credited with another cavalry victory. This time he is
                    reported to have attacked the Union forces at Buckland and succeeded in driving
                    them back to their infantry support at Gainsville. This action has resulted in
                    the capture of over three hundred prisoners, along with "horses, arms,
                    equipment, and eight wagons and ambulances."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Labor and Capital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A man frequently starts very poor, even as a common laborer, and by a
                    system of diligent labor combined with a rigid economy and self-denial, which
                    prevents him from eating and drinking and theater going and other worse than
                    useless expenditures, his whole wages, he becomes rich, he becomes the owner of
                    a surplus capital which now commands labor, it is the reward of his virtue and
                    industry--the reward which is established in the laws of Nature."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While conceding that poverty "is sometimes the result of the dispensation
                    of Providence," the author of this long and detailed piece argues that "extreme
                    poverty is the result of a criminal indulgence of the animal propensities of our
                    nature of idleness, of intemperance, of immorality." Since poverty is largely
                    the result of character rather than fate or circumstance, it is wrong for the
                    poor to envy the rich. In particular, the author argues that any call for the
                    redistribution of capital accumulated during the period of conflict must be
                    resisted since "[a]ll capital represents labor and self-denial somewhere."
                    Later, while applauding "christian charity" as "one of the most ennobling
                    principles existing in human nature," the letter warns that "the improvident
                    portions of our race can never be wholly supported by the charity of others,
                    without a consequent increase of demoralization requiring a still further
                    expenditure, and if pursued to its utmost limit the final ruin of any nation."
                    Finally, the author states that "no hardship that can be endured constitutes a
                    sufficient guarantee for disturbing the social order, or for violating the
                    rights of property."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Fiction</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The extreme popularity of a book is prima facie evidence of its want of
                    merit, and of its being based upon principles which neither originate in the
                    holier inspirations of our spiritual nature, nor in the sublime and difficult
                    attainments of human reason."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A jeremiad against the popular culture of the day, with a focus on the
                    proclivity of the public to prefer the "novel and the strange" to the more noble
                    truths of science and religion. This article continues the theme from the
                    previous letter and argues that this proclivity on the part of the public arises
                    from a widespread "natural tendency to lethargy and indolence of mind, as well
                    as of body." Works of fiction and dramatic performance are believed to reinforce
                    this predisposition to lethargy by presenting alluring distractions from the
                    consideration of the sublime truths available only through extended effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Yankee General Thomas</head>
                <origin>Spirits of the Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an anecdote about Union General Thomas, who was from Southampton
                    County, Virginia. When General Thomas returned from the Mexican War, the ladies
                    of the county presented him with a dress sword. After he decided to cast his lot
                    with the Union, General Thomas wrote his sister requesting her to send him the
                    sword. Declaring that no sword presented by the women of Virginia could be used
                    against their "brave fathers, sons, and brothers," the general's sister refused
                    the request. Furthermore, she added "that instead of sending the sword she would
                    rather prefer to see it thrust through his traitorous heart."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Virginia Salt Works</head>
                <origin>The Lynchburg Virginian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reassures readers who had heard rumors of raids upon the salt works in
                    southwestern Virginia that the works remain secure. Given the natural terrain
                    and the presence of a strong Confederate military force, the salt works will
                    remain safe barring "an advance of the enemy in force."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Escape of Rucker</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is noted that Wm. P. Rucker has escaped from Pittsylvania County. The
                    Governor has offered a reward for the recapture of the fugitive. It is also
                    opined that "it would be a great pity if he should go unwhipped of justice,
                    which would be the case if he should succeed in escaping to the Yankees."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>George R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of the marriage of Rev. George R. Jefferson and Sarah M. Whitmore on
                    October 15th at the residence of the bride's father, near Parnassus. The
                    services were officiated by the Rev. D. W. Arnold.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Laura T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An obituary for Laura T. Cline, the daughter of Capt. Joseph E. Cline, who
                    died of diphtheria at the age of three years eight months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Continuing the sad news of the Cline family, it is reported that Capt
                    Cline's infant son Samuel died just four days before his father's death at the
                    age of twenty-nine years and six months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements and announcements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
