<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.07.14">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/10/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/6/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-07-14">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.07.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Psalm Of Life</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A sentimental account of life during wartime.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5, 6</column>
                <head>General T. J. Jackson</head>
                <origin>The London Index</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauds General Jackson's sterling character.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>General Lee's Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"As a part of the history of the present times, we publish the following
                    orders of General Lee, which reflect as much credit upon him as a man and
                    General as the brilliant victories which crown his arms in the field."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints Lee's orders, which command his soldiers to avoid damaging private
                    property and to pay for all supplies while in "the enemy's country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Retaliation in a Small Way</head>
                <origin>The Atlanta Confederacy</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Yankees had stripped our men of their boots and shoes, and forced them
                    to walk barefooted. Capt. Davis, learning this, ordered every Yankee in his
                    hands served likewise, and compelled them to walk to this point, nearly 150
                    miles. The Yankees complaiend bitterly, but it was only 'tit for tat,' and their
                    complaints were not listened to."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts an incident in Kentucky in which Confederate soldiers retaliated
                    against Northern soldiers because the Union men had treated their prisoners
                    cruelly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Yankee Raid In North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the plundering ways of Northern troops in North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Romantic Incident Of The War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of a humane exchange between soldiers of the opposing sides.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Mostly advertisements and legal notices, also includes a list of deserters
                from the 52nd Regiment, Virginia Volunteers</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.07.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>From Gen. Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The despatches which have been sent from Martinsburg in reference to military
                        operations in Pennsylvania have been so very contradictory and unreliable
                        that it has been impossible to form any satisfactory idea of what has really
                        been done. We had intended to publish them, but found them so unreliable,
                        and some of them so palpably false--reporting battles when none were
                        fought--that we determined not to occupy space with them. The Richmond
                        Dispatch learns from an officer of Wright's brigade, who left Gettysburg on
                        Saturday, the 4th, that in the fight of Wednesday and Thursday we whipped
                        the enemy badly. On Friday the fight again commenced, being chiefly done by
                        our centre, which was composed of Longstreet's corps and two divisions of A.
                        P. Hill's corps. Neither the right nor left wing was seriously engaged. We
                        drove the enemy back five miles to the heights, which he had fortified. In
                        driving them this five miles we broke through two of their lines of battle
                        formed to receive the onset of our troops, and finally charged them to the
                        heights. Here our men were ordered to charge the heights, and the order
                        being executed, resulted in our repulse.</p>
                    <p>On Friday night our wagon trains were ordered to fall back, and commenced
                        going to the rear. It is supposed that our army fell back from want of
                        provisions. There was no scarcity of ammunition, for there were many trains
                        or ordnance out of which not a single cartridge or shell had been taken.
                        Some of them were attacked by the enemy, but Imboden's cavalry successfully
                        drove them off. Those of our men who were slightly wounded and could walk
                        were sent off Saturday about noon. Those who were severely wounded were left
                        in the hospitals near the battle field. In the fights of Wednesday,
                        Thursday, and Friday, General Lee took about 10,000 prisoners, who were
                        promptly sent to the rear. During the same time we lost about 4,000
                        prisoners and about 11,000 killed and wounded--making our loss 15,000 in
                        all. The battle was the most furious that has taken place in this country,
                        and the losses of the enemy in killed and wounded must exceed ours. In the
                        charge in which we drove the enemy five miles, their loss, while flying
                        before our troops, was enormous. Wright's brigade suffered severely. One of
                        the regiments which went into action with a Colonel, Lieut. Colonel, and
                        five or six Captains, came out in charge of a Second Lieutenant, the ranking
                        officers having been either killed or wounded.</p>
                    <p>After the battle of Friday, Gen. Lee withdrew his army to Hagerstown, Md.,
                        about thirty miles Southwest of Gettysburg, where the battles were
                        fought.--A telegram to the Richmond Enquirer of Friday last states that
                        there had been a severe fight at Boonsboro, Md., on Wednesday, the 8th, in
                        which we had repulsed the enemy after a fight of three hours. Boonsboro is
                        situated about 15 miles, a little East of South, from Hagerstown. From what
                        we have been enabled to learn--and that is precious little--we suppose that
                        General Lee's army has taken a position not far from Hagerstown, and is
                        there awaiting the approach of the enemy, in anticipation of another
                        terrible struggle.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuing account of the battle of Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Battles of Gettysburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of dead and wounded officers and soldiers from Garnett's,
                    Barksdale's, and Kemper's brigades.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fifth Va. Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We have been unable to learn much about the casualties in this
                    regiment. The reports are so various that it is impossible to know what the
                    truth is. We have been enabled to learn only the names of the following who have
                    suffered--though we fear that the casualties were great:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meeks</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Steele</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of dead and wounded soldiers from the Fifth Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fifty-Second Virginia Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We are gratified to hear that this regiment has suffered but little in
                    comparison with others. Thus far we have heard of no one belonging to it being
                    killed. The following are reported wounded:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Of the nature of their wounds we cannot speak with certainty."</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant-Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Stribling</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snell</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrill</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of wounded soldiers from the Fifth Virginia Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Battle at Jackson, Miss.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a series of skirmishes between Grant and Johnston that took
                    place near Jackson, Mississippi.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Yankees On James River</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the incursion of Union naval forces on the James river.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fall Of Vicksburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is our painful duty to announce that heroic Vicksburg has fallen."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the events that led to the surrender of Vicksburg to Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Attack Upon Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe they will be repulsed, and that if Charlestown ever falls, it
                    will be a long time before it occurs."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the successful landing of Northern troops on Morris' Island, near
                    Fort Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Two Yankee Captains Doomed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Confederate authorities have randomly selected two Union prisoners from
                    Libby prison for execution. They will be killed in retaliation for the execution
                    of two Confederate captains captured in Kentucky and sentenced to death for
                    being spies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>General Bragg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We should hope and strive for the best, whilst we should be prepared to
                    suffer with fortitude the worst, if misfortune should befall us."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the deteriorating situation in the western theater of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Colonel A. W. Harman vs. WM.H.H.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We publish in this issue the proceedings of the Court of Inquiry in the
                    case of Col. A. W. Harman. From these proceedings it will be seen that the
                    silver ware therein spoken of was captured by J. C. Hogan, who took it to Col.
                    Harman and told him he designed it as a present for Mrs. Harman, and that Col.
                    Harman had it sent to his home. When it arrived at his home, it was shown by his
                    wife to Mr. W. H. Lynn, a relative of the family, and Editor of the "<emph
                        rend="italic">Vindicator.</emph>" In the next issue of his paper, he made
                    the following statement concerning it:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"<emph rend="italic">We saw a beautiful silver set which was captured and
                            sent as a present to Mrs. Col. A. W. Harman.</emph>" </p>
                    <p>Being surprised at the announcement, in the next issue of the "<emph
                            rend="italic">Spectator</emph>," we quoted the statement of the "<emph
                            rend="italic">Vindicator</emph>" and noticed it in the following
                        language: </p>
                    <p>"<emph rend="italic">We acknowledge that the above announcement contained in
                            the Vindicator of last week surprised us. We had supposed that
                            everything captured by soldiers in the Confederate service became the
                            property of the Confederate States. Have we been mistaken in this
                            supposition?</emph>" </p>
                    <p>And by way of illustrating his purpose to do so in a <emph rend="italic"
                            >forcible and striking manner</emph>, he assaulted us on the 21st of May
                        for the offence of suggesting that that was the <emph rend="italic">proper
                            course to pursue</emph>.--At that time he did not deny the truth of the
                        statement of the Vindicator, but denominated it a "youthful indiscretion."
                        His feelings of friendship for his relative may have induced him to withhold
                        the denial, and rather suffer himself the reproach of appropriating public
                        property to private use, than to place the stigma of falsehood upon the
                        character of his relative; for it follows necessarily that, <emph
                            rend="italic">if the statement of the Vindicator were true</emph>, Col.
                        Harman was guilty of sending, as a present to his wife, property which
                        belonged to the Confederate States. </p>
                    <p>Before the Court of Inquiry, however, he was not so regardful of the
                        reputation of his friend, the Editor of the <emph rend="italic"
                        >Vindicator</emph> has perpetrated a most outrageous slander against his
                        friend and relative. He falls, too, under the denunciation of the Court of
                        Inquiry, which declares "that the imputations cast upon Col. Harman's
                        character as a gentleman and a soldier are <emph rend="italic">without
                            foundation</emph>." It is for the Editor of the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Vindicator</emph> to show how he was justified in making the statement
                        he did. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">If the finding of the Court be correct</emph>, then the
                        Editor of the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph>stands guilty of making a
                        false and slanderous statement. </p>
                    <p>In reference to another statement of the Editor of the Vindicator, Col.
                        Harman, before the Court of Inquiry, was equally unmindful of the reputation
                        of his relative. In an attempted defense of the conduct of Col. Harman, the
                        Editor of the Vindicator, in his issue of May 29th, <emph rend="italic"
                            >denied</emph> that Col. Harman had <emph rend="italic">sent</emph> the
                        silver ware to his home. In that paper he said: </p>
                    <p>"We did not say that Col. H. captured or <emph rend="italic">sent</emph> it,
                            <emph rend="italic">both</emph> of which would have been <emph
                            rend="italic">untrue</emph>." </p>
                    <p>Col. Harman, before the Court, said:</p>
                    <p>"<emph rend="italic">I told my servant to take it to my house</emph>." </p>
                    <p>For the honor of the Confederacy we would like to see Col. Harman exculpated
                        from the charge contained in the statement of the Vindicator, for we would
                        not like to have any Confederate officer guilty of an offence which would be
                        a reproach to our Confederate soldiery; and, on the other hand, we would
                        like, for the honor of the Editorial fraternity, the Editor of the
                        Vindicator to be able to exculpate himself from the charge of having uttered
                        a slanderous falsehood against an officer of the Confederate service. The
                        Court of Inquiry has endeavored to protect the honor of the Confederacy, it
                        remains to be seen whether the Editor of the Vindicator will exhibit equal
                        concern for the honor of the Editorial fraternity.</p>
                    <p>Will he, either as a man or editor, rest contented under the brand of
                        falsehood which Col. Harman has placed upon him? <emph rend="italic">Nous
                            verrons.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a legal battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Prof. Robert T. Massie</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the life of Prof. Robert T. Massie, Esq.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Capture at Loupe Creek</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts a military victory by Confederate troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Mission of Vice President Stephens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the futile efforts of Vice President Stephens, who traveled to
                    Washington, D.C., to enter into meaningful negotiations with administration
                    figures on the conduct of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Explosion Of A Locomotive Engine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The scene is represented to have been fearful in the extreme. The cries
                    of the wounded, mingled with the shrieks of frightened ladies, (one of whom
                    fainted) and every thing was in almost inextricable confusion."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the explosion of a locomotive engine on the Richmond &amp;
                    Petersburg railroad and the accompanying loss of life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Courts of Inquiry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A fictional discussion between a father and son on the role of courts of
                    inquiry. The moral of the story is that the courts "white-wash their [officers']
                    character till they become as white as ascension robes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Loss Of The Enemy In The West</head>
                <origin>The Jackson Mississippian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Estimates that the Union forces in the West have lost 95,000 men since May
                    1, 1863, including an estimated 75,000 around Vicksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Affairs in Arkansas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short mention of the capture of 800 or 900 blacks in a Union regiment
                    commanded by a black man "belonging to a Mr. Bright, who ran away from Fort
                    Smith."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Resignation</head>
                <origin>The Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the retirement of Brig. Gen. John Echols. He had been in command
                    at Lewisburg, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Vallandigham</head>
                <origin>From Bermuda papers received in New York</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Continuing coverage of Mr. Vallandigham's efforts to return to Ohio.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Death of Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An elegiac poem on the death of General Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5, 6</column>
                <head>Col. A. W. Harman, 12th Virginia Cavalry, C.S.A.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Only a man of his extraordinary energy could have accomplished this
                    hard task. Yet on his arrival in Staunton, he found himself unjustly and
                    grievously assaulted (we hope by mistake) giving cause to the subjoined
                    proceedings, which have been copied without his knowledge, and are now
                    published, by an Officer of the 12th (Va.) Cavalry."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the treatment of Col A. W. Harman in Staunton and the legal
                    proceedings against him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>$400 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advertisement for four runaway male slaves from Alleghany county, Virginia.
                    They are believed to be "making their way to the Yankees."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
