<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.12.22">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/30/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/29/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-12-22">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.12.22.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaho</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dennison</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>H.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>C.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyder</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKendree</ln>
                        <fn>G.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>A.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berry</ln>
                        <fn>G.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulwider</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hemp</ln>
                        <fn>W.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyton</ln>
                        <fn>G.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>M.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Jno.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sprouse</ln>
                        <fn>M.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>St. Clair</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tisdale</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogsett</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J.M. McCue writes that he recently visited the wounded and sick soldiers of
                    the 5th and 52nd regiments in the Richmond hospitals, and he includes a list of
                    the men he saw.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Defiant Memphis Woman</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following communications from a Memphis lady, is clipped from the
                    Bulletin of a recent date:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The women of Memphis will stick to the Confederate cause like Ruth clung
                    to her mother in love, and say to it, where thou goest I will go, where thou
                    livest I will live, where thou diest I will die, and there will I be buried.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to a recent article in the Memphis paper calling on the
                    populace to celebrate a day of Thanksgiving called for by President Lincoln, one
                    women replied with great fervor against the proposed observance. She questions
                    the sincerity of those citizens of Memphis who have pledged loyalty to the
                    Union, attributing their pledges to fear of the "military despotism" of the
                    system in Memphis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following is the proclamation of Lincoln which was published with
                    his message:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"I do solemnly swear, in presence of Almighty God, that I will henceforth
                    faithfully support, protect and defend the Constitution of the United States,
                    and the Union of the States thereunder, and that I will in like manner abide by
                    and faithfully support all acts of Congress passed during the existing rebellion
                    with reference to slaves, so long and so far as not repealed, modified or held
                    void by Congress, or by the decision of the Supreme Court, and that I will in
                    like manner abide by and faithfully support all proclamations of the President,
                    made during the existing rebellion, having reference to slaves, so far as not
                    modified or declared void by decision of the Supreme Court. So help me God."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Whereas, in and by the Constitution of the United States, it is provided that
                        the President shall have power to grant reprieves and pardons for offences
                        against the United States, except in cases of impeachment and whereas, a
                        rebellion now exists whereby the loyal State government of several States
                        have, for a long time, been subverted, and many persons have committed, and
                        are guilty of treason against the United States; and whereas, with reference
                        to said rebellion and treason, laws have been enacted by Congress declaring
                        forfeitures and confiscation of property and liberation of slaves, all upon
                        terms and conditions therein stated, and also declaring that the President
                        was thereby authorized at any time thereafter, by proclamation to extend to
                        persons who may have participated in the existing rebellion in any State or
                        part thereof, pardon and amnesty, with such exceptions, and at such times,
                        and on such conditions, as he may deem expedient for the public wellfare
                        [sic]; and whereas, the Congressional declaration for limited and
                        conditional pardon accords with the well established judicial exposition of
                        the pardoning power; and whereas, with reference to the said rebellion the
                        President of the United States has issued several proclamations with
                        provisions in regard to the liberation of slaves; and whereas, it is now
                        desired by some persons heretofore engaged in said rebellion to resume their
                        allegiance to the United States, and to re-inaugurate loyal State
                        governments within and for their respective States, therefore, I, ABRAHAM
                        LINCOLN, President of the United States, do proclaim, declare and make known
                        to all persons who have directly, or by implication, participated in the
                        existing rebellion, except as hereinafter excepted, that a full pardon is
                        hereby granted to them and each of them, with restoration of all rights of
                        property except as to slaves, and in property except as hereinafter
                        excepted, that a full pardon is hereby granted to them and each of them,
                        with restoration of all rights of property except as to slaves, and in
                        property cases where the rights of third parties shall have intervened, and
                        upon the condition that every such person shall take and subscribe an oath,
                        and thenceforward, keep and maintain said oath inviolate, and which oath
                        shall be registered for permanent preservation, and shall be of the tenor
                        and effect following, to wit:</p>
                    <p>I do solemnly swear, in presence of Almighty God, that I will henceforth
                        faithfully support, protect and defend the Constitution of the United
                        States, and the Union of the States thereunder; and that I will in like
                        manner abide by and faithfully support all acts of Congress passed during
                        the existing rebellion with reference to slaves, so long and so far as not
                        repeated, modified or held void by Congress or by the decision of the
                        Supreme Court, and that I will in like manner abide by and faithfully
                        support all proclamations of the President, made during the existing
                        rebellion, having rference [sic] to slaves, so far as not modified or
                        declared void by decision of the Supreme Court. So help me God.</p>
                    <p>The persons except from the benefits from the benefits of the foregoing
                        provisions are all who are or shall have been civil or diplomatic officers
                        or agents of the socalled [sic] Confederate Government, all who have left
                        judicial stations under the United States to aid the rebellion, all who are
                        or shall have been military or naval officers of said so called Confederate
                        Government, above the rank of colonel in the army, of lieutenant in the
                        navy; all who have left seats in the United States Congress to aid the
                        rebellion, all who resigned commissions in the army or navy of the United
                        States and afterwards aided the rebellion, and all who have engaged in any
                        way in treating coloured persons, or white persons in charge of such,
                        otherwise than lawfully as prisoners of war, and which persons may have been
                        found in the United States service as soldiers, seamen or in any other
                        capacity. And I do further proclaim, declare and make known that whenever,
                        in any of the States of Arkansas, Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Tennessee,
                        Alabama, Georgia, Florida, South Carolina and North Carolina, a number of
                        persons not less than one-tenth in number of the votes cast in such States
                        at the Presidential election of the year of our Lord 1863--each having taken
                        the oath aforesaid, and not having since violated it, and being a qualified
                        voter by the election law of the States existing immediately before the so
                        called act of secession, and excluding all others--shall re-establish a
                        State government, which shall be republican, and in nowise contraving said
                        oath, such shall be recognized as the true government of the State, and the
                        State shall receive there under the benefit of the constitutional provision
                        which declares that "the United States shall guarantee to every State in
                        this Union a republican form of government, and shall protect each of them
                        against invasion, on application of the Legislature, or of the Executive
                        when the Legislature cannot be convened, and against domestic violence."</p>
                    <p>And I no further proclaim, declare and make known that any provision which
                        may be adopted by such State government in relation to the freed people of
                        such State, which shall recognize and declared their permanent freedom,
                        provide for their education, and which may yet be consistent as a temporary
                        arrangement with their present condition as a laboring, landless and
                        houseless class, will not be objected to by the national Executive. And it
                        is engaged as not improper that, in constructing a loyal State, government
                        in any State, the name of the State, the boundary, the sub divisions, the
                        Constitution and the general code of laws, as before the rebellion, be
                        maintained, subject only to the modifications made necessary by the
                        conditions hereinbefore stated, and such others, if any, not contravening
                        said conditions, and which may be deemed expedient by those framing the new
                        State government.</p>
                    <p>To avoid misunderstanding, it may be proper to say that this proclamation, so
                        far as it relates to State governments, has no reference to State
                        governments, has no reference to States wherein loyal State governments have
                        all the while been maintained. And for the same reason it may be proper to
                        further say that whether members sent to Congress from any State shall be
                        admitted to seat constitutionally, rests exclusively with the respective
                        house, and not to any extent with the Executive; and, still further, that
                        this proclamation is intended to present to the people of the States wherein
                        the national authority has been suspended, and loyal Sate [sic] governments
                        have been subverted, a mode in and by which the national authority and loyal
                        State governments may be re-establish within said States or in any of them;
                        and, while the mode presented is the best the Excutive [sic] can suggest
                        with his present impressions, it must not be understood that no other
                        possible mode would be acceptable.</p>
                    <p>Given under my hand, at the city of Washington, the eighth day of December,
                        A. D. one thousand eight hundred and sixty-three, and of the independence of
                        the United States of America the eighty-eighth.</p>
                    <p>ABRAHAM LINCOLN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>A recent proclamation by President Lincoln establishes the criteria by
                    which individuals and states can re-enter the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements, announcements, and a poem entitled "To A
                Little Bird That Flew Into Our Prison"</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.12.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Christmas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A notice to the subscribers that "[a]s the Editor is absent" the employees
                    have decided to suspend publication of the paper during the holidays.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lectures In Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We think it would be well if the citizens of Staunton would make some
                        arrangement to have a series of Lectures delivered in this place, the
                        proceeds to be appropriated for the benefit of the families of poor
                        soldiers. We have no doubt that the services of able and eloquent Lecturers
                        could be obtained, that the attendance would be good, and that the proceeds
                        would amount during the Winter, to a very considerable sum, which, properly
                        dispensed, would afford great relief to many deserving families. They might
                        get Dr. Hoge to deliver the Lectures in this place which he is now
                        delivering to crowded houses in Richmond for a similar object. The service
                        of other Lecturers could be obtained, so that one or more lectures might be
                        delivered each week during the Winter Season. Such lectures would afford
                        innocent and instructive entertainment and would be well attended. Will not
                        such an arrangement be made?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator's editor encourages Staunton residents to follow Richmond's
                    example and hold a series of lectures during the winter season. He believes that
                    such lectures could provide a useful and informative respite from the concerns
                    of the day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Loss Near Chattanoga</head>
                <origin>The Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The losses of the Confederacy at Chattanooga are listed as 323 killed, 1996
                    wounded, and 2319 missing. The Union losses are believed to be about 4000 killed
                    and wounded, and 6000 captured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wm. E. Coffman Not Hung</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Following up on an article from the week before, it is reported that Wm.
                    Coffman has not been hanged despite his court martial. Since Mr. Coffman is a
                    civilian it has been decided that his fate must be judged by a civilian trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The most of them will, of course, adopt the former alternative and leave
                    us, but we cannot say that we either expect or desire them to do otherwise. They
                    who are not willing to share with us the fortunes of the Confederacy, should
                    abandon the country."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is little doubt that the Congress will very soon pass a law
                        conscripting all foreigners in the Confederacy. This ought to have been done
                        long ago. It is a shame that these men should be permitted to enjoy all the
                        privileges of the country, without bearing its full burdens. They have made
                        fortunes out of the war, while the natives have fought the battles. This is
                        manifestly wrong. Every one of this class should be made to select between
                        leaving the country, or going into the army. The most of them will, of
                        course, adopt the former alternative and leave us, but we cannot say that we
                        either expect or desire them to do otherwise. They who are not willing to
                        share with us the fortunes of the Confederacy should abandon the
                    country.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the legislature is likely to adopt a measure conscripting all
                    foreigners residing in the Confederate States into the armed services. The
                    probability that many will choose to leave the country rather than enter the
                    army doesn't bother the author at all.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The News</head>
                <origin>The Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"...such organizations [Home Guard units] would be composed of reliable
                    men, and where they were unable to withstand the numbers of the enemy, might at
                    least hold him in check long enough to gain time."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a number of serious engagements near Salem and Roanoke, Virginia.
                    In addition, the article also includes news from Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Lower Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Rumors have been in circulation for two days past as to the approach of
                    the enemy up the Valley. So far we have no reliable information that they have
                    advanced as far as Harrisonburg. Suffice it to say, that if they attempt to move
                    upon this point, they will most assuredly find a lion in their path."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports unsubstantiated rumors of enemy movements in the lower Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"The Age"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Reports that a new publication, called "The Age," is being printed in
                    Richmond. The new magazine will focus on the arts and sciences.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Reynold's Brigade</head>
                <origin>The Atlanta Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He held that position for an hour and a half, and was the last that
                    retired from the field, and then in perfect order."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Atlanta Register has corrected the error of earlier reporters who
                    believed that Reynold's brigade was the first to give way in the battle on
                    Missionary Ridge. In fact, Reynolds and his brigade fought valiantly and held to
                    the last.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>P. O. Department</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The latest report of the postmaster general provides the specifics on the
                    volume of mail handled by the postal service and notes the revenues and costs of
                    the bureau.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Retaliation</head>
                <origin>The Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In retaliation for the Union decision to hold seventeen Confederate States
                    navymen in irons and to try these men as pirates, the Confederacy has selected a
                    like number of Union navymen for similar treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Raid Into Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"...destroying nearly if not quite one million of dollars worth of stores,
                    and making the enemy pay his expenses, in the space of fifteen days, without
                    losing a man in killed, wounded or captured, and bringing them all out in better
                    condition than when he went into Kentucky."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent excursion by Captain Peter M. Everett, of the 1st Battalion
                    Mounted Rifles, was remarkably successful, inflicting serious damage on the
                    enemy while suffering minimal injury.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is alleged that this officer extorted large sums of money from
                    prisoners confined in that institution, by promising to use his influence for
                    their benefit, and in some cases of permitting the prisoners to go at large,
                    upon paying him large sums of money."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Capt. George Washington Alexander, commandant at Castle Thunder, has been
                    relieved of his position and charged with malfeasance in office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Congressional</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Military Committee reported a sort of omnibus bill, organizing a
                    reserve corps, requiring persons who have furnished substitutes to render
                    military service, and enumerating those who are to be exempt hereafter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The majority of action at the legislature has been devoted to the question
                    of substitution in the military service. A number of measures were introduced
                    and acted upon without final enactment by both houses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Yankee Opinion Of Their Friends In East Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The rebel ladies are intelligent, well-bred, and good looking--dignified
                    and bold, in their demeanor. But they won't talk to us--consider themselves our
                    superiors, simply from the fact that we are fighting for their inferiors, the
                    Union ladies. They are not to blame, I often blush when I think of the common
                    herd that I am periling my life for. God save me from such ignorant trash."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter intercepted by Southern forces indicates that at least some of the
                    soldiers serving in Tennessee have a very low opinion of the Union sympathizers
                    in that State.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Legislative</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The legislature has not produced much of note recently. One of the few
                    bills to actually pass both houses was a bill that increased the compensation of
                    the members of the general assembly, governor, judges, and other officers of the
                    state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I know that it is impossible for every poor soldier who has a family to go
                    home at once. I think there is a way though to fix this which would suit and
                    benefit the soldier, the government, and the cause. It is this: Let congress
                    pass a law that so many men out of every hundred go home every 15 days, [i.e.]
                    as fast as one lot could go and come let another go. I think if the government
                    had pursued this policy from the first that the ranks this day would be more
                    full, and there would not be so much discontent among the soldiers."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A soldier discusses the widespread discontent in the army and predicts
                    problems unless remedial action is taken. In particular, the men have to be
                    provided with opportunities to visit their homes and take care of familial
                    concerns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>In Limbo</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Captain Joseph Biller captured by Confederate troops at Missionary Ridge is
                    believed to be the same Joseph Biller who was tarred and feathered and run out
                    of Savannah upon conviction for theft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Gov. Watts in his inaugural address, speaks in the following
                    complimentary strain of the benign old mother of us all:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"While Virginia stands as an adamantine wall, against the onward march of
                    Lincoln's column, never let the voice of despondency be uttered from our lips,
                    or find a lodgement in our hearts."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During Governor Watts's inaugural speech, he praised Virginia in most
                    effusive terms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Emmerson</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>M. X.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. M. X. White and Miss Mary J. Hogshead were married at her father's
                    home on the 10th of December. The services were conducted by Rev. Mr. Emmerson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sitlington</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On December 13th, Mr. Andrew Stilington passed away in his 80th year of
                    life, while residing in Millboro Springs, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements and announcements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
