<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.12.01">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/24/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/17/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-12-01">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="01">1</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.12.01.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Victory Or Annihilation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"Dr. Elliott, the patriotic Bishop of Georgia, in a late sermon preached
                    in Savannah, exhibits the alternative before us in a few sentences pregnant with
                    all the fire of a prophet and a patriot. These are, indeed, words that burn:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"We might have gone backward a year ago, when our armies were victoriously
                    thundering at the gates of Washington, and were keeping at bay the Hessians of
                    the West had we been content to bear humiliation for ourselves and degradation
                    for our children. But even that is no longer left us. It is now victory or
                    unconditional submission; submission not to the conservative and Christian
                    people of the North, but to a party of infidel fanatics, with an army of needy
                    and greedy soldiers at their backs. Who shall be able to restrain them in their
                    hour of victory?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Forward, my hearers, with our shields locked and our trust is God, is our
                        only movement now. It is too late even to go backward. We might have gone
                        backward a year ago, when our armies were victoriously thundering at the
                        gates of Washington, and were keeping at bay the Hessians of the West had we
                        been content to bear humilation [sic] for ourselves and degradation for our
                        children. But even that is no longer left us. It is now victory or
                        unconditional submission; submission not to the conservative and Christian
                        people of the North, but to a party of infidel fanatcs, [sic] with an army
                        of needy and greedy soldiers at their backs. Who shall be able to restrain
                        them in their hour of victory? When that moment approaches, when the danger
                        shall seem to be over and the spoils are ready to be divided, every outlaw
                        will rush to fill their ranks, every adventurer will rush to swell their
                        legions, and they will sweep down upon the South as the hosts of Attila did
                        upon the fertile fields of Italy. And shall you find in defeat that mercy,
                        which you did not find in victory? You may slumber now, but you will awake
                        to a fearful reality. You may lie upon your beds of ease, and dream that
                        when it is all over you will be welcomed back to all the privileges and
                        immunities of citizens, but how terrible will be your disappoinment [sic]!
                        You will have an ignoble home, overrun by hordes of insolent slaves and
                        rapacious soldiers. You will wear the badge of a conquered race. Pariahs
                        among your fellow creatures, yourselves degraded, your delicate wives and
                        gentle children trust down to menial service, insulted, perhaps dishonored.
                        Think you that these victorious hordes, made up in the large part of the
                        sweepings of Europe, will leave you any thing? As well might the lamb expect
                        mercy from the wolf. Power which is checked and fettered by a doubtful
                        contest is very different from power victorious, triumphant and
                        irresponsible. The friends whom you have known and loved at the North; who
                        have sympathized with you in your trials, and to whom you might have looked
                        to for comfort and protection, will have enough to do then to take care of
                        themselves. The surges that sweep over us will carry them away in its
                        refluent tide. Oh! for the tongue of a prophet, to paint for you what is
                        before you, unless you repent and turn to the Lord, and realize that "His
                        hand is upon all them for good that seek Him." The language of Scripture is
                        alone adequate to describe it: "The earth mourneth and languisheth: Lebanon
                        is ashamed and hewn down: Sharon is like a wilderness. They that did feed
                        delicately are desolate in the streets: they that were brought up in scarlet
                        embrace dunghilia. They ravished the women of Zion and the maids in the
                        cities of Judah. They took the young men to grind, and the children fell
                        under the wood. The joy of our heart is ceased; our dance is turned into
                        mourning. The crown has fallen from our heart; wo [sic] unto us that have
                        sinned."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A strong appeal from the pulpit for a steadfast commitment to a
                    continuation of the war. Using scripture and emotional rhetoric, the Bishop from
                    Georgia paints a dismal picture of the consequences of defeat for the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Alabama</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Intelligence from Liverpool indicates that the Alabama is currently
                    cruising the Bay of Bengal and keeping Northern ships confined to their harbors.
                    It is also reported that the Northern ship, the Vanderbilt, has found
                    "discretion the better part of valor" when it comes to engaging the Alabama.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Mr. Stuart's Scheme</head>
                <origin>The Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary>"Three weeks ago we published the scheme of Financial relief recommended
                    by Mr. Stuart in his letter to Mr. Armstrong of the Virginia Senate. The
                    Richmond Whig of Wednesday week contains a long and able communication from Mr.
                    Stuart explaining his scheme more fully, and advancing arguments in support of
                    it. The communication being too long for publication, in extenso, in our
                    columns, we are constrained to content ourselves with the publication of a
                    synopsis furnished by the Dispatch.'"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The first thing to be done is to stop the issue of more treasury notes.
                    Unless this be done, all further action upon the subject is evidently vain; for
                    it is the redundancy of the currency that has raised prices to their present
                    fabulous height, and that having occasioned the depreciation in the first
                    instance, renders its downhill march inevitable as the volume."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A summary of a letter from Mr. Stuart to the Richmond Whig explains more
                    fully his economic plans and seeks to address the concerns of adversaries of the
                    plan. Stuart calls for the government to cease currency production and to apply
                    an export duty on cotton, tobacco, and naval stores. While some object to the
                    burden these duties will place on producers of these goods, Mr. Stuart argues
                    that when a good is scarce and desirable, the increased cost will be passed on
                    to the consumer (i.e. foreign markets) rather than borne by the producer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short piece mentions that Joshua Giddings, described as "one of the most
                    rabid Abolitionists in the whole North," has been arrested by the Canadian
                    government for "kidnaping" British subjects and sending them into the Union
                    states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Cincinnati Commercial</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another filler reports that there are believed to be about twenty-five
                    thousand black men carrying rifles and muskets in the Union army at the present
                    time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>In addition to various legal announcements and commercial advertisements, this
                page also contains a poignant poem entitled "Father's Growing Old." This page is
                partly illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.12.01.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The news from the late battle at Lookout Mountain is not as favorable as
                    was desired, but is not so bad as the first despatches, seemed to indicate."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports from the Georgia theater indicate that the enemy continues to take
                    substantial losses but is pursuing its military goals relentlessly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fight At Campbell's Station</head>
                <origin>The Lynchburg Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Based on "a private letter from a member of Longstreet's corps," it is
                    reported that the Union forces were "badly beaten" in a recent engagement in
                    Tennessee. The scope of the defeat forced a quick retreat to Knoxville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Banker's Project</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The volley from the 'Spectator' did not disturb the equanimity or shake
                    the confidence of the 'Whig,' but the broadside of heavy guns brought to bear by
                    'A Farmer,' has caused the Whig to surrender."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Richmond Whig wrote in support of a project of finance formulated by a
                    convention of bankers in South Carolina. It also claimed that the plan was
                    "generally approved by the press." The paper dismissed the Staunton Spectator's
                    concerns about the plan, but was forced to concede that "there are insuperable
                    objections to that scheme" in response to a series of letters submitted by "A
                    Farmer" to that paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Genl. Wise's Letter</head>
                <origin>The Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Enquirer of the 26th ult., contains a long letter addressed by Gen'l.
                    Wise to Hon. J. E. Holcomb of S. C. Gen'l Wise sums up the remedies he would
                    propose as follows:"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Another series of proposals on how to correct the economic woes of the
                    South, this time offered by General Wise. This plan contains fourteen steps
                    ranging from an increase in the pay of soldiers to the repeal of the taxes in
                    kind.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Word To The Wise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Advises the male population to enlist in Home Guard units immediately, as
                    it is predicted that the legislature will soon pass a bill enlisting all males
                    between 15 and 55 years of age. As it currently stands, membership in a Home
                    Guard unit will defer their conscription into the army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In mentioning the advertisement of "Rollins, the Comedian," the author
                    notes that, while he has yet to see the performance, those who have expressed
                    themselves pleased say that he makes them "Laugh and grow fat."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A member of the 12th Va. Regiment, Mahone's brigade, was executed for
                    "skulking on the battlefield." Two others were sentenced to the same punishment,
                    but their execution was postponed until further notice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Prayer For Peace</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In announcing this period of devotion to his congregations on Sunday week
                    we understand that the Roman Catholic Bishop of the Richmond Diocese, the very
                    learned and exemplary Dr. McGill, explained to his people that the peace for
                    which he expected them to pray was such a peace as honorable and patriotic men
                    could accept, and which did not involve any sacrifice of their rights and
                    liberties."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pope Pius IX called for a universal devotion of twenty days for peace in
                    America. While commending the Pope for this spiritual plea for peace, the author
                    cites an English ritual that asks that God may "abate the pride, assuage the
                    malice, and confound the devices of our enemies...."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Impressment In Alabama</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recently introduced bill in the Alabama legislature would establish
                    penalties for "any person to falsely represent himself to be either a State or
                    Confederate agent for the purpose of impressing property."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Georgia Legislature and Gamblers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Georgia Senate has rejected a bill to suppress gambling by a vote of 13
                    to 21. A subsequent measure to reconsider the bill at a later date was passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A filler piece announces that all contrabands in Washington, dependent on
                    the government, are to be quartered south of the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--Since the adjournment of the Legislature, three weeks ago, when
                        an attempt was made to protect sheep from the butcher as well as THE DOGS,
                        several hundred of the finest sheep have been killed in Staunton for food
                        and ONE HUNDRED BY DOGS, viz.: Gerard B. Stuart's, Berry Hinton's, Wm.
                        Crawford's, John C. McCue's and others. When will this evil be cured? When
                        will the public open their eyes to the necessity of AT ONCE checking the
                        evil?</p>
                    <p>A SHIVERING SOLDIER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A Shivering Soldier</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the actions of the legislature to protect sheep from dogs and
                    slaughter for food, a "Shivering Soldier" alleges that several hundred sheep in
                    Staunton have been killed for food or by dogs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Savannah News</origin>
                <commentary>"The Savannah News exhumes the following from an oration delivered by
                    Edward Everet, at Concord, (Mass.) in 1825. It was on the occasion of a fete
                    given in commemoration of the battles of Lexington and Concord. It contains
                    truths which the orator has forgotten, but which some of our own people may use
                    with effect when they choose to appeal to the valor and patriotism of the
                    South:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"But the people never invade: and when they rise against the invader are
                    never subdued. If they are driven from the plains they fly to the mountains.
                    Steep rocks and everlasting hills are their castles; the tangled, pathless
                    thickets their palisades; and nature--God--is their ally...."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the oratory of Edward Everett's commemorative speech of 1825, the South
                    is reminded of the universal truth that "the people always conquer," and if
                    driven from the battlefield they will continue their struggle in an unorthodox
                    manner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4, 5</column>
                <head>Financial Relief--The Plan Of The South Carolina Bankers Reviewed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I cannot question for a moment, the integrity or patriotism of the South
                    Carolina bankers, but it is marvelous how men's minds may be warped by the habit
                    of looking for a series of years to one particular interest, to the exclusion of
                    others."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A long and detailed letter, originally mailed to the Richmond Whig by "A
                    Farmer," that discusses the South Carolina Fiscal Plan and raises a number of
                    serious objections to its course of action. In particular it argues that the
                    proposed tax will fall most heavily on artisans and other laborers while
                    benefiting bankers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cribbins</ln>
                        <fn>Annie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. John E. Mason of Staunton married Mrs. Annie Cribbens of Mt. Sidney
                    on November 26th. The ceremony was conducted by Rev. R. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Kinney, Esq., of Staunton died on November 25th, at the age of 69
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>M. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>Charles Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the death of Capt. Charles Lewis Francisco at the age of
                    twenty-eight years. The young man died near Gettysburg, Pa., where he was
                    serving with the 17th Regt. Va. Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the death of Mrs. Margaret W. Stuart, widow of James Stuart. Mrs.
                    Stuart died on Oct. 1st at her home on the Cowpasture River, Highland County,
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous advertisements and announcements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
