<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.08.04">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/11/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-08-04">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.08.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5, 6, 7</column>
                <head>A July Jaunt in the Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Bucolic account of a summer day's wandering in the Valley with mention of
                    many specific locations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.08.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>From Gen. Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the military situation as settled with no general engagement
                    anticipated for the next several weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mexico Declared An Empire</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reporting on recent events in Mexico, the article notes that Mexico has
                    been declared an Empire, and that Maximilian has been declared Emperor. Should
                    Maximilian decline the offer, he is requested to select a person in whom he has
                    full confidence to occupy the throne.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Recognition Question</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that Mr. Roebuck has been asked by Lord Palmerstown to withdraw his
                    motion of recognition of the Confederacy. Furthermore, it is reported that
                    Parliament has refused to even discuss the question of recognition in the
                    present session. There is greater optimism for a positive response from France
                    on the recognition question.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lieut. Thos. C. Kinney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notifies the public of the death of Lieut. Kinney of typhoid fever on July
                    28th in Staunton. The young man was stricken with the disease while serving with
                    General Lee and was brought to his home to die. The article also discusses his
                    having graduated from the Virginia Military Institute and notes his honorable
                    service for his country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Wounded at Gettysburg</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary>"In the hospitals at Gettysburg there are, by the statement of a
                    correspondent of the New York Herald, about 8,000 wounded Confederate soldiers,
                    and 10,000 Yankee. There were more cases of amputation with our soldiers than
                    with the enemy, and they have been more fatal. This correspondent says that
                    their hospitals are much better managed than ours. He says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"The wounds of the patients were inflamed and the bandages dry. When asked
                        where their nurses were, they said they only had one or two to each floor,
                        and they could not attend them all. In each corner was a pile of dirt, and
                        the flours were wet from the careless spilling of water when the wounds were
                        wet. We went into the yard, and there were some two hundred slightly wounded
                        and convalescent rebels, able to draw and cook their own rations, eating
                        their breakfasts. In our hospitals these would have been made to take their
                        watches with the helpless as nurses; but they would not raise a hand to help
                        their more unfortunate fellows. So true is this that many of them express
                        the most ardent desire to get into Union hospitals, where they will have
                        proper attendance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Records the numbers of wounded in the hospitals of Gettysburg--8,000
                    Confederate and 10,000 Union soldiers. The Herald criticizes the unwillingness
                    of some Confederate soldiers to help their more grievously wounded brethren.
                    Many Confederate soldiers express the most ardent desire to get into Union
                    hospitals, where they will receive better treatment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>General Armistead</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that, despite newspaper accounts in Northern papers that General
                    Armistead died as a result of wounds suffered on the battlefield at Gettysburg,
                    he is in fact alive and has written to his son. The Examiner believes that this
                    misreporting is yet another example of the fact that the Yankees are so much
                    under the influence of the "'father of lies' that they can tell the truth
                    neither of the living nor the dead."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Hostage Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the proposed response to the confinement of two Confederate
                    officers, Gen. Wm. H. F. Lee and Capt. Winder, as hostages against the planned
                    execution of two Union officers by the Confederate authorities. The Confederate
                    authorities have advised the Union that the Confederate government will not be
                    intimidated by any such threats and that the execution of said officers will
                    take place as soon as the President sees fit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>General Morgan's Raid</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the details of General Morgan's raid through Kentucky, Indiana,
                    and Ohio and the subsequent capture of Morgan and his men as they attempted to
                    escape to Virginia by crossing the Ohio River. The article notes the damage
                    Morgan did to Union infrastructure, the bravery of General Morgan, and the fact
                    that he and his men are being held in a penitentiary as hostages "for the
                    officers of Negroes whom we hold in close confinement."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Impressment of Horses in Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last Tuesday was an exciting day in Staunton to all the owners of
                        horses.--The impressment officer had it made known very early in the
                        morning, by having all the ways of egress "blockaded," that "he was about,"
                        and that he was as anxious to get possession of equine flesh as was Richard
                        III when he exclaimed on Bosworth field with all the force of his lungs,
                            "<emph rend="italic">A horse! A horse!! My kingdom for a
                        horse!!!</emph>" Such was the hurry, and so great the seeming emergency that
                        locks were broken and doors prized off their hinges, as there was not time
                        to wait for the owners to bring the keys. The horses of physicians and
                        undertakers were taken; but were graciously restored to their owners when
                        apprised that the sick would die and the dead go unburied if the horses of
                        physicians and undertakers were not given up. The citizens were taken by
                        surprise, and were at a loss to know what caused such a <emph rend="italic"
                            >pressing emergency</emph>. They were perfectly willing to give up their
                        horses, if needed, but had some objection to the <emph rend="italic">quo
                            modo</emph>--the manner in which the officer performed his duty. They
                        modestly thought that there was a right and a wrong way of doing a right
                        thing, and were under the impression that the officer did the right thing in
                        the wrong way. The persons in the best humor on Tuesday last in Staunton
                        were those who were so fortunate as not to own a horse. They gratulated
                        [sic] themselves with the reflection: Blessed is the man who owns "nary a
                        hoss." These fortunates would hallo across the street to their friends and
                        inquire, "how are you off for horse flesh?" When they would get the reply,
                        "I didn't have any horse <emph rend="italic">flesh</emph>, but all my horse
                            <emph rend="italic">bones</emph> have been impressed." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the events that took place in Staunton a week earlier when the
                    impressment officer sealed the town's exits and confiscated almost all the
                    horses in Staunton. The article claims that, while the townspeople of Staunton
                    do not begrudge their government the horses, they do feel that the measure was
                    carried out in the wrong manner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**Homefront</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Fight at Manassas Gap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes a military engagement at Manassas Gap that took place on July
                    23rd between an advance brigade of General Ewell's corps and between 6,000 and
                    8,000 Union soldiers. Despite numerical inferiority and a weak strategic
                    position, Wright's brigade of Georgians fought bravely and managed to inflict
                    heavy casualties on the enemy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Death of Col. Patton</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the death of Col. W. T. Patton's, the son of the late Hon. John
                    M. Patton of Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Soldiers, the Great Desideratum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The great need of the South at this time is more soldiers. All of all defeats
                        and losses are attributable to a want of soldiers. As we have before noticed
                        the President has issued a proclamation calling out all men, not exempted by
                        law, between the ages of 18 and 45. This call is rendered proper, and indeed
                        indispensable, by Lincoln's call for 300,000 conscripts to swell his forces
                        to be employed for our subjugation.</p>
                    <p>In the language of the Fayetteville (N.C.) <emph rend="italic"
                        >Observer</emph>, his armies, whatever force they may amount to, must be
                        met, if it should require every man and boy in the Confederacy. It is a hard
                        duty, but it <emph rend="italic">is</emph> a duty which cannot be avoided
                        but with the loss of everything that as individuals and as a community the
                        people of the Confederacy hold dear. </p>
                    <p>The Yankee Congress has already passed laws to confiscate the property of the
                        people of the Confederacy, and to emancipate their slaves, and the savage
                        malignity of their conduct, wherever they have secured a foot-hold in the
                        South, shows, beyond peradventure that those laws will be enforced if they
                        ever get the power to enforce them. Their soldiers have been promised farms
                        in the South as the reward of their services in conquering us; and they must
                        be wilfully [sic] blind who imagine that the hundreds of thousands of
                        soldiers who have had a taste of blood and ample liberty to rob and outrage,
                        will ever be permitted to return to the North in case of the conquest of the
                        South. The only hope of preserving the lives and property of non-combatants
                        in the large Northern cities, would lie in the quartering of those
                        blood-thirsty villains at the South.</p>
                    <p>Under such circumstances, and our readers know that we have stated them
                        correctly, <emph rend="italic">it is idle to talk of peace</emph>, until the
                        North shows a willingness to have peace, or at least to enter upon
                        negotiations. That they are not prepared for this is manifest from their
                        refusal even to listen to so distinguished a Commissioner as Vice President
                        Stephens upon a secondary point. </p>
                    <p>We repeat, <emph rend="italic">it is idle to talk of peace</emph>, until the
                        North shows a willingness to have peace, or at least to enter upon
                        negotiations. That they are not prepared for this is manifest from their
                        refusal even to listen to so distinguished a Commissioner as Vice President
                        Stephens upon a secondary point. </p>
                    <p>We repeat, <emph rend="italic">it is idle to talk of peace</emph>. We must
                        talk of war and wage war until the enemy tires of war. History is full of
                        examples for our encouragement, of more unequal and even more bloody wars,
                        that finally resulted in the triumph of the people fighting for their
                        rights, their homes and their lives. It is the will of God that we suffer
                        occasional disasters. Let us not, by our own will, permit a combination of
                        all the worst disasters that can befall a people--immediate loss of
                        property, liberty, honor, and eventual loss of life also. Courage, then,
                        Southrons! Brave and true men seize the moment of adversity, not to indulge
                        despair, but to nerve themselves against disaster, and to compel victory.
                        Assured that we are beating for the right, nothing but the will of God
                        should conquer us, and that will has been, so far, more manifested in our
                        favor than against us. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for increased enlistment in the war effort. The author declares it is
                    "idle to talk of peace" until the enemy tires of war. Furthermore, the reporter
                    interprets the North's refusal to negotiate with Vice President Stephens as
                    confirmation of the North's unwillingness to enter into serious peace
                    negotiations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Col. William Dabney Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>William Dabney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes the career and death of Col. William Dabney Stuart, son of Col.
                    Thomas Stuart. He died in Staunton on July 29, 1863 from a wound he received in
                    Pickett's charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Conduct of the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A somewhat rambling essay that touches on a number of issues. The failure
                    to exchange troops is seen as indicative of the Union's desire to fight a war of
                    attrition and take advantage of its larger population. In addition, mention is
                    made of the Union government's refusal to meet with Vice President Stephens.
                    There is also a long discussion on the injustice of the North's selecting
                    General W. H. F. Lee and Capt. Winder as hostages to stay the Confederacy's hand
                    in the execution of two Union officers. Finally, the newspaper reminds its
                    readers that "All this forbearance and chivalrous courtesy on our part--all the
                    Christianity and civilization, as General Lee says--has been thrown away upon
                    such an enemy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Illness of General Floyd</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alerts readers to the imminent death of retired General Floyd from diseases
                    contracted during his time in the service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>President's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We invite attention to the proclamation of President Davis appointing Friday,
                        the 21st of this month, as a day of fasting, humiliation and prayer, and
                        express the hope that it will be observed in the proper christian spirit. It
                        will be observed that the President attributes our trials and reverses to
                        the prevalence of the sins of presumptuous self-confidence, and the
                        idolatrous worship of Mammon. Our people have been too forgetful of the
                        living God, from whom all blessings flow, and have been recklessly seeking
                        gain, seemingly oblivious of the fact that it is impossible to serve God and
                        Mammon. It is too true, as the President says, "that the love of lucre has
                        eaten, <emph rend="italic">like a gangrene</emph>, into the very heart of
                        the land, converting too many of us into worshippers of gain, and rendering
                        them unmindful of their duty to their fellowmen [sic], and to their God." As
                        long as the people practice the sin of extortion upon each other, and the
                        officers of the Confederacy rob the Government, we cannot expect to be
                        vouch-safed the boon of freedom and independence. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notifies the readers of President Davis's proclamation that Friday the
                    twenty-first of August is to be a day of fasting, humiliation, and prayer. The
                    article notes that the President "attributes our trials and reverses to the
                    prevalence of the sins of presumptuous self-confidence, and the idolatrous
                    worship of Mammon."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**Churches/Religious Activities</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Small filler that notes the death of Hon. Jno. J. Crittenden at Frankfort,
                    Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The American Question in France</head>
                <origin>The New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the recent visit by Messrs. Roebuck and Lindsay to Fontainebleau,
                    France, for the purpose of persuading the Emperor to make an official movement
                    at London for the recognition of the Southern States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Meade's Mendacity</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following official communication from General Lee illustrates the
                    unreliability of despatches emanating from Yankee Generals."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on a recent communication from General Lee that disputes despatches
                    from General Meade about the number of Confederate troops captured as Lee's army
                    retreated to the south bank of the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation of Governor Brown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following is an abstract of the recent proclamation by Governor
                    Brown of Georgia:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the recent adoption of conscription in Georgia, which became
                    necessary because of the drop in enlistments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The President's Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President has issued a strong appeal to the soldiers of the Confederacy
                        absent from their commands to return IMMEDIATELY, and promises amnesty to
                        all who are absent without leave if they return within twenty days from this
                        date, after which time all will be treated and punished as deserters.
                        General Lee and President Davis have both issued calls for soldiers to
                        return immediately--the emergency is great and every soldier should be at
                        his post of duty. The address was received too late for insertion in this
                        issue.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alerts the readers to the fact that the President has issued a strong
                    appeal for all soldiers absent without leave from the armed forces to return
                    within twenty days or be treated as deserters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**Homefront</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Baltimore Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the horrific losses of the 1st Michigan Regiment which,
                    according to reports, began the war with 1,050 men and came out of Gettysburg
                    with only 87.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the death of Hon. Wm. L. Yancey, a member of the Confederate
                    Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notifies readers that Lt. Col. Henry Clay Pate of the 5th Virginia Cavalry,
                    who was wounded in the cavalry battle of Aldie, is recovering in Clarke County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to a recent announcement from Washington, D.C., "the place of a
                    drafted man who had been exempted by payment of $300 will not be filled by
                    another drafted man."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A small filler announcing that General Cooper has ordered all
                    Quartermasters and Commissaries to detail disabled soldiers so that citizens
                    employed in those positions can be made available for immediate conscription.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee's Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Publication of General Orders, no. 80, ordering all officers and soldiers
                    now absent from duty and not detached on special service to return immediately
                    to their regiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vance</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Henry Smith and Miss Mary Ann Vance, both of Augusta County, were
                    married on July 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of the death of Mary Ann Gordon, daughter of Samuel and Martha
                    Gordon, on July 24,1863 at the age of 24 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There was no soldier in the Confederate army more brave than Mr. Bell."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of the death of Mr. David Bell, Company C, 5th Virginia
                    Regiment, on June 24th at a hospital in Lynchburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of the death of John B. Rankin, Sr., on July 26th at the age
                    of 64 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Ambrose</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcment of the death of Nancy Davis, wife of Ambrose Davis, on July
                    26th at the age of 45 years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements and announcements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
