<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.11.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/20/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-11-18">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.11.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Modern Antaeus</head>
                <origin>Chicago Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Modern Antaeus.</p>
                    <p>From the Chicago Times</p>
                    <p>In contemplating matters in the Shenandoah Valley, one will find himself at a
                        loss whether to most admire the vast number and extent of Sheridan's
                        victories or the remarkable stolidity with which the rebel Early endures
                        frequent annihilation. For the last two months the enemy have exhibited the
                        remarkable peculiarity of being defeated overwhelmingly at very short
                        intervals, and within a few days after each defeat presenting themselves in
                        stronger force than ever to again undergo a defeat more disastrous than any
                        of its predecessors. There was once, in some olden fable, a dragon that
                        possessed the somewhat singular power of producing a half dozen or more new
                        heads whenever one of its old ones was chopped off, and in Early we see the
                        modern prototype of this fabled monster. The more Sheridan [illegible] away
                        his limbs, the greater becomes his task, for, from each bleeding stump
                        springs a crop of new limbs, till the rebel chieftain now resembles the
                        hundred handed Briareus.</p>
                    <p>Early was first routed at Winchester, and a little later is found at Fisher's
                        Hill waiting to be routed again. He is once more routed, with tremendous
                        loss; and three days after, his demoralized cohorts present a firm array at
                        Harrisonburg. From this place he is routed, with fearful slaughter, so that
                        there is scarcely enough left to carry the tala [sic] of disaster to the
                        rebel capital. A little later, and Sheridan falls back to Strasburg, but has
                        hardly reached there ere Early's broken legion precipitate themselves upon
                        him with the fierceness of tigers. Again are they routed with tremendous
                        slaughter. Sheridan falls back to Strasburg, but has hardly reached there
                        ere Early's broken legion precipitate themselves upon him with the
                        fierceness of tigers. Again are they routed with tremendous slaughter.
                        Sheridan falls back to Cedar creek, and has but just gone into camp when the
                        routed Early is again upon him, driving him four miles, and captures twenty
                        cannon. But the success is only a momentary one, for the gallant Sheridan
                        dashes upon the field, reforms his broken regiments, and turns the tide of
                        battle. Again does the unlucky Early undergo the crucifixion of being routed
                        in a style which, for effectiveness, the record of defeats furnishes no
                        parallels.</p>
                    <p>The worse Early is routed, the speedier and deadlier is his next attack. Like
                        the old Antaeus, he only strikes the ground to arise a stronger, bigger
                        giant than before. The more violent he is hurled to earth, the higher is his
                        rebound. The more completely he is "settled" and the sooner he regains
                        strength to be "settled" again.</p>
                    <p>Wonderful as is this recuperative power in Early, it is not more so than his
                        inexhaustible ability to furnish cannon. He lost a large number of cannon
                        when Sheridan first "settled" him; and he lost a considerable large number
                        the second time he was "settled" be Sheridan. A little later, and Sheridan
                        once more "settled" Early and captured all his cannon. Within a week he
                        "settled" him again, and again captured a good many cannon. Day before
                        yesterday he once more "settled" the unfortunate Early and captured fifty
                        cannon; and we have no doubt that to-morrow or the next day he will again
                        "settle" Early and once more capture a great many cannon--probably not less
                        than fifty or sixty. The more cannon Early loses, the more he seems to have
                        left; so much so, that if Sheridan keeps on "settling" him for six months
                        longer, the Federal Government will be able to stop all its foundries,
                        having enough cannon for its own supply and a large surplus for the next war
                        with Canada, Maximilian, or Great Britain.</p>
                    <p>One would thin that either Sheridan would get tired of "settling" Early, or
                        Early of being "settled." But they do not. Judging by the past, Sheridan
                        having routed Early all the way from Stanton to Cedar creek, will continue
                        routing and "settling" him from Cedar creek to the Pennsylvania
                    boundary.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Times cannot decide whether to admire the many victories the North has
                    had in the Valley of Virginia or to admire the Confederate forces there who have
                    suffered so many defeats yet continue to resist and fight back. Each time
                    General Early fights back more quickly and more deadly, only to be defeated more
                    severely each time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Negroes in the Army</head>
                <origin>Savannah News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negroes in the Army.</p>
                    <p>The Savan[n]ah <emph rend="italic">News</emph> refuses to publish
                        communications in referance [sic] to placing negroes in the army, for the
                        reason that it does not regard the question in detail as a proper one for
                        newspaper discussion. And it adds: "In opposing it, and pointing out the
                        many evils sure to result from such a policy, our correspondents are led
                        into arguments and reasoning which, while they suggest, themselves to every
                        reflecting mind, are unsuited for news paper circulation either North or
                        South. A measure so disorganizing, so unnecessary, unwise and impolitic,
                        will, we feel confident, be rejected by our people and our Congress.
                        Consistency self-respect, Southern honor and humanity demands it."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Savannah News refuses to publish letters regarding the question of
                    placing African Americans in the Southern army, deeming the topic unsuitable for
                    discussion in a newspaper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Failure of Grant's Recent Advance</head>
                <origin>New York World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Failure of Grant's Recent Advance.</p>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">World</emph>, commenting on the general
                        failure of Grant's advance, says:</p>
                    <p>It is no longer a secret that the rebels have again thwarted Gen. Grant's
                        movement for the capture of Richmond. His attention was to have accumulated
                        a vast army of three or four hundred thousand men, with a view to invest
                        Richmond on every side. After the fall of Atlanta, it is supposed he could
                        spare fifty or sixty thousand troops from the West, and take all the
                        conscripts to be added to the army of the Potomac and of the James. But he
                        invasion of Missouri by Price and the menacing of St. Louis, the attack of
                        Hood upon Sherman's rear and the activity of guerrillas and rebel raiding
                        parties throughout Tennessee and Kentucky, and last of all, the wonderful
                        vitality of the rebel armies in the Shenandoah, have prevented the
                        concentration of troops in Grant's army to be effective in time for the
                        Presidential election.</p>
                    <p>A large part of this army is composed of raw recruits, and General Grant is
                        supposed to be unwilling to force them against the strong defences of
                        Richmond, while he would not have hesitated had he a sufficient number of
                        Sheridan's or Sherman's veterans. The theory is that in all probability, the
                        campaign against Richmond will be postponed until next May; that another
                        draft for three hundred thousand men may be made after the election, which
                        draft will be a real one, and all the men will be secured and incorporated
                        in the armies during the coming winter. With these, the Administration hope
                        to carry all the important points of the South.</p>
                    <p>There is now no harm in stating that at least two army corps, under General
                        Sheridan, were on the way to the Army of the Potomac when they were recalled
                        to beat back Longstreet's force in the Valley. While the rebel army has been
                        defeated, Lee's strategy has won a strategic victory in the postponement of
                        the campaign.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>General Grant was to have assembled a large number of troops in order to
                    take Richmond from all sides, but was still unable to capture the city. In the
                    end, some of the troops he had hoped to assemble were engaged elsewhere,
                    including in the Valley. The current theory is that Grant will wait until spring
                    to try to take the city again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Ludicrous Mistake</head>
                <origin>Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that one brigade of Yankees, on their way to join Grant's forces in
                    the recent battle to take Richmond, were unfamiliar with the area, got separated
                    from the rest of the troops, and finally stumbled upon a railroad that they
                    thought was the one they were supposed to destroy. The rail line they destroyed,
                    however, was one just built by Grant's men to run from Petersburg to City Point.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, notices, war news, and a report on Henry
                Ward Beecher's last stump speech in the United States presidential
            campaign.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.11.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The President's Message.</p>
                    <p>We said before our readers in our last issue the message of President Davis.</p>
                    <p>From it we have a most encouraging statement of affairs. These portions of
                        our states held by the enemy have nearly all been reclaimed or the tenure of
                        the enemy upon them much weakened. Our finances are in much better condition
                        than many had supposed and with the addition of the seemingly practicable
                        suggestions of the Secretary of the Treasury it is hoped may still further
                        be greatly improved. And the arming of slaves in defence of our liberties is
                        not deemed essential at present. The various suggestions of the Message meet
                        with the approval of the people with the exception of the recommendation of
                        the repeal of all class exemptions. This is condemned as unwise not only by
                        the people but the men in the field. The last Congress modified the
                        exemption bill so as to apply to Preachers, Teachers, Printers, Physicians
                        and Druggists, which classes were deemed essentially necessary for the
                        public good. There has been much acerbity of feeling shown against the
                        Executive on account of this recommendation, but we are among those who
                        believe that President Davis is eminently a patriot, that he would do
                        anything consistent with reason and right for the advancement of the
                        interests of his country, but that the suggestion on this subject was
                        elicited by the perusal of the exemption bill as it stood before it was
                        modified by the last Congress, the vast array of classes mentioned therein
                        being sufficient to cause the request for the repeals of all exemptions as a
                        patriotic duty on his part. But Tanners, Shoemakers, Telegraph operators,
                        Workmen in mines, Blacksmiths, Millers, and in fact all save the classes
                        named above have been subject to detail and not exempted since the framing
                        of the new exemption bill by the last Congress. We doubt not that when the
                        President calls to mind that only a few classes, deemed essentially
                        necessary, were exempted, instead of the array mentioned in his message that
                        he will be as averse to a change of the law as the people, the press or the
                        army.</p>
                    <p>We do not for a moment believe that were Editors, Preachers &amp;c.,
                        detailed that President Davis would exercise any authority to muzzle the
                        Press or the Pulpit. For it must be clearly understood by him that the free,
                        outspoken sentiments of the Press have contributed largely to make us the
                        united people we are, that where the administration has been wrongfully
                        assailed ten friends have been made for one enemy and that the concordant
                        utterances of the Press have kept up the continued cheerful and determined
                        spirit of our people. This at least is understood by our enemies, for in
                        their invasions they make it an universal practice to destroy this great
                        confederate agency, by demolishing all printing establishments in their
                        reach. This has been especially the case in our Valley; but our enemies have
                        been foiled in their attempts for nearly all have arisen Phoenix-like from
                        their ashes and still lend their sufficient aid to their Government. The
                        great moral power of the press is universally conceded but what a falling
                        off therefrom would there be were the representatives of of [sic] free
                        speech and thought compelled to seek, with supplicatory appeal, for details
                        from the powers that be--However free in the expression of thoughts yet it
                        would all be considered as winked at by Government for effect, and the moral
                        effect of the Confederate Press be forever gone.</p>
                    <p>We think it is patent that those who are at present exempted are essentially
                        necessary for the public good and that details not exemptions are the
                        subjects of fraud.</p>
                    <p>We agree with a contemporary of Lynchburg that it is idle to believe that an
                        enlightened Congress will interfere with the liberties of the Press or
                        Pulpit and with another of Richmond that it is better to let well enough
                        alone as the chances are greatly in favor of making matters worse.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor comments on President Davis's message, the text of which was
                    published in the previous week's issue, and the encouraging report it contains.
                    Most areas in the Confederacy taken by the enemy have been recovered, or at
                    least the enemy's hold has weakened, finances are more stable, and the arming of
                    African Americans is not necessary at present.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that little has happened in Richmond and Petersburg, that Hood is
                    said to be heading to Nashville, and that Sherman is said to be moving away from
                    Atlanta. The article further states that nothing has happened in the lower
                    Valley since Rosser captured two hundred prisoners on November 12, 1864. The
                    prisoners arrived in Staunton on Wednesday on their way to Richmond.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Election of Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Election of Lincoln.</p>
                    <p>The latest Northern exchanges received at Richmond concede the election of
                        Abraham Lincoln as President of the United States for another term of four
                        years. Laying aside the moral effect upon the world at large, of the
                        election of Lincoln after a four year's exhibition of incapacity, we must
                        view it in the relations which obtain with reference to ourselves.</p>
                    <p>The unbridled licentiousness of the past four years is to be continued for
                        the next four, with all the ingenious adjuncts which the minds of our
                        Barbarian Enemies can devise. The destruction in our beautiful Valley will
                        be vastly obscured by the ravages of other invaded portions, but the cry of
                        failure thus far to subjugate the Confederate States, if we be true to
                        ourselves, will be reiterated at the expiration of the last year of his
                        second term. We must prepare now for a longer war than many surmised,
                        without relying upon dissentions among the people of the United States or
                        failure of their financial system or anything else for relief except the
                        physical force and determined will of the people of our Confederacy. We
                        should hoard up our resources, doing away with the wasteful extravagance
                        exhibited in so many instances, save the lives of our men by all the devices
                        of engineering skill, ever be ready to take advantage of circumstances to
                        strike our enemies severe blows, infuse discipline, so needful to retain the
                        advantages gained, retaliate for all of their wanton acts with "Oriental
                        Scrupulosity," and we will prevent the accomplishments of their designs and
                        in the end achieve that independence which the unbiased opinion of the world
                        at present would and should declare our due.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor reports that exchanges from Northern papers announce the
                    reelection of Lincoln as president. This means, the editor believes, that the
                    barbarism and outrages will continue for another four years. The ravages of the
                    Valley will pale in comparison with what will follow, and the South must now be
                    prepared for a longer war than anticipated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel Charles Peyton, enrolling officer, has been transferred to the
                    Albemarle district and will be replaced by Captain W. T. Fry for this
                    congressional district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lincoln Elected</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln carried the popular vote by around 225,000, and he won
                    the electoral vote by 192. McClellan carried New Jersey, Delaware, and Kentucky.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Cavalry</head>
                <origin>Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thirty farmers from Augusta County, many of whom had already seen service,
                    arrived in Richmond when their detail duties were revoked. They waived their
                    medical examinations at Camp Lee and were assigned as a body to duty in the 13th
                    Virginia cavalry under Colonel Robert A. Caskie. Colonel Lucius Davis will be
                    brigade commander of this and other regiments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Rockingham's Losses</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Rockingham's Losses.</p>
                    <p>The following is a fair and an accurate exhibit of the losses inflicted upon
                        this great and noble county of the "old commonwealth" by the Yankees in
                        their last raid up the Valley. It has obtained by our County Court, after
                        diligent effort, and the employment of all the means necessary to
                        approximate accuracy in such a calculation. The Court after being called
                        together for this purpose, appointed a committee of 72 persons, consisting
                        of 36 citizens of respectability and standing, located in every section of
                        the county, and after a careful and an accurate canvass of the county, they
                        have furnished the estimate of the lesser hereto appended. Has any other one
                        country in the Confederacy suffered to the same extent? Look at the exhibit:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Losses.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Dwelling House burned,</cell>
                            <cell>30</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Barns burned,</cell>
                            <cell>450</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Mills burned,</cell>
                            <cell>31</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Fencing destroyed, (miles)</cell>
                            <cell>100</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bushes of Wheat destroyed,</cell>
                            <cell>100,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Bushes of Corn destroyed,</cell>
                            <cell>50,000</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Tons of Hay destroyed,</cell>
                            <cell>6,233</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Cattle carried off,</cell>
                            <cell>1,750</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Horses carried off,</cell>
                            <cell>1,750</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Sheep carried off,</cell>
                            <cell>4,200</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Hogs carried off,</cell>
                            <cell>3,350</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Factories burned,</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Furnace burned,</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>In addition to which the[re] was an immense amount of Farming Utensils of
                        every description destroyed, many of them of great value, such as
                        McCormick's Reapers, Threshing Machines; also, Household and Kitchen
                        Furniture, Money, Bonds, Plates, &amp;c., &amp;c. The whole loss
                        being estimated at the enormous sum of $25,500,000. This estimate is in
                        Confederate prices, and should be reduced, we think, about one-fifth, in
                        order to bring it to the government standard.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Rockingham Register.</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The latest Yankee raid resulted in the following damage to Rockingham
                    County: 30 houses, 450 barns, and 31 mills burned; 100 miles of fencing torn
                    down; 100,000 bushels of wheat, 50,000 bushels of corn, and 6,232 tons of hay
                    destroyed; 1,750 cattle, 1,750 horses, 4,200 sheep, and 3,350 hogs carried off;
                    3 factories and 1 furnace burned; an immense number of farming utensils
                    destroyed; and countless household furnishings wrecked.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel F. Shank married Elizabeth Miller, both of Rockingham County, on
                    October 28, 1864, with Reverend C. Beard officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCord</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca McCord married John C. Coiner, both of Augusta County, on November
                    6, 1864, with Reverend C. Beard officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holland</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Virginia S. Brown married Francis M. Holland at the home of John D. Brown,
                    Esquire, on November 9, 1864, with Reverend William E. Baker officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>M. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>Robert A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lucy Hopkins died of diphtheria on October 16, 1864, and Robert A. Hopkins
                    died of diphtheria on October 21, 1864. Both died at Midway and were the
                    children of W. J. and M. M. Hopkins.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>One Cent Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Livingston W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>A. G. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. G. S. Vanlear announces a reward of one cent for the return of
                    Livingston W. Hall, who was bound to him by Hall's father until he became of
                    age. Hall ran away on September 21, 1864. He is seventeen, "well grown, stout
                    and healthy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hd. Qr's Res. Forces V. D.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bosserman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>David D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fox</ln>
                        <fn>David J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gale</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindig</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pitman</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Perry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuff</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Blueford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woolland</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wiserman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Womoldorf</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Brig. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>A. A. A. G.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Brig. General E. G. Lee issues an order, via John H. McCue, A. A. A. G., to
                    persons in Augusta and Rockbridge counties who are listed to report to the
                    headquarters of the reserve forces of the Valley District to pick up their
                    detail papers. Failure to do so will result in their papers being withheld.
                    Those persons from Augusta County include William Andrews. David Argenbright,
                    Jacob Argenbright, John Bosserman, David D. Coiner, David J. Fox, George Fix,
                    David C. Gilkeson, John Gale, A. K. Kindig, A. A. Pitman, James Perry, George
                    Rusmisel, Joseph T. Smith, George W. Smith, William W. Shuff, Jacob Stover,
                    Blueford Smith, William W. Woolland, John A. Wiserman, George W. Womoldorf, and
                    R. W. Wright.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, advertisements, and
            notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
