<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.12.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/25/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-12-02">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.12.02.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are several articles on the war, advertisements, notices, and a
                poem.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.12.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>War News.</p>
                    <p>Since our last issue, nothing of interest has occurred on our lines below
                        Richmond and Petersburg. It is stated by some prisoners recently, taken,
                        that another Yankee picket line has been captured in front of Mahone, on the
                        morning of the 28th. They state that it was very dark, and they could not
                        discern the full force that took them; but that the attack was very sudden,
                        that 20 or 30 were killed on the spot, and about 60 or 70 captured. The
                        general impression with the knowing ones seems to be, that Grant is
                        evidently making ready for another advance on our right, and is massing
                        troops in that quarter. Our batteries still continue to shell Dutch Gap, and
                        it is reported that Gen. Picket, from his lines South of Battery Howlett's,
                        had also opened with his cannon upon the enemy in his front, who are
                        believed to be mostly negroes. The Richmond papers state that a report was
                        current there, that Grant had sent off a considerable body of troops to
                        co-operate with Sherman in Georgia, and to aid that General in reaching and
                        establishing a base on the Atlantic coast.</p>
                    <p>The latest intelligence we have from Georgia is contained in the following
                        extract which we copy from a Georgia paper.</p>
                    <p>The Augusta "Sentinel," of the 22d, states that intelligence reached Augusta
                        the evening before, by the passenger train on the Georgia Railroad, that our
                        authorities had burned the bridge over the Oconee river, and that the Yankee
                        column, moving down the road, had diverged from it and was hastening to join
                        the main body.</p>
                    <p>It is stated that the Yankees had a large wagon train with them, which was
                        divided after leaving the Georgia road, in order to sweep all supplies from
                        the section within reach of the two routes taken. Scouts report them five
                        brigades strong.</p>
                    <p>The rumor that the Court House and depot at Madison had been burned is
                        correct.</p>
                    <p>The Macon train arrived the night of the 21st at its usual time. The train
                        left for that city next morning at its usual hour.</p>
                    <p>The Macon "Telegraph" says it intends to hold forth in Macon until the
                        Confederate flag ceases to wave over the city.</p>
                    <p>From the Richmond "Whig," who was furnished with a copy of the Augusta
                        "Constitutionalist" of the 25th we learn that Gen. Wayne has whipped
                        Kilpatrick's cavalry division at the Ocenee bridge, driving them headlong
                        and in confusion. He telegraphs that he is perfectly able to take care of
                        himself.</p>
                    <p>Wheeler, with many thousand men, has intercepted the enemy at a point, at
                        present unmentionable, and is giving them no rest, night or day.</p>
                    <p>The main body of the enemy is moving down the western side of the Oconee, and
                        has shown no disposition thus far to attempt its passage.</p>
                    <p>The "Constitutionalist" adds that three hundred prisoners arrived last
                        evening from up the Georgia Road, and four hundred more are to arrive
                        to-day.</p>
                    <p>These prisoners report that a division of three thousand of our cavalry has
                        followed them all the way, dashing upon them constantly, picking up
                        stragglers and capturing wagons.</p>
                    <p>We have nothing from the army of Gen. Breckenridge since the affair of the
                        9th ult., in which the enemy were driven beyond Strawberry plains. The next
                        we hear from this chivalrous chieftain may be that he has penetrated his
                        native State with his gallant army, and hoisted the Confederate banner,
                        under the ample folds of which we hope he may redeem that downtrodden State
                        from the tyranny of Yankee rule, and place her where her heart is, and where
                        of right she ought to be, among her sister States of our glorious
                        Confederacy.</p>
                    <p>The news from the "Army of Tennessee" is becoming interesting again. We are
                        now informed that it was concentrating near Columbia, Tennessee, last week,
                        and that Thomas was falling back towards Nashville, having evacuated
                        Huntsville, Decatur and Pulaski. The main body of Hood's army crossed the
                        Tennessee river at Florence, on the 13th instant, the day after Sherman left
                        Kingston on his Georgia expedition. Lee's corps had previously occupied
                        Florence.</p>
                    <p>Nothing of interest has taken place in the army of Genl. Early, during the
                        past week.</p>
                    <p>The Yankees are said to be encamped below Strasburg, their headquarters at or
                        near Kernstown.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Little has happened in Richmond and Petersburg in the past week, except a
                    report of capture of another enemy picket line on November 28, 1864. Indications
                    are that Grant is amassing troops in the area in preparation for another
                    advance. The editor includes reports from Georgia and Tennessee and states that
                    nothing of interest has happened in the Valley. The enemy is said to be encamped
                    below Strasburg and to have headquarters at or near Kernstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Word to the Wise</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Many portions of our State have been entirely free from the annoyances to
                    which our Valley has been subjected and we are informed that in those sections
                    the crops have been generally good and produce abundant--certainly more abundant
                    than in this pillaged district."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A Word to the Wise.</p>
                    <p>The success of our arms, in the glorious struggle for independence in which
                        we are engaged, depends as much upon sustaining our armies in the field as
                        upon the invincible spirit of the brave men who bear the brunt of battle.
                        That it is of the primest necessity that they should be well fed, well clad
                        and well armed no one will pretend to gainsay, but as to the means of doing
                        this there may be a diversity of opinion. Our section has been sorely
                        oppressed by two invasions of the enemy--its barns, mills, factories, fences
                        &amp;c. burned; cattle, horses, sheep and hogs killed or driven off;
                        wheat and long-forage, seized or destroyed, thus leaving but little for
                        subsistence for our people. To be fed on the meagre remnant left by the
                        Vandal invaders are the non-producers as well as the producers themselves.
                        In some portions of our County, the little our farmers had left has been
                        impressed for the ruse of the army of the Valley, leaving, in many
                        instances, an insufficiency for their own immediate wants, to supply which
                        they must go into the depleted market with the non-producer and buy.</p>
                    <p>We do not doubt that the necessity, at times, was such that the army of the
                        Valley would have suffered if this course had not been pursued, and on this
                        account many have hesitated to complain, but the evil seems to be a growing
                        one and we therefore raise our voice, against the evident mismanagement
                        which makes its continuance necessary. Many portions of our State have been
                        entirely free from the annoyances to which our Valley has been subjected and
                        we are informed that in those sections the crops have been generally good
                        and produce abundant--certainly more abundant than in this pillaged
                        district. They are indirect Railroad connection with this place, and ample
                        supplies may be procured and easily transported to this point and thus
                        relieve our people and the army for a further draft upon their already
                        scanty allowance. Besides this the transportation of supplies from Staunton
                        to the army is over a good road and can be much more speedily done than from
                        our different farm houses over mud roads.</p>
                    <p>If it is desirable that a crop should be raised in our Valley next year it is
                        necessary that our people should have enough left to subsist them, which can
                        not possibly be the case if continuous drafts are made upon their present
                        small supply and hence we appeal to those who have this matter in hand to
                        take hold of and arrange it so that the army will be supplied from more
                        plentiful sections and the chances for a crop next year in this locality be
                        greatly increased.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The feeding of the troops is of utmost concern to all southerners, but the
                    recent destruction in the Valley leaves insufficient produce to feed the local
                    people, much less supply the troops. The editor joins his voice with others
                    raising the concern that supplies are not being managed properly. The many areas
                    of the state that have suffered so much less than the Valley and that, in turn,
                    have more abundant produce should be called upon to provide produce for
                    impressment and to provide food for people in the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Enlistment of Negroes</head>
                <origin>Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Negroes for the Army.</p>
                    <p>In the Senate on Tuesday, Mr. Henry of Tennessee, from the committee on
                        Military Affairs, reported a bill to amend an act to increase the efficiency
                        of the army by the employment of free negroes and slaves in certain cap
                        cities. The bill increased the compensation given to free negroes and and
                        [sic] other free persons of color to $18 per month; authorizes the
                        employment of 40,000 slaves, instead of 20,000 by the Secretary of War--to
                        impress them, if unable to hire them, and those not engaged in agricultural
                        productions shall be the first impressed, and then those engaged in
                        agricultural pursuits are to be taken from persons having more than fifteen
                        able bodied hands, between the ages of 16 and 50 years. The bill was ordered
                        to be printed, and placed upon the calendar.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The writer points out that, in light of the recent discussions regarding
                    use of African Americans in the Confederate army, readers should be aware that
                    James Madison recommended their employment in the Revolutionary army. He
                    proposed that slaves be offered their freedom and wages if they enlisted. Owners
                    received compensation of a maximum of 120 pounds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Negroes for the Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Senator Henry of Tennessee introduced a bill to employ free
                    blacks and slaves in the Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen'l Lee's Army</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Express reports that the men of Lee's army are in the "best
                    possible condition and in unsurpassed spirits" and that the North will never
                    starve or defeat the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. E. Logan, Salt Agent for Augusta County</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>W. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. E. Logan, salt agent for Augusta County, replies to the query in last
                    week's issue regarding the price of salt in the county. Logan invites the writer
                    to visit him at his home or to wait until his report is filed in the clerk's
                    office of the county court in order to receive an answer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Education of the Children of Deceased and Disabled Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W. J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The central committee on the education of the children of deceased and
                    disabled soldiers in Richmond has appointed a committee in the Valley, composed
                    of George B. Taylor, C. R. Mason, M. G. Harman, W. H. Peyton, W. J. Shumate, and
                    W. J. D. Bell, to identify children who need to be in school and to solicit
                    donations for the purpose of placing these children in school.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A List of Prisoners of the 52nd Regiment Va. Infantry, now at Elmira New York,
                    including those who have died while in prison</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jimison</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathews</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathews</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>W. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crumb</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wells</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradshaw</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Redaford</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harshbarger</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>G. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrish</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stockdall</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stockdall</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stockdall</ln>
                        <fn>H. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barger</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tally</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollace</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimbro</ln>
                        <fn>K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawp</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>J. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summers</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zack</ln>
                        <fn>William Z.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keyser</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerry</ln>
                        <fn>P. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zack</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynkswiler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Archey</ln>
                        <fn>S. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prisoners from the 52nd Regiment now in Elmira, New York, or who have died
                    there include: from Company A: J. Croft, T. Cox, William T. Jimison, D. Mathews,
                    J. Mathews; from Company B: H. Coiner, William Swan, J. W. Terrell; from Company
                    C: W. J. Fix, J. Croft; from Company D: Samuel Huffer, J. Crumb; from Company E:
                    C. C. Wells, Bradshaw; A. J. Black, William Clark, James Wood; from Company F:
                    J. Myers, J. Redaford, J. Harshbarger, C. Allen, died; from Company G: B. F.
                    Coffman, T. Rankin, G. K. Hanger, William Parrish, E. F. Stockdall, William
                    Stockdall, died, H. T. Stockdall, died, J. E. Wheeler, died, J. C. Barger, died,
                    J. W. Smith, died, T. J. Tally, J. L. Harris, died; from Company H: J. H. Lee,
                    H. B. Hollace, K. Zimbro, William Wayd; from Company I: J. Cox, James Hawp, J.
                    E. Harris, J. Miller, died, Sergeant Summers, died; from Company K: William Z.
                    Zack, M. D. Keyser, P. L. Kerry, J. H. Zack, died, J. Lynkswiler, S. P. Archey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Harrison Bryan, a member of Company L, West Augusta Guard, 5th
                    Virginia Regiment, was killed in the battle at Monocracy. His funeral will be
                    held at the Baptist church in Staunton on December 4, 1864, at eleven o'clock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Negroes for Sale</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Peck advertises that he has four black women and girls for sale privately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>$400 Reward!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>$400 Reward.</p>
                    <p>Ran away from the subscriber on Thursday the 24th of this month, my negro boy</p>
                    <p>Pitman.</p>
                    <p>He is about fifteen years old, tall for his age and slender of a clear black
                        color, can read, has an appearance of simplicity when spoken to and often
                        twists up his forehead when addressed. He had on a Grey jacket, brown pants
                        and a brown shirt and took with him a hand satchel believed to be black. He
                        is probably making his way towards Gordonsville or Charlotte County.</p>
                    <p>I will give Four Hundred Dollars for his arrest and detention in jail or
                        otherwise se[e] that I recover possession of him.</p>
                    <p>Hugh W. Sheffey.</p>
                    <p>Staunton Dec. 2--3t 1864.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Pitman, about fifteen years old, tall and slender, a clear black color,
                    wearing a gray jacket, brown pants, and a brown shirt, and carrying a hand
                    satchel thought to be black, ran away from Hugh W. Sheffey on November 24, 1864.
                    Pitman, who can read and "has an appearance of simplicity when spoken to and
                    often twists up his forehead when addressed," is probably on his way to
                    Gordonsville or Charlotte County. Sheffey offers a reward of $400 for the return
                    of Pitman to him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>$100 Reward!!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>$100 Reward.</p>
                    <p>Ran away from the subscriber near Greenville, Augusta Co., Va., on the 26th
                        day of October last, a mulatto boy named</p>
                    <p>George Lee,</p>
                    <p>about 15 years old, walks with his toes somewhat inward. One Hundred Dollars
                        will be given for his apprehension and confinement in the Staunton or
                        Lexington jail so that I may recover him.</p>
                    <p>A. F. Kinney,</p>
                    <p>Depositary.</p>
                    <p>Dec 2--4t.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lee</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hess</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Lee, a mulatto boy about fifteen years old who "walks with his toes
                    somewhat inward," ran away from Joseph T. Hess in Greenville, Augusta County, on
                    October 26, 1864. Hess offers a reward of $100 for his return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are other articles on the war, especially developments in
                Georgia, and additional advertisements and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
