<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.01.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/10/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/22/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-01-22">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.01.22.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are a reprinted list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of
                Virginia Volunteers, war news, anecdotes, advertisements, a poem, and instructions
                on income tax. Part of this page is missing.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.01.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>There is Work for All</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No feeling but of ultimate success pervades the men of our armies, . . .
                    and they do not despond but now stand ready to meet the hosts of the enemy as
                    they have ever met them steady and unflinching."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Congress asserts that heavy work is ahead in the spring and summer, and the
                    editor notes it is not only for men in the field but also for those at home. The
                    editor calls on the public to meet the challenge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The American Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nadenbousch</ln>
                        <fn>J. Q. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Colonel J. Q. A. Nadenbousch and Dr. William S. McChesney bought the
                    American Hotel recently, renovated and refurnished it, and hired Joseph N.
                    Woodward as hotel keeper. The owners want to make the hotel one of the best in
                    the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton Artillery.</p>
                    <p>Captain A.W. Garber, of the Staunton Artillery is in town and is desirous of
                        securing fifty recruits for his Battery. It is needless to say anything in
                        behalf of this battery to the people of this vicinity for they too well know
                        its efficiency since its first appearance on the field of first Manassas. It
                        has not lost in many desperately contested engagements the reputation then
                        so nobly won. Bear this Battery in mind in making our selections.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain A. W. Garber of the Staunton Artillery is seeking fifty more
                    recruits. The editor encourages readers to consider the Staunton Artillery first
                    when selecting the service to join. The Staunton Artillery is well-esteemed
                    because of the efficiency of its first appearance at first Manassas and because
                    of its record of victory in other "desperately contested engagements."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>No Compromise with the Rebels</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>No Compromise with the Rebels.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Baldwin of Mass. submitted a resolution in the Yankee Congress, to the
                        effect that any proposition to negotiate with the rebel leaders, for the
                        restoration of loyalty and order in the Confederacy, was simply recognizing
                        those leaders as entitled to represent and bind the loyal people of the
                        United States whom they oppress, and giving countenance to their
                        pretensions, and should be rejected. This was to do away with the effect of
                        a proposition made some time since to confer with the leaders of the
                        rebellion upon what terms peace could be restored and the Union preserved,
                        and was adopted by yeas 89 nays 24, thus showing that it is the intent and
                        purpose of our enemies to subjugate us. Perhaps the Yankee Congress is of
                        the opinion that if they pass the bill of Mr. Howe, of Wisconsin, to raise
                        one million of men for ninety days they can certainly secure the subjugation
                        of the rebels, and hence their utter opposition to ending the war in any
                        other manner. If so, there is quite a difference of opinion on the subject.
                        The New York Times says it would take three months to muster them into
                        service, and three months longer to drill and brigade them and 36,000
                        officers to command them, who can't be found. It speaks very truthfully
                        perhaps of the result in the following:</p>
                    <p>"Considering the state of the South, however, it would seem wise for our
                        crusaders to take at least a million of sheep with them to cook as they went
                        along, and it would be well for every man to drive his own animal.</p>
                    <p>They would be sure to die like cockroaches before they ever got near the
                        enemy. And we need hardly say, that when they did meet him, ten thousand of
                        such troops as Lee or Johnston command would be a match for one hundred
                        thousand of them, and would readily drive that number off the field in utter
                        rout.</p>
                    <p>The sole result of his "grand-uprising" would, therefore, probably be the
                        desolation of some hundred thousand Northern homes, and the leaving down
                        South in the hands of Jefferson Davis' "ragmuffins" one million muskets, one
                        million liats and coats, and pocket-handkerchiefs, several hundred tons of
                        pie and hard tack, and, we were going to add, one million pairs of
                        pantaloons; but, we believe, that our fugitives stick to their pantaloons as
                        well as their pantaloons to them, even in the wildest rout. In a word, no
                        force can carry either food or clothing to the Richmond captives except a
                        highly disciplined, well organized and perfectly manageable one, led by able
                        and experienced officers. The Senate Committee on Military Affairs know
                        this, so they will of course not waste much time over the consideration of
                        Mr. Howe's bill."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This editorial discusses two issues before the United States
                    Congress--negotiations between the Confederacy and the United States and a
                    proposal to raise a large number of additional troops to defeat the Confederacy
                    more quickly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Yankee Brutality</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An example from some time ago of brutality by Northern soldiers involved
                    the body of the son of an influential citizen of Hardy County. Northern soldiers
                    overtook the two-horse wagon transporting his body home, captured the horses,
                    and left the wagon and coffin standing in the road until they consented to leave
                    the worst of the horses to pull the wagon home.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Exhibitions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recent exhibitions of the St. Francis Catholic School were well
                    attended and enthusiastically received.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Central Bank</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf>President</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The stockholders of the Central Bank elected the following directors at
                    their annual meeting: N. K. Trout, President, H. W. Sheffey, B. F. Points, H. G.
                    Guthrie, F. M. Young, H. H. Peck, and William Kerr, Directors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Eulton W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary A. White married Eulton W. Brown at Mt. Sidney on January 6, 1864,
                    with Reverend R. Smith officiating. All are from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Mildred Bumgardner, daughter of James Bumgardner, Sr., married Captain
                    James Bumgardner of the 52nd Regiment of Virginia Volunteers, on December 27,
                    1863, with Reverend McFarland officiating. All are from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news, advertisements, and notices, including several
                for the return of stolen horses.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
