<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.10.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/19/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 7/1/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-10-21">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.10.21.01">
            <pageNote>On this page are advertisements, notices, a poem, articles on prices set
                throughout the Confederacy by the Commissioners of Revenue, and assorted other
                articles.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.10.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Retribution Will Come</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Retribution Will Come.</p>
                    <p>In the recent temporary occupation of the Valley of Virginia the enemy again
                        exhibited that malignant malice which characterized the invasion of Hunter.
                        Then the outcry was against Hunter, as a worse than Butler the Beast, in
                        which, so detestable was his course, that Northern journals joined and
                        reiterated the cry, but condemned no one superior to the commander of the
                        expedition. Then our provisions were taken, a few mills burned, and a few
                        houses plundered, but the order of Grant required Sheridan to burn barns,
                        wheat and hay-stacks, to drive off or kill all live stock and to carry off
                        the negroes--in fact to make the Valley a "barren waste." How well his aid
                        has accomplished the fell design of his superior is already known to many of
                        our readers. All that he could do, after the reception of the order of
                        grant, and in the haste with which he made a retrograde movement on account
                        of the near approach of Early, he did, being far more than Hunter with his
                        licensed crew did in the entire length of the Valley, yet we hear not a word
                        from the North condemnatory of the vile acts of Gen. Grant through his
                        accomplice Sheridan.</p>
                    <p>This war has been declared by the Yankee Administration to have been
                        commenced against those in arms against the Government of the United States.
                        But now Grant, wearied and sick of fighting the veterans of Lee with no
                        avail, has turned his arms against the women and children of our land,
                        hoping, doubtless, that he may gain a glorious victory (!) over them, a
                        result already discovered by him impossible to be attained over the former.</p>
                    <p>The destruction in the Valley effects the inhabitants seriously, especially
                        the poor, but none others, surely not the army here, for it can draw its
                        supplies from other equally plenteous sources and will, regardless of this
                        destruction, be amply supplied. It will not cause the withdrawal of the army
                        of the Valley, nor will it cease on this account to menace the capital of
                        our enemy. Hence the destruction of property here was to reduce to the last
                        extremity the non-combatants of this region as it must have been evident to
                        Barbarian Grant that they alone could be effected by it. These facts will be
                        treasured up by the fathers, husbands, brothers and sons of those who were
                        desired to be placed in a destitute condition by the wholesale destruction
                        of their property and they will some day have retribution. Let not the North
                        then cry out that Southern Barbarians are let loose upon them, but remember
                        that we can point to the campaigns in the Valley of the Shenandoah for
                        precedents for all the acts our soldiery may commit and a full off-set to
                        which will be necessary to make retribution justice.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor compares the recent enemy occupation of the Valley with a
                    previous occupation. Before, the destruction was not as vast and severe, and the
                    public outcry, including in the North, was against Hunter and his tactics. This
                    time, however, the destruction is of far greater consequence, as Sheridan
                    attempted to carry out Grant's order to make the Valley a "barren waste."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Star</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Props</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silling</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fix</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCutcheon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zimmerman</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cole</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helm</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plunket</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Valentine</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vines</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greiner</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Powers</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rease</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fretwell</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killiam</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCord</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karicoffe</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stitzer</ln>
                        <fn>_____</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCord</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Y. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnes</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brien</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riley</ln>
                        <fn>B. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the members of Company L of the 5th Virginia who are prisoners at
                    Fort Delaware, according to Paul Scherer, who was a prisoner there but who has
                    been exchanged and returned home. From Company A: W. Evans, W. Graham, R.
                    Parker, and W. Star; from Company C: J. Beard, D. Bell, _____ Props, J. Silling,
                    S. Walker, and _____ Wilson; from Company D: J. Beard, M. Fix, _____ Fix, D.
                    Hanger, J. Hanger, J. Y. McCutcheon, T. Smiley, _____ Weaver, H. Wright, _____
                    Zimmerman, William Cole, and Sam Helm; from Company E: J. Campbell, G. Fitch, W.
                    Hite, G. Hite, G. Hite, J. Plunket, Samuel Valentine, and J. Vines; from Company
                    F: L. Dunlap, D. Hanger, and J. Trimble; from Company G: D. Greiner, D. Powers,
                    and _____ Rease; from Company H: _____ Fisher, W. Fretwell, S. Killiam, and John
                    McCord; from Company I: _____ Andrews, N. Blakemore, J. Fauber, _____ Karicoffe,
                    and _____ Stitzer; from Company K: B. McCord, and J. McCoy; and from Company L:
                    Y. M. Bickle, J. C. Barnes, J. B. Campbell, M. O'Brien, B. L. Riley, and J.
                    Thompson. Paul Scherer, son of Mr. J. B. Scherer, was captured May 5, 1864, in
                    the battle at Wilderness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>John Baldwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf>Esquire</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Baldwin Arnall, 18, son of J. T. Arnall, Esquire, of Staunton, was
                    wounded in battle on Saturday, October 15, 1864. He died the next day and was
                    returned to the home of his father on Saturday night. His body was interred on
                    Sunday, with military honors, at Thornrose Cemetery. He was a member of Captain
                    McClung's Company of the 1st Va. Cav.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Eighty-three prisoners arrived in Staunton yesterday. They were captured in
                    recent operations in the Valley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>War News.</p>
                    <p>We learn from the Express that the situation on the Petersburg line remains
                        unchanged. The enemy at no point on that line show any disposition at
                        present to make a move. It is the opinion of those best informed on the
                        subject, that Grant is evidently awaiting the result of his operations on
                        the North side of the James before he makes an attack here.</p>
                    <p>On the North Side all has been quiet since the affair of the 20th, and at
                        present there appears no immediate prospect of a fight. It is considered
                        doubtful, whether Grant intends to assault our new lines--at least not until
                        he can bring up his fleet and assault Drury's Bluff at the same time.</p>
                    <p>We learn through the Richmond papers, that the news from Georgia, is indeed
                        very pleasant. Gen. Hood's movement in the rear of Sherman has so far proved
                        successful. An official dispatch, received at the War Department on
                        Wednesday states that Gen. Hood's forces have destroyed the Western and
                        Atlantic Rail Road from Rasaca to Tunnel Hill and a portion of the Cleveland
                        road, capturing Dalton, and all intermediate garrisons, with stores, arms,
                        and equipments, and about one thousand prisoners. On the 15th Hood was at a
                        point not far from Chattanooga; the precise locality not given. Southern
                        papers state that Atlanta is closely invested by our cavalry, our pickets
                        being within one and a half miles of the city. A general engagement between
                        Hood and Sherman has been anticipated, but the impression now prevails that
                        Sherman in due season will be whipped by strategy, without a general
                        engagement.</p>
                    <p>From Gen. Vaughn's official dispatch dated the 12th we learn that he met the
                        enemy on that day, at Greenville, killed and wounded many, captured two
                        stands of colors--many horses, small arms, some prisoners, and still in
                        pursuit.</p>
                    <p>The St. Louis papers owing to the operations of Gen. Price give a gloomy
                        account of affairs in Missouri, stating that they are decidedly worse than
                        they have been at any time since the beginning of the war, and some of them
                        openly advocates the abandonment of Arkansas to save Missouri. Gen. price
                        has received large accessions to his command, numbering in the aggregate
                        15000 Cavalry, and nineteen pieces of artillery. At last accounts he is
                        reported at Booneville, fifty-two miles north of Jefferson City on the
                        Missouri river.</p>
                    <p>From the lower Valley we learn from a gentleman who just received a dispatch
                        from New Market, that Gen. Early on Wednesday morning attacked Sheridan at
                        or near Cedar Creek, and whipped him. No particulars given.</p>
                    <p>The indefategable [sic] and ubiqu[i]tous Col. Mosby has been heard from I the
                        following official dispatch from Genl. Lee.</p>
                    <p>Head Qr's Army Northern Va.</p>
                    <p>October 16th, 1864.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Hon. J.A. Seddon</emph>, Secretary of War:</p>
                    <p>On the 14th instant, Colonel Mosby struck the Baltimore and Ohio railroad at
                        Duffield, destroyed a United States mail train, consisting of a locomotive
                        and ten cars, and secured twenty prisoners and fifteen horses.</p>
                    <p>Among the prisoners are two paymasters with one hundred and sixty eight
                        thousand dollars in Government funds.</p>
                    <p>(Signed) R.E. Lee, Gen'l.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Among the war news summarized by the editor this week is a report from New
                    Market that General Early attacked and beat General Sheridan Wednesday morning
                    at or near Cedar Creek. No other information is available at this time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn>H. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General H. B. Davidson, former Commandant of the Post in Staunton, visited
                    here several days before leaving on Tuesday to report to General Early. His
                    previous military record leads the editor to believe that his new assignment in
                    the field will bring him additional honors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John N. Hendren was nominated for and has accepted the position of
                    Treasurer of the Confederate States. The editor is certain that the appointment
                    will meet with everyone's approval.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Vindicator has discovered why the county's quota of salt
                    and cotton has been delayed. The salt supply is stuck in Lynchburg awaiting
                    transport. The cotton is in Richmond, and its shipment has been delayed by a
                    lack of transportation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Interesting Proceedings at Camp Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The large number of Virginia conscripts who have reported for duty in
                    response to the recent order has overwhelmed the medical examiners and delayed
                    the men from beginning their service. Colonel Shields addressed the men, telling
                    them he would guarantee their placement in Virginia regiments if they would
                    waive their right to an examination and that General Lee was in need of "stout
                    hearted Virginians like them." More than a thousand volunteered to enter the
                    ranks immediately.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Returning to the Front</head>
                <origin>Charlotte Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Times reports that large numbers of convalescent and furloughed
                    soldiers are pouring back into Gen. Lee's ranks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Rockingham Register</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Rockingham Register has ceased publication temporarily because its
                    press was destroyed. The editor of the Vindicator is certain that his
                    contemporary at the Register will resume publication as soon as possible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bare</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Bare, a member of Company L, 5th Virginia Infantry, was wounded in
                    the recent battle at Winchester and died in the General Hospital in Staunton
                    last Wednesday. He was the son of Henry Bare of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, reprinted runaway slave notices, a
                number of estray notices, and a list of persons who have mail being held at the Post
                Office at Staunton as of September 30, 1864.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
