<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.05.13">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/08/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/23/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-05-13">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.05.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Review</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A woman writes a review of having seen General Rosser and General Smith
                    assemble, review, and address their cavalry brigade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Office Recorder of Va. Forces</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Joseph Jackson, Jr., Recorder for the Virginia Forces, writes the people of
                    Virginia to inform them that the state legislature intends to gather the names
                    and accompanying information of all Virginians who have served, are serving, or
                    will serve in the armed forces. This goal is complicated by the fact that no
                    such information has been assembled systematically in the three years of the
                    war. Jackson calls upon the people to form societies devoted to the gathering of
                    such information.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, a poem, war news, and other news
            items.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.05.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Great Battle</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details troop movements, battles, and other skirmishes in Virginia during
                    the first part of May 1864.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Our Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Our Wounded.</p>
                    <p>For for the past few days large numbers of those wounded in the late fights
                        have arrived at Staunton. They were met at the trains by many of the Ladies
                        of this place, who supplied them with various little delicacies prepared for
                        them. Our hospital is full of these gallant unfortunates, who have been
                        wounded in defending our homes and firesides from the ruthless invader, and
                        while we can not heal their wounds by a simple wish, we can ameliorate their
                        condition much by sending many little things not generally needed for family
                        use, which will be thankfully received by them.</p>
                    <p>The attention of the Country people is especially directed to this patriotic
                        and humane duty. Send to the wounded anything you can spare and send at
                        once.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A large number of soldiers wounded in recent battles are in the hospital at
                    Staunton and have been well supplied by the women of the area with "little
                    delicacies prepared for them." The editor calls on readers to do what they can
                    to ameliorate the soldiers' conditions and especially asks persons living in
                    rural areas to do their "patriotic and humane duty."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor alerts the readers to the article from the Recorder for the
                    Virginia forces and calls on them to help in his task by forming community
                    organizations to gather and report the desired information.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From the Lower Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>General</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>General Imboden recently engaged the enemy at Lost River in Hardy County,
                    was victorious, and took some prisoners and wagons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A list of casualties from Augusta County is unavailable at press time but
                    will be published next week if available.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>$50 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>$50 Reward.</p>
                    <p>Ran away from Esteline Furnace Augusta County, Va., on Monday night the 23rd
                        of April 1864</p>
                    <p>Isaac.</p>
                    <p>who was hired of M.F. Gooch, Sheriff of Louis Co. Va., he belongs to Richard
                        Cotton. Said boy is about 5 feet 5 inches high, about 25 years of age very
                        black, he is a quick active boy, and talks very fast.</p>
                    <p>The above reward will be given if arrested and confined so that we get him
                        again.</p>
                    <p>Burke &amp; Kunkle.</p>
                    <p>May 13 3t. Spec. copy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cottom</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac, a slave, ran away from Esteline Furnace in Augusta County on Monday
                    night, April 23, 1864. He is about five feet five inches tall, about 25 years
                    old, is very black, is "a quick active boy," and talks very fast. He was hired
                    by M. F. Gooch, Sheriff of Louisa County and belongs to Richard Cottom. The firm
                    of Burke and Junkle offers a reward of $50 for his return.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>The bottom left corner of this page is missing. Also on this page are other
                advertisements and political announcements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
