<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.09.02">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/17/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-09-02">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.09.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The "Impending Crisis" at the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We present below a few specimens of those turbulent manifestations
                    which have lately filled the Northern press, and are designed to have their
                    effect upon the issue of the impending conflict between the Democracy and the
                    Black Republicans. . . ."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This series of excerpts from the Philadelphia Age, the Portland (Maine)
                    Advertiser, the Clairmont Ohio Sun, the Buffalo Courier, and the New York World
                    reflect sentiment among some Northerners against President Lincoln and the
                    course of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Absentees from Gen. Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Absentees from Gen. Lee's Army.</p>
                    <p>Below we append a general order recently issued by Gen. Lee. It reads like
                        the gentle admonitions of a loud father to his erring children. And well may
                        Gen. Lee thus appeal to his soldiers, for he has been to them like a father,
                        and it is their correlative duty to yield him that obedience due from
                        children to a kind and indulgent parent. This appeal is as follows:</p>
                    <p>Hdq'rs Army of Northern Virginia,</p>
                    <p>Aug. 10, 1864--6 P.M.</p>
                    <p>General Orders, No. 54.</p>
                    <p>All persons connected with this army who are absent without proper authority
                        are enjoined to return to their respective commands without delay.</p>
                    <p>This order is intended to embrace those who have remained absent beyond the
                        time limited for their return, or after the cause of their absence has
                        ceased. All such persons are admonished that every day they remain away from
                        their posts, adds to the dangers and labors of their comrades, while it
                        increases their own responsibility to the laws they are violating.</p>
                    <p>The commanding General deems it only necessary to remind those who have erred
                        throughtlessness [sic] or negligence, of the shame and disgrace they will
                        bring upon themselves and their families if they shrink from the manful
                        discharge of duty in the hour of their country's need, and leave their homes
                        to be defended, and their independence to be secured by the unaided courage
                        of others.</p>
                    <p>"To those whose absence has been prolonged until they have incurred the guilt
                        of desertion, he can only say that a prompt and voluntary return to duty
                        alone can palliate their offence, and entitle them to expect any clemency.</p>
                    <p>If arrested and brought back, justice to the faithful and true, as well as
                        the interests and safety of the country, require that they shall suffer the
                        extreme penalty of the law.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This reprint of the text of General Lee's General Order Number 54 calling
                    for the return of absentees reveals, in the opinion of the editor, the
                    paternalistic relationship between the commander and his men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>From the North</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Among the news items from the North is one reporting rumors that a
                    commission of three Republicans and two Democrats from the United States are on
                    their way to Richmond to make arrangements for a peace settlement.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements and other articles on the war.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.09.02.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Chicago Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Chicago Convention.</p>
                    <p>Just now the all-absorbing centre of interest to the people of the United
                        States is at Chicago. From the sentiments of that people, as emitted by
                        their press, we conclude that the action of the convention, now sitting at
                        Chicago, is looked forward to by the great mass in the North, Republicans as
                        well as those arrayed in the opposition, as being of momentous consequence
                        to them.</p>
                    <p>In the action of that convention is embraced the assertion of the rights of
                        the States as sovereignties, and the nomination of a peace candidate on the
                        platform of State Sovereignty, or the ignoring of that doctrine entirely,
                        and the nomination of a war Democrat. However, with the mass of the
                        opposition in favor of peace, and the number of Republicans who also
                        entertain that sentiment, it is scarcely reasonable to presume that they
                        will not select as their candidate an out and out peace man.</p>
                    <p>It may not be well to calculate on such action, for the notes of warning of
                        the New York Herald, in anticipation of conflict and bloodshed at Chicago
                        this week, and the probable necessity for the city authorities to call on
                        United States forces to preserve the peace, together with the fact that one
                        Illinois regiment has passed Cairo on its way home (as it is said) from
                        Memphis, may not be ill-timed, and the conflict may have culminated, and
                        forces may have been asked for in anticipation of difficulties, but to be
                        used to influence the action of the convention. The arbitrary power of the
                        sword has been so long used with impunity by the Northern administration in
                        controlling elections, and thereby strengthening its power, that it is hard
                        indeed to do away with it. Besides, many members of that convention are
                        already under the ban of the Administration's displeasure, and may be
                        arrested ere they take their seats.</p>
                    <p>If the convention be harmonious in the choice of a peace candidate, or their
                        convening be disturbed by the arrest of its members, or otherwise, we may
                        hope, ultimately, for a favorable result to us, but if unharmonious and both
                        a peace and war candidate, or two peace candidates, be put in nomination by
                        its factions, then may we look for the continuance of this desolating war.
                        In the latter case let us not be despondent, but remember that the most
                        disastrous campaign to our enemies is that of 1864, in which they have made
                        greater preparations, and shown more energy and determination to subdue us
                        than in any before. We are now better prepared to prevent the accomplishment
                        of the enemy's designs that heretofore, but if the action of the Chicago
                        convention should bring about a peace, on the principles so long contended
                        for by us, which are acknowledged by the impassive world to be just, without
                        the further bloodshed of our gallant countrymen, it would be a consummation
                        most devoutly to be wished. A few days longer, and we shall know what the
                        sentiment for peace in the United States means--let us bide the time in
                        patience.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor comments on the Democratic Convention being held in Chicago and
                    notes that the extent of Northern sentiment for peace and for states' rights
                    will be evident in the outcome of the meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>War News.</p>
                    <p>Nothing of interest has transpired in front of Petersburg, since the battle
                        at or near Reams Station. The enemy still continue to shell the city,
                        without doing serious damage. The Yankees still occupy the Weldon road in
                        considerable force, and both armies are in close proximity to each other,
                        ready to obey the commands of their respective leaders; who are no doubt
                        busily engaged in arranging their plans for future action.</p>
                    <p>The result of the recent fight on the Weldon road is to us very significant,
                        apart from the loss inflicted upon the enemy. The further injury of the road
                        is completely checked, and a force is thrown in Grant's rear, to co-operate
                        in any movement which may be made upon the front. We thus occupy positions
                        in his front and rear, which renders it almost impossible for him to operate
                        to any extent, or even hold his position for any length of time.</p>
                    <p>We still hold the captured works, which are said to be strong, and if the
                        enemy attempt to dislodge our troops, it will only result in loss to Grant,
                        by killing and capturing a few more thousand of his men.</p>
                    <p>The month of August just closed, ends the summer campaign of 1864, and
                        Richmond, the grand object of the entire Yankee notion, still stands
                        confident of her safety, with the unconquerable army of Gen. Lee between her
                        and the hated for.</p>
                    <p>The following official dispatch of Gen. Hood to the War Department gives the
                        latest intelligence from Atlanta:</p>
                    <p>"Atlanta, Aug. 28, 1864.</p>
                    <p>"Hon. James A. Sedden:</p>
                    <p>"The enemy have changed their entire position--the left of their line resting
                        near the Chattahoochee, about Sandtown, and their right extending to a point
                        opposite and near the West Point railroad, between East Point and Fairburn.
                        They had all the crossings on the Chattahoochee, but not with a continued
                        line.</p>
                    <p>"Dispatches from Gen. Wheeler, of the 19th, report the capture of Dalton,
                        with large quantities of stores, about two hundred prisoners, and two
                        hundred miles.</p>
                    <p>"He destroyed three trains of cars and twenty-five miles of railroad. His
                        command is in good condition.</p>
                    <p>J.B. Hood, General."</p>
                    <p>By stage passengers direct from the lower Valley, we learn that General Early
                        encountered the Yankees on Friday last near Charlestown, and after a
                        spirited contest, drove them back some distance.</p>
                    <p>That portion of Gen. Early's army encamped at Bunker Hill for the past few
                        days, is again advancing in the direction of Martinsburg, and ere long
                        stirring news may be expected from that quarter.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides the latest information from the Petersburg battlefield.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Colonel W. L. Jackson accidentally shot himself in the thigh when returning
                    his pistol to its holster after driving the enemy out of Shepherdstown. Jackson
                    arrived in Staunton yesterday and is not seriously wounded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Stickley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hacket</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmonson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Colonel</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stickley Wright of Colonel Edmonson's cavalry shot James Hacket of Davis's
                    Battalion a week ago last Sunday. Hacket's left arm was amputated, and Wright is
                    in jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Reverend</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Hester V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hester V. Coffman of Augusta County married William H. Tolley of Tennessee
                    on August 23, 1864, near New Hope, with Reverend R. Smith officiating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Isaac S. Maupin, Orderly Sergeant of Company A, 52nd Virginia Infantry, was
                    killed in action near Winchester on July 20, 1864, at the age of 21. He was the
                    first volunteer in the first new infantry company raised in Augusta County after
                    the war began. This obituary praises Maupin's example as a son and soldier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hague</ln>
                        <fn>Harman A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Orderly Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Among the members of Company L, 5th Virginia Infantry, killed recently were
                    Harman A. Hague of Staunton, killed in the battle at Wilderness on May 5, 1864;
                    P. Baskin of Augusta, killed in the engagement with Hunter; and Thomas Bryan of
                    Staunton, killed at Monocacy, Maryland. This obituary eulogizes the "gallant
                    dead" and their heroism. Also killed, from the same company was Orderly Sergeant
                    James M. Doom, son of Madison Doom of Staunton and younger brother of John Doom,
                    who was killed at Port Republic. Doom was killed in the first battle of the
                    Wilderness on May 5, 1864. He was buried on the spot where he died, but was
                    reinterred at the cemetery in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are war news, advertisements, and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
