<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1864/va.au.rv.1864.08.12">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Chancey</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/19/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>1st Pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 6/30/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1864-08-12">
            <year>1864</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1864.08.12.01">
            <div type="c">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>Agnes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The next session of the Augusta Female Seminary will open the middle of
                    August and will close the middle of June. Miss M. J. Baldwin is Principal, and
                    Miss Agnes McClung is manager of the boarding department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>What the War Has Cost--Appalling Loss of Life</head>
                <origin>New York Daily News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Daily News reports that the three-year war has involved
                    1,775,000 Northern soldiers, with 500,000 in the field currently, and with about
                    375,000 discharged because of wounds, sickness, or disability or deserted,
                    leaving about 900,000 dead and buried. By comparison, Northern soldiers have
                    freed about 100,000 slaves, many of whom are worse off now than when they were
                    with their masters. The projected war debt already stands at four billion
                    dollars. The article concludes that the costs far outweigh the gains of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Singular Battle Field Incident</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Petersburg Register tells of a slave who had run away from Alabama, was
                    fighting for a Northern regiment, and recognized his former master in battle.
                    The former slave threw down his musket, ran up to his former master, threw his
                    arms around his master's neck, and ended up shielding a shot intended for the
                    Confederate soldier. The soldier and slave were carried off the field, and the
                    slave's wound was attended to. Many other former slaves were killed in battle
                    that day, July 30, 1864, but this particular former slave was safe because of
                    his decision to protect his former master.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are advertisements, an article entitled "A Highly
                Interesting French Chemical Process," an article entitled "Lying and Its Effects,"
                an article entitled "Eating Economically," an article entitled "The Conspiracy for
                the Formation of a Northwestern Confederacy," and other articles on the
            war.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1864.08.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Just retaliation, though long delayed, has commenced at last, and will
                    continue to be practiced until the corrupt dynasty, which rules at Washington,
                    shall direct its minions in the field to cease their Vandalism, and return to
                    that mode of warfare practiced by all civilized nations."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>War News.</p>
                    <p>Since the little affair of Friday last, in which Gen'l Beauregard tried his
                        hand in springing a mine, the situation in front of Petersburg remains
                        unchanged. The "Express" states that the object of the explosion of our mine
                        on Friday was to blow up a sap which the enemy was running towards an
                        important position on our centre. This was effectually done, as it is known
                        that the enemy's gallery ran very close tot he point at which the mine was
                        sprung. The result will, it is believed, completely check further mining
                        operations on the part of the Yankees at this point, and render them
                        exceedingly cautious elsewhere. The loss of the Yankees was, no doubt, small
                        as the mine did not extend quite to their breastworks. The explosion had
                        however the effect of causing a panic among the enemy, and at the same time
                        gave them to distinctly understand that this interesting game of mining is
                        one in which two cam play, the decision of which, is not always in favor of
                        the one who institutes the game. It is also reported that Grant is sending
                        away his troops, and that he is removing his heavy guns from the front,
                        which indicates an evacuation of his present position. If the sequel should
                        prove this report to be correct, there will be no more fighting of any
                        magnitude around Petersburg. The next grand battle between Lee and Grant may
                        probably be fought on northern soil.</p>
                    <p>From the army in front of Atlanta Gen. Hood reports the repulse of two
                        assaults on different portions of his lines on Saturday with some loss to
                        the enemy. Since then nothing additional has been received from that point,
                        but we are nevertheless satisfied that all is well in front of the Gate
                        city, and when the battle is joined no tears need be entertained as to the
                        result.</p>
                    <p>From the lower Valley we learn, through the Northern papers--that a portion
                        of Gen. Early's command occupied Hagerstown on the 4th, another portion
                        estimated at 7000 strong were in the neighborhood of Harpers Ferry, whilst
                        Gen. Early with the remainder of his command, was at Bunker Hill guarding
                        the trains of plunder and grain moving up the Valley. The Harrisburg papers,
                        in commenting upon the situation, say that the force of Gen. Early is now
                        very large, having been recently largely reinforced, and predicts that an
                        incursion into either Maryland or Pennsylvania will be successful. What
                        position Gen. Early at present really occupies, we are not informed, but
                        feel assured that he is not inactive, but in due time will turn up at the
                        right place.</p>
                    <p>A report has reached here, within the past day or two stating that Bradley
                        Johnson's forces, attached to McCausland's command, were surprised, having 4
                        pieces of artillery, and 300 men and horses. We trust when we receive a
                        correct account, it will not be so bad as at first represented.</p>
                    <p>The burning of Chambersburg by McCausland meets with the universal approval
                        of the Confederate press. Just retaliation, though long delayed, has
                        commenced at last, and will continue to be practiced until the corrupt
                        dynasty, which rules at Washington, shall direct its minions in the field to
                        cease their Vandalism, and return so that mode of warfare practiced by all
                        civilized nations.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor summaries developments in the war in the past week,
                    concentrating on Petersburg, the lower Valley, and the burning of Chambersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Escape of a Supposed Murderer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harney</ln>
                        <fn>Willoughby</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Several months ago a man named McQuain, traveling from Pendleton County to
                    Harrisonburg to invest his money in Confederate bonds, was murdered. The
                    suspects, named Lake and Harney, were arrested. While being conveyed to
                    Pendleton, Willoughby Harney escaped from the guards at Lebanon White Sulpher
                    Springs in Augusta County on August 1. He has not been captured. The other
                    suspect, Lake, appeared before court in Pendleton County and is now in jail in
                    Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Reserves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCune</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Reserves of the Valley District assembled on August 9 and organized
                    into five battalions. Each battalion elected its commanding officers. The First
                    Battalion, composed of men from Warren, Page, and Shenandoah Counties, organized
                    into four companies and elected William A. J. Miller of Page County as its
                    commanding officer. The Second Battalion, composed of men from Rockingham
                    County, organized into four companies and elected Ar. Taylor of Rockingham as
                    its commanding officer. The Third Battalion, composed of men from Augusta
                    County, organized into four companies and elected Samuel McCune of Augusta
                    County as its commanding officer. The Fourth Battalion, composed of men from
                    Rockbridge, Bath, Highland, and Alleghany counties, organized into five
                    companies and elected James J. White of Rockbridge as its commanding officer.
                    The Fifth Battalion, composed of Reserves (Boys) from Rockbridge, Rockingham,
                    and Augusta counties, organized into four companies and elected George Crisman
                    of Rockingham as its commanding officer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Some Tomatoes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. W. H. Peyton presented the editor with a gift of thirty-one tomatoes,
                    all large and ripe, growing on the same stem in a cluster, looking from a
                    distance like a single tomato, and weighing ten pounds. The editor encourages
                    other friends to treat him so kindly and to share their curiosities with him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor alerts readers to the advertisement in another column from the
                    committee appointed by the town of Staunton to purchase wheat. The committee
                    proposes to pay for the wheat with bonds of the Corporation of Staunton, and the
                    editor claims these bonds are good investments since the town is not in debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Great Inconvenience</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor states that the conflict between the Postmaster General and the
                    President of the Virginia Central Railroad has caused everyone a great
                    inconvenience because it has stopped delivery of the mail. Wherever the fault
                    may lie, the editor protests the situation, asserts that the people of the area
                    are the ones suffering, and calls for the delivery of mail to be resumed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenten</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hill</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An Executive Committee composed of Thomas J. Michie, Kenten Harper, H. M.
                    Hill, and N. K. Trout announces that an assistant surgeon in the room of Dr.
                    Davis at the Central Lunatic Asylum will be elected on the first Saturday in
                    September. Interested candidates should submit applications before August 25.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Staunton Gas Company</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waterhouse</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowes</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph A. Waddell, President, of the Board of the Staunton Gas Company,
                    announces a meeting of stockholders to be held at the store of Garber and Price
                    on Monday evening, August 22, 1864, at 7 o'clock to make arrangements for the
                    management of the works since the lease of Waterhouse and Bowes has expired.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also on this page are additional articles on the war, advertisements, and
                notices, including one listing approximately 175 people who have undelivered mail at
                the Staunton Post Office.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
