<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.12.11">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-12-11">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.12.11.01">
            <pageNote>Entire page consists of printed text of Buchanan's State of the Union
            Address.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.12.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>President's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator gives a brief comment on the President's address, writing that it
                    was "able" and "patriotic," but wishing that Buchanan had taken a stronger
                    position against secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Vote of Virginia for Bell and Everett</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginia cast its electoral votes for Bell and Everett.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Nothing to Regret</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Though the country is enveloped in gloom and darkness, and the minds of the
                        people oppressed with anxiety and dread, those who supported the Union
                        ticket have done nothing for which they can reproach themselves. They did
                        all they could to avert the dangers which at this time threaten the
                        Government with destruction. If they had succeeded in the election of their
                        ticket the country would now be at perfect peace with a bright and hopeful
                        prospect for continued happiness and prosperity. They predicted the evils
                        which would ensue in the event of their defeat, but the people turned a deaf
                        ear to their entreaties and expostulations. They are now, though in a great
                        minority, doing all they can to save the country. The train which contains
                        all the vast interests of this great country is now on a descending grade,
                        driven with an excess of steam, and it is time the conservative "brakes"
                        were put down with vigorous force, else there will soon be a general smash
                        up.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial arguing that those who supported and voted for the Union ticket
                    have nothing to be ashamed of, and that a conservative force is needed now more
                    than ever to save the country.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssdec60.html#12.11a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>They Know Not What to Do</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The members of Congress, like the people generally, seem to be at a perfect
                        loss to know what to do in the present perilous condition of the country.
                        They are like persons groping their way in a dark cave where not a ray of
                        light penetrates, and where there is constant danger that a misstep may
                        precipitate them over a fearful precipice. All is gloom, darkness, danger
                        and dread. They feel that it will not do to stand still, and yet they know
                        not in what direction to move, for fearful dangers environ them on every
                        side. The people look to Congress to lead the way out of this labyrinth of
                        dangers, but it seems that that body does not possess an Ariadne who can
                        furnish the clue by which that object can be attained.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial claiming that the people are looking to Congress to lead the
                    nation out of the peril in which the Union now stands, but it seems that there
                    is no one in that body who has any idea how to find a solution.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssdec60.html#12.11b</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glass</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ransbottom</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Glass married Eliza Jane Ransbottom on December 6 near Middlebrook.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirey</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoss</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchens</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Washington Hoss married Mary Hutchens on December 4 at the Staunton Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"S"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Gustavus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Estill</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Gustavus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crockett</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Obituary for three children of the Crockett family, all of whom died of
                    diphtheria.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J.W.P.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mary Ann Ryan died in Port Republic on November 22 at age 44.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>First two columns are conclusion of Buchanan's message, continued from
                previous page. Columns 4-6 consist of an exchange of letters between an unidentified
                Augusta County man and John Minor Botts. The Augusta man seeks advice about
                secession, and Botts rejects the secessionist impulse.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.12.11.03">
            <pageNote>Proceedings of Congress, column 1. Remainder of page is advertisements,
                auctions and sales, etc. Bottom right is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.12.11.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements; bottom left is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
