<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.07.17">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-07-17">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.17.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Oakland Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"A Spectator"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pringle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author gives a report of proceedings at an exhibition and picnic at Oakland
                    Seminary at the Old Providence Church in honor of the seminary's first
                    anniversary. The morning exercises were conducted by Miss Pringle, the school
                    tutoress in the presence of Rev. Dr. Thompson and Rev. William Pinkerton, among
                    others. Robert L. Doyle, Esq., delivered an oration and Rev. Dr. Thompson
                    delivered a few remarks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 5 has a story titled "The Origin of 'Hail Columbia'" purporting to tell
                the story of the origin of the national song. Most of page is taken up by morality
                tales, literature, poetry, and agricultural tips.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Duty of Democrats to Support the Union Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Democrats "will see before that time [election day] arrives that the Bell
                    and Everett ticket is the only one which avoids the Scylla of
                    Squatter-Sovereignty on one side, and the Charybdis of disunion on the other.
                    They will be convinced that safety resides in the middle way between the
                    dangerous extremes."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If there be truth in the positive asseverations of leading Democratic
                        politicians, and their most influential presses, and patriotism in the
                        masses of that party, the vote of this State will certainly be cast for Bell
                        and Everett, it matters not what determination they may arrive at in
                        reference to the Democratic electoral ticket. A portion of the Democratic
                        politicians and presses of this State affirm with earnestness that to
                        support electors favorable to the election of Douglas, would be treason to
                        the rights and institutions of the South, destructive to the Constitution
                        and subversive of State equality. Whilst, on the other hand, nearly an equal
                        number as earnestly and positively maintain that to support electors
                        favorable to the Breckenridge or Secession ticket, would be treason to the
                        Union, as that ticket is the representative of a <emph rend="italic"
                            >disunion</emph> party, organized for the purpose of effecting a
                        dissolution of the Union. Democrats cannot vote for Douglas; for by doing so
                        (if the authority of Democrats be of any value) they would be traitors to
                        the rights of the South, enemies of State equality and heedless violators of
                        the Constitution. They cannot vote for Breckenridge for good Democrats would
                        affirm that, by doing so, they would be voting for a <emph rend="italic"
                            >disunion</emph> ticket, which was nominated for the purpose of
                        involving the North and the South in a sectional contest, which would lead
                        directly and inevitably to disunion and civil war. They cannot vote for
                        Lincoln, for both wings of their party unite in determined opposition to
                            <emph rend="italic"> that Northern sectional</emph> party of which he is
                        the nominee. There is then but <emph rend="italic">one</emph> ticket for
                        which they can vote, and by their votes remain true to the Union, the
                        Constitution, the South and the equal rights of <emph rend="italic"
                        >all</emph> the States, and that is the <emph rend="italic">Constitutional ,
                            National, Union</emph> ticket--Bell and Everett.-- Those Democrats who
                        object to the <emph rend="italic">disunion</emph> Breckenridge ticket should
                        vote for Bell, the nominee of a party organized chiefly for the purpose of
                        preserving the "Union one and in separable, now and forever." He represents
                        a party whose chief object is the antipode of that which they ascribe to the
                        secession ticket--the <emph rend="italic">preservation</emph> of the Union
                        being the object of the one and its destruction that of the other. If then
                        they are really the friends of the Union, they should cast their votes for
                        the Union ticket. Those Democrats who oppose the election of Douglas,
                        because he occupies a position hostile to the institutions of the South,
                        should vote for Bell, who is a firm and true a friend of the "peculiar
                        institution" of the South as any man who was ever born upon its soil or
                        breathed its atmosphere. He believes that it has the sacred sanction of the
                        Bible--that it is religiously, morally, socially, and politically
                        right--that it is the fountain from which springs the vast stream of our
                        national wealth and prosperity--that it is the Midas which converts all it
                        touches to gold. </p>
                    <p>As it is the duty of both wings of the Democracy to support Bell and Everett,
                        (as has been shown by their own statements) if they possess sufficient
                        patriotism to perform the duty incumbent upon them, it is pretty evident
                        that the vote of this state will be cast for the <emph rend="italic"
                        >only</emph> national, constitutional, Union ticket. We believe the masses
                        of the Democracy to be honest, patriotic, Union-loving men, and that they
                        will vote accordingly on the day of the election. They will see before that
                        time arrives that the Bell and Everett ticket is the only one that avoids
                        the Scylla of Squatter-Sovereignty on one side and the Charybdis of disunion
                        on the other. They will be convinced that safety resides in the middle way
                        between the dangerous extremes. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator argues that Democratic voters who are truly for the South and the
                    Union have a duty to vote for Constitutional Union candidates. Voting for
                    Douglas is treason to the South, and voting for Breckinridge is treason to the
                    Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly60.html#7.17a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Arrest of Horse Thief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Elijah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of the arrest of Elijah Hunter for stealing horses from John
                    Churchman. Spectator reports that they and most of the town are surprised, as
                    Hunter had a reputation as an honest man in the county.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Organize and Rally--Victory in View</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator calls on all citizens in Augusta County to rally and organize
                    behind the Constitutional Union party.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of a buggy accident involving William Howell of Spring Hill, who was
                    injured but not critically.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Prospect in Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> Never before in the history of the Old Commonwealth, says the <emph
                            rend="italic">Baltimore American,</emph> was there so glorious a chance
                        for the Opposition to redeem Virginia from the iron thraldom of Democracy.
                        Fettered, bound down, prostrated, the Whigs of the Mother of States and
                        Statesmen have for many decades presented to the world the attitude
                        precisely of the Tyrant in the State's coat of arms. But the facts reverse
                        the picture. It is not Liberty trampling Tyranny under foot, but Party
                        rioting in irresponsible power over the outstretched form of Conservatism,
                        for surely there was never in any State so courageous, so steadfast,
                        long-suffering and invincible a band of patriots, true to every just
                        sentiment of nationality and to every portion of the Union as the Whigs of
                        Virginia, nor was there ever in any part of the enlightened world a party
                        more unrelenting in the exercise of power than the Democratic party of the
                        same State. The story of the wrongs endured on the one hand and the high
                        handed outrages inflicted on the other, is not unfamiliar to our readers.
                        For years and years seventy thousand gentlemen, comprising the pith and
                        flower of the Virginia population, have been virtually disfranchised.--Men
                        of wealth, of learning, of influence, of the first order of ability in all
                        things pertaining to public affairs, they have nevertheless had no more lot
                        or part in the State government than if they had lived in China or
                        Timbuctoo. They were not permitted to hold the lowest office within the gift
                        of the Executive. They were ousted from the Boards of the Colleges, the
                        University, the Banks, and even the Railroads.--Party lines were drawn where
                        they ought never to have existed, and political tests were made where
                        politics ought to have been rigidly excluded. </p>
                    <p>To be a Whig was to be incompetent for any public position however
                        insignificant. To be a Whig in Virginia was to be no citizen. To be a Whig
                        was for the young man to cut himself off from all chance of a career. To be
                        a Whig was, save in the barren exercise of a franchise rendered purposely
                        null and void, to be an alien. The Congressional districts were so altered
                        as to make it next to impossible to return a Whig to the National
                        Legislature. The same tyrannical system was resorted to in the formation of
                        new counties, and all the old counties would have been re-arranged if the
                        Democracy had dared to attempt a thing so monstrous. Wherever the Democratic
                        party could obtain control they obtained it without regard to consequences,
                        and without a thought as to the baneful effects of thrusting politics where
                        politics in no manner belonged. In a State claiming to hold above all others
                        sound views of government, in a State boasting to be the special guardian of
                        State Rights, in a State blatant about constitutional limitations, a tyranny
                        was practiced in exact accordance with the theory of Divine Right, Unlimited
                        Monarchy, and without a parallel in the annals of the Republic. To the
                        credit of the Old Dominion be it said, that one bright spot appears in all
                        the long and dark expanse of partizan [sic] misrule--the Judiciary, made
                        elective, was, nevertheless, high, pure and undefiled from the pollution of
                        the party.</p>
                    <p>The time has now come when the oppressed may throw off the shackles and once
                        more stand free. The sufferings of years may now be avenged. The State may
                        be redeemed. The redemption of the State may be the salvation of the Union.
                        A glorious hour is at hand for the Whigs of Virginia. A noble work, a great
                        work, a task worthy so unselfish, so unconquerable, so patriotic a band, is
                        to be done. The State divided against itself by the fends of Wise and Hunter
                        was nearly won a year ago. But the feud between the friends of Douglas and
                        of Breckenridge is a more serious, indeed a fatal thing. The Valley goes
                        almost <emph rend="italic">en masse</emph> for Douglas, the Tide- water
                        region declares for Breckenridge. Yet this does not tell the tale entirely.
                        Douglas has hosts of friends in the Cis-Allegheny country. He is known to be
                        the stronger man. Papers have hoisted the Breckenridge flag that make no
                        secret for their preference for his opponent. Papers remain silent which
                        intended ere long to come out for Douglas. The Central Executive Committee
                        of the Democratic party has been called together. The sigh is ominous.
                        Douglas emissaries are pouring into the State, and are enthusiastic. The
                        friends of Breckenridge are slow and unwilling in their work. Douglas wants
                        the State to go for the Union party.--Money will not be spared. Intrigues
                        are thickening daily. The wires that once worked so smoothly and effectively
                        are all crossed, tangled, intertwisted. The wire workers are out-of-sorts,
                        at logger-heads, undecided, stunned, paralyzed. The rank and file of the
                        party are in like hapless condition. The fissure widens hourly--the breach
                        yawns welcome to the Whigs. On, on gallant gentlemen, the citadel is
                    yours!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator argues that the Constitutional Unionists can seize control of
                    Virginia, which is ripe for the picking. The Democrats should be overthrown.
                    Former Whigs who have been locked out of office for so long by the Democrats in
                    power will emerge victorious. Urges people to rally behind the Constitutional
                    Unionists.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjuly60.html#7.17b</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Successful Invention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The car-coupling invention of L. and W.H.H. Waddell, owned by Mr. Imboden,
                    has been put into use on the Central Railroad and has been found to work
                    successfully. It will be placed into use on other roads soon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>"The Pacificator" Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article and letter from Secretary of War John Floyd to Messrs. Sibert and
                    McCue indicating the favorable impression for their new gun, the "Virginia
                    Pacificator," received in Washington.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>State Democratic Convention</head>
                <origin>Staunton Vindicator</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article from the Staunton Vindicator indicating that the Douglas Democrats
                    of Virginia will never attend the State Democratic convention planned for
                    Charlottesville, which will support the Breckinridge ticket. The Douglas
                    Democrats will meet in Staunton instead. Article is followed by a letter from
                    John Harman to Douglas Democrats calling them to meet in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Public Festival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W.W. King, President, J.D. Hanger, Sec'y</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Public invitation to citizens to attend a public picnic at Brown's Spring
                    near Fishersville. Submitted by W.W. King and J.D. Hanger, President and
                    Secretary, respectively, of the committee created to arrange the picnic.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of an upcoming solar eclipse, column 1. Short political articles
                scattered on the page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.17.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements, land sales, etc.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.07.17.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
