<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.05.29">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-05-29">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>29</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>First three images are mislabeled as 05.28.1860. Actual date is
        05.29.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.05.29.01">
            <pageNote>Speech from Mr. Hilliard of Massachusetts delivered at the Baltimore
                convention, column 6; short biographical portraits of John Bell and Edward Everett,
                column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.05.29.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The undersigned have sold their interest in the Staunton Spectator to their
                        late partner in the proprietorship, Richard Mauzy, Esq., who introduces
                        himself below to those of our readers who are not already acquainted with
                        him. In surrendering the control of the journal, it is a satisfaction to
                        know that it falls into the hands of a gentleman so competent to conduct it
                        with ability, and whose political sentiments accord so entirely with our
                        own. With an intimate knowledge of his character, talents and attainments,
                        we can most conscientiously, as we do most cordially, commend the Spectator
                        to the continued patronage of the public.</p>
                    <p>In retiring from the position which we have held for nearly twelve years, as
                        the editors of the "Staunton Spectator," we confess to a feeling of sadness
                        such as those feel who are about to part, perhaps finally, from friends
                        endeared to the heart by long and intimate association. We have been cheered
                        and sustained in the arduous and sometimes disagreeable duties of an
                        important and responsible profession by the kind and encouraging words of
                        many generous friends, and are indebted to the party whose principles we
                        have steadily advocated, for a liberal and substantial patronage. To all
                        with whom we have held weekly communings, we are under obligations for an
                        unmerited appreciation of our labors in their behalf, and we would return
                        them our sincere thanks.</p>
                    <p>To paraphrase slightly the language of a favorite ballad, we may say--</p>
                    <p> "Many the changes, since <emph rend="italic">first</emph> we met." </p>
                    <p>In the political world, which has been our peculiar element, parties have
                        sprung into existence, run their careers and passed away. It has been our
                        lot to feel but little of the genial sunshine of success, but animated by
                        the consciousness of higher motives than mere party triumphs, we have
                        endeavored to steer steadily where "right and duty pointed the way"--even in
                        the midst of disaster and defeat. During our administration we have
                        witnessed the dismemberment and decay of the glorious old Whig party, and
                        the sudden extinguishment of its apparently vigorous successor, the American
                        organization, and have remained on the watchtowers long enough to see the
                        great Babylon of Democracy, against which we have unfalteringly battled,
                        tottering to its fall. On the other hand, we have seen the great Northern
                        power of Black Republicanism, so threatening to the perpetuity of our
                        institutions, grow into gigantic proportions; and participated in the last
                        glorious effort of the true patriots of the land to build up a party on the
                        broad platform of the Constitution for the salvation of the Union and the
                        enforcement of the laws. Our heart's desire is, that this great and
                        patriotic movement may be crowned with success, and although not among the
                        leaders in the contest, we shall perform duty faithfully and cheerfully as
                        private soldiers in the ranks.</p>
                    <p>Many changes have taken place in the town of Staunton since we assumed the
                        management of the Spectator. The population has increased largely, and is
                        almost entirely changed. Most of those who were known as the old and
                        substantial citizens of the place twelve years ago, have passed from the
                        threatre of action, and their places are supplied by others--many of them
                        not "natives to the manor born." Staunton has become changed from a town to
                        a city--and now rejoices in a Railroad, Telegraph, Gas, and many other
                        wonderful things to which she was a stranger then. And now another change
                        has passed upon the venerable journal of the county, whose reputation we
                        confidently commit to the keeping of its new editor and proprietor, and
                        whose fortunes we commend to the fostering care of its numerous patrons.</p>
                    <p>To our contemporaries of the press with whom we have maintained a long and
                        agreeable intercourse, and to whom we are indebted for many flattering and
                        encouraging words, we can only say "farewell"--a word that conveys our best
                        wishes for their personal prosperity and professional success. We shall
                        often refer to their pages with interest, and renew with satisfaction the
                        pleasant acquaintance of "auld lang syne."</p>
                    <p>JOS. A. WADDELL,</p>
                    <p>L. WADDELL, Jr.</p>
                    <p>Salutatory.</p>
                    <p>As will be seen by reference to the "Valedictory" of my former partners in
                        the proprietorship of the "Staunton Spectator," I have become the sole
                        Editor and Proprietor of this paper.--Under the editorial administration of
                        my late associates, the "Spectator" has acquired an enviable reputation as
                        an able, dignified and chaste journal. I have too just an appreciation of my
                        own abilities to be vain enough to believe that I shall be able, "solitary
                        and alone," to render the paper as valuable and acceptable as when favored
                        by their combined talents and learning. I will endeavor to preserve the
                        reputation which the paper now possesses for dignity, truthfulness, sound
                        morality and wise conservatism.</p>
                    <p>Since my earliest recollection, I have entertained an exalted esteem for the
                        character of Henry Clay, the Orator, Statesman and Patriot; and since I have
                        arrived at man's estate, I have been as humble, though earnest and zealous
                        advocate of his policy of Government. In politics, therefore, there will be
                        no change in the character of the paper.</p>
                    <p> Believing that there exists no incompatibility between the "<emph
                            rend="italic">Union</emph> of the States and the <emph rend="italic"
                            >rights</emph> of the States," I am in favor of the preservation of
                        both. Whilst I would surrender none of the rights of the State, I would
                        never none of the bonds of the Union, for the preservation of the Union in
                        its integrity is necessary to the preservation of our liberties. With the
                        "Father of his Country," I esteem the "Union as the palladium of our
                        liberties," and cordially endorse the [illegible] of the great expounder of
                        the Constitution--"<emph rend="italic">Liberty and Union</emph>, now and
                        forever, one and inseparable." </p>
                    <p>I favored the adoption of the peaceful measures known as the Compromise of
                        1850, as a settlement of the vexed questions which agitated the public mind,
                        and which, till settled, destroyed the peace and periled the existence of
                        the Union.</p>
                    <p> I was opposed to the adoption of the Kansas bill, for the reasons, chiefly,
                        that it would reopen the bitter fountains of agitation which had been sealed
                        by the Compromise measures of 1850--that it was a violation of the most
                        solemn pledges given by both of the great National parties in National
                        Conventions assembled--that it recognized the <emph rend="italic"
                        >odious</emph> doctrine of Squatter Sovereignty, which would prove to be to
                        the institutions of the South what the Grecian horse had been to Troy--that
                        it would result in preventing the extension of slavery as a permanent
                        institution in <emph rend="italic">any</emph> Territory, even that <emph
                            rend="italic">South</emph> of the line of Latitude 36 deg. 30 min.--that
                        it would destroy the reverence which the people felt for Compromises--that
                        it would give a dangerous potency to a Northern sectional party--that it
                        would sow the dragon's teeth of disunion--that the South would be selling
                        its birthright for a mess of pottage, as it would exchange its dearest
                        interests for a profitless abstraction. </p>
                    <p>The present frightful proportions of the Black Republican, and the distracted
                        and dismembered condition of the Democratic party, and the fate of the
                        cherished institution in Kansas, do not diminish the confidence I have felt
                        in the correctness of my opinions in reference to the blunder committed by
                        the South in its advocacy of the Kansas bill.</p>
                    <p>There are enemies to the country in both sections of it--abolitionists and
                        Black Republicans in the North, and disunionists and secessionists in the
                        South. That our free institutions are imperiled cannot be concealed, and
                        hence there exists a necessity for the friends of our Government to arise in
                        the majesty of patriotic strength, burst asunder the slavish shackles of
                        party prejudice, forsake as well that party which has proven itself corrupt
                        and incapable of administering the Government, as that which is purely
                        sectional, that they may rally with the might of freemen to the support of
                        such candidates as will, if elected, preserve the Union and sacredly guard
                        and protect the rights of all the States.</p>
                    <p>It is fortunate for the country that an opportunity for the performances of
                        this patriotic duty is now presented to the friends of the Union.--The
                        ticket for the emergency has been nominated and reads as follows:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For President</emph>, </p>
                    <p>JOHN BELL, of Tennessee,</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Vice President</emph>, </p>
                    <p>EDWARD EVERETT, of Massachusetts.</p>
                    <p>These are candidates for whom the people can vote with pride and pleasure.
                        Let all who feel that they have a "country to serve as well as a party to
                        obey," rally enthusiastically to the support of the Union ticket, and
                        victory will perch upon its glorious standard.</p>
                    <p>RICHARD MAUZY.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Joseph A. Waddell, L. Waddell, Jr.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Waddell and L. Waddell, Jr., the editors of the Spectator,
                    relinquish control of the paper to Richard Mauzy, Esq. The old editors lament
                    the passing of the Whig party and the rise of the Republicans, and hope that
                    patriotism will prevail. They bid farewell to the town they have served.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay60.html#5.29a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1-2</column>
                <head>Salutory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Richard Mauzy</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Mauzy announces that he is assuming the position of editor of the
                    Spectator and states that he hopes to maintain the paper's reputation as a
                    bastion of Unionism and patriotism. He expresses his support for the
                    Bell-Everett ticket.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Census of 1860</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watts</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The U.S. Census Marshall for Western Virginia has named Major John H. Watts
                    the census deputy for Augusta County. A statement of the information needed by
                    Watts will be published in the next issue.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ice Cream Saloon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cease</ln>
                        <fn>M.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. M.S. Cease has opened an ice cream saloon in his confectionery on Main
                    St.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>District Offices</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wayt</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hailman</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackwood</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>W.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Apple</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>G.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koyner</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellis</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dalhouse</ln>
                        <fn>A.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennerly</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gentry</ln>
                        <fn>J.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Batts</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>C.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Revercomb</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>D.N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hottle</ln>
                        <fn>J.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hull</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>W.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Election totals for Magistrates and Constables in Augusta County: 1st
                    District, Magistrates -- J. Wayt Bell, John A. Harman, William G. Sterrett, S.B.
                    Brown; Constable -- Thomas Marshall. 2nd District, Magistrates -- W.A. Bell,
                    R.G. Bickle, H. Nelson, B.F. Points; Constable -- E.M. Cushing. Middlebrook,
                    Magistrates -- M.D.W. Hogshead, B.F. Hailman, James K. Grove, David Kunkle;
                    Constable -- Alex S. Craig. Greenville, Magistrates -- A.M. Moore, David
                    Blackwood, W.F. Smith, John Newton; Constable -- George M. Apple. Waynesboro,
                    Magistrates -- G.A. Bruce, A. Koyner, J.S. Ellis, Joseph Morrison; Constable --
                    A.N. Dalhouse. New Hope, Magistrates -- Robert Guy, S.R. Finley, Rev. S.
                    Kennerly, J.N. Gentry; Constable -- J.H. Batts. Mt. Sidney, Magistrates -- Cyrus
                    Brown, W.D. Anderson, A. Ross, William H. Gamble; Constable -- C.K. Hyde. Mt.
                    Solon, Magistrates -- J.M. McCue, James T. Clarke, J.C. Revercomb, D.N. Van
                    Lear; Constable -- J.F. Hottle. Churchville, Magistrates -- William Guy, J.M.
                    Hull, W.W. Montgomery, James Wilson; Constable -- George A. Hanger.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Rockingham Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of Rockingham county met and passed a resolution condemning
                    the actions of those Democrats who seceded from the National Convention and
                    supporting the course of Rockingham's delegates who remained at the convention
                    with the remainder of the Virginia delegation.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Circuit Court</head>
                <origin>Harrisonburg Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tooms</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Devier</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Tooms was convicted of involuntary manslaughter and Robert Reeves
                    was acquitted in the case of the shooting of James H. Dever.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Pugnacious</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report that many fights broke out during the elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Election of Judge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Judge Thompson received majorities of 200 votes in Bath, of 1,300 in
                    Rockbridge, and of 1,600 in Amherst and Nelson. His total majority for the
                    Circuit was about 3,000 votes.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Bath Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Terrell</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathena</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Payne</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Vote totals in Bath: Thompson elected over Fultz, 385 to 83; Terrell
                    elected Commonwealth's Attorney by 230 votes over Brooks; Robert B. Mathena
                    elected Sheriff over Payne by 143 votes.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Great Political Failure of the Day</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial excerpted from the New York Herald, which is critical of other
                    papers across the country which have been calling the Constitutional Union
                    ticket a "failure." It argues that terming the ticket a failure may be a party
                    trick to defame the Constitutional Unionists.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yewel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>Frances</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>St. Clair</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John D. Yewel of Rockbridge married Frances Young of Augusta County. The
                    wedding was performed at the home of St.Clair Young, father of the bride, by
                    Rev. W.G. Campbell.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Vote totals for various offices are listed across tops of columns 3-5, but
                print is illegible. Weekly proceedings of Congress, column 5. Short articles,
                rumors, etc. about internal politics of both the Democratic and Republican parties,
                as well as short pieces favorably reflecting on Constitutional Unionism are
                scattered throughout the page.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.05.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Irish Hegira for 1860</head>
                <origin>Journal of Commerce</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Dispersed over the broad domain of the great Republic, the foreign
                    ingredient speedily assimilates to the native population, losings its
                    distinctive features, and leaving but a faint impress on the national
                    character."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the large Irish immigration of the late 1850s and 1860.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presiding Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Augusta"</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Massie has declined reelection to the Magistracy and someone else will
                    have to be chosen. The author advocates the choice of J. Mashall McCue.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Elliott's Knob</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Polmer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moody</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fink</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Captain Polmer announces there will be a picnic for the county on June 15,
                    and it would be appreciated if Captains Imboden, Baylor, Moody, and Fink brought
                    their respective companies to the event.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.05.29.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
