<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1860/va.au.ss.1860.04.10">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Jeff McClurken</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/22/95</tagDate>
            <tagNote>2nd Pass; Josh Rothman did first pass.</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1860-04-10">
            <year>1860</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1860.04.10.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>3-7</column>
                <head>Judicial Election (Communicated)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator has now taken to creating a separate section for lengthy
                    expositions of writers on the election for Circuit Court Judge. This installment
                    has letters full of personal invective and political opinions from "Z,"
                    "Junius," "A Countryman," and others. Letters generally are at least one column
                    in length.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1860.04.10.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Farmer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter on the judicial election continued from previous page.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Presidential Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As the times approach for holding the National Conventions of the various
                        political parties of the country, the Washington correspondents of the New
                        York press are busily at work figuring out the chances of the different
                        Presidential aspirants, first for a nomination and then for election. These
                        gentlemen are exceedingly well posted, but their calculation do not always
                        prove correct, and we give them for only what they are worth. The Democracy
                        of Virginia having elected a majority of Hunter delegates to the Charleston
                        Convention, the two most prominent candidates before that body will probably
                        be Mr. Hunter and Judge Douglas. In a contest between the Democrats and
                        Republicans, Mr. Hunter would undoubtedly receive the electoral votes of all
                        the slaveholding States, and probably of California also. This would give
                        him 124 votes, whereas 152 are doubtful. The Richmond Enquirer says that the
                        friends of Gov. Wise believe Mr. Humter "to be utterly unavailable, with no
                        strength in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Indiana or Illinois." These States,
                        together with Minnesota and Oregon, casting 65 votes, are classed as
                        "doubtful." They will probably turn the scale in the Presidential election,
                        and leading politicians of both parties, who are not wedded to particular
                        men, will endeavor to nominate the candidate who is most likely to obtain
                        their support.</p>
                    <p>In regard to Judge Douglas, his friends claim that he will go into the
                        Charleston Convention with 128 votes certain. While he may carry the
                        doubtful Northern States, it is apprehended, on the other hand, that he
                        would lose South Carolina, Mississippi, Alabama and perhaps other Southern
                        States. His opponents, however, estimate his strength at Charleston as only
                        77 votes. Should Hunter and Douglas both go over board, Gen. Lane, of
                        Oregon, who is already looming up as a formidable candidate, is as likely to
                        carry the day as any one else.</p>
                    <p>The result of the Connecticut election is regarded as favorable to Mr.
                        Hunter. If the Democrats had carried that State, it would have been taken as
                        an indication in favor of Judge Douglas; but the Republicans having
                        triumphed, it shows how little aid is to be expected from the North, and
                        will discourage the nomination of a candidate from that section. It has also
                        probably improved the prospects of Seward for the Republican nomination,
                        that party being emboldend [sic] by the result to put a man on the track who
                        is fully identified with their principles.</p>
                    <p>The third party, whose Convention meets at Baltimore on the 9th of May, will
                        have a finger in the pie, and the recent election in Rhode Island is a straw
                        which shows how the wind blows. In Connecticut where the contest was between
                        the Democrats and Republicans, the latter triumphed; in Rhode Island, the
                        Whigs and Americans nominated a conservative candidate for Governor, who was
                        afterwards endorsed by the Democrats, and the Republicans were defeated.
                        This result encourages the hope that the Constitutional Union party, if it
                        accomplishes nothing more in the Presidential contest, may rescue some of
                        the Northern States from the Republicans, possibly throwing the election
                        into the House of Representatives, where, it is admitted, a Republican
                        President cannot be chosen.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator makes predictions about the upcoming presidential election and
                    believes that given the calculus between the two major parties, the
                    Constitutional Union party could draw some states away from the Republicans and
                    ultimately throw the election into the House of Representatives, thus precluding
                    a Republican victory.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr60.html#4.10a</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of a fatal fire in Rockingham.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Full Exposure</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are fond of curious investigations and have been amusing ourselves with
                    various calculations in regard to the canvass now progressing -- not as to the
                    result of the election but as to the amount of time, labor, stationery, lights,
                    fuel, &amp;c., consumed by the friends and partisans of the various
                    candidates for office since the opening of the campaign. . . . Reams of paper
                    have been blackened by gallons of ink freely shed to the cause, while countless
                    grey-goose quills have been ruthlessly torn from their parent birds."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator ridicules the effort exerted by correspondents in their letters
                    regarding the Judicial election. It anxiously awaits the day of the election
                    when these battles will end.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Real Public Good</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It has long been the reproach of the people of the United States that they
                        pay so little attention to Bathing, and much of the ill health of our
                        people, male and female, may fairly be attributed to the want of convenient
                        and healthful baths.</p>
                    <p>It is proposed, we understand, to supply this great want in our community by
                        establishing at once a complete bathing establishment, furnished with warm
                        and cold, plunge and shower baths, upon the most approved plans for the
                        accommodation of all who have enough of the old fogy about them to resort to
                        water bathing when they have the opportunity to indulge in the great luxury
                        of a Russian steam bath.</p>
                    <p>This Russian bath is to be the great attraction of the establishment, and if
                        the half be true that we have heard of its pleasures and its benefits, it
                        promises to be one of the greatest comforts and blessings ever bestowed upon
                        our community.</p>
                    <p>We understand that the Baths are to be located and constructed with express
                        reference to the comfort of ladies and families, the object being to merit
                        and to secure the patronage of our entire community, and to induce strangers
                        to make our town a place of summer resort.</p>
                    <p>The Russian bath is no new experiment even in this country. There is one now
                        in successful operation at the University of Virginia, where it is taken by
                        Professors and Students, as a luxury, in winter and in summer, and is highly
                        commended by the Medical Faculty on the score of health.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator proposes the establishment of a local Russian bath, believing it
                    would contribute both to public health and to the attraction of Staunton as a
                    tourist location.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr60.html#4.10b</note>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Corporation Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>G.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>W.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoy</ln>
                        <fn>Judson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Town officers elected.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Extraordinary Conduct of Slaves</head>
                <origin>New Orleans Crescent</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Story about a group of fifty slaves who came to New Orleans from a town
                    fifty miles away to consult a lawyer as to who their master was, since their
                    master had died five years before and they had recently been placed under a
                    cruel overseer.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelley</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>R.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Officers elected for the Boot and Shoe Leather Manufacturing Company.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mooman</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Appointments of Postmistresses</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Citizen</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author recounts the tragic death of a man at the hands of a group of
                    rioters at a wedding party in Rockingham County.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To Newhope District</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Rotation</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Author calls again for honesty and forthrightness from candidates for
                    Sheriff.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>T.E. Montgomery</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of a meeting in Deerfield at which candidates for various county
                    offices were recommended.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Voter</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larew</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aude</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author writes that Larew had not promised deputyships to Beard and Aude,
                    but had only suggested that they might serve under him should he win the
                    election.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>One of the People</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Author suggests that William Kayser should be elected Commissioner of the
                    Revenue for Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Arrest of Sanborn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the arrest and subsequent release of Frederick Sanborn, an
                    abolitionist called to testify before the Congressional committee investigating
                    Harper's Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Colored Race of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Statistical analysis of black vs. white American population, surmising that
                    the white population will continue to outstrip blacks.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Weekly proceedings of State Legislature, column 3; of Congress, column
            5.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1860.04.10.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Requisition Granted</head>
                <origin>Timon (Iowa) Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor Kirkwood has issued a warrant for the arrest of Barclay Coppic,
                    brother of one of John Brown's men.</summary>
                <note/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Mostly advertisements; bottom right is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1860.04.10.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
