<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.09.05">
	<header>
		<title>Valley Spirit</title>
		<tagger>
			<taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
			<tagDate>08/16/99</tagDate>
			<tagNote/>
		</tagger>
		<address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
		<date n="1866-09-05">
			<year>1866</year>
			<month norm="09">September</month>
			<day norm="00">05</day>
			<weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
		</date>
		<frequency>weekly</frequency>
		<extent>04</extent>
		<editionNote/>
	</header>
	<paperBody>
		<page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.05.01">
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>Speech of J. McDowall Sharpe, Esq.</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>In the House of Representatives of Pennsylvania, on the Bill for the
						Adjudication and Payment of Military Damages.</p>
					<p>DELIVERED FEBRUARY 24, 1864.</p>
					<p>MR. SPEAKER: On last Wednesday the courtesy of this House assigned this
						evening for the consideration of this bill. It is not my purpose to waste
						precious time, or to trespass upon the patience of this House, by making a
						tiresome political harangue.--I have said from the first, and I repeat it
						again, that there are no politics in this bill, and that there ought to be
						none in its discussion. When the gentleman from Washington (Mr. Kelley)
						introduced his resolution of instruction to the select committee to whom
						this bill had been committed, I was induced to make some remarks, because I
						at the time believed that the resolution contained a covert attack upon the
						loyalty of my constituents. Since that time the gentlemen has disavowed all
						such intention; I am bound to accept his disavowal for truth, and I do so
						cheerfully. On last night the gentlemen from Dauphin (Mr. Alleman) made a
						positive and direct accusation of disloyalty against some of my
						constituents. I hope to have an opportunity, on some future occasion, to
						answer the gentleman. But I will not undertake to do so to-night, because I
						have matters of far more importance entrusted to my charge for this evening.</p>
					<p>Mr. Speaker it may be proper for me to say, whilst standing on the threshold
						of this debate, that I have no pecuniary interest whatever in the passage of
						this bill.--Should I be betrayed, in the heat of discussion, into what may
						seem unusual seal in its support, I trust that my earnestness may be charged
						to the account of that nobler impulse of the heart which prompts the
						representative, under all circumstances consistent with his duties to the
						State at large, to maintain the rights of his constituents. I do confess a
						deep, intense and abiding interest in the fate of this bill. Nor is there a
						single gentleman upon this floor who would be surprised at this, could he
						walk with me through the beautiful valley of the Cumberland and examine for
						himself the blighting ravages committed by an insolent foe flushed with
						success, and still to be read upon the ground in desolated farms, prostrated
						fences and ruined forests? Would that you had an opportunity to mingle with
						my constituents, and to hear the sad tale of the husbandman, stripped of the
						means of livelihood, and turned over, with his family, to the cruel tyranny
						of poverty. Would that you all could hear the touching story of the fond
						mother, how the rebels came in their pride and power, and drove away the
						favorite horse of her darling boy--who was far away from home and
						kindred--in the land of the stranger and enemies, fighting for the imperiled
						Constitution, with his eye fixed even in death upon the flag of his country.
						Would that you all could listen to the still more pathetic tale of the widow
						who has given all her household gods as offerings upon the altar of
						patriotism--husband and sons--and now by the fortunes of war a bankrupt not
						only in heart, but also in property; a husbandless, childless, penniless
						female, dependent upon the bitter bread of charity. The fate of this bill
						may, indeed, be of little consequence to man y upon this floor. They can
						return to their homes where the tread of armed legions have never left their
						footprints of blood, and where the hum of honest industry has never been
						drowned by the roar of cannon or the roll of musketry, believing that they
						have done a wise thing in voting against this bill. What matters it to them?
						These things are but history to them--not living truths. But to me they are
						stern realities. Even here, in this presence, methinks I hear the Macedonian
						cry of my constituents, calling to all the loyal and true-hearted sons of
						Pennsylvania. "Come over and help us!" These scenes, like Banquo's ghost,"
						will not down at my bidding. They need no magician's wand to call them up
						before my mind's eye; they are there always--living, stubborn, stern
						realities.--Mr. Speaker, is it surprising that I am earnest in this cause?
						Would it not rather be amazing if I were not? Could any heartless cold and
						hard than adamant, listen with stolidity and indifference to the voice of
						duty which "pleads like angles, trumpet tongued," against the selfish
						parsimony which could contemptuously refuse the measure of this relief?</p>
					<p>But the success of this bill needs no support from that morbid sympathy which
						is ever prone to weep at the tale of suffering. It stands fairly and
						squarely upon the broad <emph rend="italic">foundation</emph> of its own
						intrinsic merit. I trust this measure with confidence to the calm, sober,
						unbiased judgemen of this House. I invoke not in its behalf those tender
						emotions which overflow the flood gates of the heart whenever the fountain
						has been started by the hand of violence and outrage. But I also, on the
						other hand, deprecate that blind and unreasoning prejudice which would
						condemn my cause before it is heard. Every principle of State duty, every
						principle of right and justice demand, in imperative tones, the passage of
						this bill. </p>
					<p>Will the House indulge me whilst I strive in my own feeble way to prove this?
						A fair understanding of the act will prove synonymous with its passage.</p>
					<p>A brief history of the origin of these claims for damages may become
						necessary at this point.</p>
					<p>Scarcely had the last sounds of the bombardment of Fort Sumfer died upon the
						air--hardly had the pulsations of the national heart recovered from the
						shock of the deep mouthed cannon of treason, ere Harper's Ferry and all the
						country on that side of the Potomac were seized by the Virginia troops. They
						kept up, for a considerable length of time, a menacing attitude towards the
						State of Pennsylvania. There were no forces upon our borders, to repel the
						threatened invasion, and no natural obstructions, except the narrow Potomac,
						to prevent their penetration into the Cumberland Valley, and the burning of
						this capital. At this juncture it was deemed advisable by the military
						authorities of the Government to concentrate the opposing force at
						Chambersburg. The Seventh, Eighth and Tenth regiments of three months'
						Pennsylvania volunteers were ordered to that place. They took possession of
						the farm of a loyal citizen, being contiguous to that borough, and occupied
						the same as a military camp for the period of about two months. In the month
						of June, 1861, the Government determined to increase the force on the border
						to a corps numbering about twenty-five thousand muskets, with the view of
						pushing them down the valley of Virginia, under the command of General
						Patterson.--This augmented force spread their encampments over large tracts
						of the most fertile land in Franklin county, whilst the crops were beginning
						to whiten for the harvest, and remained in the occupancy thereof for about
						three weeks. It requires no fancy to conceive how great would be the injury
						to crops, fences and timber at the hands of so large a force of then raw and
						undisciplined soldiery. These troops were in the service of the United
						States. But no steps have as yet been taken by the General Government or by
						the Legislature of Pennsylvania, for the adjucation and payment of the
						damages inflicted by them upon the citizens of this Commonwealth. It is true
						that Governor Curtin appointed two very competent citizens of Franklin
						county to make assessments of these damages. The commissioners so appointed
						have done their work well, and have made report of their labors to the
						Executive. But inasmuch as their appointment by the Governor was
						unauthorized by law, and no legislation has ever been had to validate their
						reports, and no appropriation has ever been made to pay the claims
						adjudicated by them, their labors have ended in faith, not in fruition. In
						September, 1862, the rebel General Longstreet's corps took possession of
						Hagerstown, in the State of Maryland, and all the territory intervening
						between it and the State of Pennsylvania. A universal panic seized upon the
						whole country. The heart of the North stood still, as if paralyzed with
						sudden fright. The Governor, with commendable zeal and earnestness, sounded
						the alarm bell, which struck a sympathetic chord in every heart. His
						proclamation calling upon the citizens of Pennsylvania to come up to the
						help of the Government against the mighty, to shoulder the knapsack and
						musket, and marching to the border, there, upon the confines of their native
						State, to receive upon the points of their bayonets the insurgent hordes
						that were reveling in the intoxication of victory of the second fatal Bull
						Run, sped over mountain, through valleys and across streams, like the
						ominous symbol borne by the fleet footed Highlander in days of yore, known
						and recognized by all the clans, as the bloody signal of their chieftain
						which summoned them to the harvest of death. With the same heroic devotion
						with which the clansman was wont to answer the fatal summons of his chief,
						did the true hearted and sturdy sons of this grand old Commonwealth answer
						the call of their Executive. The voice of duty had scarcely ceased to speak,
						before thousands answered it, in person. The farmer left his plough in the
						furrow, the merchant forsook his merchandise, the lawyer forgot his cause,
						the minister turned his back upon his pulpit, and the artisan rushed from
						his shop, and all with one common purpose and firm resolve marched forward
						toward the foe, keeping step to the music of the union. The earth, like a
						prolific mother, seemed to have brought forth in a single night, innumerable
						legions of armed men. Transportation could not covey them to the borders as
						fast as they desired to go. Thousands of them were quartered upon the farms
						and in the buildings of citizens of Pennsylvania. This large force, thus
						suddenly put into the field, could not, by any possible exertions of the
						military authorities of the State, be adequately provided with tents rations
						and other necessasies for their comfort. They had a good right to make
						themselves comfortable, and I hope I may be pardoned for saying that they
						exhausted all the resources within their reach, to attain this desirable
						consummation. We were glad to see them there and we do not complain against
						them now, because they left a record behind them of their presence, which
						can be read to this day upon our farms, buildings and forests. In addition
						to this militia force the Governor ordered the "Anderson Troop" to the
						border, which was at that time lying in the barracks at Carlisle. Time could
						not be spared to mount these troops in the regular way. It was of the
						highest importance that they should be put into the saddle, as scouts,
						without delay; and no other alternative remained but to impress the
						necessary number of horses, with their accoutrements, for immediate service.
						After the exigencies of the occasion had passed away, many of these horses
						were returned to their owners, in a very bad condition, and others never
						returned at all.--These horses were taken out of the plows of our farmers in
						the fields, and out of their wagons on the public highway, yet so high is
						the standard of loyalty among my constituents, that not only did they not
						murmur against this act of oppression, but they indeed acquiesced in it with
						alacrity and cheerfulness. These claims have also been adjudicated and
						assessed by two very intelligent citizens of Franklin county, acting under
						the appointment of the Governor. This appointment was also, at the time it
						was made, unauthorized by law, and consequently nothing has been done toward
						the payment of these damages. In October, 1862, the rebel General Stuart,
						with a cavalry force numbering about two thousand sabres, passed through
						parts of the counties of Adams and Franklin, destroying considerable
						property, and taking with them large numbers of horses. At the last session
						of the Legislature an act was passed, approved on the 22d day of April,
						1863, which prouided that the court of common pleas of Dauphin county should
						appoint three appraisers, who, after being sworn, should proceed to examine
						and ascertain the losses and damages sustained by citizens of this
						Commonwealth, by reason of the occupancy of and trespass upon their lands by
						any part of the militia force which was called into active service in
						September, A. D. 1862, for the purpose of defending the southern border of
						the State; also, to examine and ascertain the losses and damages sustained
						by the citizens of this State by reason of the impressment of their horses,
						wagons, teams, forage and other property, into the service of the United
						States for the use of the Anderson cavalry in the month of September, 1862;
						and also the losses and damages sustained by citizens on the southern border
						of the State by reason of the rebel raid under General Stuart, on the tenth
						and eleventh days of October, 1862. The appraisers were also required to
						make report of their assessments of losses and damages, together with the
						testimony taken by them, to the court. It was made the duty of the court to
						review these reports, and authority was given to approve or set them aside,
						in whole or in part. In pursuance of this act of Assembly the court of
						common pleas of Dauphin county appointed General Worral, Judge Hiester and
						Mr. Weidle, three intelligent and upright gentlemen of this county, who have
						so far discharged their duties as to have ascertained all the losses and
						damages occasioned by the Stuart raid, and the court is now in possession of
						their reports. Since the passage of the ac tof April, 1863, it has become a
						part of the history of this war, that General Lee. with his whole army, has
						invaded the State causing immense loss to the citizens of the border
						counties, in crops, grain, forage, horses, cattle, and other property. That
						again the loyal and devoted sons of the Commonwealth rushed to the border to
						defend, from the contaminating touch of the vandal hordes, that sacred soil
						which William Penn had dedicated to peace and good will toward all men, more
						than a century ago. Again our citizens suffered the ravages of a badly
						provided and poorly fed body of undisciplined troops. It is also well known
						that considerable damage was doneto the property of citizens of Allegheny
						county, and of other counties, by the erection of defensive works by our
						troops, and in various otherways during the excitement of last summer. The
						bill now before the House simply proposes to enlarge the powers of the
						commisioners so as to enable them to ascertain and assess all damages
						occasioned by the enemy and by our own troops, State and national, within
						the limits of this Commonwealth, since the commencement of the war. Thus,
						that which was made local and special relief by the act of 22d of April,
						1863, has been changed, by the present act into a redress as broad as the
						boundaries of the State herself. This is eminently right and proper. This
						act also contemplates that the appraisers shall make their report to the
						court of common pleas of Dauphin county, and the same duty is laid upon the
						court to review these reports, and dispose them in such a manner as to court
						may seem right and just. The commissioners are also required to administer
						oaths, and to reduce the testimony of claimants and witnesses to writing and
						to return the same to the court. This bill also proposes to give the
						commissioners the right, if they think proper to do so, to adopt the
						assessment heretofore made by the appraisers appointed by the Governor, and
						to return them to the court as part of their report, with the same duty of
						review imposed upon the courts as in other cases. The bill also requires the
						attorney General of the Commonwealth to depute an attorney for each county
						to which its provisions may apply, to appear before the board of
						commissioners as counsel for the State. Each claimant is also required to
						file, with his claim, an affidavit setting forth, in specific terms, that he
						has never borne arms against the United States or the State of Pennsylvania;
						that he has never given aid, information or encouragement to those in armed
						hostility to the Government, that he has never discouraged enlistment in the
						armies of the United States; that he will support the Constitution of the
						United States and of the State of Pennsylvania, and bear true faith and
						allegiance to the same, and behave himself as a loyal citizen thereof. When
						these damages shall have finally adjucated, the bill provides that the State
						of Pennsylvania shall issue coupon certificates of indebtedness to the
						claimants, bearing five per centum interest per annum, payable
						semi-annually, at the State Treasury, redeemable in twenty years or sooner,
						at the option of the State, and that an additional tax of one quarter of a
						mill shall be laid on all property now taxable for State purposes, and the
						fund arising therefrom shall be appropriated solely to the redemption of
						these certificates.</p>
					<p>Such, Mr. Speaker, is a brief and cursory narrative of this origin of these
						claims, and such a rough and hasty sketch of the measure of redress proposed
						by the bill. Is there any gentleman upon this floor, whose heart prompts him
						to ask me, why do your constituents come here asking for relief? I answer
						him, in their name (for I am only authorized to speak for them,) because
						they have a right to do it. The first and highest duty of a State is
						protection to her citizens in life, liberty and property. Protection is the
						price of allegiance, and allegiance is the duty that follows protection.
						Where one of these duties dies, the other dies with it. They are reciprocal,
						co-extensive and coordinate obligations. They can no more be separated from
						each other and live, than can the soul and body be severed and natural life
						remain. In a state of nature, man has an inalienable right to consult his
						own safety, welfare and interest, in his own way, and in obedience to no
						restraints, except his own unchained volitions. The result of this was that
						might made right. The strong oppressed the weak. No man was safe in his life
						liberty or property, so long as there lived a stronger than he, who might
						deprive him of these inestimable blessings. A universal feeling of security
						reigned throughout the earth. The want of a power that could restrain the
						strong arm of the oppressor, shield the weak, help the helpless and coerce
						the untutored volitions of the natural man, was universally felt and
						acknowledged. It was at once discovered that this power could only be found
						and lodged in an aggregation of individuals. Mankind was not long in
						learning that an aggregations of individuals cannot exist without
						government, and that as all could not be governors there must necessarily be
						a class whose duty it was to govern, and a class whose lot it was to be
						governed, and whose duty it was to obey. Starting with these things in view,
						men agreed to form a government and to surrender to their rulers a part of
						their unlicensed freedom which they had enjoyed in a state of nature, in
						consideration of the security they expected to possess as the fruit of the
						government. This we believe to be the true origin of all human governments
						and from these premises, we can with ease deduce the co-relative duties of
						the people. The one owes protection, and the other allegiance. Different
						forms of government have appeared upon the earth. We have had and now have,
						despotism, constitutional monarchies and republics. But no difference what
						shape the government may assume, it never can rid itself of the original
						object of its institution--protection to its people in all their rights.
						There never has been a despotism in all the annals of history that has ever
						forgotten this high obligation which it owed its subjects when their
						interests had been infringed upon by other nations. No matter how cruel
						might be the heel of domestic tyranny upon the necks of the citizens, still
						the despot in dealing with his subjects and foreign states, stood true as
						the needle to the pole in his discharge of this holy and sacred trust. Even
						now the Emperor of France has upon this continent a powerful army whose
						eagles have overrun a neighboring republic, in a crusade for the restoration
						of the violated rights of his citizens. Can it be that this great State, the
						theory of whose government is founded upon the broad and eternal principle
						that the people are the source of all powers--that they indeed are the
						sovereigns, and the rulers, for the time being, the servants? Can it be,
						sir, that this great Commonwealth, with such a political conception as that,
						can swerve the tithe of a hair from her high mission? Can it be that the
						people who, in this State are the government, shall fall below the standard
						of security which despotism has set up for the rights of its subjects? Can
						it be that this people, through their representatives on this floor, will so
						stultify themselves as to deny protection to themselves? Until it is shown
						that those whom I represent here have thrown off their allegiance to their
						government, and forfeited the right of protection; until it is proved that
						they are derelict in their duty; until it is shown that they have struck,
						with parricidal hand, a blow at the heart of that government that nursed
						them in safety during infancy, and protected their property in manhood; sir,
						until these things are shown here upon this floor, I ask this relief for my
						constituents not as a matter of grace--I demand it as a matter of right.</p>
					<p>Is there still some gentleman in this House who ask why my constituents come
						here and ask for this relief? I answer him because they deserve it. The
						highest civil duty of the citizen is to discharge his duty to his
						government. There may be some gentlemen upon this floor who may think that I
						put the case too strongly, when I say that under all circumstances, fully
						performed every obligation that they owed to the Government. I repeat, sir,
						with emphasis that they have done so, and I challenge contradiction, come
						from what quarter it may. There is a passive obedience to the Government
						which a citizen may give, and which is enough, in ordinary circumstances, to
						entitle him to protection in life, liberty and property. In other words,
						every State is bound to protect her citizens against all assaults upon their
						rights, so long as they hold allegiance to that Government, and do not act
						in open hostility to it. This is the universally acknowledged obligation of
						States to their citizens. But it may be argued that the relief provided by
						this bill is unusual and extraordinary. Sir, let it be so admitted, for the
						sake of argument, (but only for the sake of argument,) and I still insist
						that my constituents are entitled to it, because their obedience to the
						Government has been an extraordinary and willing one--a service of the
						heart, not of the lips.--Their burdens and their struggles have been
						extraordinary in its behalf, and when compared with those of the other
						citizens of the State, may, in a certain sense, be termed works of
						supererogation. Mr. Speaker, my district sent one of the first companies
						that arrived in this city, after the bombardment of Fort Sumpter. It
						furnished that glorious battery of artillery commanded by the gallant
						Captain Easton, which covered itself with honor at Drainesville, and whose
						heroic commander, rather than surrender his guns to the enemy, upon the
						first of the seven ill-fated days before Richmond, calmy bared his breast to
						the storm of lead, exclaiming with his dying breath, "This battery never
						Surrenders!" It furnished two full companies to the Pennsylvania Reserve
						Corps. It sent the first Pennsylvania Regiment to gather laurels upon the
						battle fields of Kentucky and Tennessee; I refer to the 77th Pennsylvania
						volunteers. It sent a full battery with that regiment to the Army of the
						Potomac. In August, 1862, it sent the famous 126th regiment now commanded by
						the gallant Capt. Mc Dowell. It furnished the 107th regiment to the same
						army, and upon the blood enriched fields of Fredericksburg, the grass grows
						over the graves of many of both regiments. It has furnished three cavalry
						companies for the war. It has filled up its quota under the impending draft,
						and besides that has furnished recruits to other portions of the State. Upon
						every battlefield of this cruel and unnatural war, the sons of my district
						have been found lying with their feet to the foe and their faces towards the
						stars. There were no politics in their deaths, as there had been none in
						their lives, after the stability of the Union was imperiled. There they lay,
						cold in death, Republican and Democrat, side by side, just as they had
						fought in life. Remember Mr. Speaker this is the military record of a
						district that lies within cannon shot of the enemy's country. This is a
						military record of a people whose homes were daily threatened with
						desolation, and which have, in truth twice been ravaged. Have I not reason,
						sir, to be proud of such a constituency? Have I not, sir, just cause to be
						sensitive, when I am told, by gentlemen on this floor, that my people
						invited and abetted this invasion of this Commonwealth? Did I say one word
						to much, sir, when I declared that my constituents desire the relief of this
						bill? But, sir, the one-half is scarcely told. We have paid our taxes
						promptly. We have invested our means liberally in government securities. I
						make no merit of this, sir, because all good citizens have done the same.
						But, sir our country has twice been overrun with the rebel hordes. Twice
						have our citizens been robbed and plundered by an insolent foe. Twice have
						our people been drowned by the deluge of militia men who swarmed over our
						fields like locusts, and eat up our substance. Many of our tenants have lost
						their entire stock, which they gathered together by the patient industry of
						a life time. They are now penniless and without the means of livelihood. Our
						mothers, our wives, our sisters and our daughters, have stood upon the
						streets of our towns and villages, and at our railroad stations, to feed the
						hungry and nurse the sick soldiers, who had come from afar to defend their
						homes. We have lived in a State of constant suspense and dread. In the
						morning our families were forced to exclaim, "would to God it were evening,"
						and in the evening, "would to God it were morning." Our business has been
						broken up. Our grass crops have been permitted to rot in the fields, and our
						grain to perish for want of the sickle, and our corn has been trusted to the
						dews and rains of a beneficent Creator, unassisted by human labor. Our
						industry as been paralyzed, and our times put out of joint. Yet all this we
						have borne without a murmur. The cry of my constituents for help and
						protection went up and filled the ears of those in power, at Washington yet
						no heed was given to their call. Desparing of assistance beyond their own
						border, they at last only implored for permission to keep their own
						citizens, which had entered the service of the United States, at home, as a
						guard to protect themselves against sudden calvalry raids.--The necessities
						of the nation demanded that this prayer should also remain unanswered. Thus
						were we compelled to send from our midst those who otherwise could and would
						have defended our property, at least from the rebel raid of Stuart. We did
						not slumber upon the brink of ruin, nor blindly shut our eyes to the danger
						that environed us. We made known our apprehension to the government, and we
						fully informed those in authority of the consequences of neglecting our
						demands. But they were as those who had heard not, though having
						ears.--Under such depressing circumstances, and treated with such stoical
						indifference, did my constituents falter in their loyalty?--No, not they.
						They had hearts large enough to comprehend that their government was not
						indifferent to their fate, only too impotent, at the time to help them in
						their sore straits. They had intelligence enough to understand that the kind
						mother that had nursed them into prosperity, failed only to come to their
						rescue, because she was herself struggling in the expiring throes of
						impending dissolution. They could pity the anguish of a parent, stung to
						death by the serpent tooth of her own children's ingratitude. They could
						sympathize as well as blame, and when they cast their eyes over and across
						the troubled sea of revolution, and beheld the ship of State struggling amid
						the boisterous waves, with night and the tempest closing around her, when
						their eyes peered through the murk atmosphere of the battlefield, and
						followed with long and anxious glances the starry banner of their country
						through the varied and chequered fortunes of each bloody day, the words of
						cavil and complaint changed upon their lips into shouts of honest admiration
						for the sublimity of the struggle, and the divinity of the fortitude it
						exhibited.--Therefore, Mr. Speaker, my constituents stand to-day, as they
						have stood in all time firm as a rock, against which all the mad waves of
						rebellion and civil strife may dash; but still the receding flood will leave
						them fixed and immovable as before. They have borne long and patiently, even
						for three long, weary years. They now stand in this presence, and through
						me, as one of their representatives, demand that tardy justice shall at last
						be done to them. Did I Mr. Speaker, go beyond the bounds of moderation and
						prudence, when I declared these people deserve this relief?</p>
					<p>Is there still some gentleman upon this floor whose heart prompts him to ask,
						why do your constituents demand this relief? I answer because there is no
						reason founded in either justice or right, why they should be compelled to
						carry heavier burdens than other portions of the State, more fortunately
						located. Look at this question, Mr. Speaker, in a spirit of candor and fair
						dealing. We are all sons of Pennsylvania alike. The aegis of the same
						Constitution protects us all alike. We have a common heritage of State glory
						and renown, we have a common duty of allegiance to bear toward our
						government, we have common burdens to bear, and common aspirations and
						common hopes. The golden thread that links us in a common state brotherhood,
						begins on the shores of Lake Erie, and runs over mountains, through valleys
						and across rivers, until it gathers within its links, us who dwell near the
						banks of the Potomac. If all things else be common, why should our
						misfortune be peculiar?--If we have a joint tenancy of everything else, why
						should we suffer the fortunes of war in severalty? There can be now answer
						adverse to my cause, unless it be spoken by the force of that selfish
						parsimony, which, wrapping itself up in the mantle of its own affluence and
						contentment, can shut his heart against the pleadings of justice, and turn a
						deaf ear to the tale of sorrow. There is no use in mincing words about this
						matter. Cold, calculating selfishness can alone deny the provisions of this
						bill. No higher impulse will or can have aught to say, in making such a
						decision.</p>
					<p>Is there still some gentleman upon the floor who inquires, why do your
						constituents ask this relief? I answer him, because they have precedent for
						it. The principle that peculiar hardships experienced by any portion of the
						people beyond the ordinary hardships of the masses, is entitled to the
						special redress, has always been recognized since the first dawn of our
						national existence. The journals of every Congress and State Legislature are
						filled with successful applications of this character. So important have
						these causes become in our country, that a peculiar court has been created
						for their settlement. I know of no civilized nation that does not
						acknowledge the binding force of this obligation. The destruction of
						property by mobs in our cities, as by express legislation been compensated
						out of the common public purse. If any gentleman will cast his eyes over the
						House file, he will discover more than one relief bill. Individuals are here
						year after year applying for relief. Here it is, the surety of a defaulting
						officer that prays he may be released from his bond--there it is, a man who
						has been unsuccessful in some enterprise, out of which he expected to make a
						fortune--then again, it is some poor unfortunate who lost his limbs in his
						country's service. It may be answered that those relief bills are of small
						amount. But I care not for the amount; it is the principle I am seeking for.
						The principle involved in a small bill is the same principle that is
						involved in a large one. Since the principle ahs been established, it is too
						late to retrace our steps because the amount is larger than usual. Is that
						not rather a reason why we should go forward? If the relief is too much for
						the state to give, it is too much for my constituents to lose. If is too
						much for my constituents to lose, then it is too much for the State to give.
						I stand then, sir, upon the principle of the precedents, which loom up at
						all points along the pathway of our State and national legislation. Is there
						still some one here who feels disposed to inquire why do your constituents
						come to us for this relief? I answer because they have nowhere else to go.
						The Treasury of the United States Government is barred against them. I
						believe this to be right, because the General Government could not without
						going into a commission of bankruptcy, begin to pay all the damages which
						loyal men have suffered since the war began. The day may, no doubt will
						come, when the government can do so, but not now. But the case is different
						with Pennsylvania.--She can well afford this relief to her own citizens.
						What do I ask of her? I ask her to pay claims which will not exceed one
						million of dollars--at least one half of them incurred in repelling invasion
						and in defending her own existence. I ask her to issue certificates of
						indebtedness to her creditors, under this bill, bearing <emph rend="italic"
							>five percentum interest per annum</emph>, and redeemable in twenty
						years, or sooner, at her option. I ask her to levy an additional tax of a
						quarter of a mill on all property now taxable for State purposes amounting
						to one hundred and fifty thousand dollars annually, until a sufficient fund
						is raised to pay these certificates of indebtedness. Is this "the whole
						front of my offending?" Is this the measure of my demand? Is this indeed,
						all? No, no this is the lowest part of my request; this is the mercenary
						portion of my demand. I ask what is of far more value than this. I ask
						Pennsylvania to be true to her high duty. I ask her to be worthy of herself.
						I ask her to be just, not generous to her citizens. This, this is the sum
						total of my offence. </p>
					<p>Now, Mr. Speaker, I have endeavored to prove that my constituents may well
						demand this relief as a matter of right. I have shown that they deserve to
						have it--that there is no just or true reason why they should be subjected
						to greater misfortune than other portions of the State more happily located
						--that their claim has been established by a long and unbroken chain of
						precedents, and that they have no other place to go for this redress. I
						cannot, therefore conceive what plausible objection the most refined
						cavalier can raise to the bill, unless it be that it is premature; tat it is
						too soon to pay these claims. I confess, Mr. Speaker, that until within the
						last few days this objection never occurred to my mind. I chanced in the
						matter: I happened to meet, the other day, an intelligent and respectable
						Senator, walking though the capital grounds. In the course of conversation,
						I spoke of this bill and expressed a hope that he would support it. "Sir,"
						said he, "your bill is premature; it is too soon to pay these claims." I am
						candid enough to admit, Mr. Speaker, that I was startled by the novelty of
						the objection. "Sir, your bill is premature; it is too soon to pay these
						claims." The words kept ringing though my head and fell upon my heart like
						the incubus of a night-mare. I have often read how the fatal words, "it is
						too late," have been wrung from the anguish-riven soul of ambition, when it
						saw its last chance pass by and its sun begin to set. I have often heard of
						it being "too late" to do justice. We are told that the sinner's death-bed
						often witnesses the expiring cry, "it is too late" to be saved. I have often
						thought that the most melancholy sound in all the realms of the lost, will
						be the despairing soliloquy of the soul that has gone down to death from the
						mount of gospel privileges, "It is too late for mercy here." But, sir, I
						have never yet heard or read that when wrongs have been suffered which the
						State is bound to redress, that justice can come too soon. I have yet to
						learn that relief, when deserved, can be premature. What, sir, would that
						patriot statesman whose chair you now occupy, have said had he been told
						that the redress, which our Revolutionary fathers demanded of the British
						crown, was premature? What would he have answered had he been told that it
						was too soon to resist oppression and tyranny of the mother country? What
						would he have said, sir, if he had been told that the blood of Lexington was
						shed too soon? What would he have answered had he been informed that the
						Declaration of Independence was premature, and our whole Revolutionary
						struggle a fatal mistake? Methinks I see his venerate form rise from the
						grave and fill that chair once more, and as his eye once more flashes forth
						the lightening of his soul, he exclaims in tones of stern rebuke. "Such
						counsels, if heeded, would have strangled patriotism, made the American
						Revolution an untimely birth, and left all its heroes slaves. Never again
						let such ill-omened words drop from the lips of the patriot so long as there
						is still a struggling son of his country presenting his claim for a redress
						of his wrongs at the august tribunal of the people."</p>
					<p>Mr. Speaker and gentleman representatives, go home to your constituents if
						you can. Go home if you dare and tell them you voted against this bill. Go
						home to your constituents if you can, go home to them if you dare, and tell
						them that Pennsylvania, the brightest star in the galaxy of States, the
						cradle of American freedom, the nursing mother of the Declaration of
						Independence, rich in the hallowed memories of Valley Forge and Germantown,
						having within its limits the birth-place of our nation, and the grave of
						treason close by the consecrated sepulchres of Gettysburg's heroes--an
						empire of three millions of people whose mountains milk the clouds, and
						whose valleys run with fatness, having within her bowels coal enough to warm
						all her friends, and iron enough to cool all her foes--a Commonwealth
						abounding in prosperity, intelligence and civilization, unknown
						elsewhere--tell your constituents, I repeat it, that this State, such as I
						have described it, through you as her representatives on this floor, has
						refused to be just to her citizens, and has declared herself to be too weak
						and poor to protect them. You may carry home to your people this disgraceful
						confession, but I humbly thank that beneficent Being, who has hitherto
						guided and protected me, that he has given me strength enough to declare
						upon the floor that I have neither part nor lot in tarnishing thus, the fair
						escutcheon of our State pride. I shift the responsibility from my shoulders,
						and here in this very presence, I shake off the dust from my feet as a
						moment against such a premeditated outrage.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Contains a copy of the speech given by J. McDowall Sharpe on February 24,
					1866, before the House of Representatives, regarding the bill for adjudication
					of and payment for military damages.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.05.02">
			<div type="e">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Col. McClure on the Deserter Question</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The effrontery of the editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> is
						most wonderful. The coolness with which, in his last week's issue, he
						stultifies himself on the deserter question, is positively refreshing. He
						seems to have forgotten that his private opinion on this subject has been
						given time without number, and, what is still more strange, he is apparently
						oblivious of the fact that, in the columns of his own journal, he has placed
						himself in an attitude of direct opposition to the one which he now assumes.
						That cause must be indeed hopeless which requires such desperate remedies.
						Driven to the wall, totally defeated in his efforts to procure the sanction
						of the Supreme Court upon the attempt to disfranchise certain American
						citizens without due process of law, he now endeavors to deceive the honest,
						law-abiding judges of election of our county as to their duty in this
						matter, by the assertion that the decision of the Supreme Court in Huber vs.
						Reilly is not to be regarded, for the reason that there is an Act of the
						State Legislature upon which that Court has not passed an opinion. </p>
					<p>He would have the judges believe, that this Act of the State Legislature is
						binding upon them, and that they are in duty bound to reject the votes of
						all persons who are marked down as deserters upon the record of the Provost
						Marshal.</p>
					<p>That this is not the case, we propose to show by the construction which the
						Supreme Court of Pennsylvania has given to the Act of Congress, and by the
						editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> himself. </p>
					<p>Section 21 of the Act of Congress approved March 3d, 1865, reads as follows:</p>
					<p>SECTION 21. <emph rend="italic">And be it further enacted</emph>, That in
						addition to the other lawful penalties of the crime of desertion from the
						military or naval services, all persons who have deserted the military or
						naval service of the United States, who shall not return to said service or
						report themselves to a provost marshal within sixty days after the
						proclamation hereinafter mentioned, shall be deemed and awaken to have
						voluntarily relinquished and forfeited their rights of citizenship and their
						rights to become citizens; and such deserters shall be forever incapable of
						holding any office of trust or profit under the United States, or of
						exercising any rights of citizens thereof; and all persons who shall
						hereafter desert the military or naval service, and all persons who, being
						duly enrolled, shall depart the jurisdiction of the district in which he is
						enrolled, or go beyond the limits of the United States, with intent to avoid
						any draft into the military or naval service, duly ordered, shall be liable
						to the penalties of this section * * * </p>
					<p>It will be seen by this section, that "<emph rend="italic">all persons who
							have deserted</emph> the military or naval service," shall be deemed to
						have forfeited their rights of citizenship. Such persons are not entitled to
						vote. </p>
					<p>But how is the fact of desertion to be ascertained? Is it to be taken for
						granted upon mere rumor? Is suspicion of the fact to be regarded as proof?
						Is the mere writing down of the word deserter by a Provost Marshal opposite
						a man's name, to be considered as evidence of desertion? No.--The
						Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of the State of
						Pennsylvania, provide, that in "all criminal prosecutions the accused hath a
						right to be heard by himself and his counsel," "nor can he be deprived of
						LIFE, LIBERTY OR PROPERTY WTIHOUT PROCESS OF LAW." There can be no
						conviction unless by the judgement of his peers, the law of the land, and
						innocence is presumed until guilt is proven. Thus it will be seen that the
						fundamental law of the land guarantees to every citizen the inalienable
						rights of life, liberty and property.</p>
					<p>The construction which the Radical party now seeks to give this Act of
						Congress would "tear down and scatter to the winds all these safeguards of
						life, liberty and property."</p>
					<p>IN ORDER TO DEPRIVE A CITIZEN OF THE RIGHT OF SUFFRAGE, HE MUST FIRST BE
						CONVICTED OF SOME INFAMOUS CRIME BY A COURT CIVIL OR MILITARY. Listen to the
						ruling of the Supreme Court in Huber vs. Reilly, speaking of the Act of
						Congress of March 3d, 1865. "It means that the forfeiture which it
						prescribes, like all other penalties for desertion, must be <emph
							rend="italic">adjudged</emph> to the convicted person after a trial by
						court-martial and sentence approved. FOR THE CONVICTION AND SENTENCE OF SUCH
						A COURT THERE CAN BE NO SUBSTITUTE. They alone establish the guilt of the
						accused and fasten upon him the legal consequences. Such we think is the
						true meaning of the Act." </p>
					<p>Again, "on the other hand, if a record of conviction by a lawful Court be not
						prerequisite to suffering the penalty of the law, the Act of Congress may
						work intolerable hardships. The accused with thus be obliged TO PROVE HIS
						INNOCENCE whenever the registry of the Provost Marshal is adduced against
						him. No decision of a board of election officers will protect him against
						the necessity of renewing his defence at every subsequent election * * "It
						is well known also that some who were registered deserters, were at the time
						actually in the military service as volunteers and honorably discharging
						their duties to the government"</p>
					<p>The plaintiff NOT HAVING BEEN CONVICTED of desertion and failure to return to
						the service, or to report to a Provost Marshal, and NOT HAVING BEEN
						SENTENCED TO THE PENALTIES AND FORFEITURES OF THE LAW, WAS ENTITLED TO
						VOTE."</p>
					<p>This is the language of the highest judicial authority in our Commonwealth,
						and as such is binding upon every citizens.</p>
					<p>Summed up in a few words, it means, even granting that Congress may pass an
						Act of disfranchising a citizen for desertion, <emph rend="italic">the fact
							of desertion must be established by proof of the conviction and sentence
							of the deserter by court-martial</emph>. No judge of an Election Board
						dare reject a vote on this ground until such proof is furnished. Without
						such proof, every vote he rejects, he rejects at his peril. </p>
					<p>We come now to the record which the editors of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph> has made for himself upon this question. </p>
					<p>At the session of the State Legislature in the year 1865, a bill was
						introduced providing for the disfranchisement of deserters.</p>
					<p>On pages 611 and 612, of the Legislative Record will be found the remarks of
						Col. McClure on this bill. We regret that we can not give them at length.
						Want of space requires us to content ourselves with a few extracts:</p>
					<p>Mr. McCLURE. Mr. Speaker, the safety of the country, imperiled by civil war,
						is to be found in a faithful adherence to its Constitution, its fundamental
						law. * *</p>
					<p>If it is possible to make a bill clearly and unqualifiedly unconstitutional,
						this bill is so. It is in direct violation of the language and the entire
						spirit of the Constitution. I ask the majority of this House to pause before
						putting upon the statue book a law which the courts of this State, I care
						not how construed, must set aside as an infaction of the organic law of the
						Commonwealth. The Constitution of the State defines the qualifications of an
						elector. This bill proposes to disqualify an elector, in direct opposition
						to the terms of the Constitution. * * * * * * *</p>
					<p>Here you propose to aim a blow at the very heart of the Constitution, by
						providing that a man shall cease to be a citizen if he has disregarded a law
						of Congress. * *</p>
					<p>Why, Mr. Speaker, I profess, as a member of the Legislature, to have some
						knowledge of the Constitution, and I cannot consent to transfer to the
						Supreme Court the performance of the duty which is incumbent upon me to
						determine, in the first instance, the constitutionality of every measure for
						which I vote. If I err in my judgement, the Supreme Court will correct me;
						but I cannot consent to a vote for a bill directly violative of the
						Constitution, and console myself with the refection that the Supreme Court
						will set it right. I beg the gentleman to pause, and not ask a majority of
						the members of this House to stultify themselves by walking squarely into
						the very vitals of the Constitution.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">There is no power in this legislature by which we can
							deprive a</emph> DESERTER <emph rend="italic">of the right of
							citizenship; and so long as he has the</emph> RIGHT <emph rend="italic"
							>of citizenship, he is</emph> ENTITLED TO ALL <emph rend="italic">its
							advantages</emph>. * * </p>
					<p>I MUST, THEREFORE, VOTE AGAINST THIS BILL, THOUGH EVERY MAN ON THIS SIDE OF
						THE HOUSE SHOULD VOTE FOR IT.</p>
					<p>How proud the editor of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> then was of
						his reputation as a lawyer!--With what lofty scorn he informs the gentlemen
						of the House that he has "some knowledge of the Constitution" and that he
						"determines, in the first instance, the constitutionality of every measure
						for which he votes!" We take the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository</emph> at his word. That bill <emph rend="italic">was</emph>
						unconstitutional. This bill which he now sustains is precisely similar in
						its provisions.--Can it be anything else than unconstitutional also? We
						submit to the honest, law-abiding Republican citizens of Franklin county
						whether or not stronger language condemnatory of this bill ever escaped the
						lips of any Democrat than that to which the editor of the Repository has
						given utterance as quoted above. </p>
					<p>But the Act of Congress disfranchising deserters was passed March 3, 1865. An
						Act of the State Legislature followed, providing for the carrying out of the
						provisions of the Act of Congress. Meanwhile the case of Huber vs. Reilly
						had been decided by his Honor Judge King, and preparations were being made
						to carry it to the Supreme Court, Colonel McClure himself being one of the
						counsel for Plaintiff in Error. Governor Curtin hesitated about signing the
						Act passed by the Legislature, doubtless on account of doubt as to its
						constitutionality on his own part, and very likely influenced by the potent
						argument (published in the Legislative Record of 1865) of his intimate
						friend Colonel McClure. But the "loyal soldiery" of the country were soon to
						meet in Convention at Pittsburgh. Intimations were thrown out to the
						Governor that unless he signed this bill, he would be denounced by that
						Convention in unmeasured terms. The bill was signed.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">And then the editor of the Repository took the position
							that if the Act of Congress should fall, the Act of the Legislature
							would amount to nothing</emph>. On the 6th of June last, we find this
						language in the letter of the Harrisburg correspondent of the <emph
							rend="italic">Repository</emph>: </p>
					<p>The Governor has signed the bill of the last legislature, providing for the
						more faithful execution of the law of Congress disfranchising deserters. It
						is expressly predicated upon the act of Congress; recites its title and main
						provision in the preamble and proceeds to define certain duties and
						penalties for public officers to secure the enforcement of the law of
						Congress. If the act of the Congress is not constitutional, then the act of
						the legislature of necessity falls to the ground, for its whole vitality is
						dependent upon the enactment of the general government.</p>
					<p>Not satisfied with this, aiming to create an impression that he was inclined
						to be candid and honest in this matter, on the 13th of the came month, he
						says editorially:</p>
					<p>If the act of Congress disfranchising deserters should be declared
						unconstitutional, then must the act of the late legislature of necessity
						fall with the parent law. It is but an auxiliary to the act of Congress, and
						that the legislature well knew the fact is clearly manifest by its preamble,
						as follows:</p>
					<p>"WHEREAS, By the act of the Congress of the United States, entitled, "An act
						to amend the several acts heretofore passed to provide for the enrolling and
						calling out of the national forces, and for other purposes," and approved
						March 3d, one thousand eight hundred and sixty-five, all persons who have
						deserted the military or naval service of the United States, and who have
						not been discharged or relieved from the penalty or disability therein
						provided, are deemed and taken to have voluntarily relinquished and
						forfeited their rights of citizenship and their rights to become citizens,
						and are deprived of exercising any rights of citizens thereof:</p>
					<p>"<emph rend="italic">And Whereas</emph>, Persons not citizens of the United
						States are not, under the constitution and laws of Pennsylvania, qualified
						electors of this Commonwealth." </p>
					<p>It Will be seen that the legislation of the Stale is distinctly predicated on
						the law of Congress, and properly so. <emph rend="italic">No lawyer would
							pretend to assume that the legislature of</emph> 1866 <emph
							rend="italic">could define and enforce new penalties for offences
							committed in</emph> 1864 <emph rend="italic">or</emph> 1863, AND FOR A
						JOURNAL OR POLITICIAN TO INSIST THAT SUCH WAS THE INTENTION OF THE
						LEGISLATURE, IS TO BETRAY A MOST LAMENTABLE IGNORANCE OF WELL SETTLED RULES
						OF LAW, AND TO MAKE A SEVERE DRAFT UPON THE SUPPOSED DISPOISITON OF THE
						PEOPLE TO ACCEPT OR REJECT THE LAWS OF THE LAND AS THEIR POLTIICAL
						PREJUDICES MAY DICTATE. </p>
					<p>Can language be stronger? The Supreme Court of the State has said that under
						the Act of Congress, the man who has not been convicted of desertion by a
						court martial has a right to vote. Will Colonel McClure "pretend to assume
						that the Legislature of 1866 could define and enforce new penalties for
						ofences committed in 1864 or 1865?" Or that the Judges of Election can take
						less proof of desertion under the act of the Legislature than is required
						under the Act of Congress? But Colonel McClure gives further evidence of his
						disbelief in the binding effect of the Act of the Legislature. After the
						decision was announced in Huber vs. Reilly, to wit, on the 27th of June
						last, he says in his paper:</p>
					<p>It is true that we have an act of the last legislature imposing penalties
						upon election officers for accepting such votes, and also upon deserters for
						offering their votes; and that law, being as yet unquestioned judicially, is
						the law of the State; but the recent decision of course declares in advance
						that the act of the State will be set aside as soon as the Supreme Court can
						get a chance to do so.</p>
					<p>And yet, although expressing the conviction that "the Act of the State will
						be set aside as soon as the Supreme Court can get a chance to do so," he
						counsels the Judge of Elections that this is their duty to carry out the
						provisions of this Act.</p>
					<p>What shameless audacity! Regardless of his own private declarations made to
						numbers of our citizens that this Act of the Legislature is utterly null and
						void; regardless of his utterances as published in the Legislative Record,
						that such an Act as this one in question is clearly unconstitutional
						regardless of his editorial statements to the same effect; in open defiance
						of the decision of the Supreme Court of the State in a case which he took
						before that Court himself, Col. McClure has the effrontery now, for base
						partisan purposes to advise honest citizens to do, what he believes, and has
						declared to be, illegal and unconstitutional.--He has sunk his manhood. He
						has given the lie to his professions of candor and honesty. He has
						condescended to practice deception upon the men of his party who look to him
						for honest counsel. It seems strange indeed that for the purpose of
						attaining political ends, men will sometimes "throw conscience to the dogs"
						and become as unscrupulous as the Devil himself.</p>
					<p>We have exposed the duplicity of the editor of the <emph rend="italic"
							>Repository </emph>. We have shown his own record. We now say to the
						Judges of the Election in Franklin county. The man who has been convicted
						and sentenced by a court martial for desertion, has no right to vote. If
						that fact is proven to you, reject his vote. <emph rend="italic">If the
							proof is not clear against a citizen</emph> THAT HE HAS BEEN CONVICTED
						OF DESERTION BY A COURT-MARTIAL AND SENTENCED TO THE FORFEITURES AND
						PENALTIES OF THAT CRIME, YOU MUST ACCEPT HIS VOTE. The Democracy have
						determined that no man shall go unpunished who deprives a single citizen of
						his vote on the ground of desertion without clear proof of his conviction
						and sentence by a court martial.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>After delivering a rebuke to the editor of the Repository for his alleged
					about-face on the issue, the editorial condemns Republican attempts to
					disfranchise deserters as unconstitutional.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>3</column>
				<head>A Card From Post-Master Deal</head>
				<origin>Repository</origin>
				<commentary>"The following card, written by A. K. McClure and signed by John W.
					Deal, appeared in last week's Repository:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p><emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository</emph>: Having
						been selected by the Central Committee of the National Union Party, without
						any knowledge and consent, a delegate to the late Philadelphia Convention
						which had called the convention, was a loyal party, with loyal principles
						and could not make common cause with traitors and copperheads. </p>
					<p>In that convention no word was uttered against treason, no word of cheer or
						assurance of protection was given to the loyal men now oppressed by traitors
						in the South, and its chief work was to form a coalition with unrepentant
						enemies of the government to restore them to honor and power.--Nor did it
						stop with the principle that traitors must be restored to the power they
						used to betray the Union into the power of treason, but the National Union
						party was transferred bodily to the copperheads in the North, and the demand
						made that the friends of the administration must support the copperhead
						candidates for Governor, Congress and the Legislature. Having long cherished
						political convictions which are not in harmony with the principles of the
						administration as now declared, it is but an act of justice to myself to say
						that I shall hereafter, as heretofore, cordially support the entire Union
						ticket and give my best efforts for its success. If for thus maintaining
						fidelity to the principles taught the nation by Andrew Johnson, I shall
						prove offensive to his administration as an official, my place is at his
						disposal, but my convictions and my sense of duty are my own.</p>
					<p>JOHN W. DEAL.</p>
					<p>Chambersburg, August 25, 186.</p>
					<p>In the face of the facts which are well known to everybody in this community,
						the publication of the above card is decidedly cool, and must have required
						a degree of assurance that we did not suppose even Mr. Deal possessed. It is
						not a pleasant duty for us to expose the shameless hypocrisy and deception,
						not to say knavery, which it is known Mr. Deal has been practicing for two
						or three months past in order to retain possession of the Post Office. But
						as he has voluntarily, and we think, imprudently put himself into print, he
						must abide by the consequences, and not complain if the record which we
						shall truthfully make for him is not calculated to elevate him in the
						estimation of high-minded and honorable men.</p>
					<p>And now let us look at the facts of the case. Some two or three months ago
						Mr. Deal conceived the idea, or rather it was suggested to him by another
						more practiced in these arts than himself, (our readers can easily guess
						who?) of securing his re-appointment as Post Master by deceiving the
						Administration as to his position on the great issues of the day. To this
						end an agent, whom we will not name, was sent to Washington to carry the
						scheme into effect. The agent succeeded in "shutting the eyes" of Senator
						Cowan and Montgomery Blair, who were induced to believe that Mr. Deal was an
						ardent and earnest supporter of the President's policy. Subsequently,
						however, he received a very pointed letter from the Post Master General
						asking him to define his position in writing. This letter he showed to a
						prominent republican of this place and told him of the plan he had adopted
						or rather that had been suggested to him by the man behind the scene, for
						deceiving the Post Master General. And that was put on a bold face in his
						reply, referring Mr. Randall in confident terms to Mr. Cowan and Mr. Blair
						for information in regard to his political <emph rend="italic"
						>status</emph>. Mr. Randall, supposing him to be "all right," if Messrs.
						Cowan and Blair endorsed him, sent in his appointment. Thus his nomination
						to the Senate was secured. He then got his radical friends here to write
						letters to Senator Wilson and other radical Senators assuring them that he
						was "all right" with them too. In this way he secured his confirmation by
						the Senate. Great chuckling and rejoicing was indulged in radical circles
						over the successful accomplishment of this great act of deception and fraud,
						and many were the witty remarks perpetrated by the "head devil" in the
						business at the expense of prominent Democrats who were supposed to have
						been so completely out-witted. </p>
					<p>But it was soon found that it was one thing to obtain an appointment by
						practicing deception, and quite another and more difficult thing to retain
						it by such means.--Troubles began to loom up almost immediately. Orders were
						received by Mr. Deal to attend the Philadelphia Convention. Here was trouble
						sure. They demanded a <emph rend="italic">public</emph> acknowledgment of
						his faith. How could he do this and retain his standing as a sound radical.
						He flew to his great counselor for advice. The advice was characteristic of
						the giver. "Go to the Convention, keep your mouth shut, come home and
						practice the deception to the end." He went, but like many other hardened
						sinners who have gone to protracted meetings determined to persist in their
						sins and yet returned home converts to the truth. Mr. Deal, on the first day
						of the Convention, was smitten with conviction, and on the second day
						publicly professed an entire <emph rend="italic">change of heart</emph> on
						the political questions of the day. On the evening of the second day of the
						Convention he came to the writer of this article, at the Merchant's Hotel,
						and voluntarily made the following statement, in substance, to wit: "I came
						here without the least expectation of being able to give the action of the
						Convention my approval. I so told my friends before I left home. But since
						my arrival here, hearing Gov. Orr's speech, and seeing the spirit of genuine
						patriotism and sincerity which seems to animate the delegates representing
						the Southern States, and the spirit concession and conciliation prevailing
						on every hand and among all parties represented in the Convention, I confess
						that my prejudices have <emph rend="italic">all been removed</emph>. I feel
						that I can <emph rend="italic">heartily support Mr. Sharpe for
						Congress</emph>, and as for Geary and Clymer, I prefer supporting Clymer for
						the reason they are both Democrats, and I believe Clymer to be an <emph
							rend="italic">honest man</emph>, whilst Geary is not." This Statement we
						are willing to substantiate by affidavit if necessary. He afterwards had an
						interview with William M'Lellan, Esq., in his room at the Merchant's Hotel,
						where he made substantially the same statement. He openly avowed himself a
						convert to the policy of the Administration, in the hotels and on the
						streets of Philadelphia, to every acquaintance with whom he came in contact.
						His endorsement of the action of the Convention and his open declarations in
						favor of the conservative cause after his return home are familiar to all
						our citizens, and need not be repeated here. He even went so far as to go
						into conference with some of our leading Democrats, and counseled them in
						relation to the plans of the campaign, all the while professing his entire
						willingness to co-operate with them cordially and in good faith. But
						scarcely a week had elapsed before it was rumored that, like "the old dog
						returning to his vomit and the sow to her wallowing in the mire." he had
						backslidden from the faith he had so lately professed affording another
						striking illustration of the truth of the adage that "sudden conversions are
						seldom lasting." Under the influence of a pressure which he had not the
						moral courage to resist, and through the manipulation of his master behind
						the curtain, these rumors soon culminated in reality in the appearance of
						the card which we have quoted at the beginning of this article. </p>
					<p>Such are the facts of the case. We have made statements reluctantly, for we
						wish it to be understood that towards Mr. Deal personally we cherish none
						but the kindest feelings. We would not have exposed the vacillation, the
						weakness and the folly of hi course, had not the publishers of his
						hypocritical card made it an imperative duty on our part. We could not, if
						we would, permit a false impression to go abroad in regard to this matter,
						without an effort to counteract its evil influence. The cause of Truth and
						Right demanded that the exposure should be made, and we have now performed
						what we conceived to be our duty honestly, fearlessly and truthfully.--For
						his sake, and for his only, we could have wished that he acted more
						consistently. As for the Democracy, his going back to his "first love" was a
						great relief to them--it was positively an act of kindness towards them,
						though doubtless not so intended by him. During the few brief days of his
						conservatism it became pretty well established that he could control no vote
						but his own, and even his own was from the first considered by many as <emph
							rend="italic">doubtful</emph>. But admitting that <emph rend="italic"
							>his</emph> vote would have been sure, according to promise, to pay two
						thousand dollars a year for one vote was thought to be rather steep. Hence
						universal joy prevailed in Conservative circles when the announcement was
						made that he had gone back. </p>
					<p>The record of "Post Master Deal" is before the public. We are willing that
						the public shall judge whether he has come out of the conflict with clean
						hands and unsullied honor?</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McClure</ln>
						<fn>A. K.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deal</ln>
						<fn>John W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Recounts the politcal conversion and reversion of J. W. Deal, who, the
					article maintains, became a loyal Johnson supporter to keep his appointment
					before returning back to the Republican fold.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>5</column>
				<head>The County Ticket</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>The Democratic County Convention which met in this place on Tuesday of last
						week, to nominate a ticket to be supported at the ensuing election, on the
						second Tuesday of October next, performed its work well. The ticket formed
						is among the strongest that has been put forward by either party for some
						years. The gentlemen comprising it are all men of high character, enjoying
						the unbounded confidence and respect of the communities in which they
						reside, and are will qualified to perform the duties of the various
						positions for which they have been named. It is emphatically a strong
						ticket, and by a thorough organization and faithful exertions on the part of
						our friends throughout the county, it can easily be elected.</p>
					<p>The nomination of Gen. R. W. McAllen for the Legislature, is one that was
						pre-eminently fit to be made. Gen. McAllen was amnng the first in this
						county to respond to the call of his country for volunteers in the spring of
						1861, to defend the capital of the nation against the assaults of the rebel
						insurgents. He organized, immediately after the bombardments of Fort Sumter,
						a regiment of men who were encamped for several weeks at "Camp McAllen,"
						west of town awaiting orders to march to the front, but through some
						misunderstanding with the military authorities, the regiment was not
						accepted. Sometime afterwards he, in connection with others, organized the
						107th regiment. He was elected and commissioned Lieutenant Colonel of the
						regiment, and marched with it to the front. This regiment did heroic service
						in defence of the Union, participating in some of the hardest fought battles
						of the war. It was in the battle of Cedar Mountain, along with Pope in his
						disastrous campaign, which ended in the second defeat at "Bull Run," and
						also in the great battles of South Mountain and Antietam. All through these
						terrible engagements, Col. McAllen was constantly with his regiment, the
						command frequently devolving upon him in the absence of the Colonel. Shortly
						after the battle of Antietam, his health, naturally delicate, having become
						very much impaired from exposure in the camp and field, he was compelled to
						resign his commission and return home.--Col. McAllen has been a brave and
						faithful solider, and the gallant soldiers of this legislative district will
						not fail to give him an enthusiastic support at the polls. AS a citizen he
						stands no less high than as a soldier. He is loved and respected by all who
						know him as a man of stern integrity, ability and purity of private
						character. He is deserving of the vote of every honest and patriotic man in
						the district.</p>
					<p>His associate on the ticket for Assembly, Thomas Adams, Esq., of Perry, we do
						not know personally, but learn that he is a substantial farmer of Perry
						county, enjoying a high reputation for honesty and integrity, in the
						community in which he lives, and will make an excellent and efficient
						Representative.</p>
					<p>Our candidate for Associate Judge, Wm. D. McKinstry, Esq., is well known to
						the people of this county. He filled the office of County Treasurer a few
						years ago with great credit to himself, and for the best interests of the
						tax payers of the county. He has been tried in a responsible position and
						proved faithful to the people's interests, and the people will not now turn
						their backs upon him. His election is certain.</p>
					<p>H. C. Keyser, Esq., our candidate for Prothonotary, being one of the editors
						and proprietors of this paper, it might not be considered appropriate or
						modest to say much in his praise in these columns. Suffice it to say that he
						filled the position once for the full term of three years, to the entire
						satisfaction as far as we know, of the court, and the people of the county,
						and we hazard nothing in saying that, if elected, he will do so again.</p>
					<p>For Register and Recorder no better nomination could have been made. Daniel
						Gelwix of Letterkenny, is a plain, honest, hardworking mechanic. He has
						literally fulfilled the scriptures, during a life of more than fifty years,
						in earning his bread by the sweat of his brow. Mechanics and workingmen of
						Franklin County, this is a nomination which appeals directly to your
						sympathies and your pride. Rally to his support as one man, and vindicate
						the honor and respectability of your calling by rolling up an overwhelming
						majority for one of your own numbers. Letterkenny is god for 150.</p>
					<p>John L. Deitrich, of St. Thomas, is the nominee for Clerk of the Courts. He
						too is a soldier who has seen service. He is also a mechanic, and is now
						earning a livelihood by daily working at his trade as carpenter. His fellow
						soldiers and mechanics will see to it that he is triumphantly elected. His
						clerical abilities are of the first order, and he is in every way well
						qualified to discharge the duties of the office faithfully and well.</p>
					<p>John Lindsay, of Green, for Commissioner, John Small, of Quincy, for Director
						of the Poor, and William D. Guthrie, of Chambersburg, for Auditor, and are
						all "good men and true," and will make honest, faithful and efficient
						officers.</p>
					<p>Such, Democrats and Conservative men of Franklin County, is the ticket
						presented for your suffrage. Rally in your strength to its support. Organize
						in every election district at once. Be earnest, be vigilant, be active. Push
						forward the whole column for the whole ticket. See to it that not a man is
						sacrificed. Let not a single name be scratched, but vote the entire ticket
						as it came from the hands of the Convention.--Do your whole duty manfully
						and faithfully as becomes men engaged in a great and holy cause, and a
						glorious triumph will crown your labors on the evening of the second Tuesday
						of next month.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>McAllen</ln>
						<fn>R. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McKinstry</ln>
						<fn>William D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Keyser</ln>
						<fn>H. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gelwix</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Deitrich</ln>
						<fn>John L.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Lindsay</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Small</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Guthrie</ln>
						<fn>William D.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Provides a brief biography/endorsement of each of the Democratic nominees
					for office from Franklin county.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>6</column>
				<head>Resolution</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary>"The following preamble and resolutions were unanimously adopted at the
					Democratic County Convention last week:"</commentary>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, The Democratic and Conservative citizens
						of Franklin county have witnessed with inexpressible pleasure the meeting of
						the National Union Convention in the city of Philadelphia, and noted with
						pride its harmonious action and glorious results; and </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, The delaration of principles and purposes
						there unanimously adopted and published to the world, are eminently wise and
						patriotic, and should receive the unqualified and cordial approval and
						support of every citizen who has the true interest of the Union at heart;
						therefore be it </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, That we call particular attention to that
						portion of the Declaration which says "representation in the Congress of the
						United States, and in the electoral college is a right recognized by the
						Constitution and abiding in every State, and is a duty imposed upon the
						people, fundamental in its nature and essential to the existence of our
						republican institutions." </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Whereas</emph>, That in Andrew Johnson, the President of
						the United States, we have a man fully adequate to discharge the high and
						responsible duties of that office, a man of unselfish patriotism and
						sterling worth, whose whole course in public life has demonstrated his
						attachment and devotion to the Constitution and the Union, and whose plan of
						reconstruction establishes his wisdom, foresight, and statesmanship, and
						must succeed; and we tender to him our earnest co-operation in his patriotic
						efforts to preserve intact the Constitution, protect and guard the rights of
						States, secure peace and harmony throughout the Union and elevate us as a
						nation to a degree of prosperity and greatness unexampled in the history of
						the world. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we recognize in Hiester Clymer the
						democratic candidate for Governor, a man of high and unspotted character, a
						democrat of true and tried fidelity--an able and fearless champion of the
						rights of the States in the Union, and of the rights of the citizen in the
						States. The freemen of Pennsylvania will elevate him to that high position
						which his virtues and statesmanship will so much adorn, by an oldfashioned
						Jackson majority of fifty thousand. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we hail with feelings of pride and
						admiration the nomination of J. McDowell Sharpe, for Congress, a pure man
						and a true democrat, an able lawyer and a profound thinker. In the councils
						of the nation his learning and eloquence will reflect credit upon his
						constituency and will plead with persuasive and political voice for the
						integrity of the Constitution and the perpetuity of the Union. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That we will give our hearty and united
						support, to the ticket this day put in nomination, and will labor with
						unbending zeal to secure its triumphant election. </p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the thanks of this Convention be,
						and are hereby tendered to the Hon. George W. Brewer, Chairman, for the very
						able and eloquent address delivered on this occasion and for the efficient
						manner in which he has presided over the deliberation of this body. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Includes a copy of the resolutions adopted by the Democratic County
					Convention.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="e">
				<column>6</column>
				<head/>
				<origin>Repository</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>IT is with inexpressible mortification that we are compelled, as truthful
						chroniclers, to state that the celebration of the colored people, on the 1st
						of August, passed off without any riot or drunkenness or fighting; whereas
						on the Saturday when Mr. Light went up in his balloon, the white citizens
						spent enough for liquor to employ a first class teacher or preacher for a
						whole year. In a few years, if we progress, a Darkey mother will whip her
						boy if she sees him playing with white children. We have a suggestion to
						make to those who were opposed to the negro procession. Long time ago, in
						Scotland, the rival clans gave so much trouble and annoyance to the
						government that they determined to let them fight it out with champions
						selected from both sides. The plan was perfected, <emph rend="italic">and
							both sides got enough</emph>. </p>
					<p>We reproduce the above from the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> of a
						few weeks ago, in order that our readers may know in what estimation they
						are held by our neighbor. In the above extract, the negro is held up as a
						pattern of sobriety and a model of good behavior, worthy of all imitation,
						whilst our white citizens, are, in effect, stigmatized as drunken rowdies.
						If negro suffrage be not an issue in the elections this fall, as is asserted
						by the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> and kindred journals, negro
							<emph rend="italic">equality</emph> certainly is not. The above places
						the negro in such apposition of <emph rend="italic">superiority</emph> that
						our debased white race can scarcely hope to attain anything near it.--White
						men of Franklin county, what do you think of the position accorded you by
						the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph>? Will you support a party whose
						organ places you lower in the scale of morality than the miserable African? </p>
					<p>As to the "suggestion" made in the extract, we think that if acted upon the
						writer of the above were one of the champions he would act much in the same
						manner as the young chief of the <emph rend="italic">Clan Quehole</emph> in
						the famous contest alluded to. </p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Using an extract from the Repository in which whites are admonished to
					behave with more decorum when in public, the Spirit chastises its rival for
					asserting that blacks act more dignified than whites.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>8</column>
				<head/>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Informs white men that the Pay Department is preparing to disburse bounties
					to black soldiers as prescribed by the Congressional Act of June 26th, which
					will total around $20,000,000.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.22.03">
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Democratic County Committee</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Kimmel</ln>
						<fn>H. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>White</ln>
						<fn>H. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Duncan</ln>
						<fn>Calvin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Martin</ln>
						<fn>Alex</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shilloh</ln>
						<fn>J. N.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>West</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Goshorn</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Orr</ln>
						<fn>James B.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>McCurdy</ln>
						<fn>R. C.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brendle</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rodes</ln>
						<fn>C. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hays</ln>
						<fn>J. W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Nickodemus</ln>
						<fn>Samuel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Boyd</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gillan</ln>
						<fn>John</fn>
						<sf>Jr.</sf>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Piles</ln>
						<fn>William</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Hunter</ln>
						<fn>William A.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Dr.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Elliot</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stake</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Simmons</ln>
						<fn>John S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Small</ln>
						<fn>E. J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Brewer</ln>
						<fn>Denton</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Johnston</ln>
						<fn>George</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ritchie</ln>
						<fn>D. F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Howe</ln>
						<fn>Wesley</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Skinner</ln>
						<fn>Henry</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists the members of the Democratic County Executive Committee.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Turn Soldiers</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Announces that a meeting of honorably discharged soldiers "favorable to the
					policy of President Johnson, and the election of Hiester Clymer" will take place
					at the Court House on Sept. 5th. The objective of the meeting is to organize a
					permanent Johnson and Clymer Club.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Hon. Montgomery Blair</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names/>
				<summary>Reports that Montgomery Blair, a "distinguished advocate of President
					Johnson's Restoration Policy," will be speaking in Chambersburg on Sept. 6th at
					the Court House.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Teachers' Institute</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shoemaker</ln>
						<fn>P. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Gaff</ln>
						<fn>J. R.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>States that the Franklin County Teachers Institute will hold a five-day
					seminar in Greencastle on November 12th.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--A Uniform Series of School Books</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript>
					<p>At a meeting in this place, on the 31st ult., of delegates appointed to
						recommend a uniform series of School Books for Franklin county it was
						resolved that the following series be recommended for adoption:</p>
					<p>Osgood's Speller and Reader; Gould and Brown's English Grammar; Martindale's
						U. S. History; Goodriches' General History; Webster's Dictionary; Dean's
						Series of Arithmetics; Davies' Algebra; Brook's Normal Geometry; Potter
						&amp; Hammon's Penmanship; Mitchell's Geographies (new series); Warren's
						Physical Geographies; Smith's Astronomy; Natural Philosophy, [UNCLEAR] ;
						Peterson's Familiar Science; Cutter's Physiology; Mayhew's Book Keeping;
						Shepard's Constitutional Text Book; Apgar's Geographical Drawing Book.</p>
					<p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That the county papers be requested to
						publish the proceedings of this Convention. P. M. Shoemaker, </p>
					<p>HENRY ONWAER, SEC. President.</p>
				</transcript>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Shoemaker</ln>
						<fn>P. M.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Lists the books used by the Franklin county schools.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="a">
				<column>1</column>
				<head>Local and Personal--Serious Accident</head>
				<origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Myers</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Miss</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ditch</ln>
						<fn/>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Mrs.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Ditch</ln>
						<fn>Jacob</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Myers</ln>
						<fn>Daniel</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>Reports that an accident involving two women, Miss Myers and Mrs. Ditch,
					occurred when the buggy they were riding in was upset while they were on their
					home from town.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Buckingham</ln>
						<fn>N. S.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Rupert</ln>
						<fn>Charles</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Shillito</ln>
						<fn>Nellie</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 14th, Charles Rupert, of York, and Nellie Shillito were married
					by Rev. N. S. Buckingham.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dyson</ln>
						<fn>F.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Vandaraw</ln>
						<fn>Franklin</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Mowers</ln>
						<fn>Maria</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 30th, Franklin Vandaraw and Maria Mowers, of Fayetteville, were
					married by Rev. F. Dyson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Roth</ln>
						<fn>G.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Harper</ln>
						<fn>George W.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Franklin</ln>
						<fn>Elizabeth</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 22nd, George Harper, of Adams county, and Elizabeth Franklin were
					married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<div type="s">
				<column>4</column>
				<head>Married</head>
				<origin/>
				<commentary/>
				<excerpt/>
				<transcript/>
				<trailer/>
				<names>
					<name>
						<ln>Dickson</ln>
						<fn>J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf>Rev.</pf>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Miller</ln>
						<fn>George H.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
					<name>
						<ln>Stoops</ln>
						<fn>Mary J.</fn>
						<sf/>
						<pf/>
					</name>
				</names>
				<summary>On August 30th, George Miller and Mary J. Stoops were married by Rev. J.
					Dickson.</summary>
				<note/>
				<look/>
			</div>
			<pageNote/>
		</page>
		<page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.05.04">
			<pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
		</page>
	</paperBody>
</hwp>
