<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.11.14">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/01/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-11-14">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="11"/>
            <day norm="00">14</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>4</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.14.01">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.14.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The November Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece provides a brief breakdown of the congressional elections held
                    November 6th, and labels the Radicals' victory as "dark and appalling."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>What is Loyalty?</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The term loyalty has been so flippantly used by our Republican friends during
                        the last five or six years that it may be profitable to inquire into its
                        meaning. In monarchical governments the term "loyalty" is used to indicate
                        fidelity or attachment to the person of the King or reigning sovereign.
                        During our late war it was used by republican politicians and demagogues to
                        denote support of the President of the United States, and unqualified
                        acquiescence in all his ministerial acts. To doubt the wisdom of his policy
                        was at once pronounced disloyalty, if not rank treason.--No one was
                        considered loyal who failed to give his assent and support to <emph
                            rend="italic">all</emph> the acts of the President. This was the theory
                        advanced by the leaders of the Republican party during the war and
                        acquiesced in by the rank and file of the party all over the country. </p>
                    <p>But how is it now? A change seems to have come over the spirit of the dreams
                        of these gentlemen. They still prate about loyalty as loudly as ever, but
                        what was loyalty then is treason now, and what was treason then, through
                        some mysterious process of transformation has become the most sublime
                        loyalty! Support of the President <emph rend="italic">then</emph> was proof
                        sufficient of a man's patriotism, support of the President <emph
                            rend="italic">now</emph> is all the evidence needed to prove him a
                        traitor. </p>
                    <p>The term "loyalty," if its use be allowable at all in this country, must mean
                        fidelity to the Government of the United States, or in other words to the
                        Constitution of the United States, the instrument upon which the government
                        is founded, and without which it could not exist. As before observed, during
                        the war our Republican friends contended that, the President being the
                        representative of the Government, support of his policy and acts as the true
                        test of loyalty, whilst the Democratic party adhered to the old fogy notion
                        that the Constitution was higher than the President, and that a faithful
                        observation of its provisions was the only rule by which a man's patriotism
                        could be judged. Tried by either of these tests the Republican party will be
                        found wanting. If fidelity to the President be the test then is it the most
                            <emph rend="italic">disloyal</emph> party that ever existed in this
                        country, for no party ever displayed so much bitter and malignant hostility
                        towards a Chief Magistrate of the nation as it to-day displays towards
                        President Jackson. If fidelity to the Constitution be the true test, as
                        contended for by the Democrats, then it is equally disloyal, because it is
                        the declared purpose of its leaders to subvert and change that instrument by
                        means of amendments, and because they have flagrantly violated one of its
                        plainest provisions by denying representation in Congress to ten States of
                        the American Union. If the Republican party is a <emph rend="italic"
                        >loyal</emph> party, as it claims to be, we would like to know in what its
                        loyalty consists? </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During the past few turbulent years, notes the editor, the Republicans'
                    definition of "loyalty" has morphed and evolved largely as a result of their
                    political standing. While Lincoln was alive, Republicans branded anyone critical
                    of the president's policies a traitor; they abandoned this position, however,
                    following Johnson's ascendance to the presidency.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates the results of the election in Maryland, which was carried by the
                    Democrats and Conservatives. The outcome, says the article, guarantees the
                    elimination of the Registry Law and secures for "every man who has the right to
                    vote the privilege to cast his ballot according to the dictates of his
                    conscience."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How Things Will Stand In The Next Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Although the returns of the late election come in quite slowly, the political
                        complexion of the next Congress can be ascertained almost with certainty.
                        The popular interest having centered in the choice of Representatives we
                        refer first to the House, the political status of which is given in the
                        following table:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>D.</cell>
                            <cell>R.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Delaware</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Illinois</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>11</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Indiana</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>8</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Iowa</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Kansas</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Maine</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Maryland</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Massachusetts</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>10</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Michigan</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Minnesota</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Missouri</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Jersey</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New York</cell>
                            <cell>12</cell>
                            <cell>19</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Ohio</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell>16</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>Oregon</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Pennsylvania</cell>
                            <cell>6</cell>
                            <cell>18</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Vermont</cell>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>West Virginia</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Wisconsin</cell>
                            <cell>1</cell>
                            <cell>5</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell cellspan="2">RECAPITULATION:</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Democrats</cell>
                            <cell>38</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Republicans</cell>
                            <cell>133</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The States yet to elect Representatives in the Fortieth Congress, and the
                        number of members to which they are entitled are as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>California</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Connecticut</cell>
                            <cell>4</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Kentucky</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>New Hampshire</cell>
                            <cell>3</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Rhode Island</cell>
                            <cell>2</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>21</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>Estimating the result of the election in these States as that of the last
                        Congressional election, excepting that in Kentucky, which recently chose a
                        Democrat to fill the vacancy in the Sixth District occasioned by the
                        resignation of Hon. Green Clay Smith (Republican), the grand result will be
                        as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Democrats</cell>
                            <cell>45</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Republicans</cell>
                            <cell>137</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>This, of course, will give the Republicans a majority in the House and plenty
                        to spare, so they will have everything their own way in the Fortieth, as
                        they have now in the Thirty-ninth Congress.</p>
                    <p>In the United States Senate there are eleven Senators to be chosen this
                        winter by the Legislatures of the following States, to wit:</p>
                    <p>Illinois, vice Lyman Trumbull, R.</p>
                    <p>Indiana, vice Henry Lane, R</p>
                    <p>Samuel C. Pomeroy, R.</p>
                    <p>Kansas, vice{ James H. Lane. R.</p>
                    <p>Maryland, vice John A. J. Creswell, R.</p>
                    <p>Missouri, vice R. Graiz Brown, R.</p>
                    <p>New Jersey, vice William Wright, D.</p>
                    <p>New York, vice Ira Harris, R.</p>
                    <p>Ohio, vice John Sherman, R.</p>
                    <p>Pennsylvania, vice Edgar Cowan, R.</p>
                    <p>Wisconsin, vice Timothy O. Howe, R.</p>
                    <p>*Deceased.</p>
                    <p>It is probable that, except in the case of Senator Cresswell, of Maryland,
                        every Republican Senator in the above list will either be re-elected or
                        replaced by a Radical; and on the other side, the seats of Edgar Cowan, of
                        Pennsylvania, and the late William Wright, of New Jersey, will be filled by
                        Radicals. Maryland of course, will elect a Conservative in place of John A.
                        J. Creswell, providing that the Radicals in that State do not succeed by
                        some hocus pocus arrangement in ousting the Conservative members of the
                        Legislature who were chosen on Tuesday. Should this forecast prove correct
                        the political complexion of the Senate will be as follows:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Democrats</cell>
                            <cell>9</cell>
                            <cell>Republicans</cell>
                            <cell>41</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>The gist, then, of the whole story is that for the next three years the
                        Radicals will have complete control of the legislation in the House of
                        Representatives, and of that in the Senate for a longer period. With them,
                        therefore, the responsibility of the acts of Congress must rest, and the
                        country will hold them accountable both for the wrong that they may do and
                        the right that they may leave undone. We can only hope that, impressed with
                        the grave responsibility now devolved upon them, they will manifest more
                        regard for the real interests of the country, irrespective of their party,
                        than they have done in the past. But we fear that this hope will prove
                    vain.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Offers a preview of the composition of the next Congress, which the
                    Republicans will dominate for at least the next three years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Cotton Crop of the United States</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The cotton crop of the United States is of the greatest importance, both in a
                        commercial and financial point of view. It is so much capital to the nation
                        at a time when it is needed to repair the damage of the past, and infuse
                        life, confidence and animation into the future. The cotton statement of the
                        Charleston <emph rend="italic">Courier</emph> for November 1, estimates the
                        crop for 1866-7 at a million and a half of bales as the maximum, and a
                        million as the minimum. On the 1st of September the estimate was fixed at a
                        higher figure. Then the maximum was placed at two millions of bales, and the
                        minimum at a million and a half of bales. The difference between the two
                        estimate is occasioned by circumstances effecting the growth and development
                        of the cotton crop, and unforeseen calamities may still further reduce the
                        estimate made at the beginning of the present month. The <emph rend="italic"
                            >Courier</emph>] very properly remarks that no estimate is good except
                        for the time when it is made, and continues: </p>
                    <p>The causes, however, of the present anxiety must give place to that
                        uncertainty with regard to the future which must render cotton cultivation
                        the most uncertain of human pursuits. Labor will form an element of so much
                        importance that, until the competition between its relative cost in British
                        India and the United States is determined, no just conclusion can be arrived
                        at, on the subject of the ability of the United States to maintain such
                        competition. Voluntary labor in British India previous to emancipation was
                        much lower than enforced labor in the United States. Since emancipation the
                        disparity has much increased.</p>
                    <p>The Southern Planter has, in fact, to sustain double competition: 1. From the
                        East India Grower, where the cost of cultivation is limited from the lower
                        price of labor; 2. From the manufacturers of woolen, linen, and silk
                        fabrics, which are employed as substitute for cotton goods when the price of
                        such goods is high in consequence of the advance of the raw material</p>
                    <p>The fact that there is a point where the price of cotton will limit the
                        demand for the article, is beginning to challenge the attention of cotton
                        growers, and to affect their action. People will substitute fabrics composed
                        of wool flax and linen, mixed with cotton, when the latter articles are
                        forced up to too high a figure. A recent writer upon this subject remarks
                        that "the day that cotton is much higher in market than flax, silk or wool,
                        is the time when these fabrics will successfully compete with cotton, and
                        begin to take their place as part of the apparel of the people of the
                        earth." The indications are that such a time is approaching, and hence the
                        interest manifested in the cotton growing regions to adopt some system of
                        labor by which the crop can be increased, and at the same time sold at a
                        reduced price.</p>
                    <p>An investigation into the amount of cotton consumed in Europe shows that the
                        rate of increase has been seriously misstated. The total consumption in
                        thirty years has been seventy-four and a half millions of bales.--The
                        increase from 1831 to 1840, was three and a third per cent. From the latter
                        year to 1550, there was a decrease of one and a quarter percent. In the
                        following ten years the increase was four and a third per cent. It will thus
                        be seen that the yearly average increase in thirty years has been a fraction
                        less than three per cent. This is but a trifling improvement when all the
                        circumstances surrounding the case are taken into consideration.</p>
                    <p>The question, at what price cotton can be produced in the United States at
                        the present time, naturally connects itself with the former view of the
                        consumption of the article. On this point a writer in <emph rend="italic">De
                            Bow's Review</emph> for November remarks: </p>
                    <p>We think one thing, at least, will be conceded by all those who have had any
                        experience in the cultivation of cotton, and that is unless those who make
                        it can receive more remunerating prices than are now being paid, the
                        production must rapidly decline, and none will be more ready to admit this
                        than these who, having no knowledge of the mode of cultivation, have blindly
                        rushed into the field with visions of the golden harvest they were to
                        reap.--After deducting the three cent-per pound tax, which, of course, must
                        come out of the pocket of the producer, and other expenses incident to the
                        shipment, and sale of his cotton, but little is left to the planter as net
                        gains at thirty cents per pound, when, by the way, is rather more than he
                        can expect, with the present market. The highest quality will not be higher
                        than what is styled in the market "low middling," or "good ordinary," for
                        which, at the present rate, he could not expect more than 27 or 28 cents per
                        pound or about 20 cents net, which can be but barely more than the cost of
                        production.</p>
                    <p>The same person ignores the views of certain ignorant persons, "that a new
                        and glorious era is opened to the South by the abolition of a wasteful and
                        iniquitous system of labor, and with free and enlightened emigrant labor the
                        South will send yearly to market twenty bales of cotton for every one
                        heretofore seen," and concludes as follows:</p>
                    <p>Unless some new system does take the place of the one now existing the
                        production of the country must greatly decrease, and some of us may yet live
                        to see the day when pound of Southern cotton will be worth its weight in
                        paper money, which, indeed would be no now sight.</p>
                    <p>Those who really desire the country the advance in material prosperity, must
                        see the necessity of national repose, in order that the labor system of the
                        South may be reorganized and the cotton crop raised again to its old
                        standard of importance. If all the freedmen of the South were employed, the
                        price of producing cotton could be reduced. This would increase the demand,
                        and in that way both the grower and the country would be benefited. The
                        Radicals prefer party to patriotism, and while they rule the people must
                            suffer.--<emph rend="italic">Age</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Facing increased competition on the world cotton market, the South must
                    reorganize its labor system and refocus its productive efforts to succeed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Valuable Mill Property</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frantz</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Frederick Foreman, of the vicinity of Upton, recently
                    purchased the Farm and Mill property of Christian Frantz, of Welsh Run, for
                    $20,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. J. A. Kunkelman, pastor elect of the English Lutheran Church, will
                    preach his introductory sermon this Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--"Bridge!" Low Bridge!"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Jonas C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>As part of his platform last election, Jonas C. Palmer promised to
                    construct 30 new bridges in the county, states the article. Now that he has won
                    the contest to become the next Commissioner, the Spirit desires to know where he
                    will begin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Temperance Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the start of the Susquehanna District Temperance Convention in
                    Shippensburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Good Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shillito</ln>
                        <fn>J. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Detrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearce</ln>
                        <fn>N. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickley</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. N. Shillito was appointed Collector and J. L. P. Detrich Assessor of
                    Internal Revenue for the sub-district that includes Franklin county. The two men
                    will replace N. P. Pearce and Augustus Bickley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Greencastle Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallheim</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 3rd, Samuel Tallheim, "a respectable and industrious citizen,"
                    died very suddenly in Greencastle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a ">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Greencastle Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davison</ln>
                        <fn>George C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George C. Davison has relinquished his Collectorship of Internal Revenue
                    for the sub-district that includes Greencastle. His successor has not yet been
                    named.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Waynesboro and Quincy Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wertz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sechrist</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Samuel Sechrist has been appointed Postmaster of
                    Quincy, in place of David Wertz, deceased.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>H. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holby</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lemanter</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On November 11th, William Holby and Catherine Lemanter were married by Rev.
                    H. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flickinger</ln>
                        <fn>G. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kensey</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kensey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 1st, G. C. Flickinger, of Strasburg, and Maggie S., daughter of
                    John Kensey, were married by Rev. William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crone</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Varnicle</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 28th, Augustus Varnicle and Elizabeth Shaffer were married by Rev.
                    J. S. Crone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crone</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fiock</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 1st, Paul Ritter and Hannah Fiock were married by Rev. J. S. Crone.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sitterhouse</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 8th, John Sitterhouse, 74, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o ">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aughinbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov. 4th, Mary Aughinbaugh, formerly of Chambersburg, died in
                    Pittsburgh. Aughinbaugh was 50 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Furry</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Nov.6th, John Furry, 78, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o ">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzelman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 30th, John Heintzelman, Sr., 76, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.11.14.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
