<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.06.20">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/20/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-06-20">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="06">June</month>
            <day norm="00">20</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1865.05.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Management of the Freedmen's Bureau</head>
                <origin>N. Y. Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>With the exceptions of the Departments of Texas and Arkansas, the
                        Commissionerships of the Freedmen's Bureau have been placed in charge of the
                        several district military commandants. The change has been made at the
                        request of General Howard and in the detailing of military commanders
                        throughout the South, in accordance with this new arrangement, Gen. Grant
                        has so far expressed his approval of General Howard's officers as to give
                        entire military change in their respective States to former Assistant
                        Commissioners, Gens. H. K. Scott, of South Carolina; Wager Swayne, of
                        Alabama; Davis Tilson, of Georgia, and Gen. A. Baird, of Louisiana. General
                        O. Brown, of Virginia, has been detailed upon the staff of Gen. A. H. Terry.
                        Gen. Whitlesey, of North Carolina, is awaiting trial before the Military
                        Commission to assemble at Raleigh on Tuesday, the 12th inst. Col. T. W.
                        Osborn, of Florida, has been ordered upon the staff of Gen. Foster, of that
                        State; and Gen. Charles Thomas, of Mississippi, is at present Chief
                        Inspector to Gen. Howard.--<emph rend="italic">N. Y. Tribune</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that, with the exception of the departments of Arkansas and Texas,
                    the Commisionerships of the Freedmen's Bureau have been placed in charge of
                    several district military commandants as a result of a policy change implemented
                    by Gen. O. O. Howard and approved by Gen. Grant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Harrisburg Telegraph</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THE extent of the swindle which it was proposed to play on the people of
                        Pennsylvania by certain lordling British financiers is best shown in the
                        fact that the engineer corps which was tramping over the mountains of the
                        central part of the State making surveys in the name of the Atlantic and
                        Great Western Railroad, have not been, and are not likely to be paid for
                        their services. A subordinate in one of the corps informs us that he had
                        resolved no money for months, and that others of his associates were in the
                        same plight. He also states it as a singular fact, that the Englishmen
                        connected with the survey were paid in full.--These are the significant
                        facts, and we hope the lesson which they convey will prove salutary
                        hereafter in protecting the American people from the speculating schemes of
                            foreigners.--<emph rend="italic">Harrisburg Telegraph</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article informs readers about an alleged swindle carried out by
                    "lordling British financiers" who hoped to capitalize on the growing need for
                    railway investors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.06.20.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Final Passage of the Obstruction Amendment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Constitutional Amendment intended to keep the Union divided and the
                        Republican party in power, as amended by the Senate, has been passed by both
                        Houses by the requisite two-thirds vote. It now goes to the Legislature of
                        the several States for ratification, requiring the ascent of three-fourths
                        of the same before it can be valid as a part of the Constitution. This
                        assent it can never receive, as is well known by the authors of the scheme,
                        but they have adopted it simply as a political platform, hoping therewith to
                        deceive the people and postpone the admission of the Southern States until
                        after the next presidential election. But the people understand their game,
                        and in October and November next <emph rend="italic">they</emph> will have a
                        word to say on this question. If the present indications of the drift of
                        public sentiment can be relied on these negro-suffrage, disunion, Jacobin
                        conspirators against the peace and welfare of the country will then receive
                        a warning whidh they will do well to heed. The people are in earnest in this
                        matter and they do not intend that the fruits of the war shall be lost in
                        order that a rotten, corrupt political party may be retained in power. </p>
                    <p>We need but refer to the closing speech of Mr. Stevens on this Amendment to
                        see the revolutionary purpose of the dominant party in Congress. They are
                        boldly avowed. He says that in his manhood and old age he had hoped to have
                        "all our institutions remodeled," whenever "any <emph rend="italic"
                            >fortunate</emph> changes should have broken up for a time the
                        foundation of our institutions, and released us from obligations the most
                        tyrannical that were ever imposed in the name of freedom." </p>
                    <p>See the boldness with which the old sinner avows his purpose to revolutionize
                        the Government of our fathers--"remodel our institutions," and the utter
                        contempt he expresses for the work of WASHINGTON, HAMILTON, FRANKLIN and
                        MADISON. He looks upon the blood and carnage of the last five years as a
                            "<emph rend="italic">fortunate</emph>" opportunity, for which he had
                        long hoped, to enable him and his party to overthrow the Constitution, break
                        up the foundations of our institutions, and release the country form the
                            "<emph rend="italic">tyrannical obligations</emph>" imposed upon it by
                        the founders of the Government. such is the infamous purpose of Thaddeus
                        Stevens, the acknowledged leader of the Republican party, as avowed by
                        himself, with unblushing boldness on the floor of Congress, during the past
                        week. Let the people arise in the majesty of their strength, and [UNCLEAR]
                        from the power of the demagogues and [UNCLEAR] who are seeking to perpetuate
                        their own rule by the subversion of the government itself, and the total
                        destruction of the rights and liberties of the people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In highly critical terms, the article denounces the passage of the
                    Obstruction Bill, describing it as a political maneuver designed to "deceive the
                    people and postpone the admission of the Southern States until after the next
                    election."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>The Right Spirit</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The central Lutheran Synod of Pennsylvania held its annual session recently
                        at Blair, Perry county. Rev. W. H. Diven [UNCLEAR] presided, and Rev. M. L.
                        Cller acted as Secretary. During the sitting of the synod the President
                        appointed a committee of five to report resolutions expressive of the
                        sentiments of the synod on the state of the country, of which our friend,
                        Capt. D. L. Trendler [UNCLEAR], was chairman. It is gratifying to observe
                        the true spirit of patriotism and Christian charity pervading the
                        resolutions. They do credit to the heads and hearts of the members of the
                        "Central Synod," and are in striking contrast with the spirit of bigotry and
                        political fanaticism which of late years has been so shamelessly manifested
                        in our churches and ecclesiastical bodies. We hope this may be the beginning
                        of a better era, when politics will be discarded from the pulpit and
                        synodical convention--when ministers will again preach "Christ and Him
                        Crucified," with all meekness and forbearance, inculcating the precepts of
                        Him who spake as never men spake, instead of the doctrine of men.</p>
                    <p>The following resolutions are the last two of the series unanimously passed
                        by the synod:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That whereas several pominent causes of
                        estrangement between the States lately in conflict have been removed forever
                        by the arbitrament of the sword, it is our duty now, as country loving
                        citizens, to labor to unite the bleeding sections of the national heart,
                        that our legal Union may be strengthened by moral bonds, and that thus,
                        forgetting the bitterness of the past and remembering only its important
                        teachings, we may be more closely and inseparably united ever hereafter. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, That in this momentous period of our
                        Country's history we look with earnest solicitude to Andrew Johnson,
                        President of the United States, whose patriotism stood the severest test of
                        times that tried men's souls, and that we invoke upon him the blessing and
                        guidance of Almighty God, that, forgetting not the just dignity of the
                        government he entertain <emph rend="italic">"charity for all and malice
                            toward none."</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>After providing a brief outline of the events that occurred during the
                    annual meeting of the Central Lutheran Synod of Pennsylvania, the editor praises
                    the body's decision to pass a series of resolutions in support of the President
                    and the Democratic platform.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>THERE is a vast deal of nonsense talked and written about reorganizing the
                        government "in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of
                        Independence. It is to be presumed that Mr. Jefferson, who wrote that paper,
                        understood its meaning, and if it was designed, as is now claimed, not only
                        to give freedom to the blacks but to make political and social equals of
                        them, it is passing strange that he neglected to communicate that fact to
                        his own negroes, but continued to hold them as slaves to his dying day. Will
                        the radical editors who are in the habit of printing windy and ridiculous
                        interpretations of the Declaration be kind enough to explain this queer
                        fact, or henceforth and forever hold their peace?</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Directing its attack against Radical editors who have sought to employ the
                    political ideals espoused by Thomas Jefferson as justification for giving blacks
                    the vote, the article questions the logic of using the opinions of a slaveowner
                    as a spokesman for their cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>President Lincoln on the Right of the Southern States to Representation</head>
                <origin>N. Y. World</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Amid charges leveled by Republicans that President Johnson's reconstruction
                    policies have deviated from those layed out by Lincoln before his death, the
                    article asserts that Johnson has actually carried on the legacy of the former
                    president, including a tumultuous relationship with the Radicals in Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Bankruptcy and the Ruin Must Follow</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial describes the spending habits of the "Rump Congress" as
                    "wasteful and extravagant, as illustrated by the various projects for which the
                    body has appropriated money for the upcoming year. Congress' worst feature,
                    however, is its "captiousness, hatred and injustice toward the whites of the
                    South and their patronage of the black race," which, it says, has created an
                    atmosphere where "distrust and ill-feeling" has delayed the region's economic
                    recovery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Latest Infamy</head>
                <origin>Age; New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"We take the following despatch from the columns of the New York Tribune
                    of yesterday."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commenting on an extract that appeared in the New York Tribune announcing
                    Governor Curtin's decision to ratify the Constitutional Amendment as soon as
                    possible, the writer declares his opposition to the proposed scheme, labeling it
                    a "shameless work," and challenges the constitutionality of the plan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The White-Washing Committee</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Focusing its vituperation on the "Rump Committee's" efforts to examine a
                    race riot that recently occurred in Memphis, the article characterizes the
                    group's findings as attempt "to gull weak-minded persons into the error that
                    negroes are saints and that the Rumps are right in their selfish and ambitious
                    schemes."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.06.20.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Damage Question in Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the resolutions introduced into Congress by A. H.
                    Coffroth relative to the bill to indemnify the residents of the border region in
                    Pennsylvania.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>S. H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hockenberry</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nesbit</ln>
                        <fn>Maria F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 12th, William H. Hockenberry and Maria F. Nesbit were married by
                    Rev. S. H. C. Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dickson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoaff</ln>
                        <fn>J. James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humler</ln>
                        <fn>Sevilla</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 12th, J. James Shoaff and Sevilla Humler were married by Rev. J.
                    Dickson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ulrich</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newbern</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 28th, Henry Ulrich and Ann Newbern were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kohl</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 26th, Adam Thompson and Mary Kohl were married by Rev. G. Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLean</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kearman</ln>
                        <fn>Philopena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On June 14th, George McLean and Philopena Kearman were married by Rev. G.
                    Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.06.20.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
