<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.09.12">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/16/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-09-12">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="00">12</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Democracy!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Contains a copy of the speech given by gubernatorial candidate Hiester
                    Clymer at a meeting of the Soldiers of the Union on August 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.12.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Mongrel Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>During the sessions of the "mean white' and susceptible negro Convention in
                        Philadelphia, last week; what is called by negro, a "grand mass meeting' was
                        held in front of the Gin Palace, on Broad street, generally known as the
                        "Union (?) League House," on Friday night. The assemblage is said, by the
                        disunion papers, to have been orderly, intelligent and respectable. So far
                        as the order and intelligence of the meeting is concerned, we have nothing
                        to say, but as to say assemblage of <emph rend="italic">white</emph> people
                        being respectable--the component parts of which delight in walking
                        arm-in-arm with negroes, listening to and applauding their speeches, we must
                        be permitted to doubt. Whether respectable or not, the great leaders of
                        Republicanism in Philadelphia were present, aiding, abetting, counseling and
                        applauding. Hon. Morton McMichael, Mayor of the city, who ran away in order
                        to avoid doing fitting honors to President Johnson, General Grant and
                        Admiral Faragut, was there. Fred Douglas, the impudent negro, was there.
                        Anna Dickinson and several other of that class of females, were there. The
                        Hon. Wm. D. Kelly was there, and performed the part introducing the "mean
                        white" who did the speaking. Among the speakers introduced by the honorable
                        gentleman, was A. J. Durant, of New Orleans. (Who the Hon. Durant is we are
                        not informed, but will venture the assertion that he is some Yankee who went
                        South during the war to steal cotton,)who, among other things said: </p>
                    <p>"And now, IF YOU ARE OPPOSED TO THE ENFRANCHISMENT OF THE LOYAL BLACK MAN,
                        YOUR OPPOSITION MUST CEASE. without their aid the loyal white men of
                        Louisiana cannot re-create a loyal government, WITHOUT , FROM THE FAR EAST
                        THROUGH THE SOUTH THE GOVERNMENT BE ALL REMODELED, SO AS TO GIVE THE RIGHTS
                        OF SUFFRAGE TO ALL LOYAL MEN, the Union cannot be redeemed and restored. * *
                        * *</p>
                    <p>"Citizens of my native State arise in your might at the ballot-box, and tell
                        Congress that YOU WILL HAE THE RIGHT OF SUFFRAGE GIVEN TO EVERY LOYAL
                        CITIZEN, BLACK OR WHITE. There will you have every State made prosperous and
                        free."</p>
                    <p>Freemen of Franklin county, will you longer be deceived Can you any longer
                        doubt that the leaders of the Republican party are endeavoring to force upon
                        you negro suffrage and negro equality White men we call upon you to leave
                        these men to worship the object of their idolatry--the miserable degraded
                        African, and vote with the white men who believe that this is a government
                        of white men. The issue is upon you and cannot be evaded. It is whether this
                        is to remain a white man's government, or be degraded into a miserable <emph
                            rend="italic">Black</emph> Republic. Choose ye. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial lambasts participants at the State Republican Party
                    Convention, particularly the whites in attendance who "worship" "the miserable
                    and degraded African," yet still profess to "believe that this is a government
                    of white men."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>How Are the Mighty Fallen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Unlike the situation six years ago, explains the article, Republicans are
                    currently in desperate shape. The situation has forced them to emulate their
                    Democratic foes by holding a series of conventions to mobilize the support of
                    Civil War veterans.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nimmons</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormany</ln>
                        <fn>B. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>Montgomery</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Provides a brief account of the Democratic meeting held on Sept. 6th,
                    which, according to the article, was such a success that it had to be held
                    outdoors rather inside the Court House, its intended locale.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Geary's Forlorn Hope--A Clear Confession and Contemplated Fraud</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary>"The following is from the Pittsburgh <emph rend="italic"
                    >Commercial</emph>, a Geary organ:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"J. W. Forney and other Radical leaders in Pennsylvania have procured from
                        the War Department a list of deserters from the army during the war, from
                        that State numbering <emph rend="italic">sixty thousand and propose to
                            challenge such of them as shall offer to vote the Conservative
                        ticket</emph>, and prevent their exercising the elective franchise." </p>
                    <p>Observe: Of these sixty thousand, they propose to challenge <emph
                            rend="italic">only</emph> those who "shall offer to vote the
                        Conservative ticket"--that is for Clymer and the Democratic nominees. All
                        others, of course, are to be allowed to be allowed to vote--provided they
                        cast their votes for Geary. If deserters have no right to vote, as the
                        disunionists say, then the disunionists will be committing a fraud in
                        permitting deserters to vote for Geary. The above is a clear confession that
                        the Disunionists intend <emph rend="italic">either to unjustly deprive men
                            of their votes, or to commit fraud by accepting illegal votes for
                        Geary</emph>, They are certainly capable of doing either or both. * </p>
                    <p>But, how comes it that there are SIXTY THOUSAND deserters-- more than <emph
                            rend="italic">one in six</emph> of all Pennsylvania soldiers in service
                        during the war? Because <emph rend="italic">all the errors and blunders of
                            Fry's corrupt Provost Marshal Bureau have been hunted up</emph> and
                        because <emph rend="italic">at least</emph> THIRTY THOUSAND NAMES OF
                        DEMOCRATS AND CONSERVATIVE REPUBLICANS, who were never in service; never
                        drafted; <emph rend="italic">who were under and over age, and otherwise not
                            liable to draft or service</emph> HAVE BEEN ADDED <emph rend="italic">by
                            the Geary Managers in order to</emph> OBSTRUCT and EMBARASS and TO
                        DEPRIVE THEM OF THEIR VOTE! There is no doubt that in districts where
                        Disunion election officers control, that every one whose name is upon such
                        bogus lists will be denied the right of suffrage. Even in they merely
                        challenge such persons and compel them, <emph rend="italic">at short
                            notice--say</emph> A FEW MINUTES BEFORE THE CLOSING OF THE POLLS--to
                        unite up papers, records and witnesses, <emph rend="italic">thousands of
                            votes will be lost for want of time to summon witnesses</emph>. Say
                        there are 1500 districts where Disunion officers preside, and that at each
                        of them <emph rend="italic">ten</emph> of the Democrats or Conservatives who
                        present themselves within <emph rend="italic">twenty minutes</emph>
                        preceding the closing of the polls, are challenged, how can they in that
                        brief space of time secure the proofs? How many soldiers, for instance,
                        would be able to go home and return with their honorable discharges? <emph
                            rend="italic">Ten</emph> votes thus lost would make 15,000 of a loss the
                        aggregate and <emph rend="italic">seven</emph> would aggregate 10,500. </p>
                    <p>It is thus easy to see the importance of the infamous game to the Geary
                        faction, if successful, but <emph rend="italic">they must be terribly
                            fearful of the result</emph> to resort to so desperate and felonious
                        scheme! It is certainly their last resort--their forlorn hope. The Democrats
                        and Conservatives must therefore meet them with FIRMNESS and VIGOR. <emph
                            rend="italic">Pay no regard to their humbug lists</emph> and insist upon
                        and secure for every man qualified under the Constitution and Election laws
                        of our Commonwealth THE INALIENABLE RIGHT TO VOTE. <emph rend="italic">Those
                            lists are mere waste paper</emph>, and every election officer attempting
                        to USURP JUDICIAL POWERS, by virtue of them, MUST BE PROSECUTED and WILL BE
                        PROSECUTED AND PUNISHED TO THE FULL EXTENT OF THE LAW.--<emph rend="italic"
                            >Patriot and Union</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, Geary intends on challenging the validity of the
                    "deserters' votes" if it appears as though he will not win their support.
                    Already, declares the piece, leading Republicans have obtained a list from the
                    War Department containing the names of 60,000 men from Pennsylvania who are
                    identified as having deserted.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In an effort to counter the Repository's attempts to mislead the public,
                    the brief piece informs readers that the Republican candidate for Congress, Col.
                    William Koontz, merely served as a Militia General during the war and,
                    therefore, saw no action.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>McClure's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>The Bedford <emph rend="italic">Gazette</emph> gives the following
                    report of McClure's speech at Bedford.--The same report will answer for his
                    speech in this place on Friday night last. We give it entire:</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By our Special Reporter.</p>
                    <p>Montgomery Blair--old
                        Blair--Blair--Blair--Blair--Rebels--Traitors--blood-stained rebels back to
                        power--Blair--Bloody
                        Scoundrels--Ghastly--Ghostly--Wasted--Treason--Rebels--Copperheads--Traitors--Treason--Unrepentant
                        Rebels--Wretches--Traitors--Treason--Treason--Scoundrels--Ghastly--Andersonville--Sharpe--Blair--Treason--Treason--Treason--Negroes--Equality--Traitors--Traitors--Bloody
                        Traitors--Rebels--Treason--Treason--etc., etc.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Contains a parody of an address delivered by Col. McClure, the editor of
                    the Repository, in Bedford.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that William Koontz, the "Radical candidate" for Congress in
                    Franklin county's district, gave a speech recently in which he declared that
                    "the time must soon come when without regard to COLOR or RACE men must be EQUAL
                    in every respect." In light of Koontz's remarks, the Spirit infers that he will
                    allow blacks to vote, to sit on juries, and to marry white girls if he is
                    elected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--"White Boys In Blue"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the local members of the Soldiers' Johnson-Clymer Club.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Omitted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gabby</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that William B. Gabby's name was omitted from the Democratic
                    County Committee list published last week in the Spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Meeting of the "White Boys in Blue"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dietrich</ln>
                        <fn>J. L. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humelaine</ln>
                        <fn>Manaria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shenafield</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spear</ln>
                        <fn>Jason</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etchberger</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stahl</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donevon</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKenna</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheller</ln>
                        <fn>B. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyssong</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelpher</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henneberger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Householder</ln>
                        <fn>Fred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michaels</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKean</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cummings</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moorehead</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwix</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shatzer</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simmers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stenger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Gives an account of the "White Boys in Blue" organizational meeting held on
                    Sept. 5 at the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Soldiers Attention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reminds soldiers that they must be assessed if they wish to vote in the
                    upcoming election</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huber</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spice</ln>
                        <fn>Susan E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 5th, William Huber and Susan E. Spice were married by Rev. J. S.
                    Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Krome</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 10th, Lewis H. Krome and Annie E. Funk were married by Rev. Dr. B.
                    S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wile</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snide</ln>
                        <fn>Ladina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 10th, William Wile and Ladina Snide were married.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gerdeman</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Hara</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 4th, George B. Wood and Catherine O'Hara were married by Rev. John
                    W. Gerdeman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn>Henry H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 29th, Henry H. Wolfe, 82, died near Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Isabella E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 3rd, Mary Elizabeth, daughter of Benjamin F. and Isabella E.
                    Lehman died. Mary Elizabeth was 11 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Margaretta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Sept. 5th, Margaretta Snively, 21, died in Fayetteville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.09.12.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
