<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.08.22">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/16/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-08-22">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="00">22</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.08.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Restoration!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an in-depth account of the National Union Convention, an event the
                    article describes as a grand attempt to "re-establish peace, harmony and good
                    feeling over all sections of our common country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.08.22.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Great Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We surrender most of our space to-day to the proceedings of the Great
                        National Union Convention held in Philadelphia, last week. We are quite
                        certain that we can do the great cause of the restoration of the Union and
                        the Constitution no better service than by giving these proceedings at
                        length. That our readers will peruse them with enthusiastic delight and be
                        inspired thereby with renewed hope and confidence in the future permanence
                        and welfare of the Republic, we have no doubt,</p>
                    <p>This Convention was the great event of the age in which we live, and will be
                        regarded by future generations as one of the remarkable epochs in our
                        country's history--the turning point in the doctrines of the nation. It is
                        the first public exhibition of that great reaction in the public sentiment
                        of the country, which is destined to sweep down that baleful spirit of
                        sectionalism and fanaticism--the cause of all our woes and the troubles in
                        the past--and to bring back the government to the principles of the
                        Constitution and a genuine spirit of nationality.</p>
                    <p>To say tat the Convention was a grand success but feebly expresses the
                        reality.--Its like was never before witnessed in this or any other country,
                        when it is taken into account the size, standing and ability of its members,
                        and the harmony of its deliberations. Composed of over twelve hundred
                        delegates, coming from every section, State and Territory in the union,
                        representing all the varied interests and sympathies incident to their
                        respective localities, and yet, not a ripple at any time appeared upon the
                        surface to mar the peace of the convention. This grand fact disappointed
                        most agreeably many of the friends of the Convention while it made its
                        enemies rage with chagrin and disappointment. The last hope of the Radicals
                        was that the Convention would fail to harmonize and "and break up into a
                        row." But the complete unanimity and perfect harmony which prevailed
                        throughout the entire deliberations of the convention, have knocked the last
                        prop from under the radical structure, and down it will come in Pennsylvania
                        on the second Tuesday of October, with a crash that will sound through, and
                        be re-echoed by every State in a restored American Union. No wonder then
                        that Forney raves and Greelly howls. They see the hand-writing on the wall
                        and well know that their doom is fixed. This movement is from the
                        people--the honest, uncorrupted and unpurchasable people, who love the
                        Constitution and Union of our fathers--and <emph rend="italic">they</emph>
                        have fully determined, by overwhelming majorities in the fall elections, to
                        notify these radical revolutionists in and out of Congress that their "time
                        has come." </p>
                    <p>It is useless to refer to the incidents of the Convention, as these are fully
                        set forth in the regular proceedings. We are, however, tempted to allude to
                        the entrance of the Massachusetts and South Carolina delegations, arm in
                        arm, into the "Wigwam" on the first day. The effect of this incident was
                        overpowering, and the excitement which ensued beggars all description. The
                        vast concourse of people assembled, with one glorious, patriotic impulse
                        instantly sprung to their feet, and sent up cheer after cheer, to give
                        expression to the joy that swelled every bosom. Tears of joyful emotion were
                        seen filling the eyes and trickling down the cheeks of hundreds of men
                        unused to weep. The moral grandeur of this incident, we think, must stand
                        without a parallel for all time. A Major General in the Federal Army and a
                        Senator in the late Confederate Senate, walking arm in arm into a National
                        Convention speaks more eloquently in favor of immediate peace and re-union
                        than all the platitudes that could be written from now until the end of
                        time.</p>
                    <p>Without saying anything further we will let the proceedings speak for
                        themselves. Read them everyone, and carefully study their overshadowing
                        significance; endeavor to catch the inspiration of this great movement and
                        work ardently, earnestly and faithfully in behalf of the great cause until
                        the laurels of victory crown your labors with success in a restored Union
                        and a perfect Nationality.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editorial provides a glowing review of the proceedings at the National
                    Union Convention in Philadelphia, and proclaims the assembly a "turning point in
                    the destin[y] of the nation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One of the largest and most enthusiastic Democratic County meetings it has
                        ever been our fortune to witness, assembled in the Court House on the
                        evening of Tuesday the 14th inst. Although the meeting was an impromptu
                        affair and the bills announcing if had been posted but a few hours, the
                        large hall was completely filled long before the hour of meeting. The
                        assemblage was called to order at 8 o'clock by D. K. Wunderlich, Esq.,
                        President of the Democratic Club, who named the following gentlemen as
                        officers of the meeting: President, John Armstrong, of Chambersburg; Vice
                        Presidents, Samuel Holliday, of Fannett; Rev. Wesly Howe, Greene; William
                        Boyd, Montgomery; William Bossert, of Hamilton; Conrad Plasterer, of
                        Southampton; Adam Kissecker, of Chambersburg; Jacob C. Snyder, of Guilford;
                        and Capt. Christian Pisle, of Chambersburg; Secretaries, Joseph Douglas, of
                        Waynesboro, and Jacob R. Smith, of Antrim, all of which gentlemen were
                        unanimously elected, and took their seats.</p>
                    <p>As soon as the organization was perfected loud cries of Brewer! Brewer!
                        Brewer!! were heard in various parts of the hall, in response to which Mr.
                        Brewer appeared and addressed the assembled Democracy in words of thrilling
                        eloquence which excited the vast audience to the highest pitch of
                        enthusiasm. After Mr. Brewer had concluded Hon. J. McDowell Sharpe, our
                        candidate for Congress, appeared in obedience to the call of the meeting,
                        and enchained its attention for more than an hour in an able, logical, and
                        eloquent speech. At the conclusion of Mr. Sharpe's speech, Hon. C. M.
                        Duncan, Senator, duly elected, but who was defrauded out of his seat by a
                        dishonest radical Senate, was loudly called for and responded in an able and
                        stirring address.</p>
                    <p>The meeting was characterized by an enthusiasm rarely witnessed in County
                        meetings, and which will make itself felt in the approaching battle at the
                        Polls, with the friends of Negro Suffrage and Negro equality.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holliday</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howe</ln>
                        <fn>Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bossett</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plasterer</ln>
                        <fn>Conrad</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kissecker</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pisle</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McDowall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duncan</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts that "one of the largest and most enthusiastic" Democratic County
                    meetings occurred on August 14th, at the Court House.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Who Are The Disunionists</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Regardless of their claims to the contrary, the Radicals, says the
                    editorial, are the true cause of the continued sectional conflict. As proof, the
                    editorial points to the recent events in Philadelphia as an example of the
                    excellent rapport that exists between northerners and southerners who adhere to
                    the same basic principles, such as the sanctity of the Constitution and the
                    notion that the U.S. is white man's country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Geary and Negro Voting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Geary says in one of his "speeches" that "negro suffrage is not <emph
                            rend="italic">now</emph> a question," but he don't say how he is on that
                        question. All his organs--with a few exceptions--declare, also, that "negro
                        suffrage is not <emph rend="italic">now</emph> a question," but why? Because
                        there is no amendment striking the word "white" out of the Constitution of
                        Pennsylvania to be voted upon at the coming election. That is their only
                        reason; but, notwithstanding, negro suffrage <emph rend="italic">is</emph>
                        an issue before the people. Should the Gearyites succeed in quietly electing
                        a majority of the Legislature, at the coming election, one of the first acts
                        of next winter will be the passage of an amendment to enable negroes to
                        vote.--There is no doubt whatsoever of this. And if Geary shall occupy the
                        Governor's chair his assent will be given to every negro measure enacted.
                        Besides this negro suffrage has become a national question, through the
                        persistent agitation of the party to which Geary is attached. Seeing that
                        political power is departing from them, their greatest efforts are being
                        made to force negro suffrage at the South through amendments to the
                        Constitution, and by means of irresponsible and revolutionary conventions,
                        such as that which met at New Orleans on the 30th ult. The leaders of the
                        Geary party want the negro vote to maintain supremacy at Washington. Geary,
                        therefore, dare not deny that negro suffrage is the question at the South
                        and that he is in favor of it. Negro suffrage and equality at the South mean
                        negro suffrage and equality in Pennsylvania. Hence he who favors one is
                        committed to the other. Geary is upon a negro platform.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite their attempts to convince voters otherwise, Geary and the
                    Republicans are proponents of black suffrage, contends the article. In fact,
                    should Geary win the gubernatorial election, the journal warns, his "assent will
                    be given to every negro measure enacted" in order to use the black vote to
                    defeat the political ambitions of the state's white man's party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>The National Issue</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>With the end of the war, says the editor, the passion and prejudice that
                    prevented calm and dispassionate discussion from taking place has been removed.
                    Yet while this bar may have been eliminated, a new, potentially more dangerous
                    issue has arisen, pitting Democrats and Conservatives against Radicals, who, he
                    claims, seek to establish a new form of government rather than restore the Old
                    Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.08.22.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Delegate Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kimmel</ln>
                        <fn>F. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that several election wards in Franklin county will assemble on
                    August 25th to select the number of delegates that each district is entitled to
                    under the new apportionment system.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Delegate Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that Democrats of the South Ward will meet at Samuel Greenawalt's
                    residence on August 25th to select four delegates to represent the ward at the
                    County Convention. Additionally, a meeting for residents of the North Ward will
                    assemble at the Montgomery House to select three delegates. Those individuals
                    selected will convene on Sept. 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haskell</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fields</ln>
                        <fn>Walter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pass</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moatz</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckner</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckner</ln>
                        <fn>Polly</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beckner</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>Orlando</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Helsey</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speigler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lotsbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Keggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bender</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ely</ln>
                        <fn>Solomon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemaker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatfield</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bentley</ln>
                        <fn>Hamilton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houreholder</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Oscar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snow</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Bert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCain</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFerren</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weyman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyant</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Ann C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ditch</ln>
                        <fn>David L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Hezekiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beck</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tibby</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moon</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garver</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sands</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sands</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitz</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Funk</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welker</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartle</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rickets</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rickets</ln>
                        <fn>Henrietta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plowden</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hatfield</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farquhar</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Comfort</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spoonhour</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Diggs</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swingler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Juliana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zarman</ln>
                        <fn>Francis</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmony</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heckerman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Minnich</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etter</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Selbert</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackley</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wyant</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dittman</ln>
                        <fn>Barbara</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilbert</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rickel</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Polk</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyner</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mower</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seyler</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCleary</ln>
                        <fn>J. Wesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hollet</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sweeney</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Theodore</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criner</ln>
                        <fn>Amos</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Criner</ln>
                        <fn>Malinda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Speigler</ln>
                        <fn>Henry M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bergenstock</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freese</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Page</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Hannah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Norris</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of the cases tried during the late term of the court. Court
                    Proceedings--Over Terminer. "Commonwealth vs. Michael Haskell and Patrick
                    Flanagan--Highway Robbery and Larceny, Verdict Guilty of Larceny. Sentenced to
                    Eastern Penitentiary for 1 year and 8 months. Same vs. Walter Fields and
                    Columbus Green, Manslaughter. After the hearing of testimony case abandoned by
                    commonwealth's attorneys and verdict of not Guilty rendered by the jury. Quarter
                    Sessions. Commonwealth vs. Mary Pass, Surety of Peace. After hearing the court
                    dismiss the case of William Beckner and sentence the prosecutor to pay the
                    costs. Same vs. Mary Jane Moatz, Surety of Peace. After hearing the court
                    dismiss the case and sentence the prosecutrix Mary Pass to pay the costs. Same
                    vs. Catherine Beckner, Surety of Peace. Having heard the evidence the court
                    dismiss the case and sentence Mary Pass to pay the costs. Same vs. Polly Becker,
                    Surety of Peace. Having heard the evidence the court dismiss the case and
                    sentence the prosecutrix Mary Pass to pay the costs. Sane vs. Abraham Beckner,
                    Assault and Battery, Defendant not guilty but to pay two-thirds of the costs and
                    Sarah Melaner the prosecutor one-third. Same vs. Jacob Helsey, False Pretense,
                    Jacob R. Smith prosecutor, Verdict Guilty, Recognizance of defendant forfeited
                    and respited until next term. Same vs. Andrew Burns, Cyrus Black and George
                    Black, Larceny, William Reber prosecutor, Verdict Guilty Verdict guilty, Cyrus
                    Black and Andrew Burns sentenced to undergo imprisonment in the Eastern
                    Pennitentiary for one year and one month and George Black to the House of
                    Refuge. Same vs. Henry M. Speigler, fornication and Bastardy, Verdict Guilty,
                    new trial granted. Same vs. Jacob L. Wingert, Blasphemy, recognizance of
                    defendant and sureties forfeited and respited until next term. Same vs. Keggie
                    Lotsbaugh, Larceny, recognizance forfeited and respited until next term. Same
                    vs. David Bender, Larceny, Defendant pleads guilty and sentenced to Eastern
                    Pennitentiary for one year, to commence at the end of prior sentence. Same vs.
                    Solomon Ely, Assault and Battery, Verdict Guilty, sentenced to pay a fine of ten
                    dollars and costs of prosecution. Same vs. John Shoemaker, Silas David Brant,
                    Horse Stealing, Verdict Guilty, sentenced to Eastern Pennitentiary for four
                    years. Same vs. Peter Hatfield, Larceny. Defendant pleads guilty and is
                    sentenced to one year and eight months. Same vs. Samuel Norris, Assault and
                    Battery, pleads guilty and is sentenced to pay a fine of one dollar and costs of
                    prosecution and to undergo an imprisonment in the county jail for 3 months. Same
                    vs. Hamilton Bentley, Larceny of one stone drill, Verdict Guilty, defendant
                    sentenced to Eastern Penitentiary for 1 year and 1 calendar month. Same vs.
                    Phillip Householder, Assault and Battery, Verdict not guilty, defendant
                    sentenced to pay one-half the costs and prosecutor the other half. Same vs.
                    Oscar Bell, Assault and Battery, a true bill, recognizance of defendant
                    forfeited. Same vs. George Snow, Assault and Battery, Verdict guilty, defendant
                    sentenced to pay a fine of five dollars and the costs of prosecution. Same vs.
                    John W. Ditchman, Selling Intoxicating Liquors to Charles Nitterhouse, Verdict
                    guilty, motion for a new trial filed, continued to term. Same vs. Jacob Kelley,
                    Surety of the Peace, After hearing defendant sentenced to pay the costs of
                    prosecution. Same vs. Peter Williams, Surety of Peace, After hearing defendant
                    sentenced to pay the costs of prosecution. Same vs. Bert Lane, Surety of the
                    Peace, After hearing the defendant sentenced to pay the costs of prosecution and
                    enter into recognizance for his good behavior. Same vs. William McCain, Henry
                    Barger, Jesse Richter, Riot and Assault and Battery, Verdict not guilty, and
                    county to pay costs of prosecution. Same vs. Peter McFerren, Assault, Verdict
                    not guilty, but defendant to pay costs of prosecution. Same vs. John Weyman,
                    Jr., Assault and Battery, Verdict guilty, defendant sentenced to pay a fine of
                    one cent and costs of prosecution. Same vs. George Wyant, Assault and Battery,
                    Verdict not guilty but defendant to pay two-thirds and prosecutor one-third.
                    Nolle Prosequi--Entered by leave of court in following cases: Commonwealth vs.
                    Charles Jones and Henry Bergenstock, Same vs. Ann C. Funk, Same vs. Ann C. Funk,
                    David H. Funk, and Mary Funk, Same vs. Mary E. Funk, Same vs. David L. Ditch,
                    Assault and Battery, Same vs. same, Larceny, Same vs. Elizabeth Gilbert, Surety
                    of the Peace, Same vs. same, Assault and Battery, Same vs. Maria Martin, Assault
                    and Battery, Same vs. Hezekiah Beck, Samuel Beck and James Tibby, Riot, Assault
                    and Battery with intent to kill, Same vs. Sarah Moon, Same vs. Peter Myers, Same
                    vs. John W. Garver, Adultery, Same vs. same, Fornification and Bastardy, Same
                    vs. James Gordon, Robert Sands, Same vs. Jacob Fitz, Assault and Battery, Same
                    vs. same, Assault and Battery, Same vs. David H. Funk, Same vs. William Welker,
                    Same vs. James Martin, Same vs. Abraham Taylor, Same vs. George W. Bartle, Same
                    vs. Thomas Stevenson, Same vs. William J. Rickets and Henrietta Rickets, Same
                    vs. Joseph Plowden, Peter Hatfield, and Charles Diggs, Same vs. David Croft,
                    Same vs. Rachael Croft, Same vs. Catherine Hoover, Same vs. John C. Reed, Same
                    vs. J. B. Farquar, Same vs T. J. Long, Same vs. Peter Comfort and Jacob
                    Spoonhour, Same vs. Wilson Reilly, Same vs. Charles Diggs, Same vs. John
                    Swinger, Same vs. John Anderson, Same vs. Andrew Burns, Cyrus Black and George
                    Black, Same vs. Juliana Cook, Same vs. Jacob Snyder, Same vs. Martha Snider,
                    Same vs. Francis Zarman, Jr., Theodore Doyle, John Harmony, Thomas Heckerman,
                    and George Minnich, Same vs. same, Same vs. Lewis Ziter, Same vs. Juliana Cook,
                    Same vs. A. B. Selbert, Same vs. Ann C. Frank, Mary E. Funk, and David H. Funk.
                    Same vs. Jacob Mackley, Joseph Mackley, Mary Bowers, and Mary E. Funk. Bills
                    Ignored. Commonwealth vs. Henry Stumbaugh, Same vs. George Wyant, Same vs.
                    Barbara Dittman, Same vs. John Parker, Same vs. Samuel Norris, Same vs. Samuel;
                    Maria, William, Edward, and Thomas Gilbert, Same vs. William Williams, Same vs.
                    William Stoner and Catherine Stoner, Same vs. Sophia Rickel, Same vs. Polk
                    Wilson, Same vs. Alexander Kyner, Same vs. Henry Mower, Same vs. Samuel Norris.
                    Cases Continued. Commonwealth vs. Henry Moore, Same vs. Samuel Seylor, Same vs.
                    James Robinson, Same vs. J. Wesley McCleary, Jeremiah Miller, Michael Houser,
                    Abraham Hays, and Samuel Wolff, Same vs. James Hollet, Same vs. John Smith, Same
                    vs. James Sweeney, Same vs. Theodore Myers, Same vs. Charles Moore, Same vs.
                    Amos Criner, Same vs. Malinda Criner, Same vs. John Johnston, Same vs. Henry M.
                    Speigler, Same vs. Sarah Bergenstock, Same vs. William Bush, Same vs. Peter
                    Freese, Same vs. Page Davis, Hannah Davis, Nancy Norris."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--The Bounty Law</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Government is not yet prepared to pay the extra bounties prescribed in
                        the new bill just passed by Congress, and the War Department has issued an
                        order referring the act to a military commission composed of Generals Canby
                        and Buchanan, and Surgeon Gen. Barnes. These officers are to prescribe rules
                        and regulations to carry out the provisions of the law. The Second Auditor
                        of the Treasury, also with reference to this act, has issued instructions
                        that soldiers, in making application to his office for the additional
                        bounty, must use the same application heretofore used for arrears of pay and
                        bounty. The number of previous settlements of bounty, should always be
                        given, and it should be stated in each case that the "application is made to
                        recover the additional bounty provided by the 12th and 13th sections of an
                        act of Congress, chapter 178, approved July 28, 1866."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the state government is not yet prepared to pay for the
                    extra bounties prescribed by the new law passed by Congress, and details the
                    measures that are being put into effect to resolve the situation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--A Word To Our Citizens</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Although the fire department has performed admirably, states the piece, the
                    recent rash of fires in Chambersburg has clearly demonstrated the inadequacy of
                    the force's equipment, an issue that must be dealt with to ensure the town's
                    safety.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--For The East</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doebler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sheriff</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Sheriff Doebler and several of his assistants have set off for
                    the Eastern Pennitentiary in Philadelphia with 8 convicts, the largest ever sent
                    by Franklin county at one time which indicates that crime is "fearfully on the
                    increase."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Admitted To Practice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that George Eyster, S. J. Henderson, and George Chambers were
                    admitted to the Bar.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Croft</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Relates that John Croft lost his life when a train frightened one of his
                    horses and sent it into a panic while he was loading his buggy with coal. Croft
                    was killed as he attempted to stop the horse, winding up beneath the wheels of
                    his rolling cart.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roth</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hender</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 7th, William Hender and Mollie E. Wolf were married by Rev. G.
                    Roth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>A. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brinkley</ln>
                        <fn>Susan J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 14th, at the residence of William McDowell, Robert McClelland and
                    Susan Brinkley were married by Rev. A. K. Nelson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>P. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burtsfield</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ritter</ln>
                        <fn>Isabel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 10th, David Burtsfield and Isabel Ritter were married by Rev. P.
                    S. Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 18th, the child of John Kennedy died at age 7 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 12th, the son of Frederick Snively died at age 3 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicewander</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicewander</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 9th, Sarah Nicewander, daughter of Christian Nicewander, died at
                    age 12.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bark</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 12th, Sarah Bark, 60, died.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtry</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Adaline</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtry</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holtry</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 3rd, Mary Adaline, daughter of Peter and Elizabeth Holtry, died
                    at age 18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Emma Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rife</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On August 5th, Emma Mary, daughter of Mary and Frederick Rife, died at 15
                    months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.08.22.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
