<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1866/pa.fr.vs.1866.10.31">
    <header>
        <title>Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/20/99</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-31">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day norm="00">31</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>4</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.10.31.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of the Governor of Mississippi's address at the opening of the
                    state's special legislative session, in which he details his opposition to the
                    policies being promulgated by the Radicals in Congress. The Assembly had
                    reconvened early to voice its opposition to the 14th Amendment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.10.31.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>On the War Path</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It was said during the late civil war that the rebels were fighting, not for
                        their own civil liberties only, but for those of the whole American people,
                        and that declaration was not generally believed then; but seen in the light
                        of events that are daily occurring, was there not more truth than poetry in
                        it? The rebellion was conquered; but has the Union been preserved? The
                        armies of the South were overcome; but is constitutional government secure?
                        Is not the Union, indeed, still practically divided, and constitutional
                        government in more danger now than at any period since 1861?--The insurgents
                        resisted the Republican party after the election of Mr. Lincoln, because it
                        was a purely sectional organization, whose design, they believed was to
                        enable the North to dominate the South, in utter disregard of the
                        fundamental law of the government, and the conditions and covenants of the
                        Federal compact. The ground of defection and conflict was denied at the time
                        by the leaders of the Republican party.--But are not those same leaders
                        persuing a course of action, and avowing principles and purposes now, which
                        fully warrant all the apprehensions which alarmed the Southern mind five
                        years ago, and precipitated the Southern people into revolt?</p>
                    <p>These and like questions find their best answer in the revolutionary threats
                        and projects of the men who are the recognized chiefs of the
                        "Torch-and-Turpentine" party in this section of the Republic. They boldly
                        incite their adherents in Maryland, for example to resist the Governor of
                        that State in the lawful exercise of his office and encourage them with the
                        promise that they will be aided in their efforts to initiate civil war in
                        Baltimore by thousands of partisans in Pennsylvania. In what respect in this
                        attempt to provoke and insurrection in Maryland less criminal than the
                        Southern rebellion? Invasion of a State, and domestic violence therein,
                        would inevitably involve the national authorities in the conflict, because
                        the National Government is bound to defend each State in such an emergency.</p>
                    <p>Those, therefore, who instigate the people, or a part of the people, of any
                        State to rise up against and resist the magistracy thereof is the execution
                        of its laws, do, in fact, forment strife that must in all probability,
                        implicate the Federal forces and enrage a revolutionary mob in a struggle
                        against the National Government.</p>
                    <p>In another quarter, and about the same time, Mr. Wendell Phillips is
                        preaching sedition in language not to be mistaken.--He calls the
                        Constitution a "swindle dignified with the name of compromise;" he calls the
                        President the "rebel in the White House," he tells the Radical majority in
                        Congress that they shall impeach and depose him, before trial, place a
                        creature of their own in his place, and, if necessary, dismiss Grant as
                        Lieutenant General of the army, and substitute Ben. Butler. And all this,
                        and more of the same character, is to be done in order, as Phillips says,
                        that the Radical Republicans may obtain absolute powers of government
                        unlimited by constitutional restraints and then "run the machine" as they
                        please.</p>
                    <p>This, then, is the spirit, and this the programme of the party which the
                        people are asked to trust as the champions of constitutional liberty, the
                        friends of national unity, and the conservators of law and order!--And the
                        people, strangely enough, have thus far consented to strengthen the hands of
                        a faction which seems determined to alter the government to suit themselves,
                        and to consolidate all power in the hands of a "rump" Congress. Be it so, if
                        the people will it. We are tired of protecting against such folly and such
                        wrong. Perhaps the nearest, or the only path to peace and settled
                        government, lies through the furnace of revolution. It was so in France in
                        1798, in England in 1688, and the same sharp discipline may be near reserve
                        for us.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite the fact that the rebellion has been put down and the South has
                    accepted its defeat, the Radicals, says the editorial, have yet to be satisfied.
                    Their ultimate goal, it asserts, is to "obtain absolute powers of government
                    unlimited by constitutional constraints." In light of the situation, therefore,
                    the Spirit suggests that it is possible that the "only path to peace and a
                    settled government lies through the furnace of revolution."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is well known that Col. F. S. Stumbaugh, member elect of the Legislature
                        from this County, is an ardent friend of Simon Cameron, and is [UNCLEAR]
                        generally supposed that long since pledged his support to that gentleman for
                        the position of United States Senator. The chief editor of the <emph
                            rend="italic">Repository</emph>, Col. McClure, being a Curtin man and
                        deadly hostile to Cameron, it was thought at one time prior to the election
                        that he and his friends would make an effort to defeat Stumbaugh at the
                        polls. But this project, if ever entertained, was evidently abandoned as the
                            <emph rend="italic">brown tickets</emph> voted by the chiefs and
                        employees of the <emph rend="italic">Repository</emph> office will bear
                        testimony. </p>
                    <p>But as developments since have proved the fight did not end here. The brown
                        ticket business was merely a suspension of hostilities. The election being
                        over, the hero of "Rutherford's Lane" seemed as determined as ever to head
                        off the hero of "Shiloh" on the Senatorial question. He circulated a
                        petition among his friends, and had it numerously signed, addressed to the
                        Chairman of the County Committee, who in compliance with its request called
                        the committee together to consult as to the propriety of calling a county
                        convention to instruct our members as to the choice of this county for
                        Senator. The committee met and decided by a vote of 15 to 1 in favor of a
                        convention for this purpose to be held on the 11th of next month. This was
                        what might be called a successful flank movement on our gallant friend who
                        won and lost his stars during the late war. The strategy of "Rutherford's
                        lane" so far, is decidedly ahead. "Go in Betsy, go in Bear, we don't care a
                        darn which whips."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>F. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Details the political in-fighting among local Republicans as they battle
                    over the party's next senatorial nominee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Punishment of Traitors</head>
                <origin>Lancaster Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While it is true that there have been calls to arrest the most vocal and
                    vitriolic Radical leaders for their attempts to instigate another civil war, the
                    article casts doubts upon the effectiveness of such an endeavor. It does,
                    however, admit that "a step of this kind on the part of President Johnson would
                    have in it at least the merit of an act of retributive justice."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Trouble in Baltimore</head>
                <origin>Age</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports on the conflict between Governor Swann, of Maryland, and
                    Baltimore's Police Commissioners, who, "in the interest of the Radicals, propose
                    to disfranchise thousands of honest and legal voters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.10.31.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Prosecuted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wit</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>It is reported that Republicans John Wit and John Snyder, both members of
                    the Election Board in Fayetteville, will be brought before the Court next week
                    to answer questions about their decision during the last election to refuse the
                    ballots of alleged deserters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a ">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local and Personal--Baseball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The boxscore of the baseball game between Franklin and Conococheague, which
                    was won by the home team by a score 55 to 46.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hummelbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>B. Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandy</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strome</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 25th, Samuel Brandy and Mary A. Strome, of Cumberland county, were
                    married by Rev. B. Y. Hummelbaugh.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehman</ln>
                        <fn>Magdalena</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 11th, Emanuel Fry and Magdalena Lehman were married by Rev. J.
                    Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>A. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ehrhart</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. Keller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 25th, A. N. Long and Maggie D. Ehrhart were married by Rev. J.
                    Keller Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bishop</ln>
                        <fn>Jason M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 18th, Jacob Jones and Sarah Martin were married by Rev. Jason M.
                    Bishop.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s ">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Manaran</ln>
                        <fn>Hiram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lowe</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 16th, Hiram Manaran and Mary Ellen Lowe were married by Rev. S. N.
                    Callender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawbecker</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frants</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Callender</ln>
                        <fn>S. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 23rd, Simon Hawbecker and Elizabeth S. Frants were married by Rev.
                    S. N. Callender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henninger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Werdebaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 20th, John Henninger and Eliza J. Werdebaugh were married by Rev.
                    F. Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kell</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 27th, Jacob Wingert and Sarah J. Kell were married by Rev. F.
                    Dyson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o ">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClelland</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 8th, Robert McClelland, 25, died. McClelland was formerly a member
                    of Co. C. 126th Pa. Volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 20th, Maria King, 18, died near Mercersburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1866.10.31.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
