<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.07.16">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-16">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>16</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.07.16.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Few Words to Our Subscribers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been determined to issue the "Spectator" as long as we could possibly
                        do so, whether at a profit or loss. Until we had furnished <emph
                            rend="italic">three</emph> soldiers from our office for the army, we
                        continued the publication of the paper by issuing a half sheet. We were
                        determined to continue publication, though at a loss to our own pocket, and
                        had just received a large supply of paper for that purpose when the call for
                        the services of the company to which we and the hands in our office belong
                        appeared--thus making it <emph rend="italic">impossible</emph> to continue
                        its publication. We know that the good and generous subscribers of the
                        "Spectator" will not complain of us for discontinuing it's publication under
                        these circumstances. We promise them that its publication will be renewed if
                        ever we return from the field of strife. We hope that our enemies will be
                        conquered, and that our subscribers and friends will enjoy long and happy
                        lives in the free and independent Confederacy of Southern States. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Apologizes to readers because publication of the Spectator will be
                    discontinued for an unspecified amount of time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fight on Rich Mountain</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a skirmish resulting in heavy Southern losses, although a
                    postscript indicates that initial reports were greatly exaggerated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From a Georgia Soldier</head>
                <origin>Central Georgian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. J.M.G. Medlock, Editor and Proprietor of the "Central Georgian," is a
                        soldier in the 1st Georgia Regiment which passed through this place a few
                        weeks since. The following is an extract from a letter of his, written at
                        Beverly, to his paper.</p>
                    <p>"The citizens of Staunton treated us very kindly. More enthusiasm I have not
                        seen anywhere. At Waynesboro, in Augusta county, Va., we found tables spread
                        with an abundance of provisions for every man on board. We all partook
                        freely of the good things set before us, and gave three hearty cheers for
                        Waynesboro--but especially the ladies--bade them farewell, and went on our
                        way rejoicing. At another station, (I regret I have forgotten the name of
                        the place) the citizens heard that our regiment was to pass up the evening
                        before, and made great preparations for giving us a supper, but they had
                        mistaken the time and were greatly disappointed. Some of the ladies of that
                        place visited our regiment after we got to Staunton, bringing baskets of
                        provisions along with them.</p>
                    <p>This is emphatically a land of milk and butter, and the milk has flown freely
                        to the weary soldier wherever it was to be had, with a few exceptions.</p>
                    <p>At Staunton we were also treated kindly. Scarcely an hour in the day passed
                        without something being sent to the camp for our comfort. The same spirit
                        that animated the hearts of our mothers in the days of '76 is still to be
                        found in Old Virginia and in other States. All my acquaintances know that I
                        have ever been a devoted friend of women, but I have now great reason to be
                        more her friend than ever before. Her hand has ever been ready to supply the
                        wants of the soldier as he passed her door, and her generous heart always
                        responsive to those ennobling virtues which render her almost divine. The
                        memory of her kindness has sunk deep into my heart of hearts, and will there
                        be cherished to the remotest period of my life. But I have not language
                        sufficient to do justice to the subject. I shall never forget a kind lady of
                        Staunton, Mrs. A. B. Cowan, who, with her own hands, prepared provisions for
                        me sufficient to last several days. Everything good that she could crowd
                        into my haversack was put in, and then a bundle placed in my hand. Her
                        kindness, and that of her family brought home more forcibly to my mind that
                        I found a tear welling up in my eye. May God bless her and her household.
                        But I have already devoted too much space to myself."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>A.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from the editor of the Central Georgian, a Georgia soldier, to his
                    paper regarding the exemplary treatment his regiment received in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Districting the State</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Outlines the new arrangement of Congressional Districts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Militia Called Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Declares it the duty of all able-bodied men to bear arms in protection of
                    the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Militia Called Out</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that all militia north of the James and east of the Alleghanies are
                    to report to Gen. Beauregard at Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Ex-Gov. Matthews of Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Ex-Gov. Matthews has two sons and a son-in-law in General
                    Johnston's army. Ex-Governor Brown is leading a company called Brown's Raiders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Horse Presented to Gov. Letcher</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that some citizens of Staunton presented a horse to Gov.
                    Letcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Copy of the Facts found by the Court of Inquiry at Beverly, Va, in the case of
                    Col. G. A. Porterfield.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Results of Court of Inquiry investigation of the retreat at Phillipa.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Generals in the Confederate State's Service</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item lists Generals in the Confederate Army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grinnan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter praises the valor of Capt. Grinnan's "Ready Rifles."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Sunday in Camp at Yorktown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from a soldier describing a day in camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Federal Troops Robbing a Virginia Bank</head>
                <origin>Wheeling Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that Union sympathizer troops in Weston seized money appropriated
                    for the building of a lunatic asylum and placed it in the Northwest Virginia
                    Bank in the name of the true State Government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter corrects a mistake by the Spectator, which claimed the 5th was
                    composed entirely of companies from Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Significant Incident</head>
                <origin>Texas Christian Advocate</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserts that a Texas overseer overheard slaves praying for the
                    safety of their master, who had gone off to war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>Diana</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kyle</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eubank</ln>
                        <fn>R.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 11.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Gen. Jackson's Motto</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A quote from Gen. Andrew Jackson used in defense of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Veteran Gone</head>
                <origin>Danville Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He breathed his last with a blessing upon the Confederate forces in the
                    field."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Report of the death of a 104 year old Revolutionary War veteran.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Corn Beer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recipe for corn beer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Stribling Springs</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that Stribling Springs will be open for visitors after June 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom left and right illegible. Two pro-Confederacy poems. Two Proclamations
                from the Governor regarding the raising of troops.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.07.16.02">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
