<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.12.10">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton Spectator</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-12-10">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Senatorial Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item announces senatorial candidates for the Rockbridge, Highland, and Bath
                    district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Ladies of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Too much could not be said in praise of the Ladies of this place, who have
                    done so much for the relief and comfort of the soldiers."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item thanks the ladies of Staunton for making gloves for the troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fatal Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the death of a Georgia soldier after he was run over by a train.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item asserts that the Federal government is sinking old ships in the
                    channels of Southern ports to prevent passage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Amendments to the Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Commissioned officer, soldiers, seamen, or marines in the regular army of
                    the Confederate States to be excluded from the right of suffrage. The object of
                    the amendment is to reserve the right of voting to volunteers in the service."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports amendments made to the State Constitution by the State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Contributions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>R.R. Phillips</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>M.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>D.V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>H.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter thanks those who have contributed items to the Baltimore company
                    stationed in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Virginia property value estimate from the First Auditor of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Correspondence</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents two letters, the first a call from Rockbridge for William Frazier
                    to stand for election to the State Senate, the second an affirmative reply from
                    Mr. Frazier.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Many who were left at home...have to a great extent, proved that they
                    intend to make a fortune at the soldiers expense."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR: Allow me, if you please, to set before your readers a few
                        thoughts which have occupied my mind for some time. When the call was made
                        for volunteers to drive from our soil the invader, and sustain our rights as
                        a free people, it was responded to by thousands of our best men, who left
                        their homes and all that was dear to them and marched to the scene of
                        action, where they have been exposed to privation and dangers of almost
                        every kind, and on taking leave of home they were consoled by the confidence
                        they had in those who did not enter the army, that all would be taken care
                        of and their wants supplied while they were in the army. In this respect the
                        ladies have done nobly, and are worthy of the highest regard of all. But, to
                        the astonishment of the soldiers, many who were left at home, in whom they
                        had the utmost confidence, have to a great extent, proved to them that they
                        intend to make a fortune at the soldiers' expense, and if we are allowed to
                        judge men by their actions, we are brought to the conclusion that a large
                        number of those who are not in the army feel as though they have no part nor
                        lot in the defence of their own homes and rights; they do not seem to be
                        willing to make any sacrifice of time and money, and look upon the soldier
                        as having no higher object in view than the small sum he receives as wages,
                        which, it is well known to all, that it should barely support a small family
                        at the prices of breadstuff and merchandize before the war began. Well, as a
                        matter of course, we could expect nothing else than that the prices of
                        almost everything to advance some; but the present prices are out of all
                        reason and are unjust, and the cause for it is in the speculators, and many
                        of them are men who managed to dodge the active service of their country and
                        have turned their whole attention to speculation--some upon a large and
                        others upon a very small scale. Now, at the very smallest estimate, many of
                        them clear from two to three hundred per cent., which cannot be considered
                        anything else than extortion. Now, as they profess to be serving their
                        country in a way of accommodation by many of those speculations, I think
                        that fifty per cent would be a fair profit, and the balance, I consider, is
                        robbed from the families of the poor soldiers. Now the question arises, is
                        it right? and how can a man who professes to live with an eye single to God,
                        feel justified in His sight while engaged in such speculations? Now, I am a
                        soldier, and have but little of this world's goods, but I have left in good
                        old Augusta a wife and four lovely little children which have, so far, been
                        well taken care of, but as a matter of course, they are depending on me for
                        a support, and if things continue as they are during the war, they must
                        suffer with others in like circumstances.</p>
                    <p>And now, my humble prayer is, that God may unite the hearts of all men in one
                        common cause to save the Confederacy, through Divine Power, that peace may
                        be restored to our distracted land.</p>
                    <p>MONTEREY</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Monterey</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes war profiteers and speculators who take advantage of the supply
                    needs of the army as an excuse to raise prices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Expedition to Start Down Mississippi</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports Federal troops preparing to advance down the Mississippi.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Federal Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table shows the number of soldiers in the Federal army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gov. Letcher's Message</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Selected extracts from the message of Governor Letcher. Majority of the
                    address concentrates on justifying Virginia's presence in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Message</head>
                <origin>Baltimore Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Summary of Lincoln's address to both houses of Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>P.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Resolutions adopted by the Augusta Fire Association on the death of John B.
                    Snider.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Camp Allegheny</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Barbour Grey</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from a soldier camped at Greenbrier River thanking the ladies of
                    Augusta for donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Religious Notice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Harris will preach at the Hebron Church next Sunday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sarah Howard married Alexander Wallace on November 21. Mr. Wallace is from
                    Rockbridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keller</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>Janetta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peace</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nicholson</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notices to appear in court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports of battles, skirmishes, and military maneuvers. List of
                letters not picked up at the post office in column 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Col. Wiley Indicted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that Col. Wiley has been indicted for treason by the Unionist
                    government in Wheeling for burning the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad bridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Official Instructions to the Federal General at Beaufort</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Orders of Adjutant General Thomas to Gen. Sherman in South Carolina to take
                    possession of crops and use slaves for labor in erecting federal defenses at
                    Beaufort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>To Tax-Payers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grills</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Instructions to tax-payers regarding payment of taxes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and reports of skirmishes and military movements from Missouri
                and Columbus.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
