<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.09.03">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-03">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="03">3</day>
            <weekday id="Tue">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>2</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.03.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Favorable Sign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The outrages committed in the Northern States in the violent efforts to
                        suppress any expressions of sentiments in the opposition to the tyranny of
                        Lincolnism, by the demolition of such presses as know their rights and dare
                        to maintain them, furnish the most conclusive evidence that there is a
                        feeling of opposition to the farther prosecution of Lincoln's unholy war
                        pervading the masses of the people of that section which inspires as much
                        dread in the minds of the tyrants at Washington as the masked batteries of
                        the "rebels," the very thought of which makes their knees knock together
                        with more violence than did those of Balthazzar when he read his doom in the
                        mystic handwriting on the wall. They tyrants know that the rights of the
                        people have been ruthlessly violated, that the constitution has been
                        trampled underfoot, that the most sacred bulwarks of freedom have been
                        destroyed, and that they would be justified in rising in the majesty of
                        their strength that they might crush the tyrants who would enslave them, and
                        consequently they fear and tremble and very properly deem their only means
                        of safety consists in a wanton and destruction of such presses as persist in
                        remaining true to the sacred rights of the people. The freedom of speech and
                        the freedom of the press must be destroyed, else the masses of the outraged
                        people will rise in mutiny. The tyrants feel that they are standing upon the
                        crust of a volcano through which the compressed fires of freedom may any day
                        burst forth, and involve them all in total and irrevocable ruin. It is not
                        the presses they dread, so much as it is the response with which their free
                        expressions meet in the hearts of the masses of the people. If the
                        sentiments of these presses did not find an echo in the hearts of the people
                        they would remain unmolested. The fact that they have destroyed such presses
                        as oppose their policy, furnishes conclusive evidence that they are
                        conscious their policy will not bear the test of criticism. They,
                        themselves, affix the brand of conviction of wrong-doing upon their own
                        brows--by their own conduct they stand self-condemned in the pillory of
                        public opinion.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the Republicans have attempted to stifle the expression of
                    dissent in the North to such an extent that the people of the North will soon
                    realize the tyranny of Lincoln and his followers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mr. James Lightner Killed in Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They are arresting and then murdering valuable citizens who have too much
                    patriotism and self-respect to bow to the Baal of Black Republicanism."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alleges that James Lightner, a native of Augusta County, was murdered in
                    Lexington, Missouri by Lincoln's troops "while their prisoner was unarmed and
                    totally at their mercy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Ladies of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>"Without the ladies we would not have a country worth defending."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item encourages the ladies to establish "Soldier Aid Societies" for the
                    purpose of collecting items for the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The President's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>President Davis, in accordance with an act of Congress, has issued his
                        proclamation notifying all of the Southern Confederacy, who do not recognize
                        the authority of the same, to leave within forty days from the date of the
                        proclamation, or they will be treated as alien enemies. The proclamation and
                        the law, we publish in another column for the benefit of all whom they may
                        concern, and advise them to shape their course accordingly. The distance to
                        abolitiondom is short and the coast clear, and the man who is not loyal to
                        the Southern Confederacy has no business in it. This is no time to harbor
                        the disaffected, every one of whom has it in his power to do mischief by
                        acting the spy. All may not do it, but all have it in their power, and
                        should, therefore, be removed beyond our limits. Ours should be a harmonious
                        and homogeneous people.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that President Davis has issued a proclamation notifying those in
                    the Southern Confederacy who do not recognize its authority that they have forty
                    days to depart or they will be treated as alien enemies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mechanical Nursing Swing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopkins</ln>
                        <fn>S.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item announces the invention of the mechanical nursing swing by Dr. Hopkins
                    of Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Various reports of battles and skirmishes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Blockade Broken</head>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the blockade has been broken at Beaufort, North Carolina and
                    an English ship landed carrying contraband. This is taken as a harbinger that
                    the blockade will prove ineffective and that the European powers will be able to
                    trade with the South in a matter of months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Impending Doom</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that two pro-South ladies have been arrested in Washington by the
                    Lincoln government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Complaints of "Phil"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Some Rockbridge man, under the signature of "Phil," in the last Lexington
                        Gazette, in a vein of facetiousness, complains that justice has not been
                        done Rockbridge county in the appointment of field officers of the 52d
                        Regiment, to which that county has furnished three companies. He complains
                        that Augusta county is receiving many honors, and Rockbridge none at all.
                        The Governor should not overlook the merits of "Phil," who would no doubt
                        wear the "shoulder straps" with dignity and grace. The following is an
                        extract from the somewhat lengthy jeremaid of "Phil:"</p>
                    <p>"But a word or so about this new Regiment. It will be seen that in the
                        appointment of officers, Augusta fares well. Inspector General Baldwin is
                        the Colonel. This is regarded as a good appointment, for Col. Baldwin has
                        the intellect to carry him through any position that may be assigned him.
                        But why double honors when there are still a few Augusta men without any
                        military titles? Col. Baldwin is Inspector General. Surely that is enough.
                        But it don't stop here. Augusta must be treble loaded with rank and titles.
                        The Lieutenant Colonel is Michael G. Harman, who, by his flaming
                        proclamations, has made himself familiar as household words to all the
                        people of West Augusta and a thousand other Western places besides, under
                        his stirring appeals and over his flaming signature of "Quartermaster and
                        Major Commanding." It appears that in the roaring tide of his affection for
                        Augusta, the Governor can find more titles and offices for that favored
                        county than he can find men to wear them. He had doubled Baldwin's, and when
                        it comes to his especial favorite, Mike, two ain't enough, he must give the
                        "Quartermaster and Major Commanding," a third, so that Mike can rise in his
                        stirrups, mount a new shoulder strap and equestrianize through the
                        thoroughfares of Staunton with Ostrich feather streaming out behind and a
                        longer title floating out before, so that we may all know that Mike, in
                        addition to what he was as Quartermaster and Major Commanding is now also
                        Lieutenant Colonel. Originally it was M.G. Harman, "Quartermaster and Major
                        Commanding," <emph rend="italic">ex officio</emph> Governor of Western
                        Virginia; now with the rank and increased dignity of Lieutenant Colonel, why
                        cannot Mike also be know and revered as Lord of Augusta and Duke of
                        Staunton? In view of the double and treble burden of rank and title which
                        the Augusta Colonel and Lieutenant Colonel of this new Regiment have to bear
                        upon their physical constitutions, we would suggest that about six or a
                        dozen additional surgeons be appointed from Augusta (or the more favored
                        because more loyal Northwest) to this new and prodigally titled regiment, as
                        special guardians of the health of the two Colonels with five titles, to say
                        nothing of the ranks and degrees that belong to their <emph rend="italic">ex
                            officios</emph>. </p>
                    <p>But what shall we say of the Major of this titulary Regiment? Well, we don't
                        know what. Just Major Ross, and nothing more; for he doesn't come in with a
                        long array of titles and <emph rend="italic">ex officios</emph>. He
                        represents Rockbridge, but from what county he is from we don't know, and
                        refer the inquisitive reader to Gov. Letcher, who possibly may know from
                        whence he hails. "Know then this truth, Enough for us to know," </p>
                    <p>he is duly labelled and credited to Rockbridge. Let us be thankful for what
                        has been intended for our brave and gallant county, although she hasn't got
                        anything. We will take the will for the deed, and be grateful to the
                        Governor for what Rockbridge ought to have but what she has not got."</p>
                    <p>The editor of the Gazette, in reference to the article of "Phil," says:</p>
                    <p>"Our correspondent, "Phil," in speaking of the field officers of the Regiment
                        composed of the volunteers out of the militia of Rockbridge and Augusta,
                        does injustice to perhaps all of the gentlemen. As to the first, Col.
                        Baldwin, no better appointment could have been made, and we regard it as a
                        noble act in him in leaving a higher position and going into more active
                        service in a lower position. Indeed we regard it as pure patriotism for him
                        to take any military position. For our part, we would prefer the fame that
                        John B. Baldwin has as a lawyer, to the military fame of any of any man in
                        Virginia. If, therefore, Col. Baldwin estimates real greatness as we do, he
                        has no reason to aspire to any military position. None can elevate him above
                        the position which he has attained by the brightness of his own genius.</p>
                    <p>We know nothing of Mr. Harman as a military man.</p>
                    <p>In respect to Mr. Ross, we have always taken him to be an admirable
                        gentleman, and we believe that he stood well as a tactician at the V.M.
                        Institute.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Addresses the complaints of a writer from Rockbridge named Phil who
                    complains that Augusta is receiving a disproportionate amount of recognition in
                    the way of appointments and accolades in the 52nd Regiment. The writer implies
                    that appointments are heaped upon the already titled and wealthy of Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Harness and Wagon Makers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Harman is seeking to contract the labor of Harness and Wagon
                    makers for the Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Battle of the Oak Hills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Official C.S.A. report of the battle of the Oak Hills.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Plenty of Lead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Southern victory in Missouri has given the South access to
                    a rich lead mine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Federal Blockade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a law passed by the C.S.A. that allows ships to dock anywhere
                    they are able to dodge the blockade. This eliminates established points of entry
                    and allows ships to pay duties at the nearest port.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation by the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclamation outlines Davis's intention to expel from the Confederacy all
                    who claim allegiance to the United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Extract of the Letter of a Lady of Bangor, Maine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extract from a letter allegedly found on one of Lincoln's soldiers at
                    Manassas from a woman in Maine whose sympathies lie with the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Touching Incident of the Battlefield</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of a letter received in New York from Atlanta about finding the body
                    of a young boy dead on the battlefield at Stone Bridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Penetrating the Nether Regions</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A humorous anecdote about a Western Virginia oilman who was having his
                    slaves bore for oil at night by firelight when they struck upon a vein of gas
                    that ignited the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Son of Virginia</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer suggests that office holders who are exempt from military service
                    should tithe to the Confederate cause from their salaries.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Southern Soldiers' Song in the Mountains of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pro-Confederate poem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Patriotism in the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article tells the story of a man with a large family who left to serve in
                    the military, demonstrating the patriotism of Southerners.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Silas Karacole Killed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karacole</ln>
                        <fn>Silas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Silas Karacole died after getting caught in a threshing
                    machine.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Hallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Robt. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hallie died on August 18 at age 1 year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Cyrus Strickler died in Charlottesville on July 26 from a wound he
                    sustained at Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbarger</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Harris died at the home of her mother, Mrs. Rosenbarger on August 8.
                    She was a member of the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shuey</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>B.F. Shuey died on July 22 at age 26 from a wound received at the Battle of
                    Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.03.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Notice, By the Governor of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor presents a plan for obtaining clothing for the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
