<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.09.10">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-09-10">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.10.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>North and South</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond Whig says that "no people who respect themselves can desire
                        association with the Yankee race--no State that cherishes independence can
                        trust its fortunes to Yankee government. One by one the bulwarks of State
                        sovereignty, and the muniment of individual liberty, have been destroyed,
                        till nothing remains worth preserving. A reign of terror prevails in the
                        Yankee States, and those subject to them, as complete, if not <emph
                            rend="italic">yet</emph> quite so violent, as swept over France in the
                        days of Robespierre. As one of their journals remarks, it requires but one
                        step to inaugurate the scenes of the French revolution when the guillotine
                        was a perennial fountain of blood. </p>
                    <p>Men and women are daily arrested in Washington, New York and Philadelphia
                        (says a contemporary, summing up the atrocities of the usurpation,) and
                        thrown into loathsome dungeons, without warrant of law, and without being
                        confronted with their accusers or advised of the charges against them.
                        Journals are suppressed for denouncing the actions of the Government.
                        Editors are lynched and their printing offices destroyed by the mob. Forced
                        loans are demanded of the banks. A system of detectives is organized at
                        Washington, to dog the steps of peaceable citizens, report to the tyrants
                        and arrest persons suspected of opposing the usurper's will. No Neapolitan
                        despotism or Spanish Inquisition ever exceeded in the measure of its
                        cruelty, the present Dictatorship at Washington. The Doge's dungeon in
                        Venice, which yet stands a monument of tyranny, is represented in Forts
                        LaFayette and Hamilton, names that are worthy of a more honorable fate. The
                        Government of the United States is prostituted to the vilest purposes of the
                        most infamous men that ever walked the earth. There is no such thing as
                        public or individual liberty in the United States. Men, to be free, must
                        sing paens [sic] to a baboon and worship the Government of usurpers. They
                        must sanction the most unholy war ever waged against a free people. They
                        must approve of the destruction of their own liberties. They must become
                        slaves, in order to enjoy exemption from molestation.</p>
                    <p>There is more in these arrests than meets the eye. It indicates a deep and
                        determined opposition to the acts of Government, among the wiser and more
                        virtuous men of the North. It evinces that the tyrants are trembling on
                        their thrones and fear the day of reckoning, which will sweep them violently
                        from their seats of power. They fear not only the armies of the Confederate
                        States, which, in the language of a member of the Cabinet, are already
                        "thundering at the gates of the Capitol." They stand in awe not merely of
                        those gallant legions, which have driven them like dogs howling back to
                        their kennels from Bethel, Manassas and Oak Hill. But they fear the, as yet,
                        unorganized masses of their own section, who are preparing for them the doom
                        of Belshazzar, and who will hold them to a just and stern accountability for
                        their crimes. They fear the rising indignation of an outraged and
                        down-trodden people, who have been betrayed by fear and excitement into an
                        acquiescence in the usurper's acts, but who have not been educated in the
                        short space of five months to support the yoke of an absolute despotism,
                        after having received the blood bought heritage of freedom from their
                        fathers, and enjoyed its blessings from their birth.</p>
                    <p>Meanwhile the Confederate States are calm and impregnable. But for the
                        mustering of the troops, which we see about us every day, we should scarcely
                        know that anything unusual was in progress. No man in the South complains
                        that his individual rights are trespassed upon. No State feels that she is
                        in danger of losing her liberties. Our independence is a fact. Our
                        prosperity is beyond a contingency. The North may hurl charge after charge
                        upon us, but their "Grand Armies" will be routed and driven back, as fast as
                        they come. Ere long foreign powers will be seen marching on the field to
                        salute the victor, and demand, in the name of commerce, humanity and
                        civilization for the sake of the world, the peaceful recognition of Southern
                        independence.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that civil liberties are being trampled in the North, as freedom of
                    speech and of the press have been curtailed and arbitrary arrests and harassment
                    by the authorities have become increasingly common. The article also reports
                    that no such abuse has occurred in the South, where calm, order and liberty are
                    maintained.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Skirmish near the Hawk's Nest in Fayette Co.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dillard</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lofland</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports a skirmish in Fayette Co. where Frank Dillard, who was acting as
                    substitute for Harry Lofland, was killed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Education</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Whilst we are endeavoring to preserve the liberty and independence of the
                    South, we should not neglect the duty we owe the youth of the rising generation,
                    who, in a few years, will be the custodians of the weal and liberty of the
                    Confederate States."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We would invite the attention of the public to the advertisement of Rev. Geo.
                        B. Taylor found in our advertising columns. Mr. Taylor possesses the
                        requisite qualifications to make an excellent instructor of youth. We hope
                        that his school will be liberally patronized. Whilst we are endeavoring to
                        preserve the liberty and independence of the South, we should not neglect
                        the duty we owe the youth of the rising generation, who, in a few years,
                        will be the custodians of the weal and liberty of the Confederate States.
                        The very best investment parents make is the money devoted to the education
                        of their children. It is better to give a child a good education, than to
                        bequeath him a fortune of ten thousand dollars.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item calls attention to an advertisement of George B. Taylor, who is "an
                    excellent educator of youth."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The 52nd. Virginia Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The 52nd Virginia Regiment under command of Col. John B. Baldwin will leave
                        this place today (Tuesday) for more active and stirring scenes. Should this
                        fine Regiment get an opportunity to pay its respects to the enemy, we feel
                        confident that it will acquit itself with credit.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the imminent departure of the 52nd from Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Battle of Cross Lanes on the 26th of August</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article gives more details of the 26th of August battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Skirmishing of the Army of the Potomac</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports successful skirmishing with the Army of the Potomac.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports resolutions of a meeting of the Lexington Presbytery at Mt.
                    Horeb Church in Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Confederate Elections</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports the upcoming Confederate elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ross</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>McCue and Ross entered a contract with the Confederacy for the manufacture
                    of saltpeter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Mexico the Ally of Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Lincoln has secured the permission of Mexico to march troops
                    through Mexican territory for the purpose of invading the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Reaction in Kentucky</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the citizens of Kentucky are in support of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Reason, Right, and Vigilance</head>
                <origin>Syracuse (N.Y.) Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An attack on the abuse of civil rights is taking place in the North. Only a
                    free press and a free ballot can counter this unconstitutional attack on rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Reign of Terror in St. Louis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that a reign of terror is taking place in the city of St. Louis.
                    The citizens are allegedly suffering from a suspension of civil rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Earthquake in Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports an earthquake in Tennessee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Spirit of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that a Mr. Watson of Mississippi has raised a company and equipped
                    it at his own expense. This is taken as a sign of the South's war spirit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Openly Defiant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that the people of Belfast, Missouri are openly defying the
                    Federal Government and have declared their disloyalty to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>An Appeal to the South, St. Charles Hotel Hospital</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the activities of the St. Charles Hotel Hospital in Richmond and
                    asks for donations from the citizens of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Commissioners for Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the appointment of Messrs. Michie, Baylor, and Crawford as
                    commissioners for the county superintending the election of President and Vice
                    President.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Northern Dispatches</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Various items of news from the North.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Captive Confederate Officers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article gives a brief biography of several captured Confederate
                    officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sketch of the Proceedings of the Council of the Town of Staunton, August 31,
                    1861</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getty</ln>
                        <fn>E.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proceedings of the town council.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer apprises the public about the condition of the sick in the
                    Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Camp Onward, near Fairfax C.H.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>W. Crawford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article reports a meeting of the Augusta Valley Rangers in which a tribute
                    of respect was offered to the late W. Crawford McCue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>More Soldiers from Rockingham</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the birth of triplets to Capt. William F. Destrick of the Company
                    G Virginia Militia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Blockade a Farce</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that ships are easily evading the Union blockade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Bloody Code for Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports that Gen. Fremont of Missouri has declared martial law.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gay</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Fanny Gay died on September 2 at age 74.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Horace George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Ella</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Horace Myers died on August 25 at age 4 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 7 advertisements and markets</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.09.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Disloyalty</head>
                <origin>New York Day Book</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We find the following editorial in the New York <emph rend="italic">Day
                        Book</emph> of August 26: </p>
                    <p>But it is said we are "disloyal." Disloyalty!--What is it? To be "loyal" must
                        we believe in "the irrepressible conflict" of Seward, "the negro equality"
                        of Chase, the "ultimate extinction" theory of Lincoln, and that the Helper
                        book is a "valuable political document?" Must we believe that Seward is as
                        great a statesman as Jefferson, that Cameron is as incorruptible as Diogenes
                        and that Lincoln is as learned as Machiavelli? Must we believe that black is
                        white, that two and two make five? In fact, must we commit intellectual
                        suicide? Does Mr. Lincoln's Administration demand all this as the price of
                        "loyalty?" If so, the price exceeds our ability to pay.</p>
                    <p>But it is said we oppose the Government. How, where or when? Bring on your
                        accusers: let the case be brought before the court. Let me see the counts
                        and the specifications. If to be "loyal" means sincere reverence for the
                        Constitution--a fervent love of the Union--an inevitable repugnance to its
                        overthrow, and earnest labor and exertion to prevent such a great national
                        catastrophe--if these be the price of "loyalty," then do we and have we
                        rendered them cheerfully, earnestly, and with a single eye to the good of
                        our country. What more can we do? We cannot prevent the avalanche of
                        falsehoods with which day after day Republican papers slander and libel us.
                        To ask justice or mercy from these fanatical journals that seek to destroy
                        the independent Democratic press because they fear its power, is to ask the
                        lion to give up its prey after he has caught it. Puritanical tyranny never
                        yielded power until choked into repentance.</p>
                    <p>At all events our right and duty as an Amer-citizen are fulfilled, and if for
                        this we fall under the ban of official punishment, we shall not fail to
                        protest against the unconstitutional usurpation, or to defend, until the pen
                        is snatched from our hand, the rights of the people, and to execrate, ever
                        though a dungeon opened its portals before us, the hypocrisy of a party
                        which, getting into power under the pretence or regard for the negro, had
                        riveted the chains of slavery upon millions of white men.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Editorial from the New York Day Book argues that the paper is not disloyal
                    just because it disagrees with many of the principles of the Republican party
                    and opposes the Lincoln administration.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Unfortunate Marylanders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that the people of Maryland are fleeing to Virginia to escape the
                    tyranny of Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
