<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.05.14">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-05-14">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote>Due to a malfunction in the printing machinery, this edition came out a day
            late, Wednesday, May 15.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Harney's Account of his Arrest and Subsequent Adventure in Virginia</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of Gen. Harney's arrest in Harpers Ferry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Missouri Legislature--The Message of the Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item quotes the Governor of Missouri asserting his intention to keep
                    Missouri in the Union at this time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Attention Volunteers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from an Alabama man to his son regarding his duties as a soldier
                    and his reasons for fighting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Baltimore Exchange</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Questions why the Northern Abolitionists, who think slavery an unmitigated
                    evil, do not allow the South to secede peacefully in order to remove the
                    contaminating institution from the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Hon. Garrett Davis's Visit to President Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts Garrett Davis's visit to Lincoln and the gist of their
                    conversation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Another Lie Exposed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p> The Boston <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph> recently published a statement
                        to the effect that several Yankee shoemakers, who had been employed in
                        Staunton, Va., were driven away from the place after being imprisoned, et.
                        Mr. G. S. Raymond, late foreman of the Staunton Shoe Factory, who is also a
                        New Englander, has the honor and moral courage to refute this gratuitous
                        slander. He publishes a card in the <emph rend="italic">Journal</emph>, in
                        which he says that the party referred to "were not interfered with in any
                        manner at Staunton, but were perfectly free to go away or remain, as they
                        chose." It seems that they preferred to leave, and went "through the entire
                        route without any molestation whatever." Mr. Raymond closes his card by
                        saying: </p>
                    <p>I have to advise the friends of those remaining there that they need have no
                        fear regarding their safety--they are free to remain or leave, as they
                        choose. The probability is that they will leave, as they have a perfectly
                        free route from Staunton to the Pennsylvania line by stages.</p>
                    <p>"Justice to the honorable gentlemen of the Staunton Shoe Company, and justice
                        to the good people of Staunton generally, demands of me these
                    statements."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raymond</ln>
                        <fn>G.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the rumor that several Yankee shoemakers had been imprisoned
                    and then expelled from Staunton is untrue.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>New York Daily News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Northern writer asks if it is worth the cost to pursue an abolitionist
                    crusade when it seems the South is concerned mainly with its own defense.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Address from the Peace Society of London to the People of the United States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Respectful letter from the Peace Society of London warning the people of
                    the U.S. not to embark upon a fratricidal war because of the dire consequences
                    that may result.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Righteous Cause of the South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the Southern cause as just and praises Virginia's intention to
                    defend itself with the sword.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom right illegible</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Pledge not to Invade</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>If Lincoln has any regard for the most positive pledge given by him in the
                        midst of the imposing ceremonies of inauguration, and under the solemn
                        sanction of that "oath" which he speaks of as being "recorded in Heaven,"
                        there will be "no invasion" of our State beyond the localities of the
                        property heretofore held by the United States Government, and "no using of
                        force against or among the people anywhere."</p>
                    <p> It will thus be seen that he gave the most positive assurance, under the
                        most solemn circumstances, that the "power confided" to him would not be
                        used to any degree "beyond what may be necessary to hold, occupy and possess
                        the property and places belonging to the Government," and that beyond this
                        there would be "<emph rend="italic">no invasion--no using of force against
                            or among the people anywhere.</emph>" If, in violation of this pledge,
                        he should send troops into the interior of the State, he would show that he
                        is a falsifier in whom the truth cannot be found, and that he has a poor
                        chance, unless a radical change takes place, even to see the record of his
                            "<emph rend="italic">oath in heaven.</emph>" </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses hope that Lincoln will keep his inaugural promise not to invade
                    the seceded states apart from those localities or properties previously held by
                    the United States.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14b</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>32nd Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The regimental muster at New Hope took place on the previous Friday. The
                    speakers "all urged the importance of unanimity in voting for the ordinance of
                    secession and resistance to Lincoln."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Consecrated remains of Gen. Washington have been removed from Mr. Vernon
                        to Lexington, to prevent them from being desecrated by the hyena-like
                        Vandals of the North.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The remains of George Washington have been moved from Mt. Vernon to
                    Lexington to "prevent them from being desecrated by the hyena-like Vandals of
                    the North."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14c</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Question at large in this Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article places blame for the current crisis on Lincoln and his political
                    ambitions. The writer also encourages the voters to vote for secession in the
                    upcoming elections.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Hon. Alex R. Boteler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter from Unionist Alex R. Boteler supporting secession in
                    view of Lincoln's call for troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Speculators</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"Virginius," the Charleston Correspondent of the Richmond Dispatch, aims some
                        very severe, though well-deserved, blows at those miserly and contracted
                        souls who would speculate upon the present dire necessities of the people by
                        demanding exorbitant prices for the necessaries of life. The following is an
                        extract from the letter of that correspondent:</p>
                    <p>"We have in this city set very good examples to the world of disinterested
                        patriotism, but I begin to hear occasionally that some "hoarse voice" that
                        was heard in revolutionary times in Hanover county, as described by Wirt in
                        one of Patrick Henry's speeches against an unprincipled speculator--"Beef,
                        beef, beef." Provisions in our city all at once popped up 50 per cent.--Hams
                        now sell at 20 cents, sides 17 cents, coffee 18 1/2 to 20 cents, flour
                        $10.50 to $12.50, and butter 50 cents. In most instances these provisions
                        were held by Yankee agents, here, and in some instances by natives, but the
                        mark will be as indelibly fixed upon them for all time as that put upon the
                        first murderer, Cain, by the finger of God Almighty, and right that it
                        should be.</p>
                    <p>In times like these, no man with a soul will speculate upon his neighbor and
                        his people, and he who does it ought to be made to feel the weight of public
                        odium and disapproval.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Criticizes speculators who are using the crisis as an excuse to raise
                    prices.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14d</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Different Kind of Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The flower of Southern honor and chivalry will cross swords with rowdies,
                    cutthroats and burglars from the corrupt cesspools of Northern cities."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>One of the most melancholy features of the horrible and bloody strife into
                        which this country is about to be involved consists in the fact that the
                        very best portion of the population of the South will be required to meet in
                        mortal combat, in great part, the very worst population of the North.
                        Whenever the South shall lose a soldier, it will lose a valuable citizen,
                        whose loss will be sensibly felt, whereas the North would be benefitted if a
                        large portion of its soldiers would never return from the battle-field. The
                        flower of Southern honor and chivalry will cross swords with rowdies,
                        cut-throats and burglars from the corrupt cesspools of Northern cities.--the
                        South sends into the field honorable, honest, moral and virtuous soldiers,
                        the North such desperadoes, and dangerous men as she is afraid to keep at
                        home. As an illustration of the spirit of our people, and the kind of men
                        who are volunteering their services to the State, we will mention the fast
                        that a number of Minsters of the Gospel who are distinguished for talents,
                        cultivation, eloquence and piety, have exchanged the "sacred desk" for the
                        soldier's tent.</p>
                    <p>The Rev. Dr. B. M. Smith and Rev. Dr. R. L. Dabney, Professors of the "Union
                        Theological Seminary," Rev. Dr. Moses oge, Pastor of the 2nd Presbyterian
                        Church in Richmond city, and Rev. Dr. Pendleton, Rector of the Episcopal
                        Church in Lexington, all of whom are well known in this county, have
                        connected themselves with volunteer companies. Dr. Pendleton is now Captain
                        of an Artillery Company in Lexington, being elected to supply the vacancy
                        caused by the promotion of Capt. McCausland to the post of lieutenant
                        Colonel of Volunteers. As Dr. Pendleton is a graduate of West Point, and has
                        served several years in the army, he will no doubt make a good and efficient
                        officer.--Though the conflict may be terrible, we do no doubt that, in time,
                        the Northern "Apollyon" will succumb to the Southern "Christian," and that
                        our brave soldiery who go forth clad in the panoply of a just cause, will
                        return with their banners--though "tattered and torn"--wreathed with the
                        laurels of victory.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article claims that the South is sending its best sons to war while the
                    Northern army is composed of the lowest breed of Northerner.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14e</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Right of Revolution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends the right of revolution, using a quote from a speech of Abraham
                    Lincoln to support this view.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>More Companies Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Asher</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roberts</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the departure of more troops from Augusta to report for State
                    service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Col. Baylor gave an address to a group of Augusta citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the Irishmen of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The following comes from adopted citizens of Charleston, and is well
                        endorsed:</p>
                    <p>Fellow-Countrymen:--Being impressed with the first and great duty which we
                        owe to the land of our adoption in these its present difficulties, we are
                        carrying out measures for organizing a Confederate Irish Regiment, for the
                        service of the Southern States. This, we must admit, is expected from us.
                        Let us take up the cause of an honorable, just and upright people. They
                        never interfered with our religious institutions, a subject which our
                        friends of Massachusetts must have forgotten very soon; or is it possible
                        that the burning of the Charlestown Convent did not make an impression, and
                        open their eyes to the true character of their hightened [sic] Puritanic
                        leaders? Although Know-Nothingism crept into a few sections of the Southern
                        States from the hot-beds of the North, it was crushed in its embryo by our
                        noble and chivalric people, who are too exalted to lend themselves to the
                        encouragement of any doctrine that would have such direful effects on the
                        prospects of their adopted fellow-citizens.</p>
                    <p>No man was ever persecuted in the South on account of his religious belief.
                        And do our countrymen at the North forget how eager their neighbors were in
                        publishing and circulating books detailing disgusting lies about escaped
                        nuns for the purpose of arousing the feelings of the Prostestant [sic] sects
                        against the Catholics? We appeal to you for your decision in favor of the
                        Southern cause, and also for the justification of the position we are about
                        assuming in standing manfully by it.</p>
                    <p>Strange scenes are being developed every day. There is one of the exiled sons
                        of Ireland who was received all through the Southern States (as only a noble
                        and generous people know how)--making preparations to march alongside of
                        John Bull, heart and hand, to subjugate the very people who conferred on him
                        the greatest encomiums, and had his name enrolled as an honorary member of
                        their societies, and denominated military companies in respect to him. But
                        is this to continue? No. Never again shall the name of Thomas Francis
                        Meagher be united with any of our Southern institutions. We say, let them
                        come, and learn that the foreigners of the Southern States have hearts as
                        true as their steel in maintaining the rights and independence of the South.</p>
                    <p>We therefore submit to you a plan for organizing our regiment. There are a
                        great many of our countrymen already enlisted in the service of the Southern
                        Confederacy, and hence our inability to raise a regiment immediately
                        here,--We have appealed to Georgia. The prospects are promising, and it
                        naturally struck us that our countrymen in Virginia would be anxious to
                        participate in the movement. If so, we will appoint place of rendezvous as
                        soon as the undertaking is sufficiently matured.</p>
                    <p>For further information, address</p>
                    <p> Many Irishmen, <lb/> Key-Box No. 5, Charleston, S. C. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Irish immigrants in Charleston asking fellow Irish to help
                    organize a Confederate Irish Regiment in support of the South. The letter
                    asserts that the Southern people have courteously respected the Catholic faith,
                    unlike the puritanical Northerners.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14f</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Vote for Secession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Conservative</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Entreats the people of Virginia to vote for secession in light of Lincoln's
                    proclamation and subsequent Northern zeal in carrying out the assembly of
                    troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>D.S. Young writes to accept the call to run for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shefffy</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter nominating Bolivar Christian as a candidate for the State Senate
                    and Maj. James Walker, Hugh Sheffey, and John A. Harman as candidates for the
                    House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vandiver</ln>
                        <fn>D.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>A.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howpe</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peck</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaghe</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maozy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>J.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wendell</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scribling</ln>
                        <fn>F.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>G.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Lucas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from many Augusta residents asking Hon A.H. Stuart to express his
                    opinion regarding the course Augusta should take in voting for or against the
                    Ordinance of Secession. In his reply, Stuart says that the people should stand
                    by the decision of the Convention in light of Lincoln's proclamation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Col. Baldwin's Position</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from Baldwin to G.B. Manly of Pennsylvania in which he supports
                    the right of revolution in view of Lincoln's proclamation and asks that the
                    North allow the South to withdraw peacefully.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is said a good many persons in this county will vote against the secession
                        of Virginia; a report which I can hardly credit. I have been as strong a
                        Union man as any one, perhaps, in the county, but believing, as I now do,
                        that the last hope for a reconstruction of the Union on fair and honorable
                        terms has fled, and that it is utterly impossible for the North and the
                        South to live together in peace, I have come to the conclusion to vote for
                        secession. Until within a few days, I thought I would not vote at all; but
                        learning from various Northern newspapers the fiendish feeling that is
                        exhibited by the whole North towards us of the South, I shall now go with
                        all my heart and soul for the South. How anyone after reading the editorials
                        of many of the leading papers published at the North, can vote against
                        secession, or even not vote at all, I cannot imagine. Is it not the
                        threatened policy of the North to invade our State and take from us by brute
                        force, our lands, our houses, and all that we possess, and divide it among
                        themselves? Their cry is "booty and beauty," which means, in plain English,
                        as I understand it, to steal our lands from us, and ravish our females. Any
                        one that doubts can get the newspapers and read for themselves.</p>
                    <p>And now I would ask, in conclusion, brave men of old Augusta, can you, will
                        you, stand this? Rather, will you not defend your mothers, your wives, your
                        daughters, and your sisters, to the very death. Then, let all come to the
                        polls, and show the North that we have not a man amongst us who, in any way
                        whatever, is willing to give the faintest shadow of a hope that he is not
                        true to the South.</p>
                    <p>AUGUSTA.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Augusta</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer supports secession based on the assumption that the goal of the
                    North is to steal Southern property and ravage Southern women.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmay61.html#5.14g</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from Stuart declining the call to stand for re-election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter writer says the county is not prepared to issue County Bonds.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>Bolivar</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Bolivar Christian accepts the call to run for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Hugh Sheffey accepts the call to run for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Many Voters</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter wishes to draft William M. Tate to stand for election to the House
                    of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. McCue announces his candidacy to the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Massie</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. Massie announces his candidacy for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Walker announces his candidacy for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Wilson declines the call to run for the House of Delegates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Bottom left illegible. Articles concerning troop movements in other states.
                Telegraphic dispatches from Confederate States discussing war
            preparations.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.14.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Women of Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Entreats the women of the state to work on making clothing for the war
                    effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Booth</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Willie Cornelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willie Cornelia Clarke, daughter of Dr. Wm. Clarke and step daughter of
                    G.W. Booth, died at age 8.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Dull died near Middlebrook on May 13 at age 57. She was a member of
                    the Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.05.14.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
