<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.01.22">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-01-22">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>4</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.01.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>God Gave Our Noble Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It came to us in darkness <lb/>It came to us through blood; <lb/>It shone out
                        like the "Promise <lb/>Of God" upon the flood. <lb/>A Beacon--it has served
                        us <lb/>With true, unerring flame, <lb/>And cast a blaze of glory <lb/>Upon
                        our nation's name! <lb/>God save our noble Union! </p>
                    <p>'Twas left us by our fathers, <lb/>Those souls of priceless worth-- <lb/>The
                        noblest types of manhood <lb/>That ever walked the earth. <lb/>'Twas bought
                        with fearful struggles, <lb/>By sacrifice sublime, <lb/>And stands a proud
                        momento <lb/>For all the coming time-- <lb/>God save the noble Union! </p>
                    <p>Our land a waste of nature, <lb/>Where beast and savage strayed; <lb/>Its
                        wealth of lakes and rivers <lb/>Unlocked by keys of trade; <lb/>Then sunlike
                        rose the <emph rend="italic">Union</emph>-- <lb/>A terror to our foes--
                        <lb/>And lo! this "waste of nature" <lb/>Now "blossoms as the rose!"
                        <lb/>God save our noble Union! </p>
                    <p>Where earth lay hid for ages <lb/>In deep primeval gloom, <lb/>Behold a
                        boundless garden-- <lb/>A continent in bloom! <lb/>With iron bands of
                        railroads, <lb/>Electric tongues of wire, <lb/>And energies within us
                        <lb/>Which time shall never tire-- <lb/>God save the noble Union! </p>
                    <p>But now upon our heaven <lb/>Are signs of coming storms; <lb/>And dark unholy
                        passions <lb/>Unfold their hideous forms. <lb/>The bravest hearts among us
                        <lb/>Are filled with doubt and fear; <lb/>While sounds of horrid discord
                        <lb/>Are grating on our ear-- <lb/>God save the noble Union! </p>
                    <p>The hallowed flag that bore us <lb/>So proudly through the wars-- <lb/>Is
                        there a hand would sever <lb/>Its <emph rend="italic">sisterhood of
                        stars!</emph><lb/>Great God! can we so blindly <lb/>Cast all Thy gifts away?
                        <lb/>Or throbs there in this nation <lb/>One heart that will not pray--
                        <lb/>God save our noble Union! </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A poem extolling the virtues of the Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan61.html#1.22a</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. John M. Botts.</head>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I am willing to fight the battles of Virginia in a just cause, but I am
                    not willing to fight the battles of South Carolina in a bad cause."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>John Botts argues against Virginia making common cause with South Carolina
                    because the states' interests are dissimilar, apart from the issue of slavery.
                    The writer feels this issue is insufficient to compel Virginia into a potential
                    war because the non-slaveholding populace will do a disproportionate amount of
                    the fighting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor:</emph>--The North and the South are two
                        different populations, presenting at present a mutual antagonism. The great
                        problem for statesmen, is not to give them unity, but concord. The Union
                        cannot be saved. It may possibly be reconstructed. A reconstruction must
                        henceforth be the aim of the patriot. One drop of blood will blot out that
                        hope forever.-- How may bloodshed be prevented? The first condition is
                        Southern unanimity. Discord among us is folly, madness, wickedness. The
                        general policy of the South will depend upon that of Virginia, and the
                        influence of Virginia will depend upon the consolidation of her sentiments.
                        Division in Virginia on so vital a question would be fatal to herself, to
                        the South, to the entire country. We must lay aside all party prejudices,
                        all preconceived opinions, forget what we have said of one another, in the
                        heat of party strife, and with one mind and heart resolve to preserve the
                        integrity of the Commonwealth and the peace of the nation. </p>
                    <p>What should Virginia do? That question a Convention must determine. If
                        coercion is abandoned by the agpressive party of the North, we may consult
                        self respect by declining to follow South Carolina, and even adhere to the
                        present confederacy, in the hope of seeing the Constitution remodeled, with
                        permanent guarantees, on a basis equal and acceptable to all the States.
                        These guarantees must be given. Now is the time for a final settlement of
                        the slavery question. The time for legislation or geographical compromise
                        has passed. The North must agree, by a permanent compact, to recognize
                        property in slaves, and to protect it whenever our <emph rend="italic"
                            >common</emph> soil extends within the limits of the Constitution. She
                        must abandon the claim she has asserted, to exclude Southern property from
                        the common soil, simply because Northern sentiment disapproves of that
                        property. She must agree to act just as she would if that sentiment did not
                        prevail. Allowing Northern men to emigrate to the common territories without
                        forfeiting <emph rend="italic">their</emph> possessions, she must consent
                        that Southern men shall do the same. She must execute her solemn engagements
                        for the rendition of fugitive slaves, and give us security for the future
                        that the anti-slavery agitation should not interfere with the rights of the
                        Southern people. If she will thus engage, it may be the glory of Virginia,
                        by timely mediation, to procure a reconstruction of the Union, and a
                        restoration of every star to its place in the grand galaxy of States. </p>
                    <p>If, on the other hand, a drop of Southern blood should be shed by a Northern
                        Administration in the effort to force back seceding States into the Union,
                        then be it called secession, or revolution, let her people, as one man
                        determine to make common cause with the oppressed. No man should call
                        himself a Virginian who would distract the councils of the State on such an
                        occasion. No false pride should cause us to hesitate, because our advice has
                        been rejected and our delicate interests disregarded by a sister State. The
                        flattering suggestions of those who should seek to embarrass our course by
                        such appeals should not be heeded, or heeded only as the voice of treason.</p>
                    <p>In such a crisis, a great gulf would divide us from the North. Common
                        interests and a common necessity would bind us to the South. To hesitate on
                        the plea of wounded pride, would be the extreme of folly. One campaign
                        together in arms would obliterate every impression of our differences.
                        Reproach and ridicule would be forgotten amid the anguish of our common
                        distress, or the exultation of a common triumph.--Hush, then, every
                        distracting suggestion. Away with every thought of dividing this glorious
                        Commonwealth directly through the heart!</p>
                    <p>It has been suggested that Virginia may be divided, to accommodate the varied
                        interests of her people. The author of such a suggestion ought to be rebuked
                        by an indignant people. If dissolution were to be followed by disintegration
                        and anarchy, the alternative would be worse than tyranny itself. There is no
                        hope for the fallen temple, if its ruins be reduced to powder. Their
                        integrity must be preserved, if ever they are to take their place in a noble
                        structure.</p>
                    <p>No! No! Virginia will not go to pieces at the word of a traitor. She will
                        maintain her integrity, her liberty, and glory, and power, we trust, the
                        guiding star through this night of storm.</p>
                    <p>When our common dangers are over, it will be time enough to discuss the
                        geographical boundaries of new confederacies; time enough to talk of union
                        with Ohio rather than with Georgia; time enough to plan a campaign against
                        Florida for the purpose of wresting from her Pensacola; time enough to set
                        up Norfolk as a rival to New York and Charleston. My soul! Shall sensible
                        men engage in these petty discussions, when the horrors of a barbaric
                        invasion are already gathered on our northern border, and the warning
                        thunder reverberates from State to State, calling us to measures of
                        immediate defence! Is this statesmanship! Is this patriotism!</p>
                    <p>In sixty days, according to all human foresight, every Southern man will be
                        compelled by circumstances to take a decided stand for or against the South.
                        The middle ground will then be untenable. We must abandon it then forever.
                        It would be more graceful, more becoming, more manly to abandon it now. We
                        do not advocate extreme opinions, but prompt and decided action--the Union
                        of the South for the sake of the Union!</p>
                    <p>The prompt decision of our Legislature ought to be sustained by a harmonious
                        public sentiment. Let Whigs and Democrats, gathered around the altar of our
                        country, forgive and forget all past differences, and pledge themselves to
                        deathless fidelity in defence of our common soil. A solid front presented
                        now will make bloodshed improbable, and our ruin impossible. Discord among
                        the Southern States will inevitably plunge us into a gulf from which
                        millions will never rise again. May Heaven interpose!</p>
                    <p>A.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer advocates remaining in the Union as long as guarantees of Southern
                    property rights can be granted by the Federal government. If war comes, however,
                    the writer feels that Virginia should join the Southern states.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan61.html#1.22b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer urges voters to select convention representatives carefully and to
                    choose men who will not rush Virginia headlong into war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 1 and 2 ads. Column 7 is a transcript of the legislative bill
                authorizing election of a Convention.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.01.22.02">
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>J.I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>G.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hulvy</ln>
                        <fn>Abram</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arey</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Ro. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumake</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiser</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hyde</ln>
                        <fn>C.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>W.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Dan'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumake</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>Ro. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Dan'l</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>Geo.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glick</ln>
                        <fn>Joel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glick</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glick</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoemake</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>S.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hilbert</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Fred.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>I.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Ro.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parkins</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakle</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fisher</ln>
                        <fn>Dan.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>V.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eidson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taliaferro</ln>
                        <fn>L.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taliaferro</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kersh</ln>
                        <fn>M.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>Chris</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumake</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Landes</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kline</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humster</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Critzer</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grooms</ln>
                        <fn>D.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>W.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>S.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rimel</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weller</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Packer</ln>
                        <fn>C.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glick</ln>
                        <fn>Jos.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Glick</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickenbarger</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wample</ln>
                        <fn>S.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yates</ln>
                        <fn>A.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>W.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>Ro. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burns</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Link</ln>
                        <fn>Peter J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wood</ln>
                        <fn>Grattan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Sam'l</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weller</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cline</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grady</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitlock</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shea</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanfossen</ln>
                        <fn>Jas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilkison</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanfossen</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sutton</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Petition signed by citizens of the Mt. Sidney District urging A.H.H Stuart,
                    Col. J.B. Baldwin, and H.W. Sheffey to run as conservative pro-Union candidates
                    for the State Convention. Accompanying the petition is a letter from A.H.H
                    Stuart announcing his candidacy based upon the petition.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Look to It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges citizens to be wary of the motivations and tactics of the
                    secessionists for gaining popular support.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Meeting of Virginia Workingmen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Frederick County meeting denounced disunion and declared that secession is
                    possible only by revolution, which is contrary to the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Union Man</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter suggesting Col. J.B. Baldwin, Col. George Baylor, and H. W.
                    Sheffey for election to the State Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Fellow Citizens:</emph>--Ten days of the session of the
                        General Assembly have passed away, and little has yet been done toward the
                        adjustment of the controversies which unhappily distract our country.
                        Knowing the anxiety which all true patriots must feel in regard to the condi
                        of public affairs, I am impelled by a sense of representative duty, to give
                        you such information, and such words of counsel, as seem to me appropriate
                        to the occasion. </p>
                    <p>Since the first day of the session, Richmond has been the scene of unexampled
                        excitement.--The disunionists from all parts of the State have been here
                        full force, and have sought to bring every influence to bear to precipitate
                        Virginia into secession and civil war. It will be for the people to
                        determine, whether their efforts shall be crowned with success. It behooves
                        them to be vigilant, if they value the peace of the country, and desire to
                        escape the burthens of Military service and grinding taxation. If secession
                        takes place, in my judgment, civil war is inevitable, and the people must
                        expect their taxes to be doubled, if not quadrupled. State bonds are now
                        selling, in New York, at a discount of twenty-five per cent, and it is idle
                        to talk of borrowing money. It must be raised, and raised in millions of
                        dollars, by taxation. The newspapers inform us, that in South Carolina,
                        negroes are, at this early stage of their struggle, taxed sixteen dollars
                        per head, and that the government has resorted to forced loans from the
                        Banks and property holders. One case is mentioned, in which a merchant, with
                        a capital of $40,000, was compelled to loan to the State $8,000.</p>
                    <p>Sooner or later, the burthen must fall on the landholders. Slaves, stocks,
                        bonds and other personal property, may be sold and removed, but the land
                        must remain, to bear the brunt of taxation. It is proper that you should
                        understand this, that you may vote intelligently on the questions which will
                        soon be submitted for your decision at the polls.</p>
                    <p>I do not propose, in this brief letter, to enter into any elaborate
                        discussion of the doctrine of secession, or to point out all the disastrous
                        consequences that would flow from it. It will suffice to say, that it is a
                        doctrine of New England origin. It had its birth among the Federalists of
                        that section of the Union, during the war of 1812, and was nurtured in the
                        celebrated Hartford Convention. In 1814, it was denounced by such
                        Republicans as Spencer Roane, and Thos. Ritchie, as treason. While I do not
                        endorse this strong language to its full extent, in my judgement, it is at
                        war with the whole theory of our institutions, and is subversive of every
                        principle of popular government.</p>
                    <p>The favorite scheme of many of the leading politicians is, to break up the
                        Union, with a view to re-construct it. Their plan is, to form a Southern
                        Confederacy. I am unalterably opposed to both of these propositions; I
                        believe that either would be the source of incalculable evil. In my opinion,
                        there is no natural antagonism between the Northern and Southern States. On
                        the contrary, each is necessary to the other. They are the complements of
                        each other, and together constitute the most perfect social, industrial and
                        political systems, that the world has ever seen. Each is indispensable to
                        the welfare of the other. They minister to each others' interests and
                        necessities. The South produces what the North wants, but cannot produce;
                        and the North furnishes what the South needs, but cannot supply for itself.
                        The diversity of productions, and systems of labor, should therefore be a
                        bond of Union instead of a source of Discord. The present condition of
                        antagonism and alienation is unnatural. It is not the legitimate result of
                        any conflict of the social and industrial systems of the two sections, but
                        is the work of those "DESIGNING MEN," both North and South, against whom
                        Washington so impressively warned us in his farewell address.</p>
                    <p>It is true that the Northern States, under the lead of such men, have been
                        guilty of gross outrages on the rights of the South--outrages which would
                        justify the most energetic measures of retaliation, but I have not been able
                        to persuade myself that a dissolution of the Union furnishes the appropriate
                        means of redress. I believe that all our rights can be secured, and all our
                        wrongs most effectually redressed in the Union, and under the Constitution.
                        Secession, instead of being a remedy, would be an aggravation of them all. I
                        have not been able to perceive how we could add to the security of our slave
                        property by surrendering the guarantees of the Constitution, and
                        substantially bringing down the Canada frontier to the borders of Virginia.
                        It would lead to emancipation and probably to emancipation in blood. Nor can
                        I see how we would <emph rend="italic">secure</emph> our rights in the
                        territories by <emph rend="italic">abandoning</emph> them. I am equally at a
                        loss to understand how we will establish any of our demands against the
                        Northern States on a firmer basis, by severing our connection with them, and
                        thereby from us, the million and a half of friends we had in those States at
                        the last election. </p>
                    <p>My view of the true policy of Virginia is, that she should remain in the
                        Union until all Constitutional means of obtaining redress for the past and
                        security for the future, shall have proved fruitless. I do not think the
                        time has come for an appeal to the arbitrament of arms.</p>
                    <p>Should the Union be dissolved peaceably, and a Southern Confederacy be
                        formed, it is clear that the policy of the new government will be shaped by
                        the Cotton States. Free trade and direct taxation for the support of the
                        Federal Government, will be the cardinal features of that policy, on your
                        interests.</p>
                    <p>The expense of sustaining the present government of the U. S., ranges from
                        sixty to eighty millions of dollars per annum. This amount is raised by
                        duties on foreign goods, imported into the country. Those persons who
                        purchase foreign goods, pay the tax, as an element in the price of the
                        goods, while those who buy no foreign goods, pay none of the tax. The tax is
                        therefore <emph rend="italic">voluntary</emph>, if paid. But under the
                        system of free trade and direct taxation, the tax would be <emph
                            rend="italic">involuntary</emph>. No election would be left to the
                        people to pay it or not, as they might think proper. It woald be levied,
                        like the State tax, by assessment on the property of the country. Assuming
                        that the cost of maintaining the Southern Confederated Government would be
                        but one half the amount expended by the present government of the U. S., the
                        contributive portion of Viginia would approximate five millions of dollars.
                        You will readily comprehend how heavily it would bear upon the people to pay
                        this large amount, in addition to the present State taxes, out of their hard
                        earnings. </p>
                    <p>The postal system in Virginia now costs the general government $263,389 more
                        than all the receipts from it. The cost of carrying and distributing the
                        mails, in the Southern States, exceeds the revenues derived from postages in
                        those States, by $3,510,648. If the Union is dissolved this expense must be
                        provided for by direct taxation, or the people must dispense with the
                        facilities afforded by their mails.</p>
                    <p>Should war follow the dissolution, the consequences must be of the most
                        frightful character. Brother would be arrayed against brother, and the whole
                        land would be drenched with blood. The border country would be ravaged and
                        laid waste with fire and sword. Firesides and fields would be desolated by
                        invading armies, and the wail of the widow and the orphan would be heard in
                        all our valleys! Real estate would be depreciated more than 50 per cent;
                        business in all its departments would be paralyzed; credit destroyed;
                        personal property of all kinds impressed for public use; our slaves incited
                        to insurrection; and ruin and desolation would overwhelm the whole country.</p>
                    <p>Passing from the contemplation of this mournful picture, I proceed to invite
                        your attention to the subject in its financial aspect.</p>
                    <p>If civil war should ensue, it would be impossible to estimate the amount of
                        additional taxes that would be required. That would depend upon
                        contingencies which no human sagacity can clearly foresee. But when we look
                        to the extent of our sea coast, and inland frontier, to be guarded, it is
                        evident that the pecuniary cost must be enormous, to say nothing of the
                        withdrawal of large bodies of our population from the productive labor of
                        the country, and the loss resulting from capital, in the form of lands and
                        machinery, lying idle.</p>
                    <p>The people should weigh these matters well before they decide to embark on
                        the unknown and tempestuous sea of convulsion and revolution.</p>
                    <p>You will perceive from the report of the proceedings of the General Assembly,
                        that Virginia has been pledged, so far as that body had the power to pledge
                        her, to make common cause with South Carolina, and to resist every attempt
                        by the Federal Government to coerce her "into submission or obedience." This
                        language is ambiguous, and I sought, in vain, to obtain a satisfactory
                        explanation of its meaning. If it contemplated resistance to any effort to
                            <emph rend="italic">subjugate</emph> the State, it would be
                        comparatively harmless, because it is hardly to be supposed that any such
                        effort will be made; but if it was intended to indicate the purpose of
                        Virginia to resist, by force, all efforts of the Federal Government to
                        coerce the citizens of South Carolina to obey the laws of the U. S., I would
                        regard it as in a high degree mischievous. </p>
                    <p>This resolution of the General Assembly did not meet my approbation, nor
                        receive my vote. In the first place, I thought the Legislature, by that act,
                        was anticipating one of the appropriate functions of the Convention about to
                        be called; and, in the next place, I did not feel warranted in assuming the
                        quarrel of South Carolina. She had chosen to act for herself without the co-
                        operation of the other Southern States, and I could see no good reason why
                        we should espouse her quarrel. I stated, on the floor of the Senate, that I
                        had but little sympathy with her extreme position. Her causes of
                        dissatisfaction were not the same with ours and her aims were entirely
                        different from ours. She was dissatisfied with the financial policy of the
                        Government, whilst we were seeking redress for wrongs of a very different
                        character.</p>
                    <p>Her object, as avowed by her leading men, was to break up the Union, whilst
                        ours was to preserve it, if it could be done consistently with our rights
                        and honor. Moreover, I expressed the fear that our inconsiderate pledge
                        might encourage South Carolina to acts of rashness, whilst, in the North, it
                        might be construed as a menace, and tend to defeat a speedy and peaceful
                        settlement of our difficulties. In these views I may have been mistaken, but
                        honestly entertaining them, I felt bound to follow the dictates of my
                        judgement, and withhold my assent from the resolution.</p>
                    <p>The bill providing for the call of a Convention has been passed, and the
                        election for members of that body will take place on the 4th of Feb. The
                        proposition originally submitted, was to call a Convention, with unlimited
                        powers, and to let its action be final. Under this scheme, the Convention
                        might have overturned the present State government, and established a
                        military Dictatorship in its stead, and the people would have had no
                        redress, except by forcible revolution. But after an arduous struggle the
                        bill was amended so as to allow the people to decide at the polls whether
                        the action of the Convention shall be final or not.</p>
                    <p>It is to be hoped that every voter of Virginia will be at the polls, and vote
                        to RETAIN THE SOVEREIGN POWER OF THE PEOPLE IN THE HANDS OF THE PEOPLE. If
                        they properly appreciate their rights and liberties, they will never trust
                        them in the hands of any set of men, without reserving an efficient control
                        over them. Who would entrust his private fortune to any one without some
                        guarantee for its security? And is it not more important to reserve the
                        right of ultimate judgement, in a matter which involves not only the
                        prosperity, but also the lives and liberty of the people?</p>
                    <p>Strong intimations have been thrown out through the public press, that a
                        treasonable scheme has been concocted at Washington to overthrow the Federal
                        Government. It is charged that Senators, and others, who have sworn to
                        support the Constitution, have conspired to subvert it. Information which I
                        have received from other sources, which I believe to be reliable, tend to
                        confirm these intimations, and induce the belief that a provisional
                        government for the South, has already been agreed on, and that its great
                        seal has been provided, a name adopted, and every arrangement made to put it
                        into operation, on or before the 4th of March. The servants of the people
                        have thus assumed to be their masters, and usurped the power which,
                        occording to our bill of rights, resides only with the people.</p>
                    <p>I repeat, then, let the people be jealous of their rights. Eternal vigilance
                        is the price of liberty. No election ever held in Virginia was half so
                        important as that to be held on the 4th of February. Let every voter be at
                        the polls. Let no business, however urgent, and no obstacle, however
                        formidable, prevent any from attending. The voice of Augusta will be
                        potential, and may control the result. Select men who will faithfully
                        represent your deliberate sentiments. Especially, let every man vote that
                        the action of the Convention shall be submitted to the people for their
                        ratification or rejection.</p>
                    <p>The usage in Virginia heretofore, has been to allow the people to vote
                        whether they would have a Convention or not. If the voice of the people was
                        pronounced in favor of a Convention, it was called, and its action was
                        submitted to the people for their approval or disapproval.--The Legislature
                        has now departed from ancient usages, and it is for the people to determine
                        whether they will blindly sanction, in advance, whatever the Convention may
                        do, or require the result of its deliberations to be submitted to them for
                        final ratification or rejection. Let the people hold the power in their own
                        hands! Let them never surrender their liberty into the hands of any body of
                        irresponsible men. It is too precious an inheritance to be dealt with thus
                        lightly and inconsiderately.</p>
                    <p>Fellow Citizens! the issue is in your hands! A heavy responsibility rests on
                        you!</p>
                    <p>May the Great Disposer of events so guide your conduct that peace and
                        happiness may be restored to our distracted country, and that the Union
                        which we have been taught to regard as the Palladium of our liberties, shall
                        be established on a firm foundation and rendered perpetual.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully, <lb/>Your fellow citizen, <lb/>ALEX. H. H. STUART. </p>
                    <p>P. S. Since the above was written, the House of Delegates have passed two
                        important bills; one for the establishment of an Ordinance Bureau, and the
                        other appropriating one million of dollars for military defence. This is but
                        the beginning of the end! <lb/>A. H. H. S. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Alex H. H. Stuart</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Stuart tries to persuade readers of the disastrous consequences of
                    secession (mostly economic) and believes that Southern grievances can best be
                    addressed within the Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssjan61.html#1.22c</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John B. Baldwin</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer establishes his pro-Union position in acceptance of his nomination
                    to run for a Convention seat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Hugh W. Sheffey</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Writer outlines his pro-Union position in announcing candidacy for a seat
                    at the Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John D. Imboden</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Candidate for Convention announces his pro-Union views, tempered by his
                    intention to stand by the state of Virginia no matter what decision is reached.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the People of Augusta</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>William Harman</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Candidate for the Convention outlines his views. He opposes session but
                    rejects the North's attempt to coerce states to remain in the Union. Harman also
                    acknowledges the wrongs the South has endured but wishes to see them addressed
                    within the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 11. Mr. Reid is from Rockbridge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calbreath</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchison</ln>
                        <fn>Martha B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Hutchison died on January 11 at age 75.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wonderlick</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wonderlick</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Wonderlick died on December 26 at age 58. She was a member of the
                    Evangelical Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubus</ln>
                        <fn>Willard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubus</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Staubus</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Williard Staubus died on January 11 at age 10 months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various articles reporting secession crisis in other Southern states. Bottom
                left and right illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.01.22.03">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="4" image="va.au.ss.1861.01.22.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
