<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.03.26">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-26">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Proposed Constitutional Amendments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article outlines constitutional amendments proposed by the State Convention
                    that would defuse the current secession crisis. These include an extension of
                    the Missouri Compromise and items ensuring that a majority of senators from
                    slaveholding states will be required to acquire territory not currently in the
                    Union. Proposed amendments would also prevent those of African heritage from
                    voting or holding elective office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from Gov. Houston</head>
                <origin>Austin Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of a letter outlining Gov. Houston's commitment to maintaining
                    the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Secession Intolerance</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Denounces the impatience and intolerance of the immediate secessionists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 ads. Columns 2 and 3 poetry and fiction. Column 5 Virginia State
                Convention records and Virginia Legislative records. Column 6 Sen. Crittendon's
                farewell speech. Bottom right illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speaking on Monday</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports an animated discussion at the Court-house between the Union
                    congressional candidate, John Harris, and the secession candidate, James
                    Skinner. Also at the meeting, Robert Doyle refused a call to run for Congress
                    for fear of splitting the Union vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Judge Breckenbrough's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Breckenbrough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Analyzes a speech given by Judge Breckenbrough on the front porch of the
                    Virginia hotel and criticizes it, not only for its secessionist content, but
                    also because it was "flat, stale, and unprofitable to an almost intolerable
                    degree." The Spectator reports that even the secessionists on hand found it
                    uninspiring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Louisiana</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Louisiana Convention by a three-fourths majority refused
                    to submit the permanent Constitution to the people for ratification.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>"States-Rights-Democracy" now means secession.--<emph rend="italic"
                        >Spectator</emph>. </p>
                    <p>This is not quite so near the truth as that submission means Black
                            Republicanism.--<emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph>. </p>
                    <p>The "Vindicator," having changed the position it occupied during the
                        Presidential election in favor of the Union to that of secession and against
                        the Union, has adopted the language of the secessionists, and charges the
                        friends of the Union with being submissionists, and as it says that
                        "submission means Black Republicanism," it, in this way, by arriving at
                        "direction by indirection," charges all the friends of the Union, including
                        all good Union-loving Democrats, with being Black Republicans. On the 4th of
                        February, the editor of that <emph rend="italic">very consistent</emph>
                        journal, by his vote <emph rend="italic">against reference</emph>, "recorded
                        himself as fearing to trust the people in the management of their own
                        business," though "they are honest and capable and patriotic and their
                        interests were immediately concerned," and on the 22nd of March charges them
                        with being Black Republicans. This is verily "adding insult to injury." Was
                        the editor of that paper a Black Republican when he was supporting Douglas
                        with so much zeal after his response to the Norfolk questions, in which he
                        declared that the election of Lincoln would furnish no cause for secession,
                        and that, if elected President, he would enforce the laws against the
                        enemies of the Union, after the manner of Jackson? </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Spectator defends itself against charges of Black Republicanism made by the
                    Vindicator. The Spectator charges the Vindicator with switching positions since
                    the Presidential election, when the Vindicator endorsed Douglas. The Vindicator
                    also changed its position on the question of a popular vote on the subject of
                    secession.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.26a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 2 Virginia Legislative records and Virginia Convention records. Columns
                3, 4, 5, and 6 Baltimore Convention of the M. E. Church records. Column 7
            ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.26.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Col. Baldwin's Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Discusses Col. Baldwin's speech to the Convention, in which he defended
                    slavery as a moral and good thing but challenged any man at the convention to
                    specify any other point of contention with the Federal government apart from the
                    slavery question. He furthermore challenged the Convention to point to one
                    current Federal Law that interfered with slavery in Virginia. The secessionist
                    could only assert that they fear future encroachments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cullen</ln>
                        <fn>Catherine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Albert Bush married Catherine Cullen on March 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Brooks died on February 27 while attending the Theological
                    Seminary in Columbia, South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry Bell, son of Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Bell, died of diphtheria on March 9
                    at age 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.26.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
