<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.12.17">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-12-17">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>17</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.17.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Another Victory</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have the satisfaction to announce a most brilliant victory gained by our
                        troops upon the Alleghany Mountain on Friday last.</p>
                    <p>For several days before the fight, parties of our men had been actively
                        scouting the road down to Greenbrier River. The first party under Captain
                        Watkins of the 52d Va. Regiment pursued a party of the Yankees far enough to
                        ascertain that they made most excellent time when turned toward their own
                        camp on Cheat. The next party under Captain Dabney, also of the 52d
                        Regiment, overhauled a party of the enemy and routed them--killing one,
                        wounding one, and taking two prisoners. The next party under Major Ross,
                        also of the 52d Regiment, fell in with a number of the enemy and killed some
                        fifteen or twenty of them. In all these affairs none of our men were hurt.</p>
                    <p>On Friday morning, the enemy having collected from Cheat mountain and beyond
                        some four or five thousand men attempted to surprise and capture the
                        position on the Alleghany mountain held by some fifteen hundred of our men
                        under command of Col. Edward Johnson of the 12th Georgia Regiment. In this
                        attempt, they found that they had emphatically "waked up the wrong
                        passenger." They drove in our pickets about four o'clock in the morning, and
                        made an attack upon both flanks of our position.</p>
                    <p>Having come so far for a fight, it is but just to say that they fought well
                        and obstinately; but after a sharp and severe conflict of about seven hours
                        they were driven back and completely routed.</p>
                    <p>We have not, as yet, been able to gather the details of the battle, but
                        enough is known to satisfy us that the fight was a gallant one, and well
                        sustained, and that the victory was complete.</p>
                    <p>No accurate list of the casualties attending this victory has been received
                        as yet. Our loss in killed and wounded is reported at about eighty of whom
                        near twenty were killed. Among the killed and wounded we have to mourn some
                        gallant officers--Captains Anderson and Mildraugh, and Lieutenants Thompson
                        and Moore.</p>
                    <p>The loss of the enemy was very heavy, and they left some of their killed and
                        wounded upon the field.</p>
                    <p>We have the satisfaction to announce to those having friends in the 52d
                        Regiment that, altho' bearing their part in the engagement, and behaving
                        with calm courage and spirit, not one officer or man belonging to it was
                        injured, except two members of Capt. John D. Lilley's Company, Barkins and
                        Welch, who were wounded in the legs in the picket fight which preceded the
                        battle.</p>
                    <p>We have many rumors of feats of individual gallantry and daring, which it
                        would perhaps be premature to publish; but we cannot be mistaken in saying
                        that with one accord it is agreed that Col. Johnson bore himself throughout
                        with distinguished gallantry--leading on his men in the thick of the fight
                        with a disregard of personal danger, which warmed the hearts and nerved the
                        arms of all his men.</p>
                    <p>As we give the Federals credit for consistency in <emph rend="italic"
                            >misrepresentation</emph>, we expect to see in a short time, a dispatch
                        of the following character published in the Northern papers: </p>
                    <p>"The War Department at Washington has received a despatch stating that on
                        Friday, the 13th inst., the Federals on Cheat Mountain made a
                        "reconnoissance [sic] in force," took the "rebels" on the top of the
                        Alleghany mountain by surprise, killed a great many of them, with but slight
                        loss to the "loyal" force, and, having accomplished the object of the
                        reconnoisance [sic], retired in good order to their camp on Cheat
                    Mountain."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barkins</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welch</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Report of a battle in western Virginia involving the 52nd Regiment, which
                    claims as members several Augusta County companies. The battle, a Confederate
                    victory according to the Spectator, will certainly be misreported by the
                    Northern press, says the Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Newspapers "Hard Up"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn from Clarke County <emph rend="italic">Conservator</emph> that in
                        the counties of Clarke, Frederick, Jefferson, Berkeley; Morgan, Hampshire,
                        Shenandoah, Page, Warren, Rockingham, Augusta and Loudoun, there were
                        published before the war, <emph rend="italic">twenty-three</emph>
                        newspapers. Now we know of but <emph rend="italic">seven</emph> that are
                        published in these counties, only three of which are published regularly
                        every week, and all, with one exception, considerably reduced in dimensions.
                        Those entirely discontinued, are the Berryville <emph rend="italic"
                        >Journal</emph>, Charlestown <emph rend="italic">Spirit of Jefferson</emph>,
                        and <emph rend="italic">Independent Democrat</emph>, Shepherdstown <emph
                            rend="italic">Register</emph>, Martinsburg <emph rend="italic"
                        >American</emph>, Berkeley Springs <emph rend="italic">Constitution</emph>,
                        Romney <emph rend="italic">Intelligencer</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                            >Argus,</emph> Piedmont <emph rend="italic">Independent</emph>,
                        Woodstock <emph rend="italic"> Tenth Legion </emph>, Luray <emph
                            rend="italic">Review</emph>, Front Royal <emph rend="italic"
                        >Gazette</emph>, Harrisonburg <emph rend="italic">Citizen</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">Valley Democrat</emph>, Staunton <emph rend="italic"
                            >Vindicator</emph> and Leesburg <emph rend="italic">Mirror</emph>. The
                        balance are published occasionally. Though the times thus ruin the Press of
                        the State, and though Editors are compelled to pay three and four times as
                        much as they need to do for articles <emph rend="italic">necessary</emph> to
                        publish a newspaper, yet there are some <emph rend="italic">few</emph>
                        inconsiderate and unreasonable persons who complain of those who keep their
                        papers in existence by the publication of half-sheets. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that many Virginia newspapers have been forced to either
                    decrease or cease publication altogether during the war, among them the Staunton
                    Vindicator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Steamer Nashville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that a Confederate steamer successfully ran the blockade.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Destructive Fire in Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a fire in Charleston, South Carolina. The Confederate government
                    sent aid to the victims of the fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Archbishop Hughes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Archbishop Hughes went to Europe on behalf of the Catholic
                    Church to seek European help in securing peace and recognition of the
                    Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that John Kinney, a citizen of Staunton who is from Charleston, has
                    been taking donations for the relief of the victims of that city's fire.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Fifty or sixty of the Federal prisoners confined in New Orleans have taken
                    the oath and joined the Confederate Army for the war."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary/>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the secession government of Kentucky was admitted to the
                    Confederacy by the Confederate Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Provisional Congress--An Important Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A bill passed by the Confederate Congress grants a bounty of ninety dollars
                    to those who serve in the army for three years. It also provides sixty day
                    furloughs to those on one-year enlistments who re-enlist for two more years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Prisoners Released</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that 30 Southern prisoners were released from Washington and
                    arrived in Charleston.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Commodore Levy, the owner of Monticello, made his will and is
                    leaving Monticello and $100,000 to the government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gen. Lane and Col. Montgomery</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As our readers may be interested in a description of these notorious
                    outlaws of Kansas infamy..."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a brief biography of the two Yankee officers, Lane and Montgomery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Acknowledges donations to the General Hospital at Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Contributions for Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>W. G. Campbell</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDaniel</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>W.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter acknowledges contributions to soldiers received by W. G. Campbell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Directs those who wish to donate to the Staunton Artillery to drop boxes
                    off at George Price's store.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Wheeling Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an anecdote from Wheeling that some officers of the Unionist
                    Virginia regiment are boarding with the wife of a secessionist editor, who had
                    fled.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Camp Near Staunton, VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galt</ln>
                        <fn>M.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from the Maryland Guards thanking the people of Staunton for their
                    donations and hospitality.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNamara</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNamara</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNamara</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNamara</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ellen and Catharine Ann McNamara died of diphtheria on December 12. Ellen
                    was 6 years old and Catharine Ann was 9 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Johnson died on October 25 at age 7. He was the fifth child of Mr. and
                    Mrs. Johnson to die at a young age.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>To the Tax-Payers of the Confederate States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grills</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Grills and Samuel Harper will meet taxpayers to clarify the
                    Confederate tax laws.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports of battles, skirmishes, and military maneuvers, much of it
                from Missouri. Portions of page not clearly legible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.12.17.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Terrible Tragedy in Mississippi--Two Men Killed and Several Wounded</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports a feud in Mississippi between the Edwards and Grey families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Salt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the price of salt is skyrocketing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
