<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.02.12">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-02-12">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.02.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Dissolve the Union!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Pro-Union poem notable for its suggestion that secessionists are traitors
                    and advocating that "Ye patriot band crush the traitors with daring hand".</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 1 and 2 ads. Columns 3 and 4 poetry and fiction. Column 6
                congressional records. Column 7 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.02.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Position and Trails of Conservatives</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the efforts of conservative men North and South who disavow the
                    radicals of their respective regions and instead embrace a more moderate
                    approach.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Harm We Are Doing</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We understand that some of the <emph rend="italic">extremists</emph> in this
                        and the adjoining counties say that "the "Staunton Spectator" is doing more
                        harm than any paper in the State." As what they mean by doing "harm" is the
                        influence it exerts in opposition to their efforts to precipitate the State
                        into secession, revolution and civil war, we accept it as the highest
                        compliment, and feel thereby encouraged to labor with more zeal and energy
                        in the cause of the Union and the preservation of peace and the avoidance of
                        oppressive and grinding taxation. If the extremists would never complain, we
                        would feel that we were laboring to but little purpose; for we are satisfied
                        that in proportion to their annoyance and complaints, we are exerting an
                        efficient and salutary influence. In the sense in which they use the term,
                        we are pleased to hear that the "Spectator" is doing "harm." We must
                        protest, however, against the acceptance of the whole extent of the
                        compliment conferred upon the "Spectator," for we do not believe, (as the
                        extremists to whom we have referred seem to do) that the "Spectator is doing
                            <emph rend="italic">more</emph> harm than <emph rend="italic">any</emph>
                        paper in the State." On the contrary, we believe that there are other papers
                        in the State which do much more of this <emph rend="italic">good kind</emph>
                        of "harm" than the "Spectator." We are glad to know that such is the case,
                        and are pleased to see the <emph rend="italic">Richmond Whig</emph>, the
                            <emph rend="italic">Alexandria Gazette</emph>, the <emph rend="italic"
                            >Lynchburg Virginian</emph>, the <emph rend="italic">Petersburg
                            Intelligencer</emph>, the <emph rend="italic">Charlottesville
                        Review</emph> and other papers in <emph rend="italic">Eastern</emph>
                        Virginia doing so much of this kind of "harm," which is destined to save the
                        country from being desolated with the ravages of civil war, if that dire
                        calamity can, by any means, be avoided. If any doubt that the "Spectator" is
                        doing efficient service for the good of the country, we refer them to the
                        vexed and annoyed extremists who say that it is doing so much "harm." We are
                        rejoiced to know that we have so many co-operators in this portion of the
                        State in the work of "harm" in which we are engaged. In this glorious "Old
                        Augusta," in noble Rockbridge, and in Union-loving Rockingham, nearly the
                        whole people are with us, working "harm" to the schemes of the disunionists.
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to criticism that the Spectator is doing more harm than any
                    other state paper, the Spectator says it will accept this taunt as a compliment
                    because the harm is done only to the cause of disunion.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssfeb61.html#2.12a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Letter of Judge Douglas</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lauds the efforts of Stephen Douglas to simultaneously stand up for the
                    rights of the South and for the cause of Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The New Southern Confederacy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the formation of the Provisional Southern Government constituted on
                    the basis of the Constitution with amendments made concerning the slave trade
                    and fugitive slaves, provisions that were at the heart of the secession crisis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Incidents at Mt. Sidney</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that the Union turnout in Mt. Sidney was so strong that some
                    Unionists rode into town four to a horse to vote. The Mt. Sidney precinct
                    contains some of "the most active and efficient working Union men."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Extremes Meet</head>
                <origin>Baltimore American</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that the vote in Morgantown, Virginia went 639 out of 640 votes for
                    referring the Convention's decisions to the people. The one who voted against
                    referral also voted for Lincoln.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Union in Rockbridge</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Union candidates to the Convention were elected
                    overwhelmingly in Rockbridge County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Surveyor's Instrument</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the invention of a new surveying instrument by J.M. Lilley of
                    Staunton and its subsequent adoption by many in the field of engineering.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Views of Hon. John J. Crittenden</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An excerpt of a letter from John Crittendon to Gen. Coombs of Kentucky
                    praising Kentucky's decision not to call a Convention. The Spectator lauds this
                    decision.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Important Facts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Points out that, in the election to the State Convention, Union men, where
                    they have won, have been elected by large majorities. In contrast, secessionists
                    have won by narrow margins in districts they have carried. Furthermore, Union
                    districts vote overwhelmingly for reference to the people whereas secessionist
                    districts vote against it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Vote of Augusta County</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Table showing the final outcome of the County election for Convention
                    members. The Union candidates Baldwin, Baylor, and Stuart won every precinct in
                    Augusta County by huge majorities. Those who wished the Convention's decisions
                    to be subjected to popular approval were also victorious.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. S.A. Douglas</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of a letter from Stephen Douglas to the Memphis Appeal
                    professing his continued opposition to extreme disunionists, North and South, as
                    well as his continued quest for peace and Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Thomas Michie espousing and clarifying his support for the
                    right of secession after having been attacked by the Spectator in an earlier
                    issue.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mills</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 7.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Earman</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hague</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stanton</ln>
                        <fn>Garrett</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on December 16 at age 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Almanoer</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 12 at age 30.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 4 and 5 are congressional records.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.02.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>President rejects the demand for Fort Sumter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the President rejected South Carolina's demand to surrender
                    Fort Sumter and warns that its seizure will be viewed as an act of war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>States that, now that Unionists have been victorious in Virginia, it
                    "remains for the conservative people of the North, if they are in the majority,
                    to make a peaceful adjustment of difficulties."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.02.12.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
