<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.04.23">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-04-23">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>23</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.23.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>They Call me a Traitor Now</head>
                <origin>Memphis Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The following lines were suggested by seeing an old man intently gazing at
                    the American flag as it floated from the dome of one of the hotels in Memphis."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Poem about an old man who had moved from Tennessee to Mississippi. He
                    reminisces about fighting under the stars and stripes during the War of 1812 and
                    says that he loves the flag. However, the people in Mississippi won't fly it,
                    and they consider him a traitor for his loyalty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Description of Attack on Fort Sumter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of the attack on Fort Sumter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the Governor of Virginia.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclamation of the Governor of Virginia ordering the militia companies to
                    ready themselves to fight against the Federal government in the event of acts of
                    war against the Commonwealth.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Shearing the Wolf</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the Northern Republicans should consider the consequences of
                    attempting to coerce the seceded states by force.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>President Davis's Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>President Davis's proclamation seeking to raise a naval force of private
                    vessels.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Proclamation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of Lincoln's call for troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Transcript of the War Department's call for state militia units to be
                    converted to Federal Service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Columns 1 and 2 advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.23.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Glorious "Old Augusta"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We feel proud of "Old Augusta"--her noble conduct challenges the admiration
                        of all brave and patriotic citizens. She contains sons as patriotic as ever
                        sacrificed their lives and fortunes for liberty, and as brave soldiers as
                        were ever commanded by Caesar or Napoleon. Her citizens are the sons of
                        brave and patriotic sires, and they have not degenerated. They are ready at
                        all times to respond with alacrity to the call to arms, and are animated
                        with a firm and determined spirit to strike till the last armed foe expires.
                        When their State calls they hesitate not to strike <lb/> For their altars
                        and their fires, <lb/>The green graves of their sires, <lb/>God and their
                        native land. <lb/>They in the same patriotic spirit which animated the
                        "Father of his country," cherished a cordial and habitual attachment to the
                        Union, and, with deep and heartfelt devotion, labored with all the
                        earnestness of their natures to preserve it as it had been bequeathed to
                        them by their ancestors. As long as there was a ray of hope, they stood
                        firmly as the friends of the Union and the advocates of a just, honorable
                        and peaceful settlement of all our national difficulties. When others
                        despaired, they still hoped; when others yielded, they still stood firmly.
                        They had the high moral courage to stand firmly where their convictions of
                        patriotic duty commanded, though their motives were impeached and their
                        loyalty distrusted by those who did not appreciate their noble
                        characters.--But as soon as the last ray of hope had been extinguished, as
                        soon as they had seen the President's proclamation, the herald of civil war,
                        and heard the call to arms, they sprang to their feet, donned their military
                        dress, shouldered their guns, bade their fathers and mothers, brothers and
                        sisters a hurried and affectionate farewell, and marched with speed to the
                        place of rendevous. They did not stop to consider the consequences to
                        themselves individually--they were willing to sacrifice all they
                        possessed--their lives and fortunes--in defence of their native State.--Many
                        left their families almost entirely unprovided for--there was no time to
                        consider individual interests when their State called for their services.
                        Some left sick wives and children, and some sick fathers and mothers,
                        brothers and sisters. It was almost enough to melt a heart of adamant to
                        witness such scenes as were present just before the troops left this place.
                        One would call upon his physician and say: "Doctor, my Dear wife is sick, I
                        hope you will attend her carefully." Another would say, "Doctor, I have left
                        two sick children, and request you to see them daily." Another would say,
                        "Doctor, my father is old and feeble, I fear I may never see him again, I
                        desire you to keep him alive if you can till I return." Another would say,
                        "Doctor, my dear mother is nearly heart-broken, I hope you will console her
                        as much as possible." </p>
                    <p>The same patriotic fires which glowed in the bosoms of their noble ancestors,
                        in 1776, burns brightly now upon the altars of the hearts of the brave and
                        chivalric sons of Augusta. This county, we have no doubt, will send more
                        soldiers to the field than any county in the State, though Rockingham and
                        Rockbridge will nobly do their duty. These three adjoining Union counties,
                        we venture to predict, will furnish more soldiers than any other three
                        adjoining counties in the State. We feel convinced that all three of these
                        strong Union counties will do their whole duty. We are sure that the brave
                        and patriotic Union men of these counties will forgive those who, in
                        ignorance of their true characters, charged them with being "submissionists"
                        and "sympathisers with Black Republicanism," and hope that those who did so
                        will have the candor and manliness to acknowledge that they wronged as brave
                        and loyal citizens as ever breathed the air of freedom. Let all feelings of
                        alienation and party spirit be buried, and all stand together in harmony and
                        friendship as a band of affectionate brothers.--"United we stand, divided we
                        fall." In "Union there is strength," in division there is weakness. Let all
                        stand together. We are still for Union--a Union of brave and patriotic men
                        for the defence of our State.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the steadfast efforts of Virginia to negotiate a settlement in the
                    Union. However, now that Lincoln has issued a call for troops and peace has
                    failed, it has become appropriate for Virginians to abandon their quest for
                    peace and fight for the Commonwealth.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr61.html#4.23a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The "Spectator" Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strasburg</ln>
                        <fn>David E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spitzer</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Two employees of the Spectator have joined the army. The Spectator will
                    continue publication unless all the men are called into service of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Massing of Troops</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harmon</ln>
                        <fn>M.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Hazel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the departure of the Augusta militia units for the East in
                    obedience to the Governor's call for troops to defend Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the North appears to be preparing for war in earnest. Union
                    fervor is rising, particularly in New York and Philadelphia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Where We Have Stood and Now Stand</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that Lincoln's aggression toward the South, involving the country in
                    a civil war that could have been avoided, is in the "Highest Degree Criminal."
                    The article maintains that Virginia will fight with the South, especially now
                    that the Convention has adopted an Ordinance of Secession that awaits only the
                    popular vote for passage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The "Home Guard"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendron</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cushing</ln>
                        <fn>E.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the raising of a militia in Augusta County that will be called the
                    Home Guard and will protect Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Appropriation by the Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that the county court of Augusta appropriated $50,000 for the
                    equipment of volunteers and support of families of soldiers called into service.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Fort McHenry Besieged! No Troops Can Pass Through Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Series of dispatches reporting, among other things, a lack of co-operation
                    by Maryland with Federal troops attempting to reach D.C., declaration of martial
                    law in D.C., and the seizure of several Federal properties by Virginia troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Action of the Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Town Council on Wednesday, the 17th inst., made an appropriation of
                        $3,000 for the purchase of 100 fire-arms, equipments and ammunition, for the
                        use of the "Home Guard" in Staunton, and $500, to be applied to the wants of
                        the families of the soldiers who have been or will be called into service,
                        and appointed a police of ten for each night till the May Court.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports that the Staunton town council has made an appropriation of
                    $3,000 for the purchase of firearms, equipment, and ammunition for the Home
                    Guard.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssapr61.html#4.23b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Proclamation of the Governor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Governor's proclamation related to the defense of the Commonwealth
                    encouraging all Federal Army and Navy personal who reside in Virginia to retire
                    therefrom and enter the service of Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Norfolk Herald</origin>
                <commentary>The Herald is "an old, true Whig, Union paper."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that, unfortunately, Lincoln's actions have swung opinion in the
                    Border States to the Southern cause. Virginia will now cheerfully join the cry
                    for a united South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Proclamation by John W. Willis, Gov. of North Carolina</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces North Carolina's intention to side with the South and defend the
                    sovereignty of North Carolina and the rights of the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Missouri's Response to Lincoln</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Missouri Gov. C.F. Jackson responds to Lincoln's call for troops by
                    refusing to send any men for the illegal and unconstitutional cause of war on
                    the South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.23.03">
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Mt. Crawford, April 20, 1861</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Mr. Editor, could the people of the North witness the enthusiasm of our
                    people, they would despair of conquering us."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from a Mt. Crawford resident, who discusses the "unusual excitement
                    in our usually quite village" as all the troops march through.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To the Farmers of South River</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Walker announced his candidacy for the Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>E. Pluribus Unum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Falron</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter nominating Tate, Finley, and Falron as candidates for the
                    Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Finley refused the nomination to run for the Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter nominating Sproul as a candidate for the Legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>S.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>Clarence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Clarence Lightner, son of A.B. and S.E., on April 7.
                    He was 8 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.04.23.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
