<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.07.02">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
            <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-07-02">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="02">2</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.07.02.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Staunton Militia Called into Service</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>By the order of Maj. Gen. Lee, Maj. M. G. Harman, Commandant of this post,
                        called into the service of the State the whole of the militia of Staunton,
                        comprised in the Companies A and B. These Companies were received into the
                        service of the State on Saturday last, and on Monday (yesterday) they
                        proceeded to the election of the Officers, which resulted as follows:</p>
                    <p>In Company A,--Philip H. Trout, Captain; Moses Strickler, 1st Lieutenant; and
                        Thomas P. Peyton, 2nd Lieutenant.</p>
                    <p>In Company B,--Rev. George B. Taylor, Captain; Hugh Connell, 1st Lieutenant;
                        and James W. Crawford, 2nd Lieutenant.</p>
                    <p>The following are the non-commissioned officers of Company A.</p>
                    <p>Rich. Mauzy, Sr. Lieut.; George Harlan, 1st Sergeant; D. G. McGuffin, 2nd
                        Sergt; Addison Fisher, 3rd Sergt; John Baum, 4th Sergt; L.B. Waller, 5th
                        Sergt; Jno. B. Hoge, 1st Corporal; Yeizer Bickle, 2nd; Alex. Lobe, 3rd;
                        Edwin Edmondson, 4th.</p>
                    <p>This call upon the militia of this place has created a great deal of
                        excitement, as the citizens have been unable to see that there is any
                        emergency demanding it. They think that there was no necessity for such a
                        proceeding as that of calling out the militia <emph rend="italic">en
                        masse</emph>, and that it discriminates unjustly against the interests of
                        this town which has already, with a population of 8000, sent three Companies
                        into the service. They are not disinclined to do their duty, but demand that
                        even-handed justice should be meted out to them. </p>
                    <p>We think that, as the chief purpose of calling out the militia of this place
                        seems to be to guard the public stores and arms at this post, the militias
                        of Companies A and B may console themselves with the hope that they will not
                        be called into the field except in the event of some pressing necessity--in
                        which event, <emph rend="italic">no one</emph> would desire to remain at
                        home. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Moses</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Payton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf>Lieut.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conwell</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mausy</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fischer</ln>
                        <fn>Addison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baum</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waller</ln>
                        <fn>L.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Yelser</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lehe</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Edmondson</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that the Staunton militia has been called into the service of the
                    State and lists the officers thereof.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Ladies of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises the ladies of Staunton for their selfless devotion to the cause of
                    Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Treacherous Outrage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alleges that two of Lincoln's soldiers who visited the Virginia camp under
                    a flag of truce fired on a soldier on picket duty as they left.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Explosion--Distressing Casualty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article calling attention to Capt. Imboden's letter in the Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Letter from Capt. Imboden</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp 3rd Brigade C.S.A.</p>
                    <p>Winchester, June 29, 1861</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor:</emph>--A painful accident occurred in my
                        Company last evening , which will naturally excite inquiry amongst our
                        friends at home. I therefore will state the facts for the information of all
                        who may feel interested. </p>
                    <p>The limber boxes of our guns have been filled with fixed ammunition for
                        several weeks, carefully packed in tow. The priming tubes for firing the
                        guns, filled with fulminating powder, are carried in a tray in the top of
                        the box. By some means one of these tubes must have worked through an
                        air-hole provided in the bottom of the tray, and lodged amongst the
                        ammunition in the box below, where, I think, by the motion of the carriage
                        on the field, it was ignited by friction and set fire to the tow packed in
                        one end of the limber box containing 25 rounds of ammunition. We were
                        drilling as usual last evening, and just as two of the guns were wheeling
                        into battery out of a trot, the limber box of gun No. 4 exploded. There were
                        thirty odd pounds of powder in it, tearing it to atoms, and throwing the
                        fragments of wood and iron in every direction, some a hundred feet in the
                        air. The cannoneers were all around the gun at the moment, and were nearly
                        all thrown some distance upon the ground and against a fence. None were
                        seriously hurt except gunner Samuel H. Coleman, who was nearest to the box,
                        and was struck in the forehead by a fragment, which fractured his skull
                        above the left eye, and produced a severe contusion on the other brow. Sam'l
                        Clarke, James Teabo, Jos. Sharpe and Henry Thise were scorched in the face
                        but not seriously, and Clarke had his left arm scorched about the elbow. It
                        is miraculous that they were all not instantly killed. As it was, poor
                        Coleman was the only serious sufferer. His injuries are very great--perhaps
                        fatal, though he is perfectly rational, free from fever and comparatively
                        comfortable this morning.</p>
                    <p>The explosion was purely accidental, and unaccountable by any other
                        hypothesis than that I have given above.</p>
                    <p>The wheel horses were considerably burnt. Sandy Peace, the wheel drive, had
                        all the hair on the back of his head singed off and his shirt blown to
                        pieces, but was not hurt. Wm. Taylor was by Coleman's side, and was thrown
                        with great violence against the fence and had his cap entirely carried away,
                        but is not hurt. The burnt men will all be well in a few days. Coleman, if
                        he survives, will be confined a long time.</p>
                    <p>This is the first serious casualty that has occurred in my command, and that
                        has thrown a gloom over us all. No possible blame can attach to any one. A
                        number of us, including Lieut. Balthis and myself, were within 20 steps, and
                        amongst the flying fragments which fortunately missed us all. One ball flew
                        across the entire battery to the other side of the field. We would all
                        rather take the chances of a five hours' battle than of another such
                        explosion. The damage to the gun will be repaired today.</p>
                    <p>In closing, I will take this first public of saying, as an act of justice to
                        my boys, that a better company of men is no where to be found in the army .
                        They have at all times behaved like gentlemen, and worked like horses. We
                        have had a great deal of hard service, and I have yet to hear the first
                        murmur of dissatisfaction. Such men, when the battle comes, I am sure, will
                        "hurt" somebody or die in the effort.</p>
                    <p>J.D. Imboden, Capt.</p>
                    <p>Staunton Artillery</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J.D. Imboden</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tesbo</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thise</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peace</ln>
                        <fn>Sandy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balthis</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Imboden's letter explains an accident that occurred in camp and the
                    resulting casualty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Feeling in Kanawha</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the resolutions of a public meeting in Kanawha in which it was
                    resolved that, despite opposition to the Ordinance, Kanawha County would defend
                    Virginia from federal invasion.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports resolutions adopted by the Maryland Legislature denouncing the
                    Northern war effort, upholding the right of secession, and denouncing the
                    suspension of habeas corpus in the case of John Merryman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Look Out for Indians</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Cherokee Nation is raising militia and has attached itself
                    to the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Hospital at Culpeper C.H.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the hospital at Culpeper is in need of supplies and is open to
                    charitable donations.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>From Alexandria</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports rumors that Beauregard has moved his forces east from
                    Manassas Junction and is trying to taunt Gen. McDowell into battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClanahan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Rev.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>Deniza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yeago</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 23.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items regarding military engagements. Much of paper too light to
            read.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.07.02.02">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
