<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.03.05">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-05">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day norm="05">5</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.05.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Nuggets from Prentice</head>
                <origin>Louisville Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A collection of anecdotes poking fun at secession and the leaders of the
                    secessionist states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 ads. Columns 2-6 poetry, fiction and assorted anecdotes. Column 7
                Virginia legislature and State Convention records. Lower right illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.05.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Inaugural</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces Lincoln's inauguration and reports that in his speech, Lincoln
                    denied the right of secession.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Speeches of Col. Baylor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We refer our readers to the proceedings of the Convention on Thursday and
                        Friday for the speeches made in that body by Col. Geo. Baylor. It will be
                        seen that he is "<emph rend="italic">all right</emph>," and that he attacks
                        the fiery dragon of secession in such gallant style as should entitle him to
                        be canonized as "St. George, the slayer of the fiery dragon."--His speeches
                        justify the good opinion entertained of him as a sound and reliable Union
                        man. Desiring the Union sentiment of the Democracy of this county to have a
                        representative in the Convention, and knowing Col. Baylor to be a good Union
                        man, who was opposed to secession in theory as well as practice, we asked
                        him to become a candidate, and rejoiced at his triumphant election, and we
                        now rejoice that he has acquitted himself so handsomely in the Convention.
                        Those of his party who are true to the principles which they advocated in
                        the Presidential canvass, will cordially approve of the speeches of Col.
                        Baylor. Those who were governed by what they deemed policy and not
                        principle--who supported Douglas because they thought he was the stronger
                        wing of the party--who sought the majority and not principle--and who are
                        now co-operating with the secessionists-- may not endorse the position of
                        Col. Baylor, but the masses of that party who are governed by principles and
                        who supported Douglas because they endorsed his principles, will cordially
                        endorse the speeches of Col. Baylor. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In praise of unionism, the article calls readers' attention to the speech
                    of Col. Baylor at the Convention, in which he attacked the "fiery dragon of
                    secession."</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.5a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hunter and Mason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The opposition of Hunter and Mason in the U. S. Senate to the Peace
                        Conference resolutions, will meet with the indignation of three-fourths of
                        the people of this State. The people will pronounce the curse <emph
                            rend="italic">anathema maranatha</emph> against them. The secessionists
                        and the worst class of Black Republicans harmoniously co-operated to
                        frustrate all efforts at settlement. Mason and Hunter paid no respect to the
                        voice of Virginia as recently expressed in thunder- tones at the polls. In
                        the language of the "Baltimore American," we ask, "what have Messrs. Mason
                        and Hunter to say in their own defence when they assume an attitude in
                        direct hostility to all the conservative men in their State?--They oppose
                        the Peace Conference resolution when it is perfectly well understood that
                        there is no remaining possibility of settlement by the present Congress, if
                        they are rejected. Moreover, they are not required to commit themselves.
                        Their opposition was a factious opposition, based upon grounds so frivolous,
                        in comparison with the momentous issues involved, that we can only wonder
                        that gentlemen of their pretensions were not ashamed to offer it." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Hunter and Mason, Virginia's senators, rejected the settlement
                    proposed by the Peace Conference. The article argues that the senators
                    overlooked the desires of the state of Virginia and are co-operating to achieve
                    disunion.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.5b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Volunteer Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>H.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boff</ln>
                        <fn>R.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces election of officers for the organization of a Volunteer Regiment
                    in Augusta.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Peace Conference Settlement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an attempt to compromise by the so-called congressional Peace
                    Conference, which is composed of moderates of all parties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Chief Object--The Preservation of the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Uses excerpts from the writings of Madison, Hamilton and Jay to argue that
                    the Articles of Confederation were abandoned in favor of the Constitution for
                    the purpose of preserving the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Several items praising pro-union sentiments. Column 4 State Convention
                records. Column 5 Congressional Records. Column 6 Virginia Legislature Records.
                Column 7 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.05.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teeling</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wall</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McQuaid</ln>
                        <fn>Annie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 23 at the American Hotel in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Esq.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lambeth</ln>
                        <fn>S.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cootes</ln>
                        <fn>B. Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Cootes and Miss Newton were married on February 26 at the home of the
                    bride's father.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tarbet</ln>
                        <fn>Nathaniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died in Greenville on February 9 at age 80.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Stafford, son of John and Elizabeth, died on February 14 at age 6
                    years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Ann Amelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Ann Amelia Clarke died on February 22 in Augusta, Georgia. She was William
                    Ruff's daughter. An infant child of Mrs. Clarke also died at about the same
                    time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on February 19.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Patterson, wife of Washington, died on February 4 at age 29. She
                    was a member of the Evangelical Lutheran Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Castleman</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the death of Thomas Castleman in Louisiana. Rev. Castleman was the
                    rector of the Trinity Church in Staunton for fourteen years.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Two obituary names illegible. Remainder of page 3 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.05.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
