<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.06.04">
 <header>
  <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
  <tagger>
   <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
   <tagDate>04/08/96</tagDate>
   <tagNote>Colleen Doody second pass, 6/7/97</tagNote>
  </tagger>
  <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
  <date n="1861-06-04">
   <year>1861</year>
   <month norm="06">June</month>
   <day norm="04">4</day>
   <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
  </date>
  <frequency>weekly</frequency>
  <extent>04</extent>
  <editionNote/>
 </header>
 <paperBody>
  <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.06.04.01">
   <div type="l">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>An Appeal to Righteousness and Peace</head>
    <origin>The Central Presbyterian</origin>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt>"Virginia, by her Union men, had gone to the verge of dishonor rather than secede."</excerpt>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A letter from a Presbyterian in Hampden Sydney defends the right of secession and
     asserts that the Central Presbyterian should have upheld this right throughout the entire
     crisis.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Military Surgery</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Advice for doctors in military service.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Mrs. Jefferson Davis</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item reports that Jefferson Davis was married first to Zachary Taylor's daughter. She
     has been dead for some years and he is now married to a woman originally of Philadelphia who
     has a brother in the Union army.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>Warning Against Overconfidence in Politics, as in Religion, All Important</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports a speech by Ex-President Fillmore that defends the South's independence in the
     face of a President elected only by the votes of the North.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>Dear General Scott</head>
    <origin>Memphis Bulletin</origin>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer>Elizabeth A. Donelson</trailer>
    <names/>
    <summary>A niece of Andrew Jackson writes a letter to Gen. Scott urging him to do everything in
     his power to avert the war that is upon the nation.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>The Despots of Europe</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Asserts that only the most tyrannical regimes in Europe support the North and compares
     the invasion of the South to the Austro-Russian invasion of Hungary.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Column 1 ads. Column 2 poetry/fiction.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.06.04.02">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>President Davis in Richmond</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item reports Davis's arrival in Richmond.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Arrest of Edward C. Randolph</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the arrest of Randolph, a suspected spy, in Middlebrook, Augusta Co. by members
     of the Greenbrier militia.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>Victory Will Be Ours</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p> We hope that no Southern man will suffer himself to become discouraged in consequence of
      the number of our enemies. He should remember that we are in the right, and that Providence
      will not suffer us to be defeated, if we perform our whole duty manfully and faithfully. "The
      race is not always to the swift, nor the battle to the strong." A contemporary well says that
       "<emph rend="italic">the success of a gallant struggle on the side of right and justice,
       against wrong and oppression, is almost inevitable.</emph>" A virtuous and gallant people in
      a good cause never have failed. If we are right, and do not falter, we must succeed. Weak as
      we may appear, and strong as the Federal Government may seem, in the hour of trial, we shall
      have the strength of David; our enemies the weakness of Goliah [sic]. Let us then rest assured
      that the battle is not with the strong, but to the vigilant, the active and the brave who
      fight for right." </p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Urges Southerners not to become overwhelmed by the seemingly superior strength of the
     Federal Armies. The South will be victorious because the South is in the right and will not be
     defeated if "we perform our whole duty manfully and faithfully."</summary>
    <note>aubrowser/ssjune61.html#6.4a</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>What Shall We Wear?</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript>
     <p>Economy is a commendable virtue at any time, but it now becomes a patriotic duty. The people
      should now economize as much as possible, that they may have more means to contribute to the
      defense of the State, and to the comfort and necessities of our soldiers. The Revolution in
      which we are now engaged will demand heavy sacrifices, and we should prepare ourselves as well
      as possible to bear them. No money should now be expended for luxuries or mere display. We
      should now confine our purchases to the necessaries of life, and to such articles as are of
      positive utility. Business of almost all kinds has been paralyzed, and the majority of persons
      will suffer heavy losses. We hope that the merely ornamental will be sacrificed to the useful.
      The gentlemen should give up fine broad-cloth suits and be content with cheaper ones that
      would wear equally as long and be quite as comfortable. The ladies should be willing to forego
      the pleasure of appearing in costly silks, and high-priced bonnets. The fashion should now be
      to wear cheap and durable apparel. The time for "Flora McFlimseys" is when the country teems
      with wealth and smiles with prosperity. In such times as we have at present, they should be
      banished from the country. We hope that those whose means would enable them to dress
      extravagantly will set the example of appearing in a dress which will combine neatness,
      cheapness and durability. The wealthy can afford to do this without any suspicion that it is
      the consequence of pecuniary necessity, and will secure the praise of doing so through
      laudable motives. But as long as costly apparel is considered a badge of respectability and a
      pass-port to good society, the majority cannot afford to consult economy, unless the
      recognized leaders of the styles should make it fashionable to do so. The chief beauty of any
      dress consists in the fit, and it should be made to fit the times as well as the person. We
      hope to see unpretending calico dresses, which have been banished from the towns, again
      introduced. Who will set the example? What lady will lead in this laudable enterprise? The
      ladies of Staunton have as good a right to "set the fashions" as the less worthy ladies of
      Paris have.--Patriotism now demands it.</p>
    </transcript>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Urges citizens to economize so that more goods can be donated to the troops. In
     particular, citizens are requested to dress modestly and cheaply.</summary>
    <note>aubrowser/ssjune61.html#6.4b</note>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Volunteers</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Lilley</ln>
      <fn>R.D.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Reports that Augusta now has thirteen organized companies, twelve of which are in
     active service. Item also reports that the Augusta Lee Rifles still have room for more
     volunteers.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>False News</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item reports that last week's news of a battle at Hampton was utterly false. The
     article argues that control of the telegraph should pass to government authorities in order
     that no more false reports are transmitted on the wire.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>What Was It?</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item reports that many people around the county heard sounds that were similar to the
     firing of heavy cannon. The closest cannon being fired were a Aquia Creek, prompting queries as
     to how far away cannon can be heard.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Circuit Court</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Thompson</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Judge</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McAlony</ln>
      <fn>Michael</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Announces the commencement of the Augusta County Circuit Court.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Firing at Aquia Creek</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports an exchange of artillery fire between a Federal Steamer and Confederate shore
     batteries.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Tim Rives</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Answers charges of submissionism directed against Tim Rives, who gave a pro-Union
     speech at the Convention.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>3</column>
    <head>Gen. Huger</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Provides a brief biographical sketch of Gen. Huger, who has been placed in command of
     the Virginia forces at Norfolk.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Fight at Fairfax C.H.--Capt. Marr Killed</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Details of a skirmish at the Fairfax Court House.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>4</column>
    <head>Military Despotism</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item reports the arrest of Mr. Merryman, the President of the Agricultural Society of
     Maryland, by Federal Troops. He attained a writ of habeas corpus from Justice Taney, but the
     President suspended the writ, leading Taney to declare Merryman's imprisonment unlawful.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Proclamation of Jefferson Davis</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>President Davis proclaims a day of fasting and prayer on Thursday, the 13th of June.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>The Government in a Quandry</head>
    <origin>New York Times</origin>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>The Washington Correspondent for the New York Times asks how prisoners are going to be
     dealt with in the conflict.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Save Rags</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Item urges the citizenry to save rags.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>The War Spirit South</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>A letter from a Texas man to a New York journal asserting that Southerners are united
     in their defense of the South and denying claims that Southerners are pressed into service.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>The Burial of Ellsworth</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the funeral of Ellsworth in New York.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>5</column>
    <head>Gen. Beauregard</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the arrival of Gen. Beauregard in Richmond.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>Regiment of Virginia Volunteers</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Newton</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Roberts</ln>
      <fn>Francis</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Baylor</ln>
      <fn>W.S.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Col.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Waters</ln>
      <fn>James</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Marquis</ln>
      <fn>James</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Blackburn</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Burke</ln>
      <fn>Thomas</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Crawford</ln>
      <fn>S.M.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Williams</ln>
      <fn>H.J.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McKamey</ln>
      <fn>W.C.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Helms</ln>
      <fn>Samuel</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Randolph</ln>
      <fn>W.H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>McComb</ln>
      <fn>M.H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Gipson</ln>
      <fn>J.W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Kerser</ln>
      <fn>J.H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Grinnan</ln>
      <fn>O.F.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Grills</ln>
      <fn>C.W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ross</ln>
      <fn>Henry</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Wilson</ln>
      <fn>J.W.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Gilkerson</ln>
      <fn>W.G.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Ramsey</ln>
      <fn>O.B.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Calhoun</ln>
      <fn>C.H.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Johnson</ln>
      <fn>W.P.</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Lieut.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>An appeal to the authorities in Richmond by the Augusta County 5th Regiment to install
     Col. Baylor as their commander. He had been replaced by the Military Board.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>Sketch of the Proceedings of the Council of the Town of Staunton, June 1, 1861</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Patterson</ln>
      <fn>James</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Reports the results of the Staunton town council meeting.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>6</column>
    <head>Removal of Government</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Reports the removal of the Confederate Government from Montgomery, Alabama to Richmond,
     Virginia.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="l">
    <column>7</column>
    <head/>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Grinnan</ln>
      <fn/>
      <sf/>
      <pf>Capt.</pf>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Writer reports that the company of volunteers from Mt. Solon, Augusta County was
     honored by the ladies of the town.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>The Star Spangled Banner</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Asserts that the flag for which the Federal troops fight is not the same as the flag
     that floated over the battlefields of the Revolution.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="a">
    <column>7</column>
    <head>By the Governor: A Proclamation</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Governor requests all volunteer companies not already mustered into service to meet at
     the designated rendezvous points.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Telegraphic dispatches and articles regarding troop movements.</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.06.04.03">
   <div type="a">
    <column>1</column>
    <head>To the Mothers and Wives of Virginia</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names/>
    <summary>Article asks women to contribute luxury items of metal and jewelry to the cause of the
     Confederacy.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
      <fn>Louisa</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Lushbaugh</ln>
      <fn>Harman</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Louisa Lushbaugh, wife of Harman, died on May 24 at age 37.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <div type="o">
    <column>2</column>
    <head>Died</head>
    <origin/>
    <commentary/>
    <excerpt/>
    <transcript/>
    <trailer/>
    <names>
     <name>
      <ln>Johnson</ln>
      <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Johnson</ln>
      <fn>William</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
     <name>
      <ln>Johnson</ln>
      <fn>Mary</fn>
      <sf/>
      <pf/>
     </name>
    </names>
    <summary>Martha Jane Johnson, daughter of William and Mary Johnson, died on April 30 at age 22.
     She had been a member of the M.E. Church.</summary>
    <note/>
    <look/>
   </div>
   <pageNote>Advertisements and Markets</pageNote>
  </page>
  <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.06.04.04">
   <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
  </page>
 </paperBody>
</hwp>
