<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1861/va.au.ss.1861.03.12">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1861-03-12">
            <year>1861</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>12</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.12.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Personal Sketches of Lincoln's Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides a brief overview of the "gentlemen who are to be the
                    Constitutional advisors of the President."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Inauguration Ball</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mentions some of the more luminous attendees of the inaugural ball and
                    discusses the agenda for the evening.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the continued assertion by the leading politicians in the seceding
                    states that "nothing could induce a return to the Union."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Inaugural</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article is a copy of Lincoln's inaugural address in which he tries to
                    calm the secessionist element in the South by declaring he has never intended
                    nor does he intend to "interfere with the institution of slavery in the States
                    where it exists." He does, however, continue to deny both the right of secession
                    and the right to adopt slavery in the Territories.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 1 ads. Column 2 poetry and fiction. Column 7 State Convention records.
                Bottom right illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.12.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that voters in North Carolina opposed holding a Convention by at
                    least a majority of one thousand votes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Secretary Seward has given his assurances that "no measures
                    calculated to lead to bloodshed will be resorted to."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports with derision that the Southern Congress has authorized Jeff Davis
                    to borrow money at 8% interest which will be paid off with an export duty on
                    cotton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Old Charge Revived</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Unionist in Virginia are being termed Black Republicans and
                    even "abolitionists" by the secessionists. The Spectator continues to stress
                    that "the extremes have met" in their effort to destroy the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Chief Object--The Preservation of the Union</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Under this caption, for the past two weeks, we have published a number of
                        quotations from the essays written upon the Constitution and the objects had
                        in view in the adoption of our present Government by those who were more
                        instrumental in securing its adoption than any others, for the purpose of
                        proving, by the most incontestable evidence, that the <emph rend="italic"
                            >chief object</emph> in substituting our present Constitutional
                        Government for the articles of Confederation was to secure the establishment
                        of a Government which would be enabled <emph rend="italic">to preserve the
                            Union</emph>. In this number we will conclude the publication of
                        testimony upon that point, though we have a great deal more at hand. </p>
                    <p>In the 15th number of the Federalist, this language is used:</p>
                    <p>"In pursuance of the plan, which I have laid down for the discussion of the
                        subject, the point next in order to be examined in the '<emph rend="italic"
                            >insufficiency of the present confederation to the preservation of the
                            Union</emph>.' It may perhaps be asked, what need there is of reasoning
                        or proof to illustrate a position, which is <emph rend="italic">neither
                            controverted nor doubted;</emph> to which the understanding and feelings
                        of <emph rend="italic">all classes of men assent;</emph> and which in
                        substance is admitted by the <emph rend="italic">opponents</emph> as well as
                        by the <emph rend="italic">friends</emph> of the new Constitution?" </p>
                    <p>It will thus be seen that that distinguished man, Alexander Hamilton,
                        actually apologized to the people of that day--when the Constitution was
                        being submitted to the different States--for entering upon an argument to
                        prove the <emph rend="italic">insufficiency of the Confederation to preserve
                            the Union</emph>," for he was about to prove what <emph rend="italic">no
                            one</emph> at that day denied. </p>
                    <p>In the 41st number, the <emph rend="italic">chief author</emph> of the
                        Constitution, James Madison, in speaking of the essential importance of the
                        Union, uses this language: </p>
                    <p>"The clearest marks of this prudence are stamped on the proposed
                        Constitution. The Union itself, which it <emph rend="italic">cements and
                            secures</emph>, destroys every pretext for a military establishment
                        which could be dangerous. <emph rend="italic">America united</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">with a handful of troops</emph>, <emph rend="italic">or
                            without a single soldier</emph>, <emph rend="italic">exhibits a more
                            forbidding posture to foreign ambition than America disunited with a
                            hundred thousand veterans ready for combat</emph>. It was remarked, on a
                        former occasion, that the want of this pretext had saved the liberties of
                        one nation in Europe. Being rendered by her insular situation, and her
                        maritime resources, impregnable to the armies of her neighbors, the rulers
                        of Great Britain have never been able, by real or artificial dangers, to
                        cheat the public into an extensive peace establishment. The distance of the
                        United States from the powerful nations of the world, gives them the same
                        happy security. A dangerous establishment can never be necessary or
                        plausible, so long as they continue a <emph rend="italic">united
                        people</emph>. <emph rend="italic">But let it never for a moment be
                            forgotten, that they are indebted for this advantage to their union
                            alone</emph>. <emph rend="italic">The moment of its dissolution will be
                            the date of a new order of things</emph>.--The fears of the weaker, or
                        the ambition of the stronger States, or Confederacies, will set the same
                        example in the new as Charles VII did in the old world. The example will be
                        followed here, from the same motives which produced universal imitation
                        there. Instead of deriving from our situation the precious advantage which
                        Great Britain has derived from hers, the face of American will be but a copy
                        of that of the continent of Europe. <emph rend="italic">It will present
                            liberty everywhere crushed between standing armies</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">and perpetual taxes</emph>. <emph rend="italic">The
                            fortunes of disunited America will be even more disastrous than those of
                            Europe</emph>. The sources of evil in the latter are confined to her own
                        limits. No superior powers of another quarter of the globe intrigue among
                        her rival nations, inflame their mutual animosities, and render them the
                        instruments of foreign ambition, jealousy and revenge. In America the
                        miseries springing from her internal jealousies, contentions and wars, would
                        form a part only of her lot. A plentiful addition of evils, would have their
                        source in that relation in which Europe stands to this quarter of the earth,
                        and which no other quarter of the earth bears to Europe. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">This picture of the consequences of disunion cannot be
                            too highly colored</emph><emph rend="italic">or too often
                        exhibited</emph>. <emph rend="italic">Every man who loves peace; every man
                            who loves his country; every man who loves liberty</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">ought to have it ever before his eyes</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">that he may cherish in his heart a due attachment to the
                            UNION of America</emph>, <emph rend="italic">and be able to set a due
                            value on the means of preserving it</emph>. </p>
                    <p>IN the 44th number, the same author, James Madison, the "Father of the
                        Constitution," after having gone over the whole ground in a series of
                        numbers concludes with this language:</p>
                    <p>"We have now reviewed, in detail, all the articles composing the sum or
                        quantity of power delegated by the proposed Constitution to the Federal
                        Government; and are brought to this undeniable conclusion, that <emph
                            rend="italic">no part of the power is unnecessary or improper for
                            accomplishing the</emph> NECESSARY OBJECTS OF THE UNION. The question
                        therefore, whether this amount of power shall be granted or not, resolves
                        itself into another question, whether or not a government <emph
                            rend="italic">commensurate to the exigencies of the UNION shall be
                            established; or</emph>, <emph rend="italic">in other words</emph>, <emph
                            rend="italic">whether the</emph> UNION ITSELF SHALL BE PRESERVED." </p>
                    <p>The history of the adoption of the Constitution and the authority of its
                        authors prove beyond all doubt that the chief object in adopting our present
                        form of Government in lieu of the Confederacy was to establish a Government
                        which would be enabled to <emph rend="italic">preserve the Union</emph>."
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Another installment in a series of articles which use the writings in The
                    Federalist to argue that the Constitution replaced the Articles of Confederation
                    principally to ensure the preservation of the Union.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.12a</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Fruits of Secession</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that the seceded states are burdening the citizens with heavy
                    taxation for the "defense of the State." The article questions "As these things
                    occur in time of peace, what may we expect in times of war?"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that troops assembled around Fort Sumter have been turned over to
                    the Southern Confederacy and placed by Jeff Davis under the command of Maj.
                    General Beauregard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Inaugural</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If it shall, in the reckless disregard of the peace of the country,
                    persist in enforcing laws where it must result in a conflict, the inevitable
                    result will be that the whole South will be united in opposition to such a
                    policy."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the first page of this paper will be found a correct copy of the Inaugural
                        Address of the President. We know that it will be read with great interest
                        by all of our readers. We hope that all will read it carefully and form
                        their own opinions with reference to its character.--We think that he
                        expresses the same views in reference to the Constitutional obligations of
                        the Executive that Mr. Buchanan did. The Constitution invests the Executive
                        with no discretionary powers in regard to the enforcement of the laws, but,
                        on the contrary, makes it his imperative and sworn duty to see that they be
                        faithfully executed. It is for the very reason that it is the duty of the
                        Executive to have the laws enforced, and the duty of the people to yield
                        obedience to them, that we have several times recommended the call of a
                        National Convention <emph rend="italic">for the purpose</emph> of obtaining
                        the consent of three- fourths of the States to the peaceful withdrawal of
                        the seceded States, and the release of the Executive from his obligations to
                        enforce the laws in them. We believe that the same power which can
                        Constitutionally change the character of our Government, can
                        Constitutionally release the citizens of the seceded states from their
                        obligations of obedience to the laws, and consequently relieve the Executive
                        from his obligations to enforce them. We believe that this policy must be
                        adopted, or that civil war, the direst of all calamities, will ultimately be
                        the result. We regret that the President did not express a desire to be
                        relieved, in the mode suggested, from his obligations to perform a duty
                        which threatens such direful consequences. As the Executive has no power to
                        recognize the independence of the seceded States, and no power to release
                        the citizens thereof from their obligations of obedience to the laws, we
                        hope that a National Convention will be called <emph rend="italic">for these
                            purposes</emph>.--To involved the country in civil war, as long as there
                        remains any means to avoid it, would be more than folly and madness--it
                        would be in the highest degree criminal. We cannot believe that any
                        President would willingly involve the country in civil war. </p>
                    <p>The Inaugural Address is understood by some to indicate a purpose to enforce
                        the laws at all hazards, and by others that the laws will be enforced only
                        so far as it can be done peacefully.--It cannot be known certainly which is
                        the proper construction, till the policy of the administration shall be more
                        clearly indicated by its acts. If it shall, in reckless disregard of the
                        peace of the country, persist in enforcing the laws where it must result in
                        a conflict, the inevitable result will be that the whole South will be
                        united in armed opposition to such a policy.</p>
                    <p>In the Senate, in Extra-Session, on Wednesday last, on a motion to print the
                        usual number of copies of the Inaugural, Mr. Clingman, a secession Senator
                        from North Carolina, opposed the policy of the Inaugural as he understood
                        it, and said if it was carried out that it would lead inevitably to war. The
                        Hon. Stephen A. Douglas dissented from the construction put upon the
                        Inaugural by Senator Clingman, and spoke as follows:</p>
                    <p>Mr. Douglas said that he could not consent that the Senator's remarks should
                        go out unanswered. He had read the Inaugural carefully, with a view of
                        understanding what the policy of the Administration is to be, as therein
                        indicated. It is characterized by great ability and with great distinctness
                        on certain points. A critical analysis is necessary to arrive at the true
                        construction. He had partially made an analysis, and had come to the
                        conclusion that it was a peace rather than a war message. He had examined it
                        candidly and critically, and he thought there was no foundation for a
                        different opinion. On the contrary, there is a distinct pledge that the
                        policy of the Administration shall be conducted exclusively with reference
                        to a peaceful solution of our national difficulties. It is true the
                        President indicates a certain line of policy, so to be conducted as to lead
                        to a peaceful solution, but it was not as explicit as he (Mr. Douglas)
                        desired. He then quoted from the Inaugural in support of his positions,
                        saying that unless the means be furnished the President cannot execute the
                        laws. He thought the President in his remarks on the subject was referring
                        to future action of Congress giving power to enforce obedience to them.</p>
                    <p>The President must have been aware that in 1832 a law was passed to enable
                        General Jackson to enforce the revenue laws in the port of Charleston. The
                        act expired in two years.--Was it to be supposed that Mr. Lincoln thought he
                        had more power without than General Jackson had with the aid of legislation?
                        He repeated that when the President pledges himself to collect the revenue
                        and enforce the laws, unless Congress withhold the requisite means, is he
                        not to be understood that his act is dependent on the further course of
                        Congress?</p>
                    <p>He thought that was the proper construction of the Inaugural, for the
                        President says he shall perform his duty "so far as practicable, unless his
                        rightful masters, the American people, shall withhold the requisite means or
                        in some authoritative manner direct to the contrary."</p>
                    <p>The President further says:</p>
                    <p>"The power confided to me will be used to hold, occupy and possess the
                        property and places belonging to the Government, and to collect the duties
                        on imports, but beyond what may be necessary for these objects, there will
                        be no invasion, no using of force against or among the people anywhere."</p>
                    <p>The President does not say he will <emph rend="italic">take</emph> and hold,
                        occupy and possess them. This was equivocal language, but he did not condemn
                        the President for it. "Beyond what may be necessary" for these objects,
                        there will be no irritation, no using of force among the people anywhere. It
                        is the duty of the President to enforce the other laws. It cannot be
                        justified that the revenue laws be enforced, and all other laws which afford
                        protection as a compensation for taxes shall not be enforced. </p>
                    <p>He thought that there were two forms in which they could find a solution of
                        these doubts. The President says: "Where hostility to the United States, in
                        any interior locality, shall be so great and so universal as to prevent
                        competent resident citizens from holding the Federal offices, there will be
                        no attempt to force obnoxious strangers among the people, for that
                        object."--The President draws a distinction between the exterior and the
                        interior. If he has power in one case, he has power in the other. If it is
                        his duty in once case to enforce the laws, it is his duty in the other.
                        There was no provision of law which authorizes a distinction in this respect
                        between places in the interior and on the seaboard.</p>
                    <p>This brought him to the construction of another clause--the most important of
                        all, and the key to the entire policy; but he was rejoiced when he read it.
                        He invited attention to it, as showing conclusively that the President is
                        pledged to a policy which looks to a peaceful solution of our difficulties,
                        and against all others. He says: "The course here indicated will be
                        followed, unless current events and experience shall show a modification or
                        change to be proper, and in every case and exigency my best discretion will
                        be exercised according to circumstances actually existing, and with a view
                        and a hope of a peaceful solution of the National difficulties and the
                        restoration of fraternal sympathies and affections." In other words, the
                        President says if the collection of the revenue will lead to a peaceful
                        solution, then it will be collected. If the abandonment of the collection
                        will have that effect, then it will be abandoned. So of the forts and
                        arsenals in the seceding States. He will recapture or not recapture them,
                        and will reinforce or not reinforce Forts Sumpter and Pickens. He is pledged
                        in either case to a peaceful policy and to acting with this view. If this is
                        not the true construction, why was there not inserted a pledge to use
                        coercion, retake the forts, recapture the arsenals, collect the revenue and
                        enforce the laws, unless there we attached to each one a condition on which
                        the pledge was to be carried out? But the pledge is only to do it in order
                        to a peaceful solution, and for no other cause."</p>
                    <p>The next day Mr. Wigfall, a secessionist, and a Senator from a State which
                        has actually seceded, made a speech putting a war construction upon the
                        Inaugural, as Clingman had done the day before, to whom Hon. Stephen A.
                        Douglas replied. The following is an extract from the reply of Mr. Douglas:</p>
                    <p>Mr. Douglas repeated what he said yesterday--that he had carefully analyzed
                        the inaugural for the purpose of ascertaining distinctly and certainly what
                        was the policy of the new administration, and he came to the conclusion that
                        it was the wish and purpose of the President to pursue a peaceful policy and
                        avoid war. He was rejoiced to be able to arrive at the conclusion. This was
                        the whole substance of what he yesterday said or desired to say.</p>
                    <p>The Senator from Texas thought the expression of this opinion or conclusion
                        was calculated to have a bad effect upon the country; but it struck him (Mr.
                        Douglas) that if the country could rest secure in the belief that they are
                        to have peace--no civil war, no armies mustered into conflict--it would have
                        a happy effect. He was sure every man who loved this glorious Union, for it
                        was glorious, and even dearer to him now than ever before--every man who
                        loved his kind, and was proud of being an American, ought to rejoice in the
                        belief that peace can be maintained.</p>
                    <p>If he were allowed to judge of the various speeches of the Senator from
                        Texas, he was forced to the conclusion that the Senator did not regard the
                        question of peace as he did. The Senator had told them more than once that
                        they could take their choice between peace and war, and that he did not
                        care. But he, (Mr. Douglas) cared- -and therein consisted the difference
                        between the Senator and himself. Because he was desirous of peace, he was
                        anxious to ascertain what was to be the policy of the administration.</p>
                    <p>He had arrived at his conclusions candidly and fairly, and had expressed his
                        gratification at the result. If he had arrived at the conclusion that the
                        Inaugural means war, he would have denounced it. He was with the President
                        as far as the President was for peace, and would be against him when he
                        departed from that line of policy.</p>
                    <p>In reference to his speech at Norfolk, during the Presidential canvass, in
                        which he replied to the questions propounded by Mr. Lamb, Mr. Douglas said:</p>
                    <p>I see no reason to change or modify any sentiment therein expressed.</p>
                    <p>I believed then, as I now do, that I expressed the sound constitutional
                        principles on which alone the government can exist. As to hanging, the
                        Senator was under some misapprehension, or his mind asserts of a character
                        which magnifies one man to two men. I only spoke of hanging one person, and
                        that in a certain contingency.-- And I did say, that if Mr. Lincoln should
                        be elected President according to the Constitutional forms, he must be
                        inaugurated; and, under my constitutional duty, I would sustain him in the
                        exercise of all legitimate duties of the station.</p>
                    <p>I then said, if, after he was elected, he should violate the constitution of
                        the country, and commit crimes against the laws of the land, I should be for
                        punishing him according to the law. And if the penalty under the
                        Constitution be to hang him, I would hang him higher than Haman. I would
                        have said the same thing of any other man who might abuse the trust reposed
                        in him by the American people. I asserted it as a general principle.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Mason followed, characterizing the Inaugural as a proclamation of war.
                        Mr. Douglas again replied, declaring his belief that the President was in
                        favor of a pacific policy, and the Republican party also sustained that
                        policy as the best under the circumstances.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reaction to Lincoln's inaugural address. The article expresses
                    understanding of Lincoln's sworn duty to uphold the laws of the country yet
                    regrets that he did not call for a National Convention in order to provide a
                    legal outlet for the seceded states to relieve the President of his duty and
                    avert war. The article indicates uncertainty over whether the President intends
                    to enforce the laws up to the point of force or if he intends to precipitate
                    armed conflict. If the latter is the case, the article states, the whole South
                    will unite against such a policy. The article quotes Stephen Douglas's reaction
                    in Congress to the inaugural. Douglas found the inaugural conciliatory in tone
                    and hopeful for peace.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.12b</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A Capital Burlesque</head>
                <origin>Alexandria Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The flag of the Republic of Hardy shall consist of a green field with a
                    shock of fodder in the right corner, an ox in the center with his forefoot
                    raised and the motto 'Cattle is King.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>I send the following Ordinance of Secession, left under the door of the
                        delegate from Hardy county the night before he left home:</p>
                    <p>"Hardy COUNTY, VIRGINIA.--<emph rend="italic">Ordinance of
                        Secession</emph>.--WHEREAS, There seems to be a manifest intention on the
                        part of Virginia to delay prompt action and remain in the Union at all
                        hazards; and, WHEREAS, the Commercial, Agricultural and Manufacturing
                        interests of Hardy county require <emph rend="italic">immediate
                        secession</emph> on the part of Virginia: Therefore, </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, 1<emph rend="italic">st</emph>, That in
                        case the State Convention does not pass an ordinance of secession within two
                        days after they assemble, our delegate be requested to withdraw forthwith
                        from the Convention, and declare that Hardy is, and has a right to be, a
                        free and independent county, and that we no longer acknowledge ourselves a
                        part of Virginia. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, 2<emph rend="italic">d</emph>, That our
                        delegate, in such contingency, be instructed to proceed immediately to
                        London and Paris to announce to the Sovereigns of those countries, that
                        Hardy is a free and independent republic, and will henceforth exercise all
                        the rights of sovereignty which have been heretofore delegated to Virginia. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, 3<emph rend="italic">d</emph>, That our
                        delegate be empowered to make treaties with the European powers, and decide
                        upon the foreign policy of the Republic of Hardy. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, 4<emph rend="italic">th</emph>, That as
                        soon as the European powers shall acknowledge the independence of Hardy, our
                        commercial relations shall be distinctly defined, and that a treaty be
                        entered into with foreignn powers by which our cattle shall be exported free
                        of duty by European vessls of sufficient capacity to navigate the South
                        branch of the Potomac with all foreign ports. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved</emph>, 5<emph rend="italic">th</emph>, That the
                        flag of the Republic of Hardy shall consist of a green field, with a shock
                        of fodder in the right corner, an ox in the centre with his forefoot raised,
                        and the motto "Cattle is King."--<emph rend="italic">Alexandria
                        Gazette</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of an Ordinance of Secession that spoofs secessionist views. It was
                    left under the door of the Convention delegate from Hardy County and suggests
                    that, if Virginia does not secede in a matter of days, Hardy County will secede
                    unilaterally and assume all powers of a sovereign nation.</summary>
                <note>aubrowser/ssmar61.html#3.12c</note>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Column 4 State Convention records. Column 5 Virginia Legislative records.
                Column 7 ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.12.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Military Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>R.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>H.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Starrett</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports the election of field officers at a meeting of the Officers of the
                    Volunteer Companies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grove</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lander</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Delila</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetzel</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Lander married Delila Alexander on February 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craver</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>N.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Tribute of respect for Isaac Craver.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1861.03.12.04">
            <pageNote>Advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
