<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.01.06">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01.10.96</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-06">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="06">6</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote>Page 1 of 1863 Staunton Spectator is generally ads. News is now on page
        2.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.01.06.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Stolen and Deported Slaves</head>
                <origin>New Yoek Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York Herald, in a late article on Lincoln's Emancipation
                        Proclamation, which it declares can have no effect, except where there are
                        armies in a position to carry it out, has the following paragraph:</p>
                    <p>The Constitution defines treason and prescribes the mode of punishing it.
                        Whole communities cannot be legally made traitors by proclamations, nor
                        their property seized and confiscated; and if Congress passed fifty laws on
                        the subject they would have no legal efficacy. Consequently, if slave
                        property should be taken away from the citizens of the United States by
                        Generals of the army, in virtue of the proclamation of the President, the
                        property must be restored or paid for by the United States Government,
                        unless the persons from whom it had been taken should be convicted of
                        treason in a court of law, and after a full and fair trial.</p>
                    <p>The Herald is correct. The slaves taken from our citizens during the war will
                        have to be accounted for at its end, either by restoration or indemnity. The
                        matter will not admit of controversy, for, in addition to the obvious
                        propriety of such a course, the exact question has been adjudicated by the
                        United States, and stands on record against them. At the end of the
                        Revolutionary War, and again at the close of the war of 1812, this point
                        came up, and it was settled in the Treaty of Peace of 1788, and in the
                        Treaty of Ghent in 1814, in favor of the restitution of slaves abducted by
                        military authority from the South.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item criticizes the Emancipation Proclamation.</summary>
                <note>Article largely illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maphis</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seely</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Youst</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Donnel</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frazier</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swoppe</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roler</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allison</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Bartholomew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peters</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of casualties (killed and wounded) in the West Augusta Guard.</summary>
                <note>Most names illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Battlefield report involving Augusta troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Col. 1 - 5 ads. Col. 6 poetry.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.01.06.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Financial Suggestion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on Southern financial difficulties.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Daring Dash</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On Sunday week, Captain McNeill, commanding Co. E, Col. Imboden's cavalry
                        regiment, Partisan Rangers, pitched into Milroy's ordinance and baggage
                        train 5 miles below Moorefield, and captured 50 fine horses and harness, and
                        25 Yankees. He brought to camp 17 of the Yankees and 48 of the horses. This
                        feat was performed in broad day-light, in an open field, and in full sight
                        of the whole marching column of the enemy. The whole work was done in 10
                        minutes. Capt McNeill had but 37 men present. The enemy shelled them
                        furiously as they fled up the mountain side with their prisoners and booty.
                        The horses captured are very fine.</p>
                    <p>Capt. McNeill has performed several most daring exploits as a partisan leader
                        during the last three months.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item describes a raid by the Partisan Rangers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Subscribers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserts that subscribers are beginning to pay what they owe for the
                    paper but a few subscribers are delinquent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Price of Slaves</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We feel curious to know what the deluded people of the North think of the
                        present unprecedented high prices of slaves in the South. Just at the very
                        time when Lincoln declares that they are to be emancipated, they command
                        higher prices than ever before. Could anything demonstrate more
                        satisfactorily the futility of his infamous proclamation? The people of the
                        South never felt that the institution of slavery was ever safer than at the
                        present time. The futility of Lincoln's emancipation proclamation eclipses
                        that of the "Pope's bull against the comet," but differs in this, that the
                        Pope's bull against the comet exhibited no evil design, whilst Lincoln's
                        proclamation shows that he was impelled by a motive of a fiendish character.
                        The Pope was innocent of crime, Lincoln was not. The Pope was ignorant of
                        astronomy, Lincoln ignorant of Southern character. The Pope was a fool,
                        Lincoln both fool and knave.</p>
                    <p>The following prices were obtained at public auction on Saturday, the 27th
                        ult., in Greensville in this county, for 13 negroes belonging to the estates
                        of John Randolph and N. Torbett, dec'd:</p>
                    <p>A man aged 25 years, and defective, $1,500; man aged 21 years, $2,305; man
                        aged 45 years, $2,000; woman and child $1,500; girl, aged 14 years, $1,500;
                        man, aged 60 years, $1,615; man, defective, aged 35 years, $1,225; boy aged
                        13 years, $2,410; boy 12 years old, $1,605; woman 25 years old, $2,050;
                        woman, 45 years old, $1,700; man, defective, 85 years old, $1, 015.
                        Amounting to $21,865.</p>
                    <p>On the 1st of January, in this place, Bruce &amp; Peck Auctioneers, sold
                        eleven slaves, two of whom were small children, for the sum of
                        $13,915--averaging $1,265 each.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randolph</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Torbett</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Article asserts that slavery is safer than it has ever been and reports the
                    results of a slave auction in Greenville.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Testimonial to Lieut. Gen. Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It will be seen from the subjoined correspondence that the people of Augusta
                        have not been insensible to the signal services rendered to them by "Old
                        Stonewall." Surely no man ever more richly merited the testimonial which has
                        been so appropriately offered, and gracefully accepted. A few months ago,
                        our country was threatened from the west, and the north, with invasion and
                        spoliation by two hostile armies under Milroy and Banks. Their advance
                        guards were at our very borders, and a general feeling of insecurity
                        pervaded the community. In the midst of our apprehension, and when some of
                        our citizens had begun to remove their families and property, a significant
                        message was received from Gen. Jackson, urging our people to remain quiet,
                        that the enemy were <emph rend="italic">not yet</emph> in Augusta! </p>
                    <p>Within a few days after this message was received, Gen. Jackson, by a
                        brilliant strategic movement, fell unexpectedly on Milroy and routed him,
                        and while Banks was under the impression that the conquering hero had fled
                        to Gordonsville, he in turn attacked the two divisions of Banks' army under
                        Fremont and Shields at Cross Keys and Port Republic, and drove them
                        discomfited and demoralized from the Valley of Virginia; and the citizens of
                        Augusta were thus, by the brilliant strategy and unsurpassed valor of the
                        gallant Jackson, relieved from all apprehension of danger.</p>
                    <p>These signal services of General Jackson sunk deeply into the hearts of the
                        people of Augusta, and the testimonial which they have now tendered to him
                        is but a faint expression of their gratitude and admiration.</p>
                    <p>Lieut. Gen. Thomas J. Jackson: <lb/><emph rend="italic">Dear Sir.</emph>--On
                        behalf of a number of the citizens of Augusta county, we respectfully beg
                        your acceptance of the horse and equipments, which will be delivered to you
                        by the bearer of this note. </p>
                    <p>The people of Augusta are deeply sensible of the important services which you
                        have rendered to the country generally, and more especially to them, in
                        protecting their homesteads from desolation, and themselves and their
                        families from insult and oppression, and they now desire to tender you this
                        small testimonial of their gratitude and admiration.</p>
                    <p>That you may pass safely through the perils of the great contest for liberty
                        and independence in which we are now engaged, and be speedily restored to
                        the enjoyments of peaceful life, is our most earnest prayer.</p>
                    <p>Very respectfully, <lb/>Your friends and ob't serv'ts, <lb/>ALEX. H. H.
                        STUART, <lb/>SAM'L B. FINLEY, <lb/>S.P. THOMPSON, <lb/>JOHN N. HENDREN,
                        <lb/>WM. B. KAYSER. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item calls attention to correspondance from Augusta Co. residents lauding
                    the accomplishments of Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Lieut. Gen. Thomas J. Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Alex H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Copy of letter sent to Gen. Jackson thanking him for service to the state
                    of Virginia and giving him a gift of a horse and equipments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter from a soldier describes the conditions of camp life. Included in
                    the letter is an account of the battle at Fredrickburg and the death of Gen.
                    Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Milroy Rivaling Butler</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports Gen. Milroy's enforcement of loyalty to the U.S. in Western
                    Virginia. He is forcing citizens to take the oath of loyalty to the U.S. and the
                    state of West Virginia or else forfeit protection of their rights.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baird</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of Virginia Fuller.</summary>
                <note>Groom's name illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Absalom</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Golladay</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Etti</ln>
                        <fn>John Luther</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Deaths of Wright, Golladay, and Etti.</summary>
                <note>The Spectator no longer publishes article sized obits and merely lists the
                    deceaseds' names and few biographical details.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports of battles and skirmishes, icluding Murfreesboro. Telegraphic
                dispatches bearing national and international news items. Col. 7 ads and
            notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
