<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.05.26">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01.23.96</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton Spectator</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-05-26">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="05">May</month>
            <day>26</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.05.26.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Further Particulars of the Last Moments of Jackson - His Religious Character.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>Let us cross over the river and rest under the shade of the trees.</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item gives further information on Gen. Jackson's death.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Cols. 1 and 2 ads. Cols. 3 - 5 Governor's proclamations regarding the upcoming
                election. Page mostly light and illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.05.26.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Election Day</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A reminder the Thursday is election day.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Card</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In the Staunton <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> of May 8, 1863,
                        appeared an editorial notice of the recent expedition to North West
                        Virginia. The tone of the article was friendly and complimentary to Colonel
                        Asher W. Harman, of the 12th Virginia Cavalry, as was very natural and
                        proper coming from a relative and friend. In the Staunton <emph
                            rend="italic">Spectator</emph> of May 12, I published an extract from
                        this article with a brief editorial comment as follows: </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">"Beautiful Silver Set"</emph>--We saw a beautiful silver
                        set, which was captured and sent as a present to Mrs. Col. A. W.
                            Harman.--<emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph>. </p>
                    <p>We acknowledge that the above announcement contained in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> of last week surprised us. We had
                        supposed that everything captured by soldiers in the Confederate service
                        became the property of the Confederate States. Have we been mistaken in this
                            supposition?--<emph rend="italic">Spectator.</emph></p>
                    <p>To this inquiry thus suggested no reply has been made and no further notice
                        has been taken of the subject in either the Vindicator or Spectator.</p>
                    <p>On the 21st of May, soon after breakfast, I was upon the street, near the
                        Virginia Hotel, when I was approached by Col. Asher W. Harman, who stated
                        that he wished to have some conversation with me, and we stepped aside for
                        the purpose.</p>
                    <p>He stated to me that I had made an allusion to him in my paper which he
                        thought I had no right to make. I asked to what he referred, and he
                        mentioned the article about the silver service. I told him I was not aware
                        that I had said anything to which just exception could be taken; that I did
                        not know by whom the present had been made or upon what authority, and that
                        my inquiry gave fair opportunity for explanation, if the transaction was in
                        fact a proper one. I also stated that if he had cause of complaint against
                        any one it was against the Editor of the Vindicator by whom the matter was
                        first brought to public notice. To this he replied that the notice was an
                        act of youthful indiscretion on the part of Mr. Lynn, of which I had no
                        right to take advantage, in order to make "a party fling" at him.</p>
                    <p>He then went on to say that the conduct of military officers was not subject
                        to criticism and comment in the newspapers, and that he would not consent to
                        have his conduct discussed by them. I stated that I thought he took pretty
                        high ground, and he replied that he meant to maintain it, and that he wished
                        me to understand that if I took any notice whatever of him in my paper I
                        would "have to abide the consequences." I told him that such had always been
                        my understanding of my position as an Editor; and that I always regarded
                        myself as responsible for the conduct of my paper. I then went on to say
                        that it was always my rule and purpose to avoid giving just ground of
                        offence to any one, but that I could not consent to be influenced in my
                        course as an Editor by threats or intimidation; that I desired no
                        controversy with any one, but while endeavoring to do right I would always
                        hold myself responsible for my conduct. To this he replied that he wanted no
                        personal difficulty and that he did not desire to intimidate or to threaten
                        me, but that he wished to <emph rend="italic">warn</emph> me that if I made
                        the least allusion to him in my paper he was determined to kill me. I told
                        him I understood him perfectly, and that I wished him to understand me, that
                        my course in the conduct of my paper would not be in the slightest degree
                        influenced by anything he had said or might do. </p>
                    <p>I do not pretend to give the conversation in detail, but this is the
                        substance of it.</p>
                    <p>Supposing the interview to be at an end I turned and walked away. I had gone
                        perhaps eight or ten steps when he again confronted me and stated that he
                        wished to impress upon me distinctly that if I ever again alluded to him in
                        my paper, I must abide the consequences. I told him he had already told me
                        that several times and that I thought we had fully understood each other on
                        the subject; and I was again in the act of turning to leave him, when he
                        suddenly seized me by the beard with one hand and struck me with the other.
                        The joint effect of the jerk and the blow brought me to the ground--he
                        falling with me. He was greatly my superior in strength and I could only
                        endeavor by holding him close to me to avoid his doing me serious damage. In
                        this attempt I seized him around the neck with my left arm, when by a sudden
                        and violent effort he broke the arm above the elbow and strained the
                        shoulder joint. I was at once helpless and in his power, and he continued to
                        beat me until taken off of me by persons passing by.</p>
                    <p>The injuries I have received are such as to disable me from all business for
                        some time and to confine me to my room.</p>
                    <p>I do not know that any commentary upon such a transaction is necessary in a
                        community like this, but I wish to have some points connected with it
                        distinctly understood.</p>
                    <p>1. I claim the right as the Editor of a newspaper and as a free citizen to
                        make fair criticism and commentary upon the conduct of all public officers,
                        civil or military and I will never consent to give up this right or to hold
                        it in any respect at the will or by the forbearance of any man.</p>
                    <p>2. I hold myself at all times responsible for my conduct as an Editor or as a
                        citizen, and I do not intent to be beaten or bulled out of what I regard as
                        the line of duty and propriety. Violence may some time triumph over the
                        right, as it has done in this case, but I rely with confidence upon the
                        ultimate success of honest purposes and correct conduct.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spectator questions Col. Harman's gift of a captured silver set given
                    to his wife. The Editor recounts a conversation had with Col. Harman where
                    Harman criticized the Spectator for bringing this to public notice. The argument
                    ended in Col. Harman beating Mr. Mauzy senseless, breaking his arm.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Path of Duty</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article encourages citizens to vote as a matter of duty.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Case of Vallandigham</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article stresses the importance of the Vallandingham case.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Attorney for the Commonwealth</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports Harman's resignation from the office of Attorney for the
                    Commonwealth and his replacement by John Hendren.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>How Yankee Soldiers are Made to Vote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article alleges that soldiers are intimidated and punished for voting in
                    opposition to abolitionist policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Staunton Gas Works</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Jos. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Copy of a letter regarding the operation of the Staunton Gas Works.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Private Soldiers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item praises the contributions of the average enlisted men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Straughan</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of Jennie Straughan and Capt. Pennington of Hampshire Co.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>Lucretia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of James Bush and Lucretia Wright.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of John Mowry and Mary Susan Coiner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Susan Wilson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of William Ramsey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Willie Hobbs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Ira Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth Y.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hobbs</ln>
                        <fn>James O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Ira Hobbs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Thomas M. Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Hugh W. Sheffey</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>Hugh W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sheffey defends himself against charges of graft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Washington Chronicle</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article from a Northern paper praising the character of Stonewall Jackson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports. Col. 6 and 7 ads and notices, including
                previously tagged candidates' announcements. Previously tagged list of election
                officials col. 7.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
