<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.10.13">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/24/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/12/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-10-13">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>13</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote>No newspaper was published on 10/6/63.</editionNote>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.10.13.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details various bills, resolutions, and messages offered by an extra
                    session of the General Assembly. Included are measures to authorize the arrest
                    of deserters by civil authorities; a resolution declaring the state "incompetent
                    to alter their [slaves'] status, and the relation of master and slave, etc;"
                    bills providing for the relief of indigent soldiers, their widows, and their
                    minor children; the organization of cites, towns, and counties into military
                    districts for the purpose of dealing with military incursions; regulations
                    specifying the conditions for exemption from military service; and resolutions
                    "asserting the jurisdiction and sovereignty of the State of Virginia over her
                    ancient boundaries."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Present Condition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"A cause was never so more hopeless--never so desperate and impossible to
                    accomplish as that which they [the North] have so rashly undertaken, nor has
                    there been a time since the commencement of the war when the prospects of the
                    South were so bright and cheering as at this moment."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It is a curious fact that though the Yankees promise themselves an early
                        conquest of the South, and a speedy termination of the war, they are unable
                        at this time to show decided demonstrations of fight at but two point in the
                        Confederacy--Charleston and Chattanooga. They have just been whipped out of
                        Texas, been terribly defeated in Louisiana, are fully matched by the
                        indomitable Price in Arkansas, and are standing stock still before Lee in
                        Virginia! Even at Charleston, they and their approaches to the city
                        contested and ostructed [sic] at every point with no early prospect of
                        securing their much coveted prise [sic], and at Chattanooga the great army
                        of the Cumberland is beseiged [sic] and threatened with disaster by Bragg.
                        Really the Yankees must be the most hopeful or the most blinded and deluded
                        people on the earth, to anticipate the early conquest of the south, in the
                        light of such a condition of things as these facts present. A cause was
                        never more hopeless--never so desperate and impossible of accomplishment as
                        that which they have so rashly undertaken, nor has there been a time since
                        the commencement of the war, when the prospect of the South were so bright
                        and cheering as at this moment.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Despite recent setbacks, this encouraging article asserts that the North
                    has little cause for its optimism about a speedy end to the conflict.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The World In Trouble</head>
                <origin>The Savannah Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thus stand the men on the chess-board of the nations, and who can predict
                    the future? Fortunately for us, we are the only party likely to be benefitted by
                    the quarrels of others."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Casting a glance about the world, the author notes the widespread political
                    turmoil characteristic of the period and argues that these conflicts will
                    potentially benefit the Southern cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Green Corn Battle</head>
                <origin>"From a private letter of a soldier on the Rapidan."</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A somewhat humorous account of a battle between unarmed soldiers that
                    resulted from both sides attempting to gather corn from a field located between
                    the opposing armies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Gen. Bragg and His Generals</head>
                <origin>The Atlanta Register</origin>
                <commentary>"The Atlanta Register has the following relative to the disagreement
                    between General Bragg and the Generals under him:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"If Sunday's fight at Chickamauga had began, as Bragg had ordered, at
                    daylight nightfall would not have intervened to save Rosencrans' beaten army;
                    and he never could have reached and entrenched himself in Chattanooga."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recent arrest of Generals Polk and Hindman because of their "alleged
                    disobedience of or orders by the two Generals named, on Sunday the second day of
                    the battle of Chickamauga" is recounted and explored. While the author believes
                    that General Polk will be able to answer the charges satisfactorily, he argues
                    that Polk's failure to follow orders allowed the Northern forces to escape a
                    devastating defeat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Sycamore Balls</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Sycamore balls saturated in grease can provide a suitable source
                    of illumination and explains the correct procedure to follow to attain the
                    desired result.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Toothache Remedy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the beneficial potential of a mixture of chloroform and tannin in
                    treating a tooth ache.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>In addition to various legal announcements and commercial advertisements in
                columns 1-4, this page also contains two poems: "Not Lost Forever," and "Lines
                Accompanying Flowers." This page is partly illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.10.13.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Finances</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In our last issue we adverted [sic] to the present depreciated condition
                    of our currency, as being the question above all others save the failure of our
                    arms in the field most fraught with danger to our cause, and most urgently
                    demanding the serious consideration and prompt action of our Confederate and
                    States governments. The opinion expressed that the excess in the volume of the
                    currency, is the original and persistent cause of our financial difficulties,
                    will not likely meet with a single dissentient [sic] voice."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last issue, we adverted to the present depreciated condition of our
                        currency, as being the question above all others save the failure of our
                        arms in the field most fraught with danger to our cause, and most urgently
                        demanding the serious consideration and prompt action of our Confederate and
                        State governments. The opinion expressed that the excess in the volume of
                        the currency, is the original and persistent cause of our financial
                        difficulties, will not likely meet with a single dissentient [sic] voice.
                        That the depreciation in the value of the currency is attributable directly
                        to this cause alone, we do not think can be confidently asserted. We know
                        that those who write on the subject would fain [sic] attribute no importance
                        to the want of confidence of our people in the ultimate success of our
                        cause, for fear of fostering such a spirit by holding it up to the people as
                        an existent fact. But, although they are right in the assumption that the
                        people with great unanimity confidently believe in our final success, yet
                        the human mind is prone to view the events of the future as probabilities,
                        which seldom partake of the nature of what we term moral certainties. The
                        views of the future too, are altogether different according to the
                        intelligence and disposition of the individual, whether he be the sanguine
                        enthusiast, who can see already a people basking in the sunshine of
                        prosperity, and peace and plenty, or the poor dupe of his own dark fancies,
                        who sees the evidence of ruin, and desolation and starvation staring him in
                        the face at every turn. People will calculate chances, and though the cause
                        to which we refer has its effect in making men prefer real estate or
                        property of almost any kind to treasury notes or Confederate bonds, yet the
                        most prominent cause of the depreciation of those notes must be attributed
                        to their redundancy. But there is another cause of still greater moment and
                        which now, beforehand, exerts its baneful influence in its effect. The
                        people can't see how the Government is to pay its debts save by repudiation,
                        a word which is the embodiment of so monstrous a heresy in national morals
                        and national policy, that even before it shows its hideous form in the
                        noon-day sun as a national act, it exerts its influence for the production
                        of evil. But more of this anon.</p>
                    <p>There is, however, another cause of the depreciation of our currency which is
                        not often considered. It must be remembered that prior to the war the whole
                        South was literally flooded with products of Northern and European
                        manufactures, embracing the whole amount of its imports, and requiring a
                        certain volume of currency to effect the exchanges in their distribution to
                        the farther limits of the Confederacy. The staples of the South usually
                        exported to meet these demands exist at present stored away in its
                        warehouses, and are not changing hands as they do in times when their [sic]
                        is an outlet for them in foreign trade. It follows, that even if the volume
                        of the currency had remained the same as at the beginning of the war, it
                        would have depreciated in proportion to the excess it bore to the
                        necessities of trade under a system of blockade, and much more when the
                        volume was further increased by the issue of treasury notes. In addition to
                        this fact the first issues of these notes were distributed through the
                        States of Missouri, Arkansas, Kentucky, Tennessee, Louisiana, and in fine
                        all that portion of the Confederacy now partially or wholly in the hands of
                        the enemy. As in our defensive policy we gradually withdrew our forces from
                        these regions, the currency becoming useless was also contracted within
                        narrower limits for effecting the exchanges for a less amount of property
                        and fewer business transactions, where by its excess was made still more
                        manifest. We have thus adverted to the principal causes of the deplorable
                        financial condition into which the country has been plunged. That it
                        originated in bad policy when we were entering upon the war, will be
                        generally conceded. Instead of levying a tax sufficient to meet the expenses
                        of the Government in the very commencement of our struggle, for fear perhaps
                        of producing discontent amongst some portions of our people, or for other
                        reasons, we have incurred the responsibilities and dangers of a financial
                        system calculated to embarrass the wisest legislation. If an issue of
                        treasury notes had then become necessary, the Government had it in its power
                        to supply itself with an amount of specie at low rates sufficient to pay the
                        interest on a corresponding issue of its interest bearing bonds, which at
                        that time would have been in great demand at a much higher premium than any
                        other stocks in the market. From the sale of these bonds large profits would
                        have been realized, directly, owing to the high premium at which they would
                        have sold, and if the investments thus made had exceeded the issue of
                        treasury notes indirectly in the effect of the consequent check upon the
                        prices of those articles necessary to carry on the war. But a different
                        policy was adopted--The Government committed its first great blunder in
                        attempting to wage war upon a credit system simply, and that too of a kind
                        of credit which in expanding the volume of the currency gave origin to a
                        rise in prices, and consequently to an increased expenditure demanding a
                        still further issue of its notes. Thus at every increase of the circulation
                        the prices rising correspondingly, the issue of treasury notes and the
                        increase of expenditure became alternately causes and effect. No timely
                        legislation was afterwards adopted to arrest the progress of the evil, and
                        thus we find ourselves, when its deplorable consequences are becoming
                        intolerable, obliged to discuss the means by which successful [illegible]
                        may be applied.--The remedy we</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A long and thorough discussion of the state of the Confederate currency,
                    with special emphasis on the need to institute governmental regulations to
                    control the monetary supply.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lincoln President For Life</head>
                <origin>The New York Sunday Mercury</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The New York Sunday Mercury of the 30th ult., publishes a letter from a
                    Washington correspondent, who says it has been determined to postpone the next
                    Presidential election until after the suppression of the rebellion and the
                    restoration of the Union. The reason he assigns for this bold movement is, that
                    the Constitution requires ALL the States to vote, and that in the present
                    condition of the country it is impossible to comply with the requirement."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In discussing a recent report from a New York paper, the author alleges
                    that president Lincoln is preparing to institute a monarchy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Yankees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Of all people, they [the Yankees] are the most visionary in their modes of
                    thought, and the least acquainted with the real susceptibilities of nature, of
                    the abstract ideas of the human mind, or of the practicability of attempting to
                    make them assume a concrete form. "</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a searing analysis of "the Yankee mind" the author discovers a tendency
                    of "concreting [sic] the lying conceptions of their fertile brain." This
                    characteristic is tied to the widespread stereotype of the "Yankee trader" who
                    is capable of selling wooden nutmegs and paper-soled shoes. This tendency to
                    manipulate or ignore reality in quest of their self-interest is seen as the
                    basis of the argument attributed to the "Yankee" that "the negro is superior to
                    the white man, born with an undoubted capacity for self-government, capable of
                    the grand intellectual efforts of a Newton, moved by all the most aesthetic
                    principles of the most refined poets, and fit to sit as co-equals with the
                    Websters, the Clays, and the Calhouns."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The War</head>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Richmond Sentinel truthfully remarks that the skies are propitious now
                    in all directions. Lee is dogging Meade out of Virginia. Words of good cheer
                    come to us from across the Mississippi. In the United States, the monetary ague
                    continues. Chase with all his arts, cannot steady the nerves of Wall Street any
                    longer. Gold is right under the eaves of 150."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An buoyant analysis of the current state of the conflict, finding reason
                    for optimism in the current domestic and foreign state of affairs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Latest News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Meade is rapidly retreating from Virginia to Washington with
                    Lee in close pursuit.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Soldiers' Families</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the cause of the widespread desertion of Confederate troops is
                    concern with the impoverished state of their families back home. In an attempt
                    to correct this situation, the paper urges support for a measure recently
                    offered by Senator Seddon that would establish warehouses for the distribution
                    of provisions to soldiers' families.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sunday School Exhibition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that an art exhibit will be held at the Methodist Church with the
                    proceeds benefitting indigent children.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Evacuation of Norfolk</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Union forces have withdrawn from Norfolk.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Duties of Our People</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We had better give all our surplus grain and meat to feed the army, and
                    thus enable our gallant soldiers to drive back our enemies from our soil, than
                    to starve the army by withholding the necessities of life, for the purpose of
                    accumulating money, that will inevitably be swept away in the general ruin that
                    must follow our subjugation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We trust that our farmers to a man will concur in the action of the meeting
                        at September Court, and sell their produce to the government at schedule
                        prices. The producers in other portions of the State are coming up to the
                        work nobly. Surely, old Augusta will not suffer herself to lag behind in
                        this glorious cause. We had better give all our surplus grain and meat to
                        feed the army, and thus enable our gallant soldiers to drive back our
                        enemies from our soil, than to starve the army by withholding the
                        necessaries of life, for the purpose of accumulating money, that will
                        inevitably to swept away in the general ruin that must follow our
                        subjugation.</p>
                    <p>We understand there are many of our farmers who devote all their produce to
                        support the army and the families of soldiers; and their names deserve to be
                        inscribed high upon the roll of honor, when this cruel war is over. In
                        regard to them, we heartily concur in the suggestion of the Richmond <emph
                            rend="italic">Whig</emph>, that the history of transactions so
                        honorable, and so worthy of being preserved, should not be left to the
                        uncertain preservation of the newspapers. The County Courts should be
                        requested to have them entered upon their record book, with the names of all
                        who bind themselves to be governed by the resolutions adopted.--Let this be
                        done, and their descendants for generations to come will look back to these
                        records us their patent of nobility. </p>
                    <p>But we regret to say that there are others, abundantly able, who will furnish
                        the government nothing except what is worried out of them by impressment.
                        Shame! shame!! Let everybody cry shame upon the men who are found so sordid
                        in this hour of their country's peril, as to refuse their government the
                        necessary supplies, because speculators and extortioners will give them a
                        little more.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While acknowledging the worthwhile example of many Augusta County farmers
                    in placing patriotism above self-interest, the author also notes that others
                    have withheld needed foodstuffs in the desire to secure a higher price for their
                    produce.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Withdrawal of Mr. Mason</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short piece that reports on the decision to recall the Confederate agent
                    to England in acknowledgment of the failure to convince England to recognize the
                    Confederate States as an independent nation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Drafts for Slaves on Fortifications</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been requested by William A. Burnett, Deputy clerk, to give notice,
                        that a requisition from the Secretary of the Commonwealth has been filed in
                        the Clerk's office of Augusta County Court, for 80 male slaves, between the
                        ages of 18 and 55, for labor on fortification of Public defence; and that
                        all the acting justices of the County are requested to meet at the
                        Courthouse on Friday, the 16th day of the present month, (October) for the
                        purbose [sic] of making the levy for said slaves, as is required under the
                        act of the General Assembly passed March 13th, 1863. The term of Service
                        required is 60 days, and it is desirable to have a majority of the justices
                        present to make the draft forthwith, as winter is approaching, and it will
                        be better to send the negroes immediately.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Upon the request of William A. Burnett, deputy clerk of Augusta County, the
                    paper notifies the public that a request has been made for the requisition of 80
                    male slaves to labor on fortifications of public defense for a term of sixty
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Magruder's Victory at Sabine Pass</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on the recent military victory of General Magruder at Sabine Pass
                    that resulted in the capture of two gunboats, 15 heavy guns, and over 200
                    prisoners without any loss to his own forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Governor Letcher has decided that persons currently holding
                    commissions in the militia are to be placed under the authority of the Conscript
                    Bureau.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Degenerate Son</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It has been discovered that Major General Thomas of the Union Army, who
                    distinguished himself at Chickamauga, is a native of Southhampton County,
                    Virginia. The article notes that Gen. Thomas's relatives in Virginia are deeply
                    pained by his actions, and the author opines that "[t]he man must have a soft
                    place in his head."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Traitor Caught</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Mosby's men recently apprehended Daniel F. Dulaney, colonel and
                    aid to Governor Pierpont. The article reports that when captured Dulaney was "in
                    a state of inebriation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Good Opening</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short filler piece that alerts ambitious readers to the need for scissor
                    grinders. It is believed that "[a]n enterprising man with a portable grindstone,
                    can accumulate a fortune in a year by going the rounds."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A "Double" Wedding</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Though war rages, and empires tremble beneath the shock of fierce
                    encounter, yet Cupid, as of old, still holds the bow and hurls with unerring aim
                    the dart of love at the hearts of gay youths and fair maidens."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Latane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armentrout</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cone</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A lengthy description of the recent double wedding that saw Mr. George M.
                    Baker of Winchester wed to Miss Fannie E. Armentrout of Staunton, and Mr.
                    Augustus A. Cone of Baltimore City wed to Miss Kate Fletcher of Winchester. The
                    services were officiated by Rev. Latane.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Men and Arms Furnished By Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent communication to the House of Delegates by the governor details
                    the contribution of men and arms to the Southern cause. According to the
                    governor, Virginia has supplied over 100,000 men and well over 10,000 arms to
                    the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>No Good Action Ever Lost</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While noting that the brave deeds of the common soldier are often lost to
                    history and unappreciated by future generations, the author assures the soldier
                    that his "deeds of patriotic valor can never die."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Our Worst Enemies</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The worst enemies of the South this moment are the heartless beings within
                        her own borders, who are withholding the means of existence from her people,
                        and charging such exhorbitant [sic] prices for the necessaries of life that
                        not only the poor, but the great mass of the community must starve and
                        freeze. What spectacles of horror must be witnessed this winter if these
                        adversaries of the country and of humanity itself cannot be reached either
                        by the laws or the melting appeals of the wretched and despairing! Thus far
                        al means of inducing them to have pity upon their fellow men have failed.
                        The time may come when that mercy they have denied others will be denied to
                        themselves.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A warning to those who are hoarding goods and charging "exorbitant prices
                    for the necessities of life" that a "time may come when that mercy they have
                    denied others will be denied themselves."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Sensible Colored Folks</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Petersburg Express is informed by Lieut. Daniels, who has just arrived at
                        Petersburg from Fort Norfolk, that some 35 or 40 Southern negroes, captured
                        at Gettysburg, are confined at Fort McHenry. He says that they profess an
                        undying attachment to the South. Several times Gen. Schenck has offered to
                        release them from the Fort, if they would take the oath of allegiance to the
                        Federal Government and join the Lincoln army. They had peremptorily refused
                        in every instance, and claim that they should be restored to their masters
                        and homes in the South. They say they would prefer death to liberty on the
                        terms proposed by Schneck.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to an account by a Lieut. Daniels, between thirty-five or forty
                    Southern blacks captured at the Battle of Gettysburg by Northern forces are
                    being held at Fort McHenry. While they have been offered release from their
                    confinement if they would "take an oath of allegiance to the Federal Government
                    and join the Lincoln army," the prisoners have refused the offer and have
                    instead insisted that they should "be restored to their masters and homes in the
                    South."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short comment that complains about the complacency of the "red-faced
                    braggart and speculator" who continues to urge a continuation of the war, and
                    thereby benefits financially, while ignoring the "woe and misery incident to
                    even a small skirmish, much less a heavy battle."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Ancient Lessons</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In looking over a religious paper a few days since, we were struck with an
                        article entitled "Lessons from Jewish History," which contained some things
                        applicable to our times. We give a brief extract:</p>
                    <p>"A wedge of gold concealed in the camp of Acham defeated the army of Israel.
                        This ungodly greed of gain led them anciently, in selling their corn and
                        wheat to make the ephah <emph rend="italic">small</emph> and the shekel
                            <emph rend="italic">great</emph> and falsify the balance by deceit."
                        That is, they lessened the measure and increased the price. This was one of
                        the great sins that destroyed that nation--the sin of dishonesty. </p>
                    <p>Are not our people doing the same thing upon a most fearful scale? And is
                        this a sin less offensive to God now than it was then? Unless this spirit is
                        averted it will work its own cure by superinducing desertions from our army
                        and turning loose a lawless mob at home that will take summary vengeance
                        upon the authors of their suffering.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author finds in an account of "Jewish History" that greed rather than
                    enemy forces defeated the Israel army. He warns that the same situation is
                    currently facing the Confederate States and that "[u]nless this spirit is
                    adverted it will work its own cure by superinducing desertions from our army and
                    turning loose a lawless mob at home that will take summary vengeance upon the
                    authors of their suffering."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A brief account of the decision by Judge Summers from Kanawha Valley to
                    throw his support behind the "Lincoln and Pierpont Government" by announcing his
                    candidacy for the U.S. Congress. The author expresses remorse that someone of
                    such gifts could fall prey to more base concerns such as avarice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Substitute For Butter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Given the high cost of butter, the author offers this substitute: "Marry
                    the nicest girl you know. You will than have her to preside at your table, and,
                    unless you are a sad dog indeed, you will not require any but her!"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Greenbrier Mirage</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A lady in Monroe co. furnishes the following explanation of the phenomenon
                        recently witnessed in Greenbrier.</p>
                    <p>It is well known that an army of Yankees, several thousand in number, have an
                        ecampment [sic] at Fayette Court House, in the county of Fayette, which
                        adjoins Greenbrier county. At the very hour mentioned, namely, three
                        o'clock, P.M., they are daily subjected to a drill, in which they go through
                        all their various military exercises. Is it not probable, &amp; more
                        than probable that these serial soldiers were produced by the same cause
                        which produce the spectre [sic] of the Brocken, and other similar
                        apparitions? That owing to the accidental condensation of some atmospheric
                        vapors at the precise time they were drilling, on the evening particularly
                        specified--an atmospherical speculum was formed by the hand of nature in the
                        mountainous locality of Mr. Piercy's residence, and that the figures seen by
                        Mr. P's family were the images of this body of Yankees, who were then
                        marching in regular order, and reflected in the air in their natural color
                        and forms.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In response to recent articles about a strange apparition witnessed in
                    Greenbrier County, one reader offers a possible explanation consistent with
                    science and reason. She argues that military exercises being practiced by Union
                    troops encamped at the Fayette Court House and special atmospheric conditions
                    caused "an atmospherical speculum [to be] formed by the hand of nature in the
                    mountainous locality of Mr. Piercy's residence, and that the figures seen by Mr.
                    P's family were the images of this body of Yankees, who were then marching in
                    regular order, and reflected in the air in their natural color and forms."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Reinforcements For Rosencrans</head>
                <origin>Chicago Evening Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Based on information gathered by a correspondent of a Chicago paper, it is
                    believed that Union troops are being sent westward to reinforce Union efforts in
                    that theater of war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Siege Of Charleston</head>
                <origin>Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The situation in Charleston appears to remain stalemated with the residents
                    attempting to create new fortifications and the Union fleet anchored offshore.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Ephraim</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetze</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the marriage, on October 1, 1863, of Mr. Ephraim Ryan to Miss
                    Sarah Bowers at the residence of Rev. H. Wetze. All the participants are from
                    Shenandoah County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Kasper B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herron</ln>
                        <fn>Julia F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the marriage of Mr. Kasper B. Koiner to Miss Julia F. Herron,
                    both of Augusta County, on the 28th of September. The services were held at the
                    residence of the bride's father and the services were conducted by Rev. R.
                    Smith.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fitch</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Noting the death of Peter Fitch in his seventy-fifth year of life, this
                    obituary assures the reader that "Having been a quiet, unassuming man, a good
                    citizen, and a faithful friend, he passed from earth in peace to his reward in
                    Heaven, where he rests from his labors and his works do follow him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mann</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Elizabeth Mann died at Oakland on July 2, 1863 at age 28.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements and announcements, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
