<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.11.10">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>09/08/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/11/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-11-10">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>10</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.11.10.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>5, 6, 7</column>
                <head>A Plan Of Financial Relief-Letter From A. H. H. Stuart</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The radical error was attempting to carry on a grand revolution without
                    taxation, by treasury notes exclusively."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Alexander Stuart reflects on the problems of the Confederate economy, in
                    particular the devaluation of the currency and the inflation of prices. He sees
                    the primary obstacle in dealing with the economic crisis being the inability to
                    coordinate the policies of all the states of the Confederacy. In order to aid
                    the economy, Stuart advocates a national program that will include the following
                    steps: 1. stop issuing new treasury notes; 2. retire one-half to two-thirds of
                    the present issue; 3. enact a specific export duty on all the productions of
                    field and forest to pay the interest and principal of the debt; 4. obtain funds
                    through the sale of bonds, not by the issue of treasury notes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Acts Passed By The Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An article that lists the fourteen acts passed into law by the legislature
                    during the previous session.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Diphtheria</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Its most manifest symptom is a false membrane, of a white color, which
                    forms upon and around the tonsils, near the palate, and which thickens and
                    extends unless checked, until the patient dies from suffocation."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A physician describes the symptoms and treatment of diphtheria. The paper
                    urges readers to cut this article out and keep it ready for a time of need.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>This page also contains a poem, and various advertisements and legal notices.
                Part of the page is illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.11.10.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary>"The famous and immortal 'Stonewall Brigade' had just been relieved from
                    picket by Hayes Brigade. If the enemy had succeeded in capturing that Brigade
                    the Yankees would have burst every cannon and broken every bell in Yankeedom in
                    ringing bells and firing cannon in honor of the event."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the state of various theaters of conflict. In Tennessee, it
                    appears the Union forces are on the move, and a large battle is expected in
                    Lookout Valley. In Virginia, a number of smaller engagements have taken place
                    with mixed results.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Grain Distilled</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Clarifying an earlier editorial, the Spectator reports that a local
                    distillery is actually consuming thirty bushels of grain a day, rather than the
                    one hundred bushels reported.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Legislature--Good Bills</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The statement we made last week that the Legislature had not passed any bill
                        of general importance save the repeal of a law of the previous session in
                        reference to the currency, did not do full justice to that body of Solons,
                        for they did pass three very good bills besides the one to which reference
                        was made, to wit: The bill against gambling; the bill for the support of the
                        indigent families of those in the military and naval service, and the bill
                        prohibiting the consumption of grain by distillers and other manufacturers
                        of spirituous and malt liquors. The following is an extract from the last
                        bill mentioned:</p>
                    <p>"It shall not be lawful for any person hereafter to make, or cause to be
                        made, any Whiskey, or other Spirituous or Malt Liquors, out of any Corn,
                        Wheat, Rye, or other grain, or out of dried Fruit, Potatoes, Sugar, Cane,
                        Molasses Cane, or Sorghum; and any person so offending shall be deemed
                        guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined for
                        every offence not less than one hundred dollars, nor more than five thousand
                        dollars, and be subject to imprisonment in the county jail, not exceeding
                        twelve months at the discretion of the court.</p>
                    <p>No person, firm or company shall execute, in whole or in part, any contract
                        heretofore or hereafter made with the Confederate Government, or with any
                        agent of said Government, for making, or causing to be made, any Whiskey or
                        ardent spirits within this State; and all such contractors who shall violate
                        this section shall be deemed subject to all the penalties imposed by this
                        and other acts against unlawful distillation."</p>
                    <p>It will be observed that persons are not only prohibited <emph rend="italic"
                            >hereafter</emph> to make, or cause to be made, any whiskey, or other
                        spirituous and malt liquors, out of any corn, wheat, rye or other grain, or
                        out of dried fruit, potatoes, sugar, molasses, sugar cane, molasses cane or
                        sorghum, but that they are prohibited to <emph rend="italic">execute</emph>,
                        in whole or in part, any contract <emph rend="italic">heretofore</emph>, or
                        hereafter, made with the Confederate Government, or with any agent of said
                        Government, for making, or causing to be made, any whiskey or other ardent
                        spirits within this State; and any person so offending shall be fined, for
                        every offence, not less than $100, nor more than $5000, and be subject to
                        imprisonment in the county jail, not exceeding twelve months, at the
                        discretion of the court. </p>
                    <p>Some persons erroneously suppose that this law violates that provision of the
                        constitution which prohibits the enactment of any law "impairing the
                        obligation of contracts." This law does not impair the "obligation of
                        contracts," but merely prohibits the <emph rend="italic">execution</emph> of
                        certain contracts within this State. The validity of the contracts is not
                        destroyed, but the execution of them, in this State, is prohibited. The
                        contractors may execute them in another State.--This law does not relieve
                        either of the contracting parties from any obligations imposed by their
                        contracts. The Legislature is competent to pass such a law, or else this
                        State has no power to protect itself. The Confederate Government might else
                        have all the grain of the State distilled into whiskey, and the citizens of
                        the State be left to starve. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While an earlier article argued that the previous legislative session
                    hadn't passed any bills of importance, this article asserts that in fact three
                    worthwhile bills were passed. These include measures to provide for the support
                    of the indigent families of servicemen; the outlawing of gambling; and a measure
                    to prohibit the production of spirituous and malt liquors. The bulk of the
                    article is a defense of the last measure against charges that it represents an
                    unconstitutional measure violating the prohibition against any law "impairing
                    the obligation of contracts."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Mr. Stuart's Financial Scheme</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While declaring themselves insufficiently knowledgeable to judge the merit
                    of Mr. Stuart's financial plan (printed on page one), the Spectator urges the
                    General Assembly to consider the measures recommended and, if deemed beneficial,
                    to adopt the plan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Dr. Rucker's Escape Through Allegheny</head>
                <origin>The Fincastle Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides further details on the escape of Dr. Rucker. This report describes
                    his narrow escape from authorities outside Covington. At the present time, it is
                    not known if he has managed to reach the enemy lines.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Aiding and Abetting Deserters</head>
                <origin>Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>For the past three days the Confederate States District Court, Judge
                        Halyburton presiding, has been engaged in the examination of ten men, from
                        Rockingham county, charged with aiding and abetting and piloting deserters
                        from the Confederate army to the Yankee lines.--These men, known
                        respectively as Geo. Yates, Samuel Wheelbarger, George Cooper, David Cooper,
                        (father and son) George W. Ramsey, George Hume, Samuel Boman, William
                        Coffman, John D. Keiser and Rev. Wm. Dunlap, have long been suspected, but
                        have hitherto managed to elude the vigilance of the authorities.</p>
                    <p>At the commencement of the investigation a message was received from the
                        Secretary of War, stating that the parties were subject and ought to be
                        tried by military authority.</p>
                    <p>To this the counsel for the prisoners objected, alleging that they were
                        citizens, and were, therefore, subject to only jury trial.</p>
                    <p>The evidence elicited, showed that the prisoners had been guilty of harboring
                        Confederate deserters, and that they had used language that showed their
                        antagonism to the Southern Confederacy and in favor of the Yankee
                        Government.</p>
                    <p>The Judge, yesterday, after hearing the evidence in the case, decided that
                        the offence was not committed within his district, and consequently
                        discharged the prisoners.</p>
                    <p>Commissioner Watson then had them arrested, and they will be sent to Staunton
                        for trial. <lb/>--<emph rend="italic">Enquirer</emph></p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ten men from Rockingham County were arrested on charges of aiding and
                    abetting deserters. After three days of deliberation, Judge Halyburton of the
                    Confederate State District Court determined that the offense was not committed
                    in his district, and he ordered the prisoners discharged. The men were then
                    arrested and transported to Staunton for trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Working Well</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Within three hours after the reception of the order upwards of fifty men
                    in one regiment alone had fastened their clutches upon delinquents at home, and
                    had written to their relations to adopt measures for their immediate transfer to
                    the army."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent measure that provides every non-commissioned officer and soldier
                    with a furlough of not less than forty days if he secures a recruit and causes
                    him to be mustered into the army has been a success.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>General Morgan</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He fought sixty-three battles and has been successful in fifty-seven; took
                    50,000,000 worth of property, taken 50,000 stand of small arms and fifty pieces
                    of artillery, 20,000 horses, and traveled 12,000 miles."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recounting of the exploits of General Morgan during his career.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Lincoln And Mexico</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Lincoln has positively expressed his intention not to take any action upon
                    the French occupation of Mexico until the 'home troubles' in which he is now
                    involved are finally concluded."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>During a recent interview with a representative of a South American
                    republic, President Lincoln conveyed his reluctance to intervene in Mexico until
                    the war is concluded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Confederate States A Nation</head>
                <origin>The Mercury</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent decision by the French judicial tribunal recognized the Northern
                    states and the Southern states as "two nations in a state of war."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>France and Russia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Prince Maximilian has decided to accept the Mexican throne
                    despite rumors from Europe to the contrary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>American Affairs In Europe</head>
                <origin>The London Times</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A recent editorial in the London Times asserts that an analysis of the
                    latest intelligence indicates "no progress whatever on the part of the North."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short piece noting that the women of Georgia have contributed 11,818
                    pairs of socks for the soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>General Bragg</head>
                <origin>The Richmond Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"On the contrary, all the accounts concur in representing the officer as
                    having acted in the most disinterested and patriotic spirit; as having implored
                    the President to make any change which he might suppose likely to advance the
                    public interests, assuring him that so far as his own personal feelings and
                    wishes were concerned, it would be a pleasing relief to be divested of his great
                    responsibilities."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of President Davis's decision not to replace General Bragg of
                    his command. It is noted that when the President visited the general, Bragg's
                    behavior was exemplary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Well-Timed Advice</head>
                <origin>The Augusta Chronicle and Sentinel</origin>
                <commentary>"The Augusta Chronicle and Sentinel says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Individuals should live upon less expensive food, wear less costly
                    raiment, and the corporations of cities and towns should abolish the superfluous
                    avocations that grow and flourish during the 'canker of a long peace.' This is
                    our only safety. Individuals must not be slow to make sacrifices suited to the
                    times. Families, although reared in the lap of luxury, must curb their desires.
                    Ladies must eschew fashions, and gentlemen their expensive habits. We must all
                    economize, if we would win our freedom."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls for self-sacrifice in support of the soldiers and the cause to which
                    they are committed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Gigantic Campaign</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A correspondent associated with Bragg's army predicts a battle in Tennessee
                    and Kentucky that will dwarf earlier engagements and will compare with the
                    complexity of Napoleon's most ambitious efforts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>President Davis, General Bragg, and General Polk</head>
                <origin>The Montgomery Advertiser</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Advertiser reports that President Davis disagrees with General Bragg's
                    decision to arrest General Polk. Davis would prefer that Polk return to the army
                    of Tennessee. However, General Polk does not want to assume that command and
                    desires a full investigation of the charges brought against him.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Brutal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is alleged that the "Yankee commander at Murfreesboro, Tennessee" has
                    issued orders prohibiting the grinding of any grain for the wives and families
                    of those who are enlisted in the Southern forces. Those violating this
                    prohibition are subject to confiscation of their property, while the offender
                    faces capital punishment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the relish with which Northern papers report the escalating cost
                    of food in the Confederacy, but reminds readers that the British did the same
                    and yet failed in their attempt to subjugate the colonists.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Simeon E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawpe</ln>
                        <fn>Adam M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces the marriage of Mr. Simeon E. Miller, of Barnwell, S. C., and
                    Miss Maggie A. S. Hawpe. Miss Hawpe is daughter of Mr. Adam M. Hawpe of Augusta
                    County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. George W. Marshall died on October 3, 1863 at the residence of his
                    father in his 26th year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>$250 Reward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Advertisement for a runaway slave named Osbert who was owned by Thomas
                    Reeves of Mt. Solon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also various legal announcements and advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
