<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.07.28">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>06/09/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/6/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-07-28">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.07.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Mother's Last Sacrifice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A poem about loss and sacrifice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Pickett's Division</head>
                <origin>The Richmond Enquirer</origin>
                <commentary>"We extract the following from a communication in the <emph
                        rend="italic">Richmond Enquirer</emph>:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>General Pickett receives the order to charge those batteries at the opportune
                        moment. The cannonade still goes on with intense fury; our batteries are
                        handled with great skill. This battery and that limbers up, advance to the
                        front, wheel into action, and again the roar of cannon becomes deafening.
                        Our shells seem robust with terrible accuracy; now a caisson of the enemy's
                        is blown up--quickly another follows; their fire slackens; the order comes
                        in advance. That flag which waved amid the wild temptest [sic] of battle at
                        Gaine's Mill, at Frazer's Farm, and at Manassas, never rose more proudly.
                        Kemper, with as gallant men as ever trod beneath that flag, leads the right;
                        Garnett, with his heroes, brings up the left; and the veteran Armistead,
                        with his brave troops, moves forward in support. The distance is more than
                        half a mile. As they advance the enemy fire with great rapidity--shell and
                        solid shot give place to grape and cannister--the very earth quivers beneath
                        the heavy roar--wide gaps are made in this regiment, and that brigade; yet
                        they quickly close up and steadily move onward--that flag goes down; but see
                        how quickly it again mounts upward! borne by some gallant man, who feels
                        keenly the honor of his old commonwealth, in this hour which is to test her
                        manhood. The line moves onward--straight onward; cannons roaring, grape and
                        canister plunging and ploughing through the ranks; bullets whizzing as thick
                        as ballstones in winter, and men falling as leaves fail when shaken by the
                        blasts of autumn. In a double-quick, and with a shout which rises above the
                        roar of battle, they charge--now they pour in volleys of musketry--they
                        reach the works--the contest rages with intense fury--men fight almost hand
                        to hand--the red cross and gridiron wave defiantly in close proximity--the
                        enemy are slowly yielding--a Federal officer dashing forward in front of his
                        shrinking columns, and with flashing sword, urges them to stand. Gen.
                        Pickett, seeing the splendid, valor of his troops, moves among them as if
                        courting death by his own daring intrepidity. The noble Garnett is dead,
                        Armistead wounded--and the brave Kemper, with hat in hand, still cheering on
                        his men, falls from his horse into the ranks of the enemy--his men rush
                        forward, rescue their General, and he is borne mortally wounded from the
                        field. Where is the gallant Williams? The First is there, but his clear
                        voice is no longer heard--he has fallen lifeless, and there goes his horse,
                        now riderless. There stand the decimated ranks of the Third; and Mayo,
                        though struck stands firm with his faithful men, animating them to yet more
                        daring deeds; but Calcott, the Christian soldier, who stood unmoved amid
                        this carnival of death, has fought his last battle; no sound shall awake him
                        to glory again, till the summons of the Great Judge, announcing to him the
                        reward of the faithful soldier, who has fought the good fight. Patton, Otey,
                        and Tery, who but a moment since, stood at the head of their respective
                        regiments, are wounded. The brave Hunton here of Leesburg, most worthy
                        successor of the noble Garnett, Stewart, and Galt, lies wounded. Carrington,
                        his gallant regiment shattered, stands firmly, flaunting defiantly his
                        colors in the very face of the enemy. Allen and Ellis killed. Hodges, too,
                        has fallen; and the modest, chivalrous Edmunds lies numbered with with [sic]
                        the noble dead; Aylett wounded, and Magruder has gone down in the shock of
                        battle.--The fight goes on--but few are left, and the shrinking columns of
                        the enemy gain confidence from the heavy reinforcements advanced to their
                        support. They, too, are moving in large force on the right flank. This
                        division, small at first, with ranks now torn and shattered, most of its
                        officers killed or wounded, no valor able to rescue victory from such a
                        grasp, annihilation or capture inevitable, slowly, reluctantly fell back. It
                        was not given to these few remaining brave men to accomplish human
                        impossibilities. The enemy dared not follow them beyond their works.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Romantic account of Pickett's Charge: "...bullets whizzing as thick as
                    hailstones in winter, men falling as leaves fall when shaken by the blasts of
                    autumn."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Charge of Pickett's Division</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A gentleman, in whose every word reliance may be placed, and who
                    witnessed the desperate struggle he describes, furnishes the following account:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                    <p>It is due to General Pickett and his division that the country should know
                        and properly appreciate the service rendered by them in the terrible action
                        of the 3d of July.</p>
                    <p>The day preceding, the division had made a long and toilsome march. At 8
                        o'clock of the 3d, they moved forward to the field of battle, and were in
                        position very early on the morning of that event... day. During a
                        considerable portion of the forenoon, the division were exposed to the
                        burning rays of a July sun and the terrible shelling from the enemy's
                        batteries. They very much exhausted by the intense heat, and seriously
                        crippled by the enemy's fire; about 8 o'clock they were ordered to charge
                        the heights. An eye witness testifies that they formed into line of battle
                        as coolly and deliberately as if forming for dress parade. Headed by their
                        gallant officers, the column being led by General Pickett himself, they
                        moved forward to the carnage across a plain, some 500 yards in width,
                        subjected to the action of guns smoking like a hurricane of death all over
                        the field.</p>
                    <p>The noble and gallant Pickett, commanding then pressed up to the ugly
                        ramparts of the enemy. It is believed that a more gallant and heroic charge
                        was never made on this continent.--Pickett's division has been in the
                        hardest fighting of this bloody war. The division have borne themselves well
                        and nobly, always and everywhere. But the crowning glory of those patriot
                        heroes was achieved in the assault upon the ironclad crest of Gettysburg.
                        The list of casualties tells, in terms of truer eloquence, the bravery and
                        patriotism of that blood-stained and self-honored division, than can any
                        figures of rhetoric or poetry. Every Brigadier fell, and a long catalogue of
                        Colonels and other officers. The division went in from five to six thousand
                        strong. Three days after the battle but fifteen hundred reported for duty.
                        Well done, noble heroes, officers and men; your country will cherish the
                        memory of your deeds and sufferings with a gratitude and affection which
                        time can never obliterate. Major General Pickett has well earned, and will
                        no doubt receive the meed [sic] of his country's praise. Without meaning to
                        disparage any other officer or division, it is, indeed, a high honor to have
                        belonged to Pickett's division and to have fought under that gallant
                        commander.</p>
                    <p>T. P.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A somewhat less colorful version of Pickett's Charge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>General Ewell Struck In The Battle Of Gettysburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts General Ewell's injury and courage at the Battle of Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.07.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that the Confederacy lost ten generals and twenty-three thousand men
                    at the fall of Vicksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An excerpt from an address by Hon. C. L. Vallandigham: "It is vain to
                    invite the states and people of the South to return to a union without a
                    Constitution, and dishonored and polluted by repeated and most aggravated
                    exactions of tyrannic power--it is base in yourselves, and treasonable to your
                    posterity, these liberties and rights to the creatures whom your own breath
                    created and can destroy."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Yankees have been committing considerable depredations in North Carolina
                        recently, in the way of stealing negroes and destroying property. The poor
                        negroes when taken are either put into the army, where they are killed by
                        Southern soldiers in the field of battle, or sent North where they are
                        killed by Yankee rioters. The best and safest place for the negro is in the
                        South with his master, where he is fed and clothes, and has nothing to dread
                        from Northern or Southern soldiers.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Complains about the depredations by Northern troops in North Carolina, who
                    have been stealing slaves and destroying property. The Spectator notes that "The
                    poor negroes when taken are either put into the army, where they are killed by
                    Southern soldiers in the field of battle, or sent north where they are killed by
                    Yankee rioters."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sixty-Second Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Partially details the casualties of the Sixty-Second Virginia regiment at
                    the battle of Williamsport (Company H).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Gen. Lee's Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of the sacrifice and tribulation of General Lee's army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From General Johnston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of the surrender of Jackson, Mississippi and General Grant's
                    move to Vicksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Charleston</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of a "spirited engagement" at Charleston, South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Cavalry Fight</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An account of a cavalry engagement outside Shepherdstown.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Huntsville, Ala.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Account of General Turchin's occupation of Huntsville, Alabama. "He it was
                    who turned loose his men upon the people of Athens, Ala., telling them, 'I shut
                    mine eyes for one hour,' and on being told by them that one hour was not enough
                    to gratify their pillaging proclivities, replied, 'I shut mine eyes for two
                    hours.'"</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The New York Riot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The fierce spirit of the rioters of New York has been lulled to sleep by the
                        appropriation of $2,500,000 to purchase the exemptions of those drafted, and
                        the treacherous promise of the authorities that the draft would be suspended
                        in the city. This fierce spirit of resistance to the draft is not dead, but
                        only sleepeth, and will, we opine, in a short time, manifest itself in a
                        more furious and terrible manner. They may be willing to see the
                        administration practicing treachery towards us, but we suppose that they
                        will not submit to have the same dishonorable game practiced upon
                        themselves. Col. Nugent, Acting Assistant Provost Marshal General, announced
                        that the draft was suspended in the cities of New York and Brooklyn. After
                        which Governor Seymour pledged his word that the draft should be suspended.
                        After the rioters became convinced of their triumph in defeating the
                        execution of the draft, they dispersed, became quiet and returned to their
                        homes and avocations. As soon as the rioters had been thus lulled into false
                        repose, the following order was issued from Washington:</p>
                    <p>WAR DEPARTMENT, <lb/>Provost Marshal General's Office, <lb/>Washington, July
                        17, 1863 </p>
                    <p>The operations of the draft lately ordered in the New England and Middle
                        States, though in most instances completed, or now in progress without
                        opposition, have in one or two cites been temporarily interrupted.</p>
                    <p>The Provost Marshals are informed that no orders have been issued
                        countermanding the draft.</p>
                    <p>Adequate force has been ordered by the Government to the points where the
                        proceedings have been interrupted.</p>
                    <p>Provost Marshals will be sustained by the military forces of the country in
                        enforcing the draft, in accordance with the laws of the United States, and
                        will proceed to execute the laws heretofore given for the draft as rapidly
                        as shall be practicable, by aid of the military force ordered to cooperate
                        with and protect them.</p>
                    <p>JAS. B. FRY, <lb/>Provost Marshal General. </p>
                    <p>The surprise and indignation which would be naturally excited in the bosoms
                        of the rioters by this order can be readily imagined. Governor Seymour
                        promised that the Constitutionality of the draft should be tested in the
                        civil courts of the State. If the draft shall be executed in spite of these
                        fair promises on the part of Seymour, and in violation of the announcement
                        made by Colonel Nugent, these people will arise with redoubled fury in
                        opposition to its execution, and their example will be followed in various
                        parts of the North. The draft will be of no benefit to Lincoln, but may be
                        of immense value to us.</p>
                    <p>Before the riot was over the New York Herald reported the casualties as
                        follows: Negroes killed and wounded, 150; policemen, 32; men, women and
                        children, 35;--total, 218.</p>
                    <p>On the 21st, the 19th ward station House, burned during the riot, fell upon a
                        number of people, mostly children, picking wood and coal from the ruins.</p>
                    <p>Twenty-five to forty people buried in the ruins.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the aftermath of the New York riots. Authorities initially
                    promised to suspend the draft in New York City and Brooklyn, but they
                    subsequently retracted that order. The article predicts further uprisings and
                    enumerates the casualties as follows: "Negroes, killed and wounded, 150;
                    policemen, 32; men, women, and children, 35;--total 218."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>** National Politics</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Death of Brigadier-General Armistead</head>
                <origin>The Philadelphia Inquirer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notice of Brigadier-General Armistead's death as a result of wounds
                    suffered at Gettysburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Florida at Work</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts the exploits of the ship The Florida off Bermuda.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Yankee Plunder</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Expresses satisfaction that there are "nine thousand head of very fine
                    cattle of every description, taken from the Dutch farmers of Pennsylvania"
                    grazing in the Valley. The paper also adds the reflection that "The Dutch
                    Yankees begin to see the War doesn't pay."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Conscription</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The late proclamation of the President, in relation to Conscripts, refers
                        only to those persons between the ages of forty and forty-five years of age;
                        and to conscripts between the ages of eighteen and forty who have not been
                        exempted heretofore, either in consequence of physical disability or other
                        causes. All persons who have been examined by a military board, or have been
                        exempted by the enrolling officer, are not called upon to report
                    themselves.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Explains the President's latest proclamation on conscripts to the readers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Yankee Raid Upon Wytheville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A long account of a raid in southwestern Virginia that resulted in the
                    repulsion of a "Yankee" attack by the Confederate forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Murder of Two Confederate Officers Proposed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Union generals have threatened to execute two Confederate
                    officers if the proposed execution of two Union prisoners is carried out.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Call for Conscripts</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the government has modified the conscription policy in order
                    to broaden the available pool of recruits.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Anecdote</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Capt. A. being at home, slightly wounded, called at the house of his neighbor
                        Mr. B. Miss B., daughter of neighbor B., made her appearance, when, after
                        the ordinary salutations, the following dialogue ensued:</p>
                    <p>Where is your brother John now, Miss B.?</p>
                    <p>He is at home.</p>
                    <p>Ah! I thought he was in the army.</p>
                    <p>Oh! no. Brother John was an original secessionist!</p>
                    <p>MORAL.--It is not always the case that those who are foremost to bring on a
                        war, are foremost in the fight. Wonder if there are any "brother Johns" in
                        these parts! K.Y.E.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recounts a dialogue with the moral that "'those who are foremost to bring
                    on a war, are not always foremost in the fight."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Delaware Republican</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Delaware "Republican" states that there are now several thousand
                        prisoners at Fort Delaware, their number having been greatly increased
                        within the present week. "The rebels suffer immensely, many of them being
                        sick. On Thursday last no less than seventeen were interred, having been
                        conveyed to the adjacent shore of New Jersey for that purpose. By the great
                        addition to the number of prisoners, the mortality will be proportionately
                        increased."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on the deteriorating conditions of rebel prisoners at the Fort
                    Delaware facility.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**Soldiers' Lives</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Patience And Perseverance</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Encourages the populace to stay the course in the war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Lieut. Wm. F. Allen</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A tribute to Lieutenant William F. Allen, who died on July 3rd on the
                    battlefield of Gettysburg at the age of 22. Lieut. Allen had been serving with
                    the 14th Va. cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Love</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Larrick</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frenger</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice of the marriage of Mr. Larrick of Fredrick County to Miss Frenger of
                    Augusta on the 9th of June, 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruebush</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>Angelina</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on June 23, 1863, both of Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Catane</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Iglehart</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. T.</fn>
                        <sf>C.S.A.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spotswood</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Berkeley</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 18th at the residence of the bride's mother in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>See</ln>
                        <fn>C. S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Griffin</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on July 23, 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William Hay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notes the death of William Hay Wilson, infant son, on July 21, 1863.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Miscellaneous announcements and advertisements, columns 6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
