<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.11.24">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>08/14/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 9/17/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-11-24">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.11.24.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Stir Among The Unnaturalized</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This apprehension, we sincerely hope, is very well founded; for Congress
                    will be exceedingly remiss in its duty if it does not promptly pass a bill, to
                    go forthwith into effect, to bring alien residents in the Confederacy, who are
                    within the conscript age, into the service."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We understand, says the Petersburg Express, that there is considerable
                        excitement among the unnaturalized "white folks" in the Confederacy. They
                        are very apprehensive that one of the first steps of Congress, upon its
                        re-assembling, will be to put those among them who are of proper age and fit
                        for service, in the army. This apprehension, we sincerely hope, is very well
                        founded; for Congress will be exceedingly remiss in its duty if it does not
                        promptly pass a bill, to go forthwith into effect, to bring alien residents
                        in the Confederacy, who are within the conscript age, into the service. The
                        law must be a stringent one, for there will be an infinite deal of hard
                        swearing about "a temporary residence," the "<emph rend="italic">animo
                            revertendi</emph>," &amp;c. Some ought to get off on the "<emph
                            rend="italic">animo revertendi</emph>," principle, but, in our opinion,
                        very few are entitled to come within this rule. Certainly, no man of proper
                        age for service, who has been engaged in business in the Confederacy since
                        the war began, let him swear never so hard, should be exempted under this
                        principle. If he does not love us well enough to be imbued with the "<emph
                            rend="italic">animo manendi</emph>." a little genuine persuasion should
                        be applied to induce him to "pitch his <emph rend="italic">tent</emph> and
                        tabernacle with us." The idea is intolerable that, while our relatives of
                        every degree are subjected to the dangers and privations of the field, a set
                        of men, who are amongst us for the purpose of feathering their own nest, no
                        matter at what cost to the Confederacy, should shirk service on the plea
                        that they are <emph rend="italic">aliens</emph>. They stay here, are
                        protected by our laws in their persons and property, pay no taxes for
                        support of Government, discredit the credit of the Government that protects
                        them by hoarding the "metals" to them so "precious," and then will fly the
                        country to enjoy the wealth they will take with them rather than life an arm
                        or pay a dollar for the defense of the asylum that has given them protection
                        and wealth. Let Congress, if it has either the brains or the nerve to do so,
                        deal promptly with these gentry. The country expects this legislation, and
                        will be satisfied with nothing else. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author urges Congress to begin conscripting unnaturalized white
                    residents of the South. It is, according to this article, "intolerable that,
                    while our relatives of every degree are subjected to the dangers and privations
                    of the field, a set of men, who are amongst us for the purpose of feathering
                    their own nest, no matter at what cost to the Confederacy, should shirk service
                    on the plea that they are aliens."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>True Patriotism</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Here is a private soldier, giving his life, the last drop of his blood,
                    and the last breath of his brave soul, to his country, and with that last breath
                    bequeathing to her every dollar of his possessions!"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While facing death from wounds received at a battle near White Sulphur,
                    Private Minner left his entire estate of $15,000, upon the death of his Mother,
                    to the Confederacy. This heroic example of patriotism serves as the basis for a
                    comparison of this noble sentiment with those in the population who continue to
                    have their actions dictated by self-interest and greed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Patriotic Speech</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"General Forrest, during a recent visit to his family in Upper Georgia,
                    made a patriotic appeal to his former command. Annexed is an abstract from it:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"If home-family-friends-liberty cannot move you to action, then, indeed, is
                    the heel of the despot upon our necks. If you cannot be stirred by those
                    hallowed associations, we are a subjected people, ready for the yoke which
                    tyrants have so long made for slaves and cowards."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An extract from a recent speech by General Forrest speaks of the necessity
                    of continued effort, while assuring the audience that the Confederate banner
                    "...is waving in triumph in almost every part of the country."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Government Whiskey</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What does the Confederate Government do with all of its whiskey? Rockbridge
                        is manufacturing it at the rate of nearly 200,000 gallons per year, Augusta
                        county about 300,000 gallons, giving a total amount for two counties of
                        500,000. Suppose these two counties to make one tenth of all that is made in
                        the State, (which is probably a low estimate), and we have FIVE MILLIONS
                        [5,000,000] OF GALLONS as Virginia's contribution to this line of supplies.
                        Now if all the other States together furnish as much more, we have no less
                        than TEN MILLIONS (10,000,000) OF GALLONS. This is enough to deluge all the
                        hospitals in the Confederacy with all the patients they contain.--[Lexington
                        Gazette.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Estimates that Virginia produces roughly five million gallons of whiskey
                    per year. The author questions the need for such levels of production.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>New Policy Of The Enemy</head>
                <origin>The Mississippi Extra</origin>
                <commentary>"The 'Mississippi Extra,' speaking of the stoppage of the exchange of
                    prisoners makes a comment and a practical suggestion:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Cut off, as we are, from the outside world, they [the North] believe our
                    armies cannot be recruited, while they are in a position to get the floating
                    population of Europe, to swell their numbers. In this way, they hope to finally
                    exhaust us by our own successes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mississippi Extra believes that the North's recent cessation of the
                    prisoner exchange indicates that the Union has adopted a strategy of attrition.
                    In the face of this strategy, the author urges the Confederate soldiers to "take
                    as small a number of prisoners as possible, and never to surrender, while there
                    is the most infinitesimal particle of hope of being able to escape."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Affairs In Tennessee</head>
                <origin>The Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Upon the whole, the Republican thinks the prospect is cheering for a
                    brilliant campaign in Tennessee. It only now needs a few dashes of the Stonewall
                    order to make the State too hot for the Yankees to subsist in and compel a hasty
                    retreat. Shall we have them? Did all of Jackson's spirit die with him? We hope
                    not. If any be left, it has now a glorious opportunity for display, and the man
                    who wins the mantle of the dead hero is immortal."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recent accounts from Tennessee indicate that the Northern forces are in a
                    precarious situation and could face major reversals. With "Burnside driven to
                    the wall, the army of Rosecrans, now commanded by Sherman, will have its hands
                    full, with the two columns united on one side of him, and Bragg on the other,
                    whilst Wheeler, with his fifteen thousand cavalry, will distress them no little
                    by operations on their line of communication with Murfreesboro and Nashville,"
                    the Southern forces are set for a major triumph as long as their spirit is up to
                    the task.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The First Secessionist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In examining the congressional record, it appears that Mr. Quincy of
                    Massachusetts may have been the first secessionist. This belief is based on a
                    speech made by Quincy during the debate over the creation of a state government
                    for the territory of Orleans. During his speech, Quincy declared "...if this
                    bill passes the bonds of this Union are virtually dissolved; that the States
                    which compose it are free from their obligations; and that, as it will be the
                    duty of some, to prepare definitely for a separation--amicably, if they can;
                    violently if they must."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Fort Sumter--The Bombardment Against It</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"A Yankee correspondent, writing of the bombardment of Fort Sumter,
                    says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"Perhaps no greater example of stern, stubborn resistance exists in all
                    modern warfare than the persistent holding of this point by the rebels,
                    certainly history does not record one."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reporting on the conditions at Fort Sumter, the Northern correspondent
                    expresses grudging admiration for the soldiers resisting the heavy bombardment
                    of their position. He notes that "[t]he defence of Fort Sumter cannot fail to
                    stir in the hearts of our men that feeling of respect, which the true soldier
                    always has for a brave and determined foe."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Peace And Union</head>
                <origin>The New York Freeman's Journal</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It is not the war they object to, nor the management of the war, but only
                    the people who manage it. There is still an inveterate delusion amongst
                    'Democrats,' that they, if they only had a chance could make peace and secure
                    'Union.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commenting on the opposition papers in the North, the author notes that
                    they are deluded in their belief that if only the Democrats had control of the
                    war effort they would be able to secure a peace settlement and preserve the
                    Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Maryland Election</head>
                <origin>The New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Tribune is very happy over the election in Baltimore.
                    While expressing its joy over the results it says:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The New York Tribune interprets the results of the recent elections in
                    Maryland as a vote to declare Maryland a free state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>In addition to various legal announcements and commercial advertisements, this
                page also contains a poem entitled "I'm Growing Old." Part of the page is
            illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.11.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>War News</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides brief accounts of military affairs from Virginia, Tennessee, and
                    South Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Enemy In Greenbrier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They had no respect of persons, and robbed those who were supposed to be
                    Union men, as readily as and thoroughly as other persons."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses recent actions by federal troops in the Shenandoah Valley. In
                    particular, the article notes a number of abuses committed upon the civilian
                    population near Lewisburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Virginia Hotel</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As Dutchmen are known to be fond of good living, and as Mr. Scheffer is a
                    'Simon pure' Dutchman, we have a good guarantee that his borders will have but
                    little cause to complain of the fare which will be furnished them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The public is notified of the sale of the Virginia Hotel to Mr. Frederick
                    Scheffer of Woodstock.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>More Prisoners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Two more prisoners have been turned over to the local jail. Mr. Henry Kelly
                    is from Lynchburg and was captured while endeavoring to pass through the
                    Confederate lines to Harper's Ferry to assist federal forces in the construction
                    of a bridge. Mr. Elias Bumbarger is from Shenandoah and is charged with aiding
                    and abetting desertions from the Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Under the magic influence of these patriotic resolutions, the price of
                    flour has advanced 100 per cent. Another such patriotic meeting would, like the
                    touch of Midas, convert every barrel of flour into gold."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Wanted for publication the names of those farmers who have strictly and
                        honestly complied with the patriotic resolutions adopted at the September
                        Court. Many resolved, but few have acted. We desire to give publicity to
                        <lb/>"The <emph rend="italic">few</emph>, immortal names" <lb/>That did not
                        "resolve"--to lie. </p>
                    <p>If our space in the regular issue be too limited to contain the names, we
                        will publish them in an <emph rend="italic">extra</emph>. Virtue is sure to
                        be rewarded. Under the magic influence of these patriotic resolutions, the
                        price of flour has advanced 100 per cent. Another such patriotic meeting
                        would, like the touch of Midas, convert every barrel of flour into gold.
                        Call another meeting--it affords such relief to the poor! </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In a sarcastic article, the paper asks for the public to submit the names
                    of all the farmers who have "strictly and honestly" complied with the patriotic
                    resolutions adopted at the September court.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>25th Va. Infantry</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We certainly think that the people of Augusta and surrounding counties
                    ought to do something for these veteran soldiers who have been fighting our
                    battles and enduring hardships since the beginning of the war."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Higgenbotham</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>As part of an appeal for socks, the author reminds the public of the
                    sacrifices and accomplishments of the 25th Va. Infantry. The author also notes
                    that Lieut. Col. R. D. Lilley is from Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Va. Central R. Road</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>An economic analysis derived from the report of the President of the
                    Virginia Central Railroad shows a net revenue of $768, 283.59 for the year. The
                    article also notes that the Cowpasture bridge is nearing completion, at which
                    time the whole road will be brought into operation as far as Jackson's river.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Withholding Corn</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As many persons are now withholding corn [which means all kinds of grain] we
                        would again call their attention to the following passage of Scripture: "He
                        that withholdeth corn, the people shall curse him," but blessing shall be
                        upon the head of him that selleth it." We would recommend those who are now
                        withholding corn, to post this upon the doors of their granaries that they
                        may read it and reflect upon it whenever the poor are beseeching them to
                        sell them grain at a fair price.</p>
                    <p>Be kind and charitable to the poor, and you will experience the "luxury of
                        doing good."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Citing biblical scripture, the author reminds merchants to sell their
                    grains at a fair price and they will reap the "luxury of doing good."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>House Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"If there had been a male at the house when the fire was first discovered,
                    it might have been very easily extinguished, but there being no one present but
                    females, it got too much headway before Mr. Ervine arrived."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The dwelling house and kitchen of Mr. Clemens Ervine of Rockingham County
                    was consumed in a fire that began, it is believed, when a spark landed on the
                    kitchen roof. The total loss is estimated at about $10,000.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Blown Up</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"This will make the Yankees rather fearful of traveling on that route."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Last week, a Baltimore and Ohio Railroad carrying Union troops was
                    destroyed by torpedoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Revival</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A meeting of great interest has been in progress in the M. E. Church of this
                        place for the last four weeks under the pastoral charge of the Rev. Mr.
                        Dice. One hundred have made a profession of religion and Seventy have joined
                        the Church--the meeting is still continued, and the congregations continue
                        to be very large.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The M. E. Church of Staunton has been experiencing a major revival of late,
                    with 170 persons making a profession of faith and over 70 actually joining the
                    church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York papers</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Northern papers describe a series of labor actions by stage-drivers,
                    tailors, tin- workers, and copper and sheet-iron workers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Homeguards Of Rockbridge</head>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary>"Our citizens know that the Home Guards at Rockbridge responded very
                    promptly to the call to rally to the support of Gen. Imboden when it was thought
                    the services were needed to meet the advancing force under Gen'l. Averill.
                    Before dismissing the Home Guards of that county, Gen. Imboden addressed them,
                    as reported by the Lexington Gazette, as follows:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In thanking the men of the Rockbridge Home Guard, Gen. Imboden notes that
                    while the guard wasn't actually in combat, "you have been nearer a battle than
                    many soldiers who had served 12 months." He also congratulates the men of the
                    company in their choice of a commander, who served with Gen. Imboden at the
                    commencement of the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Real Issue</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"These are to be thorough and perfect separation, with unconditional
                    independence, or, failing this, then absolute and hopeless subjugation to the
                    power of the Yankee race, political ostracism, social degradation, and loss of
                    everything which a white man ever deemed worthy of preservation."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Whatever may have been the true relations of the States to the Federal
                        Government prior to the partial disruption of the Union, touching which
                        there was a diversity of opinion among our own people, there is no shadow of
                        doubt now as to what must be the future relations of the States that seceded
                        to what is still called the United States. These are to be thorough and
                        perfect separation, with unconditional independence, or, this failing, then
                        absolute and hopeless subjugation to the power of the Yankee race, political
                        ostracism, social degradation, and loss of everything which a white man ever
                        deemed worthy of preservation. The issue is distinct and definite. The last
                        resort of nations can alone determine it. The people of the Confederate
                        States must lose everything, or make good their independence. There is no
                        alternative, nor ought there to be any. Absolute independence from the old
                        Yankee Government is a necessity we have to embrace, and we can never think
                        of the close of the war upon any other basis.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that there can be no compromise on the issues for which this war is
                    being fought. The alternatives are independence and total subjugation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Citizens Of Fairfield</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recent measures adopted in Fairfield, South Carolina and Clark County,
                    Mississippi seek to supply the families of soldiers with corn and necessary
                    supplies. In South Carolina, the citizens are asked to supply one bushel of corn
                    for every slave they own. In Mississippi, planters are being asked to subscribe
                    one-fiftieth part of their corn crop to the cause, and the names of those who
                    agree and those who refuse are to be published.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Capture of the R. E. Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to New York papers, the R. E. Lee has been captured along with a
                    valuable supply of quartermaster stores.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The Poor Of Savannah</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Georgia House of Representatives has passed a bill that will provide
                    ten thousand dollars a year for three years to pay the rent of the families of
                    indigent soldiers in Savannah.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <summary>Henrico County has appropriated the sum of $27,000 for the relief of poor
                    families of that county.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>"AJAX, of 62d."</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At any rate, we have an 'abiding faith' that we will some day have a more
                    intimate acquaintance with him, and that preconceived prejudices will give way
                    to the genial influences which Imboden and his command generally bring to bear
                    on Yankee acquaintances."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Responding to a lack of respect for the Southern troops on the part of Gen.
                    Averill, the author of this letter looks forward to the opportunity to engage
                    the general in battle and acquaint him with the valor of his company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For The Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The reason we do not mention the names of the perpetrators of this Yankee
                    trick, is because of the fact that they are already too well known in the
                    regiment, and we also wish to give them a warning which may teach them better.
                    If the thing is repeated we intend to publish them by name in both the Staunton
                    papers."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp Stonewall Brigade, <lb/>Nov. 11, 1863, </p>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--We wish to call your attention, and through the medium of your
                        well known paper, the attention of the public, to what we consider the
                        shameful and degrading conduct of two citizens of Augusta, who lately paid a
                        visit to our camp near Brandy Station, one of these individuals has a son,
                        and the other, two brothers in company D, 5th Va. Regt. of Infantry. These
                        persons, before they left home, pretended, to all concerned, that they would
                        take pleasure in attending to any boxes of provision or any thing else that
                        the relations and friends of our soldiers wished to send them, without
                        charging any price for their trouble. Under this impression, a great many
                        packages were entrusted to their care.--On their arrival at camp, these men
                        charged our soldiers the most exhorbitant [sic] prices for bringing down
                        things, which it can be proved were hauled at a low rate of charge to
                        Staunton, and on which they had to pay little or no freight on the cars; in
                        some instances they charged more than the value of the package or box
                        consigned to their care. The reason we do not mention the names of the
                        perpetrators of this Yankee trick, is because of the fact that, they are
                        already too well known in the regiment, and we also wish to give them a
                        warning which may teach them better. If the thing is repeated we intend to
                        publish them by name in both the Staunton papers. If there is one act of
                        meanness greater than another surely it is that low hypocrisy, which, under
                        the guise of kindness to our brave and suffering soldiers, takes care to
                        fill the pockets of scheming speculators and extortioners.</p>
                    <p>Hoping sir that you will give this article a speedy insertion in your paper,
                        and believing that you and your readers will take the same view of the case
                        as ourselves, we remain with high respect.</p>
                    <p>Yours Respectfully, <lb/>MANY SOLDIERS of 5th Va. Regt. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>"Many Soldiers of 5th Va. Regt."</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from Camp Stonewall Brigade alerts the readers to the actions of
                    two gentlemen from Staunton (names not disclosed) who recently arrived at camp
                    with packages for various soldiers. Despite the fact that these gentlemen had
                    solicited packages and announced that they would deliver them without charge,
                    upon arrival at the camp they charged the soldiers exorbitant prices for
                    carrying the goods to the camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Right Spirit</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The whole county seemed to be moved by a stern resolve to give the enemy,
                    who was then expected, the best reception possible. We were satisfied, from what
                    we saw, that Averill would have had 'a hard road to travel' had he turned his
                    face towards Staunton."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We were exceedingly gratified with the spirit of patriotism shown by our
                        neighbors of Augusta county on Friday and Saturday last.</p>
                    <p>The whole county seemed to be moved by a stern resolve to give the enemy, who
                        was then expected, the best reception possible. We were satisfied, from what
                        we saw, that Averill would have had "a hard road to travel" had he turned
                        his face towards Staunton. There were ten companies, making a fine regiment
                        of 800 or 900 then in the field ready to show the invader that the Augusta
                        Raid Guards were ready for such an emergency as then seemed likely to occur.
                        This formidable and effective organization is composed, of course, of the
                        very best citizens of old Augusta--gentlemen who are exempt from military
                        service, but who will claim no exemption from such obligations should the
                        common enemy dare to put his foot upon their soil.--We were pleased to see
                        several of our citizens who have left the county of Rockingham to reside
                        with our neighbors in the ranks of this fine organization for home defence.
                        The officers selected to lead this regiment of citizen soldiers are Hon.
                        Jno. B. Baldwin, Col., Gen. Kenton Harper, Lt. Colonel, and Capt. Antrim,
                            Major.--<emph rend="italic">Rock Register</emph>. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Col.</sf>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf>Lt. Col.</sf>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf>Major</sf>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>In response to a possible threat by Gen. Averill, the Augusta Raid Guards
                    turned out in fine fashion to repel the enemy. While they weren't actually
                    called on to engage the enemy their turnout indicates that in an emergency they
                    will acquit themselves admirably.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Liberal</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At a recent united meeting of the Richmond Presbyterian Churches, over
                    $4,000 was raised for the purchase of shoes and socks for the barefooted
                    soldiers of Gen. Lee's army. The money raised was placed in the care of Mr. W.
                    P. Munford, Chairman of the Army Committee of the Young Men's Christian
                    Association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Butler, the Beast, has issued an order that all Confederate officers or
                    soldiers caught within their lines with their arms, shall suffer death."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Recent orders from Gen. Butler have mandated capital punishment for all
                    Confederate military personnel caught within Union lines bearing their weapons.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Mississippi Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Mississippi legislature is currently considering two bills of note. The
                    first would tax all persons who refuse to receive Confederate money in payment
                    of debts, one hundred per cent or more upon the value of such debt; another bill
                    would revoke the current exemption from military service of the legislature.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Death Of General Posey</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Brig. Gen. Posey, commander of Featherstone's brigade of the 48th
                    Mississippi regiment, died in Charlottesville of wounds he received at the
                    recent fight at Bristoe Station. He was interred in Charlottesville with full
                    military honors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Capture of Dr. Peters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dr. Peters, who murdered Gen. Van Dorn, was recently captured on his
                    plantation upon the Mississippi river, where he was reportedly engaged in
                    selling wood to the Northern troops. Upon his capture, Dr. Peters claimed that
                    he had long desired to return to the Confederacy to stand trial on the charges
                    that he had murdered Gen. Van Dorn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Floridas</head>
                <origin>The Charleston Courier</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A number of citizens of Alachua County, Florida have pledged themselves to
                    furnish "to soldiers' families, and those who are not engaged in speculation,
                    whatever supplies we have to spare, for confederate money, and at the prices
                    that may be assessed from time to time by the Government Commissioners of the
                    State. We further agree to furnish FREE OF CHARGE, to such soldiers' families as
                    are unable to pay--feeling that this is no act of charity, but a debt due from
                    us to our brave soldiers."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Republican "Majorities" In Ohio</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"The following from a Northern paper, explains the great 'majorities'
                    the Republicans boast of having received in the late election in Ohio:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The people here, although expecting it, were startled upon the receipt of
                    the frauds, and are now putting their heads together as to the propriety of
                    appointing investigation committees."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The recent majorities secured by Republican candidates in the state of Ohio
                    are attributed to widespread voter fraud rather than popular sentiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>The Yankee Congress</head>
                <origin>The New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Northern Congress is believed to be about equally divided between
                    Administration (92), and Democrats and border states (90) seats.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Bettie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn>Edward J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lafferty</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Bernard S. Brown, of Rockingham, and Miss Bettie A. Armstrong, daughter
                    of Col. Edward J. Armstrong, were married on November 5th.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
