<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1863/va.au.ss.1863.09.22">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Bob Guffin</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/24/97</tagDate>
            <tagNote>first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/11/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1863-09-22">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day>22</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1863.09.22.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5, 6, 7</column>
                <head>General Assembly</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details a series of actions taken by the Virginia legislature, including
                    War Resolutions, Resolutions of Inquiry, Joint Resolutions, and Bills read and
                    passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Chinese Sugar Cane</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"From these observations I came to the conclusion that when the seed is
                    fully formed and about to turn dark, then the stalk is at the highest state of
                    perfection for use, and will make either sugar or syrup you desire; that after
                    the seed ripens it becomes unfit for syrup or sugar."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Describes the characteristics and potential of Chinese Sugar Cane as a
                    substitute source of sugar. The author deems it acceptable if harvested at the
                    optimum time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Female Lieutenant</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In consideration of her services, the Confederate Government has
                    commissioned Mrs. DeCaulp with the rank of Captain, and since her arrival in
                    Richmond, she has drawn $1,600 back pay."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The public will remember the numerous paragraphs published concerning one
                        "Lieut. Harry Buford," <emph rend="italic">nee</emph> Mrs. Williams, with a
                        history romantic in war as that of Joan of Arc. Last summer the Lieut. got
                        into Castle Thunder, her sex not corresponding with the dashing uniform she
                        wore. She was released, and went from Richmond to Chattanooga, where she
                        joined Gen'l Bragg's army, got upon the staff of General A. P. Stewart, and
                        for a time was emyloyed [sic] in the secret service, effecting important
                        arrests of spies, and doing some very daring things. </p>
                    <p>The other day she visited Richmond again, not as the gay Lieutenant, but in
                        the garments more becoming her sex, and bearing the name of Mrs. Jeruth
                        DeCaulp, she having, in the interval, married an officer of the Confederate
                        States Provisional army of that name, first obtaining a divorce from her
                        first husband, Williams, who is in the army of Gen. Grant.</p>
                    <p>In consideration of her services, the Confederate Government has commissioned
                        Mrs. DeCaulp with the rank of Captain, and, since her arrival in Richmond,
                        she has drawn $1,600 back pay.--She is now at the Ballard House, <emph
                            rend="italic">en route</emph> for Georgia, and the home of her new
                        husband. </p>
                    <p>The heroine of this sketch is a native of Mississippi, and a devoted Southern
                        woman.--[Examiner.]</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Records the arrival in Richmond of "Lieut. Harry Buford," nee Mrs.
                    Williams, the woman who donned male clothing to participate in a number of
                    battles. The article describes her continuing adventures, her divorce from her
                    husband fighting on the Union side, her subsequent remarriage to Mr. Jeruth
                    DeCaulp, and her recent commission as a Captain in the Confederate army.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Negroes At Vicksburg</head>
                <origin>The Mississippian</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The negroes are the most dejected looking lot of beings that the human eye
                    ever beheld and nearly all of them want to go home."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses the dismal conditions faced by free blacks under Union
                    supervision at Vicksburg. The author describes their unhappiness and
                    disillusionment with their present state and adds that "the knowledge comes too
                    late to help them."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>In addition to various legal announcements and commercial advertisements, this
                page also contains a poem entitled "The Extortioners." This page is partly
                illegible.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1863.09.22.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Surrender at Cumberland Gap</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We are more pained at the surrender of Cumberland than at any occurrence
                    of the war, not because of the loss of men and arms and the surrender of a
                    strong position, but because it was stained with disgrace and has the taint of
                    treason about it."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The author bemoans the recent surrender of Confederate troops at Cumberland
                    Gap. He recounts how, despite a refusal on the part of General Frazier and his
                    officers to accept a proposal for surrender on the part of the Union Army,
                    General Frazier ordered his troops to surrender and told an officer to "tell
                    General Jones that I have gone up the spout." The article does commend the
                    Virginian troops (64th Va.) involved in the battle for their refusal to
                    surrender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Successful Dash Upon the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report of a successful surprise attack launched by Confederate forces
                    under the command of Capt. John McNeill in Hardy County that resulted in the
                    capture of 147 prisoners. The article also contains an order by a Union
                    commander to surprise the Confederate force camped at Moorefield. This resulted
                    in the two armies attempting to launch surprise attacks at the same time.
                    However, since the Confederate forces had already left camp when the Union
                    forces arrived there was little left for the Union forces to do but attempt to
                    harass the enemy and recapture their prisoners, an attempt that ultimately
                    failed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Remarkable Phenomenon--Interpretation Suggested</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig and the personal account of a "gentleman of Lewisburg."</origin>
                <commentary>"We publish in this issue two account of the remarkable phenomenon which
                    was witnessed in Greenbrier county--one furnished to the Richmond Whig by an
                    intelligent officer, and the other furnished to the "Spectator" by a gentleman
                    of Lewisburg, whose intelligence, character and veracity we can endorse to the
                    fullest degree. The characters of the witnesses, who say they saw the phenomenon
                    described in these communications, are endorsed by those who have known them
                    intimately for many years. That these witnesses saw a remarkable spectacle there
                    can be but little doubt. What is the proper interpretation of this procession
                    due North of white bundles followed by figures of men robed in scanty apparel of
                    the same color? We suggest the following:"</commentary>
                <excerpt>"The absence of arms and equipments represent that they [Mississippians
                    trading cotton with the North] belong to that numerous class of 'men of war'
                    who, before the war, were so willing to spill their 'last drop of blood,' but
                    since the war have shown an unconquerable dread of spilling the 'first drop.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The white bundles represent the cotton bales which the weak-kneed
                        secessionists of Mississippi are now sending North, and the fringe of
                        green--the emblem of that color being "forsaken"--indicates how <emph
                            rend="italic">green</emph> these planters are for having <emph
                            rend="italic">forsaken</emph> their country, and the figures of men
                        marching North at a rapid pace in the scanty garb described, represent that
                        these traitorous cotton sellers should be reduced in their dress to a cotton
                        shirt fastened on their "tight hides" by a plaster of tar, and be made to
                        march North at a "double quick."--The absence of arms and equipments
                        represent that they belong to that, numerous class of "men of war" who,
                            <emph rend="italic">before</emph> the war, were so willing to spill
                        their "<emph rend="italic">last</emph> drop of blood," but since the war
                        have shown an unconquerable dread of spilling the "<emph rend="italic"
                        >first</emph> drop." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A particularly bitter interpretation of a strange phenomenon in which a
                    number of individuals in Greenbrier County saw what appeared to be a procession
                    of men dressed all in white marching in military formation across the
                    countryside.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Strange Phenomenon</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"I have given all the material facts, except that the so called men were
                    marching north or northwest, right thro' the mountains. They were of all sizes
                    and as much like men as if they had been real flesh and blood."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>On the afternoon of the 1st instant, a strange phenomenon was seen in
                        Greenbrier county by Mr. Moses Dwyer, Mrs. Pearcy, two other ladies, a youth
                        nearly grown, and a servant girl. These respectable witnesses state that
                        they saw what seemed to be a countless multitude of men, dressed in white,
                        marching in column, on the ground through an open field, up the mountain
                        slope at a rapid pace, quicker than double quick time, the columns only
                        separated by a few feet. The witnesses state that they could see the men not
                        only as a whole, but the individual parts--their heads, arms, legs and feet.
                        Occasionally one would lag a little behind, and could be distinctly seen to
                        quicken his pace to regain his position in the line. They were passing for
                        an hour or more, and, it is thought, numbered thousands upon thousands.--The
                        field over which they passed is several hundred yards in length, and they
                        covered the entire area in passing.--Their general appearance was white, and
                        they were without arms or knapsacks.</p>
                    <p>An officer, of intelligence and character, in writing to the <emph
                            rend="italic">Richmond Whig</emph> concerning this story, in a private
                        note, says: </p>
                    <p>"I put myself to some trouble to ascertain the facts, and questioned the
                        witnesses separately. They are above suspicion. I have given all the
                        material facts, except that the so called <emph rend="italic">men</emph>
                        were marching north or northwest, right thro' the mountains. They were of
                        all sizes, and as much like men as if they had been real flesh and blood."
                    </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of a remarkable vision witnessed by a number of people in
                    Greenbrier County, in which what appeared to be a countless multitude of men
                    dressed in white traversed a field measuring several hundred yards in length and
                    rapidly ascended a mountain at the end of the field. The vision is alleged to
                    have lasted for over an hour and the witnesses were described as being highly
                    credible.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Destructive Fire in Richmond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A description of the fiery loss of Congress Hall in Richmond. Congress Hall
                    was used as the Confederate States District Court, and with the exception of a
                    handful of books, all the records were consumed in the flame. The fire is
                    believed to have been the work of a group of friends of a counterfeiter whose
                    trial was scheduled to begin in the next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>From Tennessee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report on numerous rumors from Tennessee, including a report of a battle
                    between Bragg and Rosecrans, with the victory going to the Confederate forces.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Yankee Raiders Captured</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While alerting the readers to the capture of sixteen raiders apprehended in
                    Smythe County, the author editorializes that "[s]uch wretches ought never to be
                    taken prisoner, but should be shot down as spies wherever found."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A report based on the accounts of recent arrivals to town announces a
                    recent battle on the Rapidan that has necessitated the removal of wounded from
                    Charlottesville to Lynchburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Emancipation In Maryland</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Notes that Gov. Bradford of Maryland has called for a State Convention to
                    urge slaveowners to emancipate their slaves rather than following the advice of
                    Judge Bond and enlisting them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Old Issue</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mentions that Richmond banks have decided to rescind a previous resolution
                    and once again accept old issues of the Confederate Treasury as legal tender.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Christian Observer</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In announcing the recent decision of the Richmond Observer to raise its
                    yearly rate to $5 per annum, the author points out that compared to the
                    inflation of other prices, a newspaper remains a good bargain.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph> says: </p>
                    <p>Society in the South is being upheaved by the war, and, with our
                        independence, will be re-established on new orders of merit. The republic
                        will give new titles of greatness. The honours of State, the worship of
                        society, the rewards of affection, will be for the patriots and soldiers of
                        the revolution that will date our existence, while property will be a
                        despised thing, fortunate if it is not taken as the mark of the extortioner,
                        and the reward of infamy. Such are the great prizes, intertwined with that
                        of independence, which put wealth to the blush, stir our people and army
                        with noble desires, and beckon them to victory.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>New titles are being considered to honor the extraordinary exertions by
                    civilians and soldiers in the current conflict.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>The Richmond Examiner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">Examiner</emph> says: </p>
                    <p>"We owe one confession to truth in in [sic] this war. There may have been
                        some diminution of spirit in the South since the commencement of this
                        struggle; but it has been on the part of those pretentions classes of the
                        wealthy, who, in peace, were at once the most zealous secessionists, and the
                        best customers of the Yankees, and who, now in the war, are natually [sic[
                        the sneaks and tools of the enemy."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>While conceding that there may have been a diminution in spirit due to the
                    travails of the war, this article asserts that the most faint-hearted supporters
                    of the war have been the wealthy. While the rich ardently supported secession
                    before the war, they have become the primary enemies of continuing the struggle
                    through trying times.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Good Example</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have been informed that Mr. Jas. Lyle, living near Millboro, in this
                        county, has a large quantity of apples for which he could get $6.00 her
                        [sic] bushel, but that he sells them to his neighbors at $1.00 per bushel
                        and refuses to sell to distillers at any price, however great.--This is an
                        example worthy of being followed by others.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An enthusiastic endorsement of the patriotic example of Mr. Jas. Lyle of
                    Augusta County who chooses to sell his apples for one dollar a bushel to his
                    neighbors rather than sending them to distant markets and reaping six dollars a
                    bushel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Mr. W. E. Logan, salt agent for Augusta County, has announced that the next
                    allotment of salt to the citizens will be reduced from twenty to fifteen pounds
                    per inhabitant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Postponed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Because of a lack of space, the editor is forced to postpone publication of
                    a number of articles and announcements until next week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Deserters Shot</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Two brothers named Saul have been apprehended and executed as deserters in
                    Franklin County, Virginia. In addition to the charge of desertion, these two
                    brothers are also believed to have been responsible for a number of acts of
                    vandalism. These acts finally caused the inhabitants of Franklin County to seize
                    the brothers and summarily execute them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator: Remarkable Phenomenon</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>LEWISBURG, Sept. 15, 1863.</p>
                    <p>Mr. Mauzy--I drop you a few hastily written lines, hoping they may not be
                        altogether uninteresting to you and the readers of the "Spectator."</p>
                    <p>Whilst great and wonderful events are occurring in our political world,
                        apparently stranger things are going on in the physical world. But as we
                        have no good Daniel, in these degenerate days, to tell us what they mean,
                        every one must become his own interpreter. Whether what I am going to relate
                        is a good or a bad omen to the cause we are defending with all our energies,
                        and which we all love so much; whether it means peace or a longer
                        continuance of this bloody struggle, or is a mere delusion, who can say?</p>
                    <p>A remarkable phenomenon was witnessed a few miles west of this place, at the
                        house of Mrs. Pearcy, on the first day of this month at about 3 o'clock, P.
                        M., by Mr. Moses Dwyer, her neighbor, who happened to be seated in her porch
                        at the time, as well as by others at or near the house.</p>
                    <p>The weather was quite hot and dry, not a cloud could be seen, no wind even
                        ruffled the foliage on the surrounding trees. All things being propitious,
                        the grand panorama began to move.--Just over and through the tops of the
                        trees on the adjacent hills on the South, immense numbers of rolls
                        resembling cotton or smoke, apparently thousands of them, and were, perhaps,
                        an hour in getting by. After these had passed over and out of sight, the
                        scene was changed from the air above to the earth beneath, and became more
                        intensely interesting to the spectators who were witnessing the panorama
                        from different stand points. In the deep valley beneath thousands upon
                        thousands of [apparently] human beings [men] came in low traveling in the
                        same direction of the rolls marching in good order, some thirty or forty in
                        depth, moving rapidly--"double quick," and commence ascending the sides of
                        the almost insurmountable hills opposite, and had the stoop peculiar to men
                        when they ascend a steep mountain. There seemed to be great variety in the
                        size of the men, some were very large whilst others were quite small. Their
                        arms, legs and heads could be distinctly seen in motion. They seemed to
                        observe strict military discipline and there were no stragglers.</p>
                    <p>There was uniformity of dress, loose white blouses or shirts with white
                        pants, wore hats and were without guns, swords or anything they indicated
                        "men of war."--On they came through the valley and over the steep hill
                        crossing the road and finally passing out of sight, in a direction due North
                        from those who were looking on.</p>
                    <p>The gentlemen who [illegible] this is a man with whom you were once
                        acquainted, Mr. Editor, and as truthful a man as we have in the county, and
                        as little liable to be carried away by "fanciful speculations" as any man
                        living.--Four others (respectable ladies) and a servant girl witnesses this
                        strange phenomenon. W.</p>
                    <p>P. S. On the 14th that., the same scene almost identical, was soon by 8 or 10
                        of our pickets at Bunger's Mill, and by many of the citizens in that
                        neighborhood; this is about 4 miles east of Pearcy's. It was about the hour
                        passing.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J.G.R., Capt. P.A.C.S.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter provides another account of the mysterious sighting of the men
                    dressed in white.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Obituary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Meredith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Humphreys died on July 5 from wounds he suffered at Gettysburg on
                    July 2. He was a member of Carpenter's Battery of Allegheny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pickett</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj. Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corbell</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. Gen. George Pickett, "the hero of Gettysburg," married Miss Corbell in
                    Petersburg on September 14.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>R.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Van Lear</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>R. Miller</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampter</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 17.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Garber</ln>
                        <fn>Martin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>Harriett D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on September 13.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>In Council for the Town of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>September 5th, 1863.</p>
                    <p>The Mayor presented a petition signed by Robert G. Bickle and ninety-two
                        others, praying the passage of an Ordinance for the increase of taxation on
                        all taxable subjects in the Town, for the purpose of raising a fund to
                        provide supplies of Flour, Meat and Wood for the families of soldiers.</p>
                    <p>Whereupon, on motion of Col. Harman, the following resolution was adopted:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Resolved,</emph> That an ordinance by passed doubling the
                        taxes imposed by the Ordinance, passed the 9th of June last. </p>
                    <p>And thereupon, the Mayor submitted an Ordinance, which was passed in the
                        words following, to wit:</p>
                    <p>Be it ordained by the Council of the Town of Staunton, that the Ordinance
                        passed on the 9th of June last, imposing taxes for the Town of Staunton be
                        amended, by increasing the amount of taxation on all subjects therein named,
                            <emph rend="italic">one hundred percent</emph> for the purposes
                        expressed in the petition aforesaid. </p>
                    <p>And it is further ordained, that to facilitate the collection of the Town
                        Taxes, the Chief of Police be and is hereby authorized to endorse the word
                        "DOUBLE" on the face and back of his tax tickets, and collect and account
                        for the same accordingly, and, that for all taxes on licenses granted,
                        issued and collected since the 24th day of April last, the Chief of Police
                        is hereby required and authorized to make out new tickets for the amounts of
                        such taxes, and collect and account for the same accordingly, and for all
                        licenses which may be granted and issued between this date and the 24th of
                        April next, that he make out tickets therefor, in pursuance of the spirit
                        and intent of this Ordinance, and collect and account for the same
                        accordingly.</p>
                    <p>Rev. James C. Wheat, and Messrs. James W. Crawford and William B. Kayser were
                        appointed a Committee to disburse the fund to be raised under the above
                        Ordinance.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>James C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Mayor of Staunton presented a petition signed by Robert Bickle and
                    ninety-two others that asked the town to pass an ordinance that would double
                    taxes on Staunton residents in order to raise a fund to provide food and
                    supplies for the families of soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also miscellaneous advertisements and announcements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
