<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.12.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>11/13/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 11/14/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-12-30">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day>30</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.30.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Amusements of Camp Life</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Presents a parody of a soldier's life.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Wounded and Killed</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It takes but little space in the columns of the daily papers, but what long
                        household stories and biographies are every one of these strange names that
                        we read over and forget:</p>
                    <p>"Wounded and killed!" Some eye reads the name to whom it is dear as life, and
                        some heart is struck or broken with the blow made by that name among the
                        list.</p>
                    <p>It's our Henry, it's our John, or our James, or our Thomas, that lies with
                        his poor broken limbs at the hospital, or with white and ghastly face on the
                        battle-field. Alas! for the eyes that read!--alas! for the hearts that feel!</p>
                    <p>"He was my pretty boy, that I've sung to sleep so many times in my arms!"
                        says the poor mother, bowing her head in an anguish that cannot be uttered.
                        "He was my brave, noble husband, the father of my little orphan children!"
                        sobs the stricken wife. "He was my darling brother, that I loved so, that I
                        was so proud of," murmurs the sister, amid her tears; and so the terrible
                        stroke falls on homes throughout the land.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comments on the grief felt by families and friends as they read the lists
                    of wounded and killed in the newspapers and find their own loved ones' names.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements and notices, columns 1-6; anecdotes about General Jackson,
                column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.12.30.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Obituaries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that because the paper has no space to publish long obituaries,
                    the Spectator will from now on charge for obituaries and tributes of respect.
                    Notices of death will continue to be free of charge, but obituaries will cost
                    ten cents per line, the current advertising rate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cooking Utensils</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Requests that citizens donate cooking utensils, including "anything that
                    will do to bake bread and fry meat," to Imboden's troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Presiding Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J. Marshall</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announces that J. Marshall McCue has been elected Presiding Justice at
                    County Court, replacing Robert Guy, who resigned.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>For the Fredericksburg Sufferers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two young ladies of Staunton have raised $850 for the relief
                    of those in Fredericksburg whose homes were destroyed and whose property was
                    stolen by Northern troops. Expresses the hope that the people of Staunton will
                    raise this sum to $2,000 instead of the $1,000 that had been the ladies' goal.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Staunton Artillery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>A. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Major.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that the Staunton Artillery is in need of shoes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>To Slave Owners</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Instructs slave owners to have their slaves at the Court House on the first
                    day of January so that they may be sent off the next day, once the
                    "appraisement" has been completed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Lincoln to His Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"As they get whipped so often, accidents are quite common to the Yankee
                    army."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a letter Lincoln addressed to the officers and soldiers of the
                    Northern army. The letter congratulates Northern troops for their skill and
                    courage and deems the loss at Fredericksburg an "accident." The Spectator
                    comments sardonically that Lincoln's address must be comforting to the "battered
                    and bruised troops who were defeated by a mere accident."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Yankee Cabinet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the North's defeat at Fredericksburg has Lincoln's cabinet in
                    disarray. The Republican Senators had called for the resignation of Seward and
                    the re-organization of the cabinet, but the President "swore that he would not
                    yield to caucus dictation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Virginian Abolitionist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that J. H. Carskadon of the government at Wheeling is a
                    slaveholder, but also a "vile abolitionist." Notes that the "bogus" Wheeling
                    government has confined several women to jail because they are supporters of the
                    South. Asserts that most women, "we are happy to know," remain true to the
                    Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Company C of the 5th Regiment raised $142 to donate to the
                    widow of William Curry, who was killed at Sharpsburg. The widow expressed her
                    thanks to the regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--Will you allow me, through your paper, to correct an error which
                        has been made public through the same medium, and one, which reflects much
                        discredit upon me as a patriot and soldier. I ask this from you, believing
                        that you will take pleasure in granting me an opportunity to vindicate my
                        honor and patriotism.</p>
                    <p>In looking over your issue of the 16th instant, my eye fell upon an
                        advertisement of a list of deserters from the 52nd Regiment of Va.
                        Volunteers, among which I find my own name. This is the second time that my
                        name has appeared among the list of deserters. Now, I wish to inform the
                        public that gross injustice has been done to me--whether intentional. I am
                        not prepared to say--but am inclined to think it was not intentional. I have
                        the following certificate of the Surgeon in charge of the Hospital, at
                        Staunton, stating that I was regularly received at the Hospital, on the 23rd
                        of June last, under the recommendation of Col. M. G. Harman:</p>
                    <p>General Hospital, <lb/>Staunton, August 25th, 1862. </p>
                    <p>This is to certify that Private Asbury Myers, of the 52nd Va. Regiment,
                        Company "B," was regularly admitted to this Hospital, for Medical treatment,
                        on the 23rd of June, upon the recommendation of Col. Harman, and that he has
                        been in the Hospital from that time to the present date.</p>
                    <p>By order of Dr. Wm. Hay, Surgeon in Charge. <lb/>J. C. MERILLAT, Surgeon in
                        Charge. </p>
                    <p>From the time this certificate was given I remained in the Hospital, under
                        medical treatment, until the 16th November, at which time, being quite sick,
                        I was allowed a furlough of sixty (60) days to go home, which furlough has
                        not yet expired, and which I still have in my possession. I have never
                        attempted to <emph rend="italic">shirk</emph> my duty or to be absent from
                        my post, and never will unless sickness should compel me so to do. When I
                        volunteered I did so, feeling it to be a duty, and I would SCORN deserting
                        that standard of my country in this hour of her struggle for freedom and
                        independence. </p>
                    <p>The question has often been asked me, why I have not applied for a discharge
                        form the army, that I was not able for duty. My answer was then, and still
                        is, that I intend to do my duty as long as I am able to bear arms.</p>
                    <p>While at the Hospital I was assigned to light duty, and could be seen almost
                        daily on the streets of Staunton, up to the time my furlough was granted me
                        to go home, in performance of the same. I can be found at my residence, on
                        Christian's Creek, about seven miles east of Staunton, at any time between
                        this and the expiration of my furlough, after which time I can be found at
                        the Hospital, ready to take my place in the ranks, if the Surgeon in Charge
                        reports me for duty.</p>
                    <p>Trusting that the above statements will be sufficient to vindicate me from
                        the stigma of a deserter, I subscribe myself</p>
                    <p>Yours, &amp;c., <lb/>ASBURY MYERS. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Asbury Myers</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Asbury</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merillat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints a letter in which a wounded soldier protests the presence of his
                    name on a list of deserters that was published in the Spectator. Myers claims
                    that he has been in the hospital since June and includes a letter from a surgeon
                    in Staunton to confirm that fact.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Sick unto Death of the War</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There can be no doubt but that the masses of the people of the North are sick
                        of the war and are sighing for peace. Such sentiments are now beginning to
                        find expression notwithstanding the tyranny prevailing there. The following
                        is an extract from a letter written by Hon. Wm. B. Read, of Philadelphia,
                        under date of November 5th:</p>
                    <p>"It is my firm belief that the paramount wish of the masses of the North is
                        for peace--though timidity or considerations--mistakes in my opinion--of
                        expediency prevent them from saying so. It has been part of the policy of
                        the Administration to crush out this craving of a common humanity, and to
                        denounce as traitors those who think as I do, that blood enough has been
                        shed already. This has been acquiesced in too long. There are thousands who
                        think with me, whose property is endangered--whose industry is
                        paralyzed--fathers and mothers who are praying anxiously for the return of
                        their soldiers from the battle-field, or waiting for the stern doom that
                        takes from them those who are left at home. This prayer will soon find
                        utterance--and the community, weary of war and bloodshed--weary of debt and
                        taxation, of the tax-collector and the recruiting Sergeant--weary of the
                        ambulance of the wounded and the hearse of the dead--will hail with ecstacy
                        beyond control the hour when flags of permanent truce shall be displayed at
                        Washington and Richmond. I am old enough to remember the peace of 1815, and
                        the joy it excited; but it was nothing in comparison with what ours will be
                        when this brothers' war is over."</p>
                    <p>The following is an extract from the letter of a sister to her brother in the
                        Yankee army, written immediately after the removal of General McClellan:</p>
                    <p>"What could Abe and his tribe have done if from one to two hundred thousand
                        men would have marched home? I would help any soldier to desert. If the
                        Government does not do its duty, a soldier ought not to do his either. I
                        expect a scolding from you for talking so, but I can't help it. I'll run
                        down Lincoln and his friends in Congress before anybody, and if I should be
                        arrested to-morrow. I do not think the whole ship and crew of them are worth
                        one cent."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Argues that the people of the North are tired of the war and are anxious
                    for peace. Prints extracts from two letters written by Northern men.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skinner</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dabney</ln>
                        <fn>E. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>R. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>Alex B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watkins</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaver</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mayfield</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houltz</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drane</ln>
                        <fn>Ryland</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Zirkle</ln>
                        <fn>Jonathan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Gerard E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holburt</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the members of the 52d Virginia Regiment who suffered injuries at
                    Fredericksburg. None of the troops were killed in the battle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Casualties in the 25th Va. Regiment</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>R. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists casualties in the 25th Va. Inf. who were killed or wounded at
                    Fredericksburg. Captain Lilley is an Augusta County officer in this regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>J. D. Imboden</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Archer</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scott</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf>Miss</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>G.</sf>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mosby</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Balley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanderson</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>G. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGlannery</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Armstrong</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huff</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Riddell</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Applick</ln>
                        <fn>Phillip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Critzer</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knipple</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hopewell</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tannehid</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumey</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tallaferro</ln>
                        <fn>E. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henden</ln>
                        <fn>Pat</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the names of people in Augusta County who have donated clothing in
                    the last week to the troops stationed on Shenandoah Mountain. Lists the number
                    of each item that each company received.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shults</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints resolutions adopted by the Augusta Greys on the death of John H.
                    Shults.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Butler Declared an Outlaw</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that President Davis has called for the capture and execution of
                    Gen. Butler, declaring him a murderer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>How to Save Salt</head>
                <origin>Columbus (Ga.) Sun</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Instructs readers on the best way to cure meat using the smallest amount of
                    salt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Luemma</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>George Howard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catherine Luemma Harris, aged 2 years, died of diphtheria on December 9.
                    George Howard Harris, aged 9 years, died on December 19. They were the only
                    children of Peter and Susan Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various battlefield reports, including many accounts of Fredericksburg from
                various sources. Col. 6 and 7 ads and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
