<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.02.25">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-25">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>25</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.02.25.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Fort Donelson Captured by the Enemy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports the capture of Fort Donelson but encourages the Confederate
                    forces to take heart and to not give up in the face of this loss.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Brave Boy - The Right Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>To show the spirit of our "brave soldier boys," we publish an extract from
                        the letter of a boy only sixteen years of age in reply to a letter from his
                        father requesting him <emph rend="italic">not</emph> to re-enlist--This boy
                        is from Staunton, and belonged to the "West Augusta Guards," which has been
                        recently converted into an artillery company, and he is now a member of the
                        "West Augusta Battery." His letter breathes the right spirit, and we have no
                        doubt that he expresses the feelings of a large majority of the soldiers
                        from Augusta county.--He is an only son, and as his Father thought it
                        probable that he (the father) would be drafted in which event there would be
                        no one to support the mother of this young solder, his Father appealed to
                        him not to re-enlist. This certainly was a strong appeal, and the boy no
                        doubt felt the full force of it, but it was not strong enough to induce him
                        to lay down his arms when his country needed his services. In reply to his
                        Father's letter, he said: </p>
                    <p>"You and Ma are opposed to my re-enlisting in the army. If every parent gave
                        such counsel, what would become of our country? I cannot consent to leave
                        the army and quit the service when my country is bleeding and my countrymen
                        are struggling for independence, and to leave my comrades to battle with the
                        foe in their efforts to drive them from our land. It may be that you think
                        that there are many who have staid at home who should take my place. If they
                        act the coward and will not come out as freemen and declare they will have
                        their rights, and will not shoulder their muskets and march in defence of
                        their native State, but would rather stay at home, enjoying the luxuries of
                        life and speculating off the poor soldiers who are in the service, guarding
                        their homes,--if they act in this way, is that any reason why I should do
                        the same. <emph rend="italic">No</emph>, NEVER. I want to be one of those
                        who, to the last, will rally around our standard to defend our noble and
                        glorious cause, and, with out bright colors waving over us and with our
                        brave General Jackson at the head of us, and with the motto--"<emph
                            rend="italic">Victory or death</emph>"--with stout hearts and determined
                        minds, strike an effective blow for the preservation of liberty and the
                        defence of our country. If the soldiers should not re-enlist, we would soon
                        have no country--no home. They would be dishonored and disgraced, and the
                        finger of scorn would be pointed at them. I for one would rather suffer
                        banishment and exile--I would rather fill a soldier's honorable grave and
                        sleep peacefully beneath the green sod of the Valley. These are my <emph
                            rend="italic">true</emph> feelings and sentiments. I cannot see how you
                        or any one else can advise his son not to re-enlist--<emph rend="italic"
                            >especially at this time</emph>, when the tide of success is setting
                        against us." </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article lauds the reenlistment of a sixteen year old boy over his fathers
                    objections, as outlined in the letter accompanying the article. The boy is a
                    member of the West Augusta Guards.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Col. Crawford is raising an artillery company and
                    volunteers may sign up at the Courthouse.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item states that a Washington preacher was removed from the pulpit and
                    arrested when he omitted a portion of the service blessing the President of the
                    United States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Military Exemption Bill</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article outlines the provisions of the new draft law, including a list of
                    those positions and offices that are exempt from the draft.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Lieut. Burke is in Staunton recruiting for the West
                    Augusta Artillery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Proclamation by the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Declaration of Jeff Davis declaring a day of prayer and fasting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Inaugural Address of President Jefferson Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A transcript of President Davis' inaugural.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Camp Alleghany, VA</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Camp Alleghany, Va. <lb/>Feb. 15, 1862. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Mr. Editor</emph>:--You will please inform our friends,
                        as well as the friends of other Regiments and Companies of this command,
                        that if they wish to bring or send boxes of provisions, clothing &amp;c.
                        to their friends in camp, they must know that there is no whiskey in the
                        wagon, conveying the articles into camp, for Gen. Johnson has determined
                        that, in case whiskey is found in a wagon conveying such articles he will
                        confiscate the whole load. He has the boxes opened and examined and though
                        whiskey may be found in but few of them, he confiscates the whole load. </p>
                    <p>A wagon came out from Augusta county last week in which were boxes, which had
                        been sent to several of our young men from their homes, containing little
                        delicacies and warm clothing, and, although there was no whiskey in the
                        boxes, yet, because there was some in other boxes in the wagon, all were
                        confiscated; notwithstanding the fact that no order had been published in
                        regard to persons bringing whiskey into camp.</p>
                    <p>The use of whiskey in camp is a great evil and those who bring it here should
                        be severely punished, but we do not like to see the boxes or packages
                        containing provisions and clothing and no whiskey taken and distributed
                        among the soldiers who may be gathered around at the time the property is
                        taken--the young men for whom the boxes have been prepared, not receiving
                        any of the contents. We cannot see the justice in thus wronging the innocent
                        in order to punish the guilty, and cannot want our friends to chose their
                        labor in preparing such articles for our young men as they may think would
                        be acceptable to them. We would therefore advise those who may wish to send
                        boxes or packages to camp not to send any whiskey, no matter how small the
                        quantity, and although it might be for medicinal purposes. And those coming
                        back to camp to visit their friends, and bringing their wagons loaded with
                        boxes, should feel no delicacy in enquiring of those requesting them to
                        bring a box for them, whether or not there is whiskey in it, as a man was
                        placed in the Guard House and his team placed at the service of the Quarter
                        Master for a short time, because there was whiskey in some boxes which he
                        had consented to bring out, not knowing of their contents, but supposing
                        that they contained the usual articles sent to soldiers from their homes.</p>
                    <p>A.L.R.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from Camp Alleghany informing the citizens of Augusta not to send
                    any liquor to soldiers at the camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Camp "Stone-Wall" Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letter informing the Spectator of the death of William Finley of disease at
                    Camp.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>George B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ramsey</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of John Taylor and Sarah Ramsey.</summary>
                <note>Names not clearly legible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaufly</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of George Shaufly.</summary>
                <note>Reverend's and Bride's names illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Moore</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel Crawford</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Samuel Crawford Moore.</summary>
                <note>Name of deceased not clearly legible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>James Lyle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln/>
                        <fn>Nancy Templeton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of James and Nancy.</summary>
                <note>Deceaseds' last names illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items regarding battles and military movements, including the capture
                of Fort Donelson. Articles of national political and military news. Upper right
                illegible. Col. 7 local ads and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.02.25.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Foreign Intervention</head>
                <origin>Richmond WHig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article lists reasons to expect that foreign intervention is forthcoming.</summary>
                <note>Largely illegible.</note>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Governor's Proclamation's regarding the provisions of the draft law. Remainder
                of page ads.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
