<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.02.18">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-02-18">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="02">February</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.02.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Recent Reverses</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are not disposed to take a gloomy view of the seemingly sad reverses with
                        which our arms have recently met. We do not feel discouraged by them; on the
                        contrary, we believe that they will eventually result in good to the cause
                        of the South. "The bud may have a bitter taste, <lb/>But sweet will be the
                        flower." </p>
                    <p>These reverses are but the thunder-claps which were necessary to arouse the
                        giant of Southern energy from its false repose. We had indulged too long a
                        fancied security, and it was necessary for our good that we should be
                        aroused to a proper sense of our duty under the trying circumstances by
                        which we are surrounded. We were enjoying our <emph rend="italic">otium cum
                            dignitate</emph>, and acting as though there was no one to molest or
                        make us afraid, whilst a powerful and ruthless enemy was exerting all of his
                        energies, with might and main, to prepare and equip an enormous force to
                        fall upon us unexpectedly at some weak and unprotected point. That he should
                        succeed in gaining a few successes, after so much vigilance and preparation
                        on his part, and such carelessness and listlessness on ours, furnishes no
                        cause of wonder or alarm. The news of these reverses falls upon the ears of
                        the brave and patriotic like the sound of the trumpet calling to arms, and
                        inspires them with a determination to buckle on their armor and rally, with
                        the spirit of heroes, to the defence of the banner of freedom and
                        independence. Whilst we felt secure, our volunteers, who have been for a
                        long time in the service, and who were beginning to pine for the sweet
                        pleasures of home, were hesitating whether or not they would re-enlist; but
                        we mistake their spirit for bravery and patriotism, if the news of our
                        recent reverses does not determine nearly <emph rend="italic">every
                        one</emph> to re-enlist with an increased determination to meet and conquer
                        the enemy, and to share in the glory of establishing the freedom and
                        independence of their country. They have acquired a name and fame which they
                        will not tarnish by laying down their arms when their country and their dear
                        native State calls most loudly for the services of their brave hearts and
                        strong arms. The Yankees may be guilty of the shame and infamy of disbanding
                        and returning home when the sound of hostile cannon was reverberating in
                        their ears, but Southerners cannot be guilty of such dastardly conduct.--We
                        believe confidently that nine-tenths of the Virginia volunteers will now
                        re-enlist promptly and cheerfully, and we have no reason to believe that the
                        troops from other Southern States will act less bravely and patriotically.
                        This is one good effort, which we expect to result from our recent reverses. </p>
                    <p>Another is, that it will have a similar effect upon those who are not now in
                        the service. We believe that thousands will now cheerfully volunteer, who
                        have not done so heretofore, for the reason that they did not feel that
                        their services were needed. Now that they are conscious of the necessity of
                        their services, they will cheerfully offer them to the Confederacy. We do
                        not believe that the patriotic spirit which animates the sons of this good
                        old county will ever allow the necessity of a draft upon its citizens. The
                        number of volunteers required will promptly step forth when their State
                        calls for them.--This county has too fair a name and her sons are too proud
                        of it to allow the stigma of a forced draft to be put upon it. They feel
                        that to volunteer is brave, commendable, and patriotic, and that, as <emph
                            rend="italic">volunteers</emph>, they can, with heads erect, walk with
                        bold and manly step, whilst as <emph rend="italic">draftsmen</emph>, they
                        would hobble along as convicts enforced to the performance of a reluctant
                        and disagreeable duty. We cherish the hope that the required number to
                        furnish the quota of this State will cheerfully volunteer. </p>
                    <p>Another good effect which we expect to result from these reverses is, that
                        our officials, upon whom the heaviest responsibility rests, will be awakened
                        to the necessity of exercising more vigilance, activity and energy.</p>
                    <p>Last, but not least, is the effect it will have upon the conduct of the
                        enemy. The finances of the enemy are now in a precarious condition, and
                        another pound put upon the back of the camel will break it down. The
                        following is the view of the Richmond Examiner upon this point:</p>
                    <p>The enemy's exultation over their recent achievements will be extravagant
                        enough; and the Federal Congress will be emboldened to enact all the
                        measures required by the war. The demand note bill will go through the
                        Senate with the legal tender clause; and the tax bill, levying a hundred and
                        fifty millions from the people, will become a law. Expenditures, which might
                        otherwise have been abstained from, will be boldly rushed into; and the
                        government will get more deeply involved in debt than ever.</p>
                    <p>If it had been possible before to save the Northern finances, it will not be
                        now. The government will take a new plunge into the sea of financial
                        trouble, and this time into deep waters that have no bottom. The legal
                        tender clause of their treasury note bill will cut down the wealth of the
                        entire creditor classes, and impose the chief burdens of the war, in the
                        most odious form, upon the men who have so far contributed to it the most
                        important aid. The rich will be disgusted by the unjust and unequal measure,
                        and the poor be burdened by the heaviest tax they have ever yet had to
                        shoulder. The bills enforcing these measures might have hung fire in the
                        Federal Congress for a long time, but for the brave news coming up to it
                        from Tennessee and North Carolina; they will now become laws, and the
                        Northern people be made to feel, in all its weight, the burden of debt which
                        their mad and bloody policy has imposed upon them forever.</p>
                    <p>It may, therefore, after all, be a kind Providence that has directed the
                        recent reverses of the South. If they be the means of plunging the enemy
                        still deeper into debt, and of securing the passage of measures which will
                        bring home the war to the pockets of the Northern people, they may prove
                        more fortunate in ultimate consequences than the many victories we gained to
                        the field. These victories incensed them, and combined the whole public
                        sentiment to support of the war. The successes they have now achieved will
                        somewhat soothe their exasperated feelings, while the losses and taxes
                        imposed by the new financial measures of Congress will tend to cool the
                        ardour with which they have urged on the war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article encourages Southerners to take heart in view of recent reverses on
                    the battlefield and asks that the soldiers re-enlist when their terms of service
                    expire. The article suggests that the enemy is plagued by financial woes and
                    cannot continue much longer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Now is the Time for Action</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserts that Southern victories while the North is reeling from
                    financial trouble are crucial to attract foreign symoathy and discourage the
                    North from continuing the fight.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Petitions-Distilleries</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Petitions are in circulation in this county praying the Legislature "speedily
                        to enact the necessary laws to suppress the consumption of grain in the
                        manufacture of spirituous liquour, on account of the numerous evils
                        resulting to the country, under existing circumstances, from the increase of
                        distilleries.["]</p>
                    <p>We have no doubt that these petitions will be numerously signed, as an
                        overwhelming majority of the people feel that some effective step should be
                        taken to prevent such immense quantities of corn and rye from being
                        converted from a blessing into a curse--from being changed from a supporter
                        into a destroyer of life. It is supposed that, in this county, FIFTY
                        THOUSAND bushels of grain are consumed monthly by the fifty or sixty
                        distilleries which are now in active operation. In Richmond, it is said,
                        that one large distillery there consumes a thousand bushels per day. As
                        liquor will command any price, the distilleries can afford to pay an
                        enormous price for grain, and the consequence will be that corn will become
                        so high in price that the poor will have to suffer, as they will not be able
                        to buy.</p>
                    <p>The Richmond Dispatch says that "the consumption of grain in North Carolina
                        for whiskey was so great, that the press predicts that corn will be worth $5
                        PER BUSHEL IN THE SUMMER, unless the distilleries are suppressed."</p>
                    <p>In reference to the traffic in ardent spirits at this time the same paper
                        says:</p>
                    <p>"The authorities ought to take this subject in hand. Sumptuary laws are in
                        general improper and odious, but in times of great public emergency like the
                        present, the sale of ardent spirits ought to be suppressed as a measure of
                        public safety and military discipline. The Southern Confederacy would be
                        better off if every drop of spirituous liquors now within its borders were
                        emptied into the sea. The Northern authorities seeing the havoc that hard
                        drinking was doing their armies, have taken strong measures to suppress it.
                        Here is one instance in which we may learn a valuable lesson from the enemy.
                        What can be done in this matter? Who will suggest the proper remedy for an
                        evil crying aloud for reform?"</p>
                    <p>"If there should be a scarcity of grain commencing in the spring, and the
                        next crop should fail, or not be a good one, what would be the dreadful
                        consequences? That possibility must be taken into view in considering this
                        question."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports the circulation of petitions seeking to ban the use of
                    grain for distilling liquors.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Return the Public Arms</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports a request by Col. E P. Alexander, Chief of Ordnance, C.S.A,
                    that all citizens in possession of Confederate arms return the immediately to
                    the ordnance office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>War Upon the "Perfidious Destroyer"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports that Brigadier Gen. Edward Johnson has banned liquor from
                    his 3rd Brigade in West Virginia. Gen. Johnston has issued similar orders at
                    Manassas.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Col. Wm. S. H. Baylor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that Col. Baylor is raising a regiment of infantry in Augusta
                    Co.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Military Organization</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A speech from Gov. Letcher outlining a plan for the defense of Virginia
                    cities and towns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Consumption of Corn - The Whiskey Distilleries</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article reports that the War Department will shortly issue an order
                    directing the seizure of all corn currently held for the purpose of distilling
                    liquor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn>John D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item repors that John D. Imboden will arrive soon to address the people on
                    war matters.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pinkerton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crane</ln>
                        <fn>Magnus S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Ella R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Marriage of Magnus Crane to Ella Sibert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Sophia Bell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Esmonia Bell</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Emanuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Long</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Death of Esmonia Long.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>By the Governor of Virginia. A Proclamation.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Proclamation by the Governor recommending the general draft of troops to
                    defend the approaches to cities and towns.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Deserter! $80 Reward.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Temple</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice offers reward for the return of William Temple, who deserted from
                    Camp Alleghany.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Head Quarters 100th Regiment Virginia Militia.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Notice calls for the asssembly of the members of the 100th at the Hastings
                    Court of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various reports from the battlefield including political and military
                developments. Fort Donelson and Roanoke Island among the battles reported. Col. 7
                local ads and notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.02.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Contributions for the Northwestern Virginia Refugees</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dover</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chittum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>D. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrd</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrd</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>Carrie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canter</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonser</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>A. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>G. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kider</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilmore</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>Mahala</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seybert</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matheny</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruckman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruckman</ln>
                        <fn>D. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bird</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Fannie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Kate</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of donations received for the refugee soldiers of the 31st regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Col. 1 continuation of Governor's proclamation regarding the militia draft.
                Reports of military maneuvers. Remainder of page ads and local notices.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
