<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.01.28">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/20/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-28">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.28.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Defeat near Somerset, Kentucky</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports a Confederate defeat at Fishing Creek, near Somerset, Kentucky. The
                    article criticizes Maj. Gen. Crittenden for being rash and imprudent and blames
                    him for the defeat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Sequestered</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blake</ln>
                        <fn>L.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hirah</ln>
                        <fn>Gabriel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brockenbrough</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that shoe store owner Blake returned to Massachusetts the
                    previous April leaving his stock of shoes with B.F. Points. A judge ruled
                    recently that the money is to be sequestered to the Confederate States.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Past and the Future</head>
                <origin>Augusta (GA) Constitutionalist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the agony of war but holds out hope for a peaceful and independent
                    future for the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Expense of Lincoln's Government</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the North is accumulating so massive a public debt that it
                    will eventually bankrupt the Union war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that two deserters from Ohio fled to Confederate lines. The men
                    declared they had only volunteered to fight in Ohio and were made to invade
                    Virginia against their will.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Crisis of the War</head>
                <origin>Augusta (GA) Constitutionalist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The <emph rend="italic">Augusta (Ga.) Constitutionalist</emph> says that the
                        Yankee scheme of Southern conquest is rapidly hastening to a <emph
                            rend="italic">denouement</emph> and to the Yankees it is a disastrous
                        one, indeed. They have already lost more than France lost by the calamitous
                        battle of Pavia; for they have lost their honor. What little <emph
                            rend="italic">prestige</emph> was left them after the Bull Run
                        catastrophe they ignominiously lost in the Mason and Slidell back down. Now,
                        the Yankee Government stands, with all its laurels won in honorable battle,
                        in the better days of the old Republic, tarnished and drooping--its
                        swaggering gait tamed down to the mincing step of the convicted
                        poltroon--its position irrevocably assigned, as morally on a par with the
                        vain-glorious little Republic of Spanish America.--Politically it will be in
                        time scarcely more powerful or influential; for the process of
                        disintegration, once begun, will not stop until what remains of the Northern
                        Confederation will end in half a dozen discordant organizations. </p>
                    <p>Now, the monster evil of a financial panic is upon the Yankee Government and
                        its people.--This is a more appalling enemy than Southern bayonets, for the
                        Yankees have shown their ability to get out of reach of the latter. But
                        there is no running away from debt and taxation. There is no escape from a
                        prostrate credit and a bankrupt Treasury. The army and navy must be
                        supported, or disbanded. The soldiers, sailors, and marines, officers and
                        men, with their myriads of adjuncts and satellites, contractors and camp
                        followers, have got to be fed and paid; and if they are not furnished with
                        Southern plunder, or pickings and stealings from the public crib, they will
                        turn upon private property of the North.</p>
                    <p>It is an ugly fix. The time is approaching when the Lincolnite dynasty will
                        be at a loss to know which most to fear--the armies of the South, or the
                        armies of the North. It will be easier to run from the one than to get rid
                        of the other.</p>
                    <p>But now is the very time for increased vigilance on the part of the South.
                        Now is the time for us to brace every nerve, and marshal every appliance for
                        the conflicts yet to come.</p>
                    <p>It would be folly to relax a muscle--to snatch a moment for repose. The
                        Yankees are in a death struggle for national honor, national safety,
                        national existence. They are infuriated, desperate, malignant. Like the
                        savage bear, or the broad antlered moose of their frozen regions, when
                        mortally wounded and at bay, they are most fierce and dangerous. At least,
                        the Yankee Government, in its extremity, may be looked to, to put forth its
                        most desperate efforts in this dying struggle. It <emph rend="italic"
                        >must</emph> achieve some success, to propitiate Wall street. It <emph
                            rend="italic">must</emph> make an advance, to appease popular clamor. It
                            <emph rend="italic">must</emph> display some capacity to retrieve its
                        great losses, to keep British fleets from off its coast. Even conceding, as
                        in its heart it must, that defeat and humiliation are to be its portion, the
                        opening of Southern ports to the commerce of the world, and its recognition
                        of the Southern Republic, events not to be staved off many months longer,
                        there is a necessity upon it to put forth now more Herculean efforts. It
                        must achieve something on which to retire from the contest with honor. It
                        must have something to show for the blood it has spilt and the money it has
                        squandered. Therefore, we look for more bloody work, and more "grand"
                        movements upon the Southern rebels, ere the contest flags and closes. We
                        would speak a word of caution against a false security--against looking
                        abroad for British fleets and armies to avert the coming blows.--What the
                        Yankees intend to do, they will try to do quickly. Therefore, be on the
                        alert, be vigilant--be ever ready; brave soldiers of the South, 'Once more
                        unto the breach, dear friends, once more.'</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that the Yankees have lost all prestige in the international
                    community and that debt will destroy the Northern war effort.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Confederate Senators</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the election of R.M.T. Hunter and William Ballard Preston to the
                    Confederate Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>North and South</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asserts that, if the secession of the South is unconstitutional, then the
                    coercion applied by the North is more so because such force is expressly
                    forbidden in the Constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Commendable Action of Gen. Bragg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Praises Gen. Bragg for banning the sale or introduction of liquor into
                    camps under his command. The article claims that this action "will do more than
                    all else in promoting the discipline and efficiency of his army."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The Prologue and the Performance</head>
                <origin>Nashville Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Not a paper at that time, which had the remotest idea of the conflict; not
                    a journalist, who rose to the emergencies of the occasion--all was passion, rant
                    and bombast. From the Chief Executive down to the lowest constable, the raging
                    idea of 'wiping out the South," "an easy conquest," and so on, went roaring,
                    like a prairie on fire, from right to left, from left to right, consuming all
                    before it. Even now they are not undeceived; but we do not despair of bringing
                    them to their senses by a few more lessons."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Banner quotes from various Northern newspaper to illustrate Northern
                    public opinion at the beginning of the war. The Banner sharply criticizes the
                    papers for their overconfidence.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Disobedience of Orders--One Soldier Killed--Another Mortally Wounded</head>
                <origin>Petersburg Express</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells of an incident at the Norfolk depot in which one Confederate soldier
                    was shot for disobeying a superior's command to remain on the train.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Donations</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bear</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siltington</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Siltington</ln>
                        <fn>M.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>M.V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N.K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shriver</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of donations received for northwestern Virginia refugee soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Writer lauds the leadership of General Garnett who commands the 1st
                    Brigade, also known as the Stonewall Brigade. This regiment has many Augusta
                    members.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Acknowledgements</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Black</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Calhoun</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists items donated to the soldiers at Camp Allegheny.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Volunteering</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article asserts that volunteering for the Southern forces is progressing at
                    a fast rate in both Mobile, Alabama and North Carolina.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houltz</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Freeman</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on January 23 in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 13 at age 78.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 25 near Pudding Spring at age 65.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 25 near Pudding Spring at age 60.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hickle</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 10 after a brief illness at age 17. Hickle was a member of
                    Capt. Yancey's Cavalry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farnow</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 4 at his residence in Lafayette, Montgomery County,
                    Virginia. Mr. Farnow was formerly of Augusta County. He died of typhoid fever at
                    age 40.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 23 at age 29 after a brief and severe illness. Clarke died
                    at Camp Allegheny and was a member of the 52nd Va. Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shane</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on January 5 at his residence on the headwaters of the Calf Pasture
                    river.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Broke Jail</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cunningham</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hicks</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Item reports that three men broke out of the Augusta County jail. William
                    Hicks was a deserter from the 52d Va. Regiment, Capt. Watkins' Company.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Several items of news regarding the war, including battlefield reports,
                national political developments, and telegraphic dispatches; advertisements and
                markets, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Hessian Vandalism in the Valley</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Romney, heretofore a beautiful village, is now but a wreck. Everything
                    looks desolated. All the public buildings, and many fine private residences,
                    were taken for soldiers' quarters, and the evidence of their presence is
                    everywhere to be found in the ruined condition of the houses. God grant that
                    they may yet meet the reward of their more than savage vandalism."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Details the burning and looting of Romney, Virginia by Union troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 2-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
