<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.10.14">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/23/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-10-14">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>14</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.14.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Military Exemption Act</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Delineates the occupations that will exempt men from serving in the
                    military, according to a bill that was recently passed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Much of the page is illegible, particularly the upper right-hand corner.
                Advertisements, columns 1-4; poem, response from the governor to a resolution of the
                House of Delegates, column 5; an official report from General Lee concerning
                military action near the Potomac, short articles on the reception of Lincoln's
                proclamation in Tennessee and on the sale of salt in the Kanawha Valley, excerpt
                from a letter from England supporting the Confederates, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.14.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Condition and Suffering of Our Army--Afford Relief</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges individual citizens to help supply Confederate soldiers with
                    blankets, clothes, and shoes so that they might survive the winter ahead.
                    Reprints part of a letter describing the hardships the army of Northern Virginia
                    has faced in the past three months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Illegible</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Imboden</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackburn</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Describes a skirmish involving Augusta troops and a Union raid upon a
                    baggage train in which some Augusta citizens were captured.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Soldier's Pay</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an act of Congress that enables soldiers to take their oath before
                    any quartermaster or authorized state officer. The officer is not allowed to
                    charge for administering the oath, which is a prerequisite for being paid.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Small-Pox in Danville</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports an outbreak of small pox in Danville, Virginia. Four people have
                    died, and three new cases have been discovered in the last week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>To Our Subscribers</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the Spectator will increase subscription rates owing to the
                    increased cost of production. The Spectator will also require payment in cash.
                    Subscribers will not be charged for periods when the paper was suspended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Distribution of Salt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers of the locations that have been approved as distribution
                    sites for salt. Notes that further information on prices and the time when the
                    salt should be ready for delivery will be released shortly. Warns readers that
                    anyone charging more than the fixed rate for salt, which is still to be
                    determined, will be charged with a misdemeanor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Jno. J. Crittenden on Emancipation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts a letter written by John Crittenden that expresses opposition to
                    turning the war into a war for the abolition of slavery rather than a war for
                    Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Is not the heart of every man and woman moved who possess one spark of
                    human kindness when they witness the ragged and deplorable condition of many of
                    our soldiers?"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Mr. Editor:--Allow me through this medium of your paper, to enquire what has
                        become of the Soldier's Aid Societies of our county? One year ago they were
                        doing good service by furnishing our soldiers with many essential and
                        indispensable articles of clothing, and no doubt made glad the hearts of us
                        brave men who were in the tented field, exposing their health and lives for
                        the sake of the dear ones at home, and for all that is dear to them and us,
                        our National Independence. Alas! I am pained to say that with many or all of
                        these societies, apathy and indifference seems to have taken the places of
                        effort and kind feelings, so prevalent twelve months ago. I appeal to my
                        countrymen and countrywomen, to arouse from the seeming lethargy they have
                        fallen into, revive and resucitate [sic] the various Soldier's Aid and
                        Relief Societies of the county, enter into the obligation due our brave men
                        without delay, shape them into garments suitable for the soldiers whose
                        necessities are crying aloud for relief. Is not the heart of every man and
                        woman moved who possess one spark of human kindness when they witness the
                        ragged and deplorable condition of many of our soldiers? It is a shame and
                        reproach to our Government to thus neglect [illegible] brave defenders.</p>
                    <p>A FARMER.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>A Farmer</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Prints a letter in which "A Farmer" urges citizens to revive Soldier's Aid
                    Societies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>War Debt of the North</head>
                <origin>New York Herald</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Article alleges a huge and crippling Northern war debt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect to the Memory of Col. W. S. H. Baylor</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn>N. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prints the resolutions adopted by the Independent Order of Odd Fellows on
                    the death of Colonel William Baylor. The resolutions express the Order's respect
                    for Colonel Baylor. N. K. Trout reported the resolutions and preamble at the
                    meeting.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Lydia Maria Child on Amalgamation</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary>"Such a beastly proposition deserves no comment."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Excerpts a letter written for the New York Tribune by Lydia Maria Child
                    arguing that "amalgamation" between the races will not occur if a "natural
                    antipathy" exists between blacks and whites. Child points out, however, that
                    when the races have "been brought into vicinity" they have mixed freely,
                    generally because whites have desired it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Thanks</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Wm. McChesney</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William McChesney, army surgeon, expresses his appreciation to Reverend
                    Messers. Latane, Phillips, and Wheat, and to "the kind ladies of Staunton" for
                    the kindness they showed to wounded soldiers when they were in the area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>H. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maggie A. Gilkeson, age 13 years, died of diphtheria on September 30. She
                    was the second daughter of D. C. and H. N. Gilkeson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Many portions of the page have been inked out. Report on the battle at
                Corinth, column 3; details of the second battle at Corinth, tally of deaths from and
                new cases of yellow fever in Wilmington, North Carolina, column 4; General Lee's
                address to his army, more news from Corinth, brief article on the fight at Franklin
                in Southampton County, column 5; a letter to the Spectator from an army chaplain
                with about half the text blotted out, column 6; advertisements and market report,
                column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
