<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.11.04">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>10/10/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 10/26/98</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-11-04">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="11">November</month>
            <day norm="04">4</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.11.04.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Important General Orders</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Orders businesses in Charleston, a western Virginia town, to reopen in
                    order to serve the needs of the soldiers who are returning to the Kanawha
                    Valley. Brigadier General Echols also warns shopkeepers that they must accept
                    Confederate money, and at face value. A second order commands that the
                    conscription act be enforced in Kanawha County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Laws Passed</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the acts recently passed by Congress regarding the army, the
                    treasury, treasury notes, and sick and wounded soldiers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poetry and fiction, columns 4-6; article from the
                Columbus, Georgia, Times that profiles the three leading Southern generals, column
                6; anecdotes, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.11.04.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Uses of Economy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"It matters not that we have a plethora of money, or that there be an
                    abundance elsewhere to supply our lack, when we are excluded from the markets of
                    the world, and are compelled to rely upon what we have within ourselves."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is every reason to believe, from present appearances, says the
                        Lynchburg Virginian, that we shall be short of supplies for one army and
                        people next year. The short crop of when and corn for the past year, the
                        fatality that has attended the hog crop; the waste superinduced by large
                        standing waste superinduced by large standing armies; the drought which has
                        retarded the Fall operations of farmers in getting their wheat sown, and the
                        embarrassments that the agricultural portion of our citizens have suffered,
                        in consequence of the presence of the enemy, and the demand made upon them
                        by our Governments, State and Confederate, will we fear, be manifest in a
                        short supply of bread and meat next year. It believes us therefore to
                        observe the greatest frugality and economy in the use of what we have. It
                        matters not that we have a plethora of money, or that there be an abundance
                        elsewhere to supply our lack, when we are excluded from the markets of the
                        world, and are compelled to rely upon what we have within ourselves. Money
                        cannot produce one grain of corn, or increase by one pound, our quantity of
                        meat. Our supply will be limited by the circumstances that surround us, and
                        to that, whether much or little, we must contine [sic] ourselves. We cannot
                        increase it by the ordinary means of commercial intercourse. Under these
                        circumstances, we are called upon to husband our resources of bread and
                        meat, by the diminution, so far as practicable, of consumption. We should
                        stint ourselves, and those who have spread a bounteous board heretofore,
                        should, no matter what their means may be, endeavor to do with less.
                        Thousands of our gallant soldiers who were nursed in the lap of plenty, and
                        brought up in the midst of affluence, have known what it was to go for days
                        together without a meal:--and cannot we, to increase the stores that may be
                        necessary for their sustenance in the field, endure some little of their
                        patient self-denial? We can do with much less than we consume, and instead
                        of priding ourselves upon spreading an ample board, groaning with every
                        luxury, we should feel a sense of reproach for indulging in such
                        improprieties. This is no time for feasting and high carnival, but for
                        earnest self-denial, and abounding patriotism and charity. Our suffering
                        countrymen, and the dependent families they have committed to our care
                        whilst they are fighting our battles, demand that we appropriate less to
                        ourselves, and more to those who would be glad to gather the crumbs that
                        fall from many of our tables. The season, the condition of the country, the
                        wants of those to whom we have referred, and the prospect before us, all
                        call upon us, trumpet-tongued, to forego every species of luxury during the
                        existence of this war.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Blames the drought and the blockade for the shortages that the Confederacy
                    will likely suffer in the coming year. Urges citizens to be conservative in
                    their consumption so that the men in the field and their families at home will
                    have more to eat.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Small Pox</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This dangerous and loathsome disease has made its appearance in this county.
                        We have been informed that there are some cases in the neighborhood of
                        Middlebrook, and that it exists in other portions of the county. To prevent
                        its extension, every family, without exception, should have all of its
                        members vaccinated as soon as possible. Those even who have been vaccinated
                        heretofore should be vaccinated again to make "assurance doubly sure." The
                        citizens of his place are very apprehensive that it may be brought from the
                        country to the town, and we would, therefore, request our country friends to
                        be careful not to bring it here, for, as soldiers are passing daily through
                        this place to the army, it may in this way get into our army and do us more
                        harm than all the soldiers Lincoln has been able to bring into the field
                        against us. Therefore, in behalf of our common country as well as of the
                        citizens of Staunton, we appeal to our country, friends not to bring this
                        horrible disease to this place.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that small pox has "made its appearance in this county." Entreats
                    residents to have their families vaccinated and those who live in the country to
                    be especially careful not to introduce the disease into the town of Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Burglary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that an unknown person broke into the grocery store owned by Mr.
                    Samuel Hartley of Staunton the previous Sunday night. The burglar stole about
                    fifty pounds of sugar, ten dollars, Mr. Hartley's coat, and some brooms.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Confederate Notes</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is evidently some distrust in the public mind, of Confederate money.
                        This is one cause of the spirit of speculation and high prices, by which
                        public and private interests are injured.</p>
                    <p>We are inclined to think this distrust is without any just foundation. If we
                        secure our independence our currency will be perfectly good--if not, nothing
                        that we have will be of value.</p>
                    <p>But there is one view to which we would call the attention of the public. If
                        the rumors of intervention be tree, or if from any other cause an early
                        peace should become probable, it is evident that the eight per cent bonds
                        will be a most desirable investment. Capitalists will at once seek for them.
                        Confederate money is available to buy them at par, while Bank notes will not
                        necessarily be so. The 8 per cent bonds under a brisk demand, will go above
                        par, and Confederate notes will keep pace with them, because they are, by
                        law, convertible into 8 per cent bonds. By this process, millions upon
                        millions of dollars of Confederate notes will be withdrawn from circulation
                        and invested in bonds. A sudden contraction of the currency will be the
                        consequence, followed by a fall in prices, and a general smash in
                        speculations. On the whole we think people had better be on the look out for
                        squalls and haul in their sails before the storm comes. Prudence will also
                        dictate that men should hold on to Confederate money as it is likely to be
                        at a premium.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Predicts that if the Confederate government is recognized by European
                    nations, the value of Confederate currency will increase greatly. Reasons that
                    if this happens, the distrust of individuals in Confederate money will be proven
                    to have been unfounded.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>The Destruction of Roads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Confederate troops have destroyed the railroads that link
                    the Valley with Baltimore and other points of supply. As a result, if the
                    Northern army re-occupies the Valley during the winter, "they will have to
                    furnish other means of transportation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates details of a meeting held in Churchville, in which citizens of the
                    Ninth Magesterial District made plans to assist the poor during the winter
                    ahead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plumb</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bazel</ln>
                        <fn>Jas. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitmore</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branneman</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carroll</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bateman</ln>
                        <fn>Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trainer</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branneman</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coiner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antrim</ln>
                        <fn>George T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lutz</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesel</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesel</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Fulton W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kilman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trayner</ln>
                        <fn>Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Galt</ln>
                        <fn>James K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Colner</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Evans</ln>
                        <fn>William O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Francis E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowen</ln>
                        <fn>William F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Alexander</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ash</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Killian</ln>
                        <fn>Cyrus M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>George F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Monteiro</ln>
                        <fn>Walter A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keiser</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Fulton W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mathews</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCausland</ln>
                        <fn>Henry C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelly</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Whitesel</ln>
                        <fn>David H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corporal</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fredd</ln>
                        <fn>Martin V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCreary</ln>
                        <fn>Marion F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baskins</ln>
                        <fn>John L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guthrie</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spotts</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Alex E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCord</ln>
                        <fn>George H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the casualties from Company H in the 5th Va. Inf. who have been
                    killed or injured, or have died of disease, since the war began. Company H was
                    formerly commanded by Captain Antrim and is now led by Captain Gibson of Augusta
                    County. The total number of killed are eleven, total number wounded, twenty
                    nine. Twelve have died from disease, making a total casualty list of fifty two.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>From a Soldier</head>
                <origin>Rockingham Register</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Extracts a letter from a soldier discussing the destruction of the B
                    &amp; O Railroad and the cold weather that is beginning to set in.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Peyton</ln>
                        <fn>J. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>George</ln>
                        <fn>H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>M. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bryan</ln>
                        <fn>Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snyder</ln>
                        <fn>Lucy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Fanny</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>C. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>Ednora</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Joe</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>James</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>S. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merrillat</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hay</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davidson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oder&gt;</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bronaugh</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodley</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bond</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nathan</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Holt</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>G. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Captain</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Legrand</ln>
                        <fn>W. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blockley</ln>
                        <fn>M. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the citizens who contributed to the Hospital Library fund and the
                    amounts each donated.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloch</ln>
                        <fn>Lizzie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloch</ln>
                        <fn>D. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCulloch</ln>
                        <fn>Sue M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lizzie McCulloch, aged two years, died on October 9. She was the only
                    daughter of D. C. and Sue M. McCulloch.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCadden</ln>
                        <fn>John H. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John H. C. McCadden, of Augusta County, died in Moorefield on October 18 of
                    diphtheria. He was eighteen years old and a member of the First Virginia
                    Regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibson</ln>
                        <fn>Mary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raceor</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Raceor</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Raceor died in Staunton on October 23 at the home of Mrs. Mary
                    F. Gibson. She was the wife of James Raceor of Orange County, Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>Simon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Simon Stover, aged 81 years, died at his home near Churchville on October
                    31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strayer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strayer</ln>
                        <fn>Albert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Albert W. Strayer, aged about 34 years, died at the home of his father,
                    Jacob Strayer, Esq., of Rockingham County, on October 25. Strayer had suffered
                    from "a protracted illness of pulmonary consumption."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of the Confederate army's retreat from the Kanawha Valley, column 1;
                brief news items, columns 2, 3, and 4; lists of letters remaining in the Staunton
                post office, column 6; advertisements, columns 6 and 7; markets, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
