<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.10.21">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/23/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton Spectator</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-10-21">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="10">October</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.21.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation</head>
                <origin>Memphis Bulletin</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Emphasizes the contradictions between Lincoln's issuance of the
                    Emancipation Proclamation and a speech the President gave in which he declared
                    that an executive proclamation could not have any effect in freeing the slaves.
                    The article also points out that Congress passed a resolution in February of
                    1861 asserting that Congress has no right to interfere with slavery where it
                    exists. Finally, the Bulletin quotes Lincoln's assurances that he has no
                    intention to interfere with slavery in the slaveholding states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Loss in Company "C," 5th Va. Regt.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dale</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ponge</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craun</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>Washington</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rupe</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newman</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieutenant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gambol</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordan</ln>
                        <fn>L. Granville</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>R. Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>G. Lanck</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>T. Peter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byers</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rives</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houff</ln>
                        <fn>B. Franklin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sergeant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frames</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>Emory</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bush</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goins</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curry</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cress</ln>
                        <fn>Milton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pumfrey</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litten</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tutwiler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shiflett</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deaver</ln>
                        <fn>J. Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fridley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hartney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kidd</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>Madison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rankin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Harrison</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists members of Company C of the Fifth Virginia Regiment, formerly led by
                    Captain Robert L. Doyle, who have been killed or wounded, or have died from
                    disease since the war began. Killed in action were Lieutenant Dale, John Ponge,
                    John A. Craun, Washington Reed, Robert M. Doyle, Thomas Beard, and George Rupe.
                    The wounded are Lieutenant Andrew Newman, William H. Gambol, L. Granville
                    Jordan, R. Milton Wilson, G. Lanck Hamrick, T. Peter Bell, Alexander Bell,
                    Thomas Bell, James Bell, Saumel Byers, Thomas Rives, Sergeant B. Franklin Houff,
                    George Frames, Emory Bush, John Bush, William Goins, William Curry, John
                    Douglas, Milton Cress, John Pumfrey, John F. Litten, George Tutwiler, Samuel
                    Shiflett, R. M. Brown, J. Newton Deaver, James Horry, Jacob S. Sheets, ----
                    Fridley, ---- Hartney, and Edward Kidd. In addition, Madison Hogshead, John W.
                    Wright, John B. Rankin, and Harrison Thompson have died from disease.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Advertisements, columns 1-3; poetry and fiction, column 4; fiction continued,
                column 5; official dispatch from General Lee concerning the capture of federal
                soldiers by Colonel Imboden, summary of the appropriations bill, article from
                Greenville in East Tennessee reporting the expression of loyalty to the Confederate
                States that was adopted by the Cumberland Presbyterian Church, report on the
                Maryland campaign, column 6; list of boxes at Staunton that belong to members of the
                52nd Virginia, short news items, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.10.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Blankets, Clothes, &amp;c., for our Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges citizens to contribute blankets and clothing to Confederate soldiers
                    who face a winter without adequate shelter or coverings.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>General Stuart's Dashing Exploit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At Chambersburg, General Stuart destroyed public property in the amount of
                    $200,000, in which were 700,000 cartridges, 700 muskets, and a quantity of
                    shells, powder, etc. . . . Private property was not taken or destroyed."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>This distinguished and gallant cavalry officer has again astonished and
                        electrified the public by another dashing "circumbendibus" entirely around
                        the enormous army of Gen'l. McClellan Now take the map and trace the route
                        of his glorious and triumphant gallopade around the large and boastful army
                        of the enemy. He crossed near Williamsport and, going North, first passed
                        thro' Mercersburg, in Franklin county, Pennsylvania, then going North-East
                        he went to Chambersburg, the county seat of Franklin county, then going
                        South-East he went to Emmettsburg, near the Northern boundary of Frederick
                        county, Maryland, then continuing in the same direction he went to Liberty
                        in the same county, then South to New Market, also in Frederick, then in the
                        same direction to Hyattstown in Montgomery co., Maryland, then bearing
                        South-West to Barnesville in the same county, near which place he re-crossed
                        the Potomac and returned to Winchester without the loss of a single man. The
                        following is General Lee's brief despatch to the Secretary of War:</p>
                    <p>Winchester, Va., <lb/>October 14, 1862. </p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Hon. G. W. Randolph</emph>: </p>
                    <p>The cavalry expedition to Pennsylvania has returned safe. They passed through
                        Mercersburg, Chambersburg, Emmitsburg, Liberty, New Market, Hyattstown, and
                        Barnesville. The expedition crossed the Potomac above Williamsport, and
                        recrossed at White's Ford, making the entire circuit, cutting the enemy's
                        communications, destroying arms, &amp;c., and obtaining many recruits.</p>
                    <p>R. E. Lee, General.</p>
                    <p>General Stuart passed through a portion of the wealthiest part of
                        Pennsylvania. The towns in Pennsylvania through which he passed--Mercersburg
                        and Chambersburg--as before stated, are situated in Franklin, a county which
                        contains a population of more than 40,000. From the Richmond "Whig" we learn
                        that most of the country is a rich lime-stone valley, well watered. The
                        productions in 1850 were 837,000 bushels of wheat (the greatest quantity
                        produced by any county of the State, except Lancaster,) 539,976 of Indian
                        corn, 393,447 of oats, 33,591 tons of hay, 67,546 lbs butter, and 44,192 of
                        wool. The number of horses and mules in the county in 1850, [in round
                        numbers] was 9,000, neat cattle 22,000, sheep, 14,000, swine 35,000.</p>
                    <p>Chambersburg the county seat has a population of about 5,000. It is situated
                        45 miles south west of Harrisburg, and is a thriving place. The houses are
                        mostly of brick or stone, and the general appearance of the town is neat and
                        comfortable. There are manufactories of cotton, wood, flour, paper, and iron
                        in and near the town.</p>
                    <p>Mercersburg is fifteen miles south west of Chambersburg. The population is
                        about 1,400. It is the seat of Marshall College, which was founded in 1836,
                        under the direction of the German Reformed Church.</p>
                    <p>The object of this exploit we could not tell if we would, and we would not if
                        we could. It is sufficient for us to know that it was done for a
                        purpose.--What that purpose was will be developed at the proper time. In his
                        route General Stuart cut the enemy's communication, destroyed many arms and
                        a large amount of stores, and brought away 2,000 horses, without losing a
                        man.</p>
                    <p>At Chambersburg General Stuart destroyed public property to the amount of
                        $200,000, in which were 700,000 cartridges, 700 muskets, a quantity of
                        shells, powder, &amp;c. He found one car loaded with revolvers, which
                        were appropriated by his men. Private property was not taken nor destroyed.</p>
                    <p>Besides doing these things, General Stuart captured a number of prisoners,
                        fifty-one of whom arrived here on Sunday evening last, on their way to
                        Richmond.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relates that General Stuart has returned from an expedition into
                    Pennsylvania, where he and his men passed through Franklin County, cutting
                    federal communication lines, destroying arms, and appropriating about 2,000
                    horses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An item from the Cleveland (Tenn.) Banner in which the paper wishes to buy
                    a hunting dog so the editors can supply their meat needs. The Spectator looks
                    with dismay that the editor of a paper would be reduced to relying on a possum
                    dog for support owing to the delinquency of subscription payments.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Sentiment in Northwestern Virginia</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We hope the time will speedily arrive when the yoke of oppression will be
                    lifted from the galled necks of the loyal people of that section."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Relays the opinion of a "gentleman" recently traveling in Northwestern
                    Virginia that the people in that section of the state support the South.
                    Speculates that the Pierpont government fears an uprising of the people in the
                    area.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Disastrous Railroad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item reports an accident six miles west of Charlottesville involving a
                    train carrying soldiers. Five soldiers and two slaves were killed, and over
                    seventy people were injured. Lists the names of those who were killed or
                    seriously hurt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Then and Now</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes Seward as remarking in 1861 that disturbing the slavery system is
                    unconstitutional.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Yankee Outrages in Missouri</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They are bearing down upon the citizens with a much tighter rein, taking
                    from them teir farms, dwellings, and daily avocations, at pleasure, and for the
                    slightest cause."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Accuses federal troops in Missouri of confiscating property and arresting
                    citizens merely on suspicion of wrong-doing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Sacrifices for the War</head>
                <origin>Mobile Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Provides an account from Butler County, Alabama, of the sacrifices that men
                    and women at home are making. Women of all ages, and even those who own no
                    slaves at all, are laboring in the fields and making other sacrifices for the
                    Confederate cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>Lexington Gazette</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Item says that the ladies of Rockbridge plan to send a wagon of supplies to
                    Staunton every Thursday for the sick and wounded at the hospital there.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pelter</ln>
                        <fn>Sampson</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf>Mr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Sallie F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Sampson Pelter, Jr., and Miss Sallie F. Hanger were married in August
                    in Waynesboro. Miss Hanger is the daughter of William S. Hanger, Esq., all of
                    Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Brief news items, columns 1 and 2; report of a victory in Kentucky, column 3;
                various news items including reports on the battle in Kentucky, column 5;
                advertisements and notices, column 7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
