<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.04.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Sarah Roth</taggerName>
            <tagDate>9/21/98</tagDate>
            <tagNote>First pass</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-04-08">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="08">8</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.04.08.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Our Enemies</head>
                <origin>Memphis Appeal</origin>
                <commentary>"We think our home enemies are worse and more detestable than the
                    Yankees themselves:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Confederate States have three distinct classes of enemies, which the
                        Memphis Appeal forcibly describes as follows. We think our home enemies are
                        worse and more detestable than the Yankees themselves:--</p>
                    <p>1. The Government and people of the United States are our enemies. But they
                        are open enemies. They meet us upon the field with arms in their hands, and
                        make war upon us. They shoot down our soldiers, burn our houses, destroy our
                        property, and steal our negroes. We know where to find and how to deal with
                        such an enemy.</p>
                    <p>2. The second class of enemies are the croakers--the long faced men of faint
                        hearts and weak nerves, who go up and down the country, seeking to impart
                        their own despondency and cowardice to all with whom they come in
                        contact.--Everything goes wrong, according to these Dismal Jemmies. The
                        government is weak and negligent; our officers are lacking in skill; and the
                        army is destitute of courage. If the government has done its duty, this or
                        that thing would not have happened. If the officers had possessed a grain of
                        foresight, they could have held this or that position against the enemy.
                        Nothing is done right, according to these gentry, and everything goes wrong.</p>
                    <p>The enemy will certainly overrun the country; the Confederate government will
                        fail; and we will all go to perdition together. If they only had charge of
                        affairs, how smoothly and successfully everything would move. Arms would be
                        procured immediately; an army would be improvised in the twinkling of an
                        eye; and the enemy--McClellan, Buell, Halleck, and all--would be driven out
                        of the country the first pleasant day that came. Napoleon would still be the
                        "little corporal" by the side of these wonderful warriors--the mighty men of
                        valor.--Weak of purpose, faint of heart, and cowardly in spirit, they would
                        destroy the confidence of every body else and abandon every thing to the
                        Federals. We would suggest to have petticoats put upon these miserable
                        creatures, and curls hung about their craven foreheads, but for the insult
                        we should thereby offer to our brave women.</p>
                    <p>3. The speculators and extortioners constitute the third class of enemies.
                        These characters operate upon the necessities of the country.--They are
                        interested in the war, insomuch as it enables them to make money. Beyond
                        this, they care but little who wins or who loses.--They set no fixed price
                        upon what they have to sell. Their price is all they can get. The purchaser
                        may be a poor man, a needy woman, a destitute soldier, or the widow of some
                        brave fellow who has fallen in battle with his feet to the foe. Still, if
                        the extortioner can grind out of her five dollars per bushel for salt, he
                        takes it; if ten dollars, he takes it; if a thousand dollars, still he would
                        take it. As between him and a Lincolnite, we have infinitely more respect
                        for the latter. The one is an open enemy, and meets you on the field; the
                        other is a secret foe who takes advantage of your necessities, and seeks to
                        undermine the cause by oppressing the people and sapping the foundations of
                        our strength.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Lists the enemies of the Confederate cause, including not only the United
                    States government, but also Southern critics of the Confederate government and
                    army. Speculators who are amassing large profits from their countrymen in time
                    of war constitute the third group of enemies of the Confederacy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>No Additional Particulars</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Spectator has not received any more information about the
                    fight at Kearnstown. The paper awaits a list of the casualties suffered by the
                    5th regiment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the president has extended martial law over Greenbrier,
                    Pocahontas, Bath, Alleghany, Monroe, Raleigh, Fayette, Nicholas, and Randolph
                    Counties in Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Kernstown</head>
                <origin>Richmond Whig</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Fatigued, worn out, the little band of patriots 'attacked at once and
                    furiously' the huge enemy before them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that Jackson made a successful attack against the enemy at
                    Kernstown, despite the fact that his men were outnumbered five to one and had
                    marched forty-five miles in a day and a half.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>An Appeal for Bells</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"No bell in our Confederacy has ever chimed more sweetly or more acceptably
                    to Heaven than, when cast into cannon, it shall send its deep-throated
                    denunciations against the murderous invaders who come hither to despoil us of
                    our inheritance and to deprive us of our liberties, our religion and our homes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Asks that bells be donated to the war effort so that they may be melted and
                    recast into cannon. Lists the locations where the bells may be sent.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Prisoners Taken by the Enemy at the Fight at Kearnstown</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farrel</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsyth</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arlen</ln>
                        <fn>Stephen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>E.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Addison</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hester</ln>
                        <fn>Charles H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Albright</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Drinner</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Washington</ln>
                        <fn>Bushrod</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trills</ln>
                        <fn>Elliot</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Warner</ln>
                        <fn>Tanner</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lyle</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harsberger</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>T.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jenkin</ln>
                        <fn>G.G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>J.T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferrel</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleminans</ln>
                        <fn>Jno. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maddox</ln>
                        <fn>Weadon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyd</ln>
                        <fn>T.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wade</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sergeant</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkes</ln>
                        <fn>C.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morrison</ln>
                        <fn>H.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scanlin</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shawan</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rollins</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Graham</ln>
                        <fn>J.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pollock</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>S.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>H.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lucas</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMahan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waithell</ln>
                        <fn>L.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>T.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saunders</ln>
                        <fn>M.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cassady</ln>
                        <fn>H.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shank</ln>
                        <fn>J.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>J.F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowler</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKenney</ln>
                        <fn>F.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connan</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foley</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fleming</ln>
                        <fn>Ed.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Radcliffe</ln>
                        <fn>Chas. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lindewald</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brannard</ln>
                        <fn>L.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowman</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>Benj.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noland</ln>
                        <fn>Laurence</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Konner</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Debrush</ln>
                        <fn>A.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gardner</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Benry</ln>
                        <fn>W.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Connely</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lutz</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towler</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrington</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sanderson</ln>
                        <fn>G.L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leorrer</ln>
                        <fn>W.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Erwenbook</ln>
                        <fn>W.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scratheld</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>C.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMann</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Richardson</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dagan</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oliver</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCall</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arbert</ln>
                        <fn>W.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>G.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>J.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kellogg</ln>
                        <fn>W.R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burress</ln>
                        <fn>J.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cawer</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Adams</ln>
                        <fn>P.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barton</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gast</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCarty</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>D.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Antler</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Overley</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Voohees</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conley</ln>
                        <fn>J.P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Oliver</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hortsick</ln>
                        <fn>S.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Byrus</ln>
                        <fn>S.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noland</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Lorenzo</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Floyd</ln>
                        <fn>Marion</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Click</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McBride</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pendleton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conway</ln>
                        <fn>P.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruff</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witcher</ln>
                        <fn>James S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davenport</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farner</ln>
                        <fn>J.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heller</ln>
                        <fn>A.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bright</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Witmore</ln>
                        <fn>W.D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrews</ln>
                        <fn>C.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>W.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brandon</ln>
                        <fn>Thos. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrell</ln>
                        <fn>Chas.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Legg</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hawkins</ln>
                        <fn>D.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Rob't</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bonham</ln>
                        <fn>J.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>J.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barton</ln>
                        <fn>Ran.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haupst</ln>
                        <fn>Simeon</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>C.E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langhorne</ln>
                        <fn>J.H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn>L.W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conklin</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hand</ln>
                        <fn>W.A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Silver</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frederic</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Searns</ln>
                        <fn>Nat.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shilling</ln>
                        <fn>Wm.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Field</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cormack</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Elley</ln>
                        <fn>Robert W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cale</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lady</ln>
                        <fn>J.B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>J.J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kelley</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCartney</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henerkerhouse</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reprints a list from the Baltimore American of Confederates taken prisoner
                    at Kearnstown. The paper states that it cannot vouch for the list's accuracy,
                    since it contains the names of Col. Echols and others who the editor knows were
                    not taken prisoner.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Don't Despond</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We may have reverses and disasters, but brave hearts can bear them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reminds the Confederate people that their ancestors prevailed even when
                    Richmond was captured in the Revolution and Washington was taken in the War of
                    1812. Expresses confidence that the Confederates will succeed in their cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Free Fighters</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At a meeting held at the Court-house on Saturday last, with the view to the
                        organization of a regiment or battalion of Free-Fighters for the defence of
                        the Valley, BENJ. CRAWFORD was called to the Chair, and L. Waddell, Jr.,
                        appointed Secretary. The objects of the meeting were explained by Col.
                        Kenton Harper in a few brief but highly patriotic remarks, who submit the
                        following.</p>
                    <p>Plan of Organization:</p>
                    <p>1st. The object of this organization, which is to be composed of men not
                        subject to military duty, is the defence of our rights and our homes, and is
                        intended to co-operate with and form a part of the Army of the Shenandoah..</p>
                    <p>2d. While on duty it's all be governed by strict military rules. This is
                        indispensable to its efficiency. As patriot soldiers, we consent to subject
                        ourselves to personal restraints for the day that we may be free forever.</p>
                    <p>3d. The tender of our services at any time will be for a limited period, but
                        we shall hold ourselves ready to respond promptly to any call of the General
                        commanding to meet an exigency.</p>
                    <p>4th, The companies composing the command shall consist of not less than
                        fifty, rank and file, with one Captain and three Lieutenants, and shall be
                        mounted and armed in the most effective manner with rifles or muskets. Any
                        number of men too infirm for regular duty may be attached as honorary
                        members, with the privilege of fighting in the ranks.</p>
                    <p>5th, The drill shall be that of Light Troops of Skirmishers, the men to be
                        dismounted for battle, and the horses used only to relieve the march, and to
                        pass rapidly from point to point, as the necessities of the service may
                        require.</p>
                    <p>This plan was unanimously approved; whereupon the following resolutions were
                        adopted:</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That a committee of six be appointed for each magisterial district
                        of the county, to enroll members of the organization and receive
                        subscriptions in money, and provisions, and also the loan of arms and horses
                        for the equipment of such as are not able to furnish themselves.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That it be it recommended to the committees in the different
                        districts to organize the members they may enroll into companies as rapidly
                        as possible.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That all monies subscribed by citizens too infirm to engage in the
                        service, and others, together with all monies arising from fines imposed,
                        shall be equitably distributed, by the Council of Administration, to be
                        appointed by the commanding officer for the relief of such members as may
                        need assistance, from sickness, or other cause, while in the service.</p>
                    <p>Resolved, That when the meeting adjourns it will adjourn to meet at this
                        place on Saturday next (12th inst.,) at 2 o'clock.</p>
                    <p>Under the first resolution the following committees were appointed, and the
                        meeting adjourned to meet again on Saturday next.</p>
                    <p>Staunton District No. 1--Henry Harrison, L. R. Waddell, C. C. Francisco, D.
                        S. Young, Col. Wm. P. Tate, Col. Geo. Baylor, J. W. Be_, Capt. R. H.
                        Phillips.</p>
                    <p>No. 2.--Jno. Trimble, Wm. A. Bell, Alex. Anderson, B. F. Points, Geo. W.
                        Feller and Dr. W. B. Young.</p>
                    <p>Waynesboro'-- __ Bruce, Jno. B. Smith, W. W. King, Francis M. Finley, G. B.
                        Stuart and H. L. Gallaher.</p>
                    <p>Fishersville--Col. F. McCue, John Hamilton, Col. S. B. Coyner, Phillip
                        Schumucker, Col. D. S. Bell and Thos. Turk.</p>
                    <p>New Hope.--Jas. M. Stout, Dr. J. A. Waddell, Wm. Patterson, H. J. Crawford,
                        Col. Samuel Finley and Geo. Mowry.</p>
                    <p>Mt. Sidney.--Kenton Harper, Robert Guy, Thos. P. Wilson, Capt. Jno. C. Webb,
                        John C. McCue and Wm. Crawford.</p>
                    <p>Churchville--G. J. Hite, N. Hotchkiss, W. W. Montgomery, W. M. Dudley, Rev.
                        D. W. Arnold, R. J. Glendy and Ken Craig.</p>
                    <p>Spring Hill.--John A. Patterson, Jacob Streekhise, D. Theopholis Gamole, U.
                        D. Poe, Dr. Ro. Gamble and Wm. Howell.</p>
                    <p>Mt. Salon.--Col. J. M. McCue, Gen. Messersmith, J. G. Fulten, Richard H.
                        Dudley, Hatch Clark, and Chesley Kenney.</p>
                    <p>Middlebrook.--Jacob Baylor, Dr. McChesney, Wm. Dunlap, David Baylor, Capt.
                        David Martin, and James Buchanan.</p>
                    <p>Greenville.--John Newton, Jas. Bumgardner, Capt. Jas. Henry, Schuyler
                        Bradley, Jas. Henderson and John Churchman.</p>
                    <p>B. Crawford, President.</p>
                    <p>L. Waddell, Jr., Sec.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>Kenton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harrison</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Francisco</ln>
                        <fn>C. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burr</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>R. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tremble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Anderson</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Points</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Butler</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>W. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>King</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Francis M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>G. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallaher</ln>
                        <fn>H. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coyner</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmucker</ln>
                        <fn>Philip</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stout</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>J. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>H. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Webb</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hite</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>W. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnold</ln>
                        <fn>D. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grundy</ln>
                        <fn>R. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Ken</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Streckhise</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Theopholis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poe</ln>
                        <fn>U. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>Ro.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howell</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCue</ln>
                        <fn>J.M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>Richard H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Hatch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kenney</ln>
                        <fn>Chesley</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Martin</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Churchman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bradley</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on a meeting held in Staunton to organize various companies of
                    "Free-Fighters," whose purpose will be to defend the Shenandoah Valley from
                    invaders. Lists the members appointed to the committees that were formed for
                    each district.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>For the Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>M.</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doyle</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Randall</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Recounts details of the battle at Kernstown and describes the involvement
                    of soldiers from Augusta County.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Law and Order Ticket</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Should this ticket be elected, it is confidently believed there will be no
                    necessity for martial law, in Staunton, and there will be no repetition of the
                    scenes of riot, drunkenness, disorder and crime, which have been of such
                    frequent occurrence in the last twelve months."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>A number of the citizens of Staunton, satisfied that the laws have been very
                        inefficiently administered within the Corporation, during the last year,
                        earnestly recommend to the voters the election of the following ticket. They
                        have no complaint to urge against the old officers, except that their time
                        has been so much occupied with other duties, that they could not attend to
                        the proper regulation of the Corporation. The ticket proposed, is composed
                        of men who are in no wise connected with the business of the Confederate
                        States, and can therefore give the proper attention to municipal affairs.</p>
                    <p>Should this ticket be elected, it is confidently believed there will be no
                        necessity for martial law, in Staunton, and there will be no repetition of
                        the scenes of riot, drunkenness, disorder and crime, which have ben of such
                        frequent occurrence in the last twelve months.</p>
                    <p>For Mayor--W. G. Sherrett.</p>
                    <p>Town Council--Wm. G. Campbell, George M. Cochran, A. D. Trotter, Wm. B.
                        Keyser, Robt. G. Bickle, Charles T. Cochran, George Baylor, Alex. F. Kenney,
                        John N. Hendren, David O. McGuffey, and B. J. Crawford.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sherrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trotter</ln>
                        <fn>A. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bickle</ln>
                        <fn>Robert G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>Alex F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCoffin</ln>
                        <fn>David O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Proposes a ticket of candidates nominated by "a number of the citizens of
                    Staunton" to run in the mayoral and town council elections. The citizens
                    recommend W. G. Sherrett for mayor.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Announcement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stevenson</ln>
                        <fn>R. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Announcement of Stevenson's candidacy for Town Sergeant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf>L.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Waddell, age five years, died on March 28 after a sickness of 16
                    hours. He was the son of L. and N. E. Waddell.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Webb</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Webb Harman, eight years of age, died of brain fever at Belle Fonte on
                    April 5. He was the son of Major John A. Harman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>In Council for Town of Staunton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints an ordinance submitted by Mayor Trout that imposes a fine of two
                    to twenty dollars on persons found causing destruction or trespassing in
                    Thornrose Cemetery.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Report of the military action at Corinth, Mississippi, and of the "impending"
                fight at Yorktown, column 1; tribute to the "Stonewall Brigade" led by General
                Jackson, column 3; news from a battle at Arkansas, column 4; news of Captain
                Morgan's scouting expeditions in the West, column 5; instructions on how to make
                saltpetre, column 6</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.04.08.02">
            <pageNote>Poem, article describing the battle at Kernstown, column 1; articles on
                Beauregard's call for bells and the war in Florida, column 2; notices and
                advertisements, columns 2-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
