<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt;  -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="ss1862/va.au.ss.1862.01.07">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Staunton Spectator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Brian Erb</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote>First pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 8/18/97</tagNote>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1862-01-07">
            <year>1862</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day norm="07">7</day>
            <weekday id="TUE">Tuesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>02</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.07.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The New Constitution</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces the upcoming popular vote on the new constitution. The article
                    states that adoption of this constitution will be the final step in throwing off
                    Yankee rule. Also to be voted on is the extent of the franchise under the new
                    constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Commitments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marshall</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report from the jailor of Augusta County on the number of prisoners
                    committed to the county jail in the past year: misdemeanors--179;
                    drunkenness--178; felonies and larceny--30; murder--3; disloyalty (Union men
                    from western Virginia)--69; prisoners of war--18.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Public Address</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hiden</ln>
                        <fn>J.C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that Rev. Hiden, Chaplain of the Wise Legion, will give an address
                    at the Baptist Church in Staunton on January 9.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Confederate court for the western district commenced its
                    session in Staunton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>News from the Northwest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are permitted to make the following extract from a private letter
                        addressed to a gentleman of this country, from his son, who is connected
                        with the Quartermaster's Department:</p>
                    <p>Monterey, Jan. 4th, 1862</p>
                    <p>Dear Pa:--We have had quite an exciting time here for several days. I had
                        just fallen asleep night before last, (Thursday night,) when I was aroused
                        by the report that the Yankees were about to attack Monterey. Jumping up I
                        found that a special express had just arrived from Alleghany [sic] with the
                        news that the enemy was advancing in very large force (from 5,000 to 6,000)
                        on Camp Alleghany; had come down that evening, and encamped at Greenbrier
                        River, nine miles beyond, and an attack at daylight was expected. Goode's
                        58th Va. Regiment which had come this far from Fork of Waters en route for
                        Huntersville, was ordered immediately to Alleghany, and started at half past
                        one, A.M. The 34th Regiment, also, stationed at Hightown, was called and
                        went, both reaching there about 8 o'clock; but, to the surprise of all, no
                        attack was made, and at 10 o'clock General (late Col.) Johnson sent the 31st
                        and 52d Regiments forward to reconnoitre, who found that the foe had
                        retreated, leaving no sure sign of a superior force having occupied the
                        ground, there having been a great number of campfires, lighted, which might
                        have been done by twenty-five men, evidently a feint to cover some other
                        ulterior design, whose development transpired yesterday in an advance on
                        Huntersville. We had there only four small cavalry companies and parts of
                        two infantry companies, in all about 250 men, under command of Capt.
                        Alexander of Tennessee cavalry company. These were attacked yesterday at 1
                        o'clock by from 2000 to 2500 of the enemy. Two or three fires were passed.
                        Three of them were killed, it was thought, and one of our men shot through
                        the hand, when we retreated towards Monterey, bringing off everything except
                        700 barrels of flour and a large lot of salted beef, said to be 60,000
                        rations, which they attempted to fire before leaving, and think they
                        succeeded in burning the flour, not certain as to the rest, as the enemy
                        came soon enough, perhaps, to extinguish the flames. It seems to have been
                        the strangest policy in the world to have kept so large a lot of supplies
                        protected by so small a force. They had just finished salting away about 125
                        head of cattle, for whose consumption I know not, and a very strong
                        temptation--a pressing invitation, in fact, for the thieving vandals. The
                        retreating cavalry companies arrived here late this evening, leaving the
                        infantry scattered along the road near here. They don't know whether they
                        are pursued or not. I was mistaken when I said they brought all but their
                        commissaries with them; they lost their tents and some baggage. There was a
                        strong picket sent out from here to night to go 16 miles in the direction of
                        Huntersville. We may be attacked here before morning, hardly probable so
                        soon, however. Fortunately the 58th Regiment returned here to-night, which,
                        with three companies of militia and two of cavalry, together with the
                        fugitives, making in all from 1000 to 1200, could show them a little fight.
                        The 44th likewise came back to Hightown, five miles across the mountain in
                        Crab Bottom.</p>
                    <p>An approach towards Huntersville was anticipated, and Goode's regiment, as I
                        said before, was this far on its road thither, but would not have reached
                        there had it gone on, in time to have prevented the rout. Since night before
                        last we have had some expectation of a rear attack on this place, (i.e. in
                        Johnson's rear) and an attempt to destroy his supplies here and cut him off
                        from Staunton. A simultaneous attack here at Alleghany is probable now. I
                        felt and feel very little apprehension as to the result of an attempt on
                        Alleghany, even by an overwhelming force, as our fortifications are
                        thoroughly completed there, and the men are anxious and eager for an
                        opportunity to use them.</p>
                    <p>Your affectionate son,</p>
                    <p>J.E.G.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>J. E. G.</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Letter from an Augusta County soldier to his father regarding the war in
                    northwestern Virginia.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Acts Passed by Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports acts passed by the Confederate Congress. These include acts dealing
                    with the payment of postage, naturalization for persons enlisted in the
                    Confederate army, treaty stipulations with certain Indian tribes, employment of
                    former officers of the U.S. Revenue service in the Confederate Revenue service,
                    appointment of additional officers in eh navy, and appropriations for the
                    expenses of government.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Burning of the Richmond Theatre</head>
                <origin>Richmond Dispatch</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that the Richmond theater and some surrounding buildings burned
                    down the previous Friday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>That's So</head>
                <origin>Nashville Banner</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Next to murder, speculation upon the country's need is the most loathsome
                    of crimes."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Banner recommends that speculators be "drawn and quartered and stewed
                    into soup to sharpen the appetites of the men made poor by his extortions."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Salt</head>
                <origin>Fredericksburg News</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Commends a citizen of Lancaster County who made eight bushels of salt from
                    sea water.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Gen. Floyd to his Army</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gen. Floyd writes to the soldiers in the Army of the Kanawha that the
                    campaign in western Virginia has ended. He praises them for their valor and
                    commends them for withstanding so many hardships in their recent campaign.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Carrier's Address to the Patrons of the Staunton Spectator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The old year has passed, and another begun, <lb/>We've bidden adieu to the
                        year sixty-one, <lb/>And friends, new and old, and patrons so dear,
                        <lb/>I've come back to wish you a happy New Year. <lb/>I welcome with
                        rapture these holiday times, <lb/>Ever fragrant to me of HALF-DOLLARS and
                        DIMES. <lb/>Virginians declare they'll avenge every wrong, <lb/>Their hearts
                        are courageous their blades true and strong, <lb/>And they've plighted their
                        word, with courage and might, <lb/>To stand up, forever, for honor and <emph
                            rend="italic">Wright.</emph></p>
                    <p><lb/>Now nothing that ever appeared in the paper <lb/>Before, has been worthy
                        of holding a taper <lb/>To the news of the war that Yankeedom wages
                        <lb/>'Gainst the South, which this year has crowded my pages <lb/>I told you
                        last spring of old Abe's "Proclamation," <lb/>That insulted the South, and
                        united our nation: <lb/>Virginia declared, tho' opposed to secession,
                        <lb/>She'd never submit to a tyrant's oppression. <lb/>Since war is
                        declared, no longer she waits, <lb/>But hastens to join the Confederate
                        States. <lb/>Her sons were in armor, and ready to come, <lb/>At the sound of
                        her bugle, the tap of her drum-- <lb/>The preacher and lawyer, the stout
                        mountaineer, <lb/>Men of all callings and trades volunteer, <lb/>To meet,
                        with cold steel on Virginia's dear soil, <lb/>The legions who come to insult
                        her and spoil. <lb/>The Boy bids adieu to his father and mother, <lb/>The
                        maid, with a smile and a tear, to her lover-- <lb/>'Tis glory to go, 'twere
                        shame to remain-- <lb/>Virginia ne'er called on her brave sons in vain! </p>
                    <p><lb/>Thro' the papers I've brought you, you weekly have seen <lb/>The Yankee
                        exploits, both on land and marine-- <lb/>The family jar 'twixt old Abe and
                        Fremont, <lb/>And the story of Bethel, Leesburg and Belmont. <lb/>How we
                        took at Manassas, the battery called Sherman's, <lb/>And routed whole
                        legions of Yankees and Germans; <lb/>How Southern men won them bright
                        chaplets of glory, <lb/>While their enemy slain made the battlefield gory.
                        <lb/>Let the South, tho' she weep for her brave sons who fell, <lb/>Rejoice
                        that they triumphed so nobly and well. </p>
                    <p><lb/>Through the "Staunton Spectator" the people have seen <lb/>Every week
                        how exceedingly liberal they've been, <lb/>For we've chronicled daily each
                        hospital box, <lb/>And frequent donations of blankets and socks. <lb/>And
                        the ladies--God bless 'em!--we've praised 'em enough, <lb/>If there's value
                        at all in a newspaper puff! <lb/>Your sisters and sweethearts; your wives
                        and your daughters-- <lb/>It pleased you I'm certain--so shell out the
                        QUARTERS. <lb/>When times are so hard, a little hard cash <lb/>Is the best
                        thing I know of to save a hard clash <lb/>'Gainst a world whose angles are
                        turned rather sharpe; <lb/>And Besides, tho' never inclined much to harp
                        <lb/>On trials that surely are but common lot, <lb/>Yet sometimes the
                        weather has been very hot <lb/>When I've carried your paper, sometimes very
                        cold, <lb/>And nothing adjusts these small evils like GOLD-- <lb/>Remember
                        how promptly I've carried your "Spec." <lb/>If you've got nothing better,
                        just give me a "Peck." </p>
                    <p><lb/>I have told you, this year, of many a pair, <lb/>The bridegroom so
                        gallant, the maiden so fair, <lb/>When together have stood a short time at
                        the alter, <lb/>While the preacher arranged the connubial halter. <lb/>In
                        some cases, perhaps, they both have repented, <lb/>The bride has declared,
                        she ne'er had consented <lb/>Had she known but one-half of the worrysome
                        ways <lb/>Of the spouse she so <emph rend="italic">honors</emph> and <emph
                            rend="italic">loves</emph> and <emph rend="italic">obeys.</emph><lb/>The
                        bridgeroom, astonished, to quiet his fears, <lb/>And to see how angelic she
                        looks when in tears, <lb/>Says softly, "my dear, you'd be happier far
                        <lb/>If I should enlist and get killed in the war." <lb/>"Since you mention
                        it, dear, I don't know but I might-- <lb/>They are looking, just now, every
                        day for a fight, <lb/>And I should remember with triumph and pride, <lb/>How
                        noble and brave for your country you died." </p>
                    <p><lb/>How oft we've recorded, in words of deep gloom, <lb/>How loved ones have
                        gently been laid in the tomb-- <lb/>The sweet smiling face that forever is
                        hid <lb/>Beneath the green turf, and the close coffin lid-- <lb/>The best,
                        aged form, and the deep-furrowed brow <lb/>That know not of sorrow or
                        suffering now-- <lb/>The solder so gallant, so young and so brave, <lb/>Who
                        died for his country, and sleeps in the grave, <lb/>For these, how the sign
                        and the fast-falling tear, <lb/>Will sadden full many a merry New Year! </p>
                    <p><lb/>But the news from old England is better by far, <lb/>Then even the best
                        you have heard of the war, <lb/>The proud British Lion sleeps tamely no
                        more, <lb/>And Lincoln and Yankeedom quake at his roar. <lb/>Uncle Sam is
                        most certainly in for a fight <lb/>With England, by insult aroused in her
                        might, <lb/>Unless an apology, abject and ample <lb/>Declares his late
                        conduct will not be a sample <lb/>Of his future behavior, so far as respects
                        <lb/>The flag that old Britain forever protects! </p>
                    <p><lb/>For items like these, you are surely my debtor, <lb/>And the <emph
                            rend="italic">wider</emph> you open your purses the better, <lb/>But
                        even a little is better than none, <lb/>Just to make me remember old friend,
                        sixty-one. <lb/>Unclasp your porte-monnaies, and may sixty-two <lb/>Shower
                        blessings upon you all the way through, <lb/>Will be the kind wish by day
                        and by night, <lb/>Of yours, ever truly and gratefully, <lb/>WRIGHT. </p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A pro-Confederate poem extolling the virtues of the Southern war effort and
                    the Staunton Spectator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>x</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that an open house at the President's Mansion was held for those
                    who wished to greet President Davis.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hutchens</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gillespy</ln>
                        <fn>Geo. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Married on December 26.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnston</ln>
                        <fn>Serena F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Serena Johnson, daughter of William Ruff, died on November 30, 1861 at age
                    29.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ruff</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Ruff died on December 29 at age 69.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyer</ln>
                        <fn>Zeb.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieut. Dyer died on December 19 on Allegheny Mountain from wounds he
                    received in a battle on December 18. He was 24 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>Columbus Greene</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lt. Davis died on January 3 at age 29 of a disease he contracted in camp.
                    He was a member of the Augusta Lee Rifles.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The home of the deceased has been thronged by soldiers worn out and sick
                    from the ordeal through which they passed in the "Army of the North-West." Her
                    natural energy was stimulated beyond its ability in her constant ministrations
                    to their wants, and she sunk under her cheerfully assumed task."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saupe</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Saupe</ln>
                        <fn>Chas. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Margaret Saupe died on December 29 at age 31.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Willis B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>Wm. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>E.S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Willis B. Kayser died of diphtheria on December 22 at age 4.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Died on December 17 at age 98.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Various items of war news. Telegraphic dispatches reporting Federal and
                Confederate political/war developments. List of letters not yet picked up at the
                post office. Co. 7 Declaration from the Governor and transcript of the new State
                Constitution.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.ss.1862.01.07.02">
            <div type="c">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>To the Tax-Payers of the Confederate States</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>John Grills, Samuel C. Harper</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grills and Harper report that they were "laboring under a misapprehension"
                    when they informed tax payers that all persons owning less than $500 worth of
                    property were exempt from taxation. In fact, everyone owning property that comes
                    "within the list prescribed by law," except for the heads of families owning
                    less than $500 worth of property, is required to make a tax return. The
                    advertisement lists the dates that they will meet taxpayers in the Donoho's
                    district (Stuart's Draft, Waynesboro, Sherando, Greenville, Midway, Middlebrook,
                    Newport, Swope's Depot, Deerfield, and Craigsville) and the Stover's district
                    (New Hope, Waynesboro, Mt. Meridian, Mt. Sidney, Spring Hill, Mt. Solon,
                    Parnassus, Churchville, Fishersville).</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Remainder of State Constitution, columns 1-6; advertisements, columns
            6-7</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
