<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.07.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/13/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-07-08">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="07">July</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Richmond <emph rend="italic">State Journal</emph>, that epitome of truth
                        (?) ha! ha!! assails us because we complained of the course of John F.
                        Lewis, U.S. Senator. He declares our article venomous and a spiteful
                        misrepresentation, and, "on the authority of John F. Lewis," asserts there
                        was not "one word of truth in it." Well, let us see.</p>
                    <p>We stated that he was elected by Conservatives, and was allied actively with
                        the ultra Radicals, that he meddled with the elections in Washington,
                        threatened the Republicans in the Legislature, opposed the nomination of
                        Akerman of Georgia and had a Confederate contract during the war to make
                        iron, with which the Confederates dealt death and destruction to <emph
                            rend="italic">his</emph> friends, and that he does not represent his
                        people.</p>
                    <p>Does he deny that he was elected by Conservatives and has acted with the
                        ultra Radicals? The first is well known and his votes in Congress attest the
                        latter.</p>
                    <p>Does he deny that he meddled with the elections in Washington? His letter on
                        the subject affirms this count.</p>
                    <p>Does he deny threatening the Republican members of the Legislature? The
                        sample letter published in the Richmond papers, and the general assertions
                        of this fact, place that beyond dispute.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Does he deny opposing the nomination of Akerman?</emph>
                        The telegraphic dispatches from <sic>Washingeon</sic> stated it, and it was
                        not denied by him until more than a week after its publication in the <emph
                            rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> and quite two weeks after it was
                        telegraphed from Washington. This is strange--surpassingly strange.</p>
                    <p>Does he deny that he took a Confederate contract during the war to make the
                        iron which was shaped into bolts to kill his Yankee friends? This is
                        notoriously true. Indeed many assert, that, in order to get the contract and
                        to retain it, he had to assure the Confederate authorities of his loyalty,
                        and some even assert that to get a contract, an oath of fidelity to the
                        Confederacy had to be taken, and that, at a time, when he was about to lose
                        his contract, a friend had to go forward and vouch, at his instance, for his
                        loyalty. But of this we do not know and draw no conclusions from it--which,
                        if we were "spiteful" we certainly could.</p>
                    <p>Does he not know that he mis-represents his people? Surely the election of
                        Walker, on whose ticket he ran, should conclusively exhibit the fact that
                        the sentiments of his people are not in accord with his ultra course, and,
                        we repeat, that knowing it, as he must, he should resign.</p>
                    <p>It would seem then, that, with the exception of the telegram concerning the
                        opposition to Akerman, which was only denied after the lapse of two weeks,
                        the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> did not "spitefully
                        mis-represent," but merely stated the truth, or that to which the failure to
                        deny gave the semblance of truth. The <emph rend="italic">State
                        Journal</emph> and its <emph rend="italic">authority</emph> are therefore,
                        "venomously malevolent" and most "spitefully" at fault, not to use a
                        stronger expression, and the <emph rend="italic">Vindicator</emph> article,
                        by their silence, on all save one point, is acknowledged by themselves to be
                        true.</p>
                    <p>We have never been disposed wantonly to assail any one, but when the man who
                        forged iron bolts for the Confederacy, and gave information and guides which
                        came near enabling Gen. Early to bag the force of Custer, at the Cave, near
                        his home, when elected to the Senate by Conservatives, not only pursued a
                        course at variance with their sentiments, but turned round and leveled
                        epithets at the men who had hoisted him into position, we thought it time to
                        let him and others hear the sentiments of the people from whose midst he was
                        so suddenly and astonishingly raised into place and power.</p>
                    <p>We therefore again assert that it would be exceedingly gratifying to the
                        people of Virginia if he would resign, and we think it a duty he owes to
                        himself to do so.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Defends a past article written in the Vindicator attacking Senator John
                    Lewis. Goes over all parts of the article and provides either direct or indirect
                    evidence for each accusation. Accuses Lewis' press of malevolence and again
                    calls for Lewis' resignation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An election will be held on August 6th to determine whether or not to
                    subscribe $300,000 in stock of the Valley Railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sampson</ln>
                        <fn>G. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Rev. G. W. Sampson delivered a series of lectures in the Baptist
                    Church. He spoke about Goshen and Mt. Sinai, Palestine, and Jerusalem.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Newton</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Argenbright</ln>
                        <fn>Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheat</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prufer</ln>
                        <fn>Frank</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Staunton Lodge No. 45, I. O. O. F., elected officers for the coming term.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shoveler</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaskins</ln>
                        <fn>T. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>G. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morris</ln>
                        <fn>O. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jefferson</ln>
                        <fn>R. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Farrow</ln>
                        <fn>Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mt. Zion Lodge No. 12, F. A. M., elected officers for the coming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Aderhold</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. M. A. Aderhold, Augusta Agent for the Bible Dictionary, is soliciting
                    subscriptions for the book. "It contains more than a thousand pages, embracing a
                    description of every name, place, animal, bird, reptile, insect, plant or
                    mineral, alluded to or mentioned in the Bible."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>As many inquiries have been made as to the debt of the Town of Staunton, we
                        publish the following condensed statement of it, and when due:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>$100</cell>
                            <cell>due January 1861.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3,000</cell>
                            <cell>" March 1863.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>3,100</cell>
                            <cell>" Mar., Sept. &amp; Dec. 1865.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1,600</cell>
                            <cell>" Jan., Jul. &amp; Oct. 1866.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>2,100</cell>
                            <cell>" January 1869.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>14,900</cell>
                            <cell>" Apr. Sept. &amp; Nov. 1870.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>150</cell>
                            <cell>" March 1871.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>900</cell>
                            <cell>" December 1876.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell/>
                            <cell>1,800</cell>
                            <cell>" July 1891.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Total</cell>
                            <cell>$27,650</cell>
                            <cell/>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>From this it appears, that $12,500 is past due; $12,300 will be due next
                        September and November making an aggregate of $24,800 due in November, and
                        the remainder, $2,850, due in 1871, 1876 and 1891, respectively, as stated
                        above.</p>
                    <p>The interest on the whole debt has been regularly paid, semi-annually, up to
                        the present date.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Goes over Staunton's debts, the dates and amounts due or coming due, and
                    payment of interest. Basically much of the debt is past due while interest is
                    paid on time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Staunton Male Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Young</ln>
                        <fn>C. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Arthur</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Marks</ln>
                        <fn>C. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Summerson</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hudson</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stubbs</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weller</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Haile</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jackson</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Matthews</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Atkinson</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stratton</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reese</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Staunton Male Academy held closing sessions on June 22nd. C. E. Young,
                    Principal, announced the students who achieved distinction in their studies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the Town Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The members of the newly elected Town Council qualified on the 1st inst. and
                        organized by the election of Wm. A. Burke, President, <emph rend="italic"
                            >pro tem</emph>, and adjourned till Tuesday night, the 5th inst.</p>
                    <p>On Tuesday last the Council met pursuant to adjournment.</p>
                    <p>The election of officers was postponed until Wednesday night, the 13th inst.</p>
                    <p>Wm. H. Gorman was appointed Commissioner of Streets, <emph rend="italic">pro
                            tem</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Report of D. Taylor, Supt. of Water Works, was presented, showing amount of
                        work done for citizens, during the month of June, to be $97.34--for the
                        town, $5.</p>
                    <p>The usual monthly accounts were presented, allowed and ordered to be paid,
                        including the semi-annual interest on the Town Debt.</p>
                    <p>On motion, the former Street Commissioners were requested to report at the
                        adjourned meeting of the Council on Wednesday night next, the condition of
                        the unfinished work in the Town, what amount of appropriations have been
                        expended for same and what contracts have been made for work ordered by the
                        Council.</p>
                    <p>On motion, a committee of five was appointed to consider and report upon the
                        financial condition of the Town of Staunton, and recommend a plan for the
                        liquidation of the debt now due.</p>
                    <p>The Council then adjourned until Wednesday night next, the 13th inst.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the business conducted at the Town Council, mostly dealing with
                    finances and the election of officers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Howard</ln>
                        <fn>Sicily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Baxter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Sicily Howard, an African American woman, fell from a cherry tree on Baxter
                    Crawford's farm. She broke her leg and died from the effects.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>Harvey</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hughes</ln>
                        <fn>D. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harris</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harvey Risk and Mrs. D. A. Hughes, formerly of Mobile, Alabama, were
                    married in Staunton at the Wesleyan Institute on June 30th by the Rev. William
                    A. Harris.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Beard, son of James Beard, died near Parnassus on July 3rd. He was
                    27 years old. "The subject of this notice was a great sufferer. He bore his
                    afflictions without a murmur, and expressed his resignation to the will of his
                    Divine Master. He was the only earthly support of aged parents, whose wants he
                    labored incessantly to supply, and the attention he received from all who knew
                    him, was a living testimony of the esteem in which he was held."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.07.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
