<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.08.19">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/15/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-08-19">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="08">August</month>
            <day norm="">19</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.08.19.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.08.19.02" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The failure of the County of Augusta to subscribe $300,000 to the stock of
                        the Valley Railroad rendered it necessary, that, if we would secure this
                        valuable road to this county, some other feasible plan must be adopted at
                        once and vigorously pushed to a successful conclusion.</p>
                    <p>It is believed that the counties and towns along the line will increase their
                        subscriptions sufficiently to make up the amount necessary to be subscribed
                        by <emph rend="italic">counties and towns</emph>, and that the balance of
                        the stock subscription will be readily taken by individuals. Staunton has
                        proposed, as will be seen by her ordinance elsewhere, to add to her
                        subscription. Lexington has done the same thing and Rockbridge, it is
                        believed, will also add to her already large subscription.</p>
                    <p>With this hope, the Directors of the Valley Railroad held a meeting a few
                        nights since and determined to solicit individual subscriptions. They have
                        had prepared and put in circulation a large number of subscription papers.
                        As the heading of these papers sets forth the terms and conditions very
                        concisely, we copy it below for the information of our readers:</p>
                    <p>"WHEREAS, the County of Augusta, in her corporate capacity, has declined to
                        subscribe the sum of $300,000 to the Valley Railroad, and WHEREAS it appears
                        evident that unless the said amount of subscription be not obtained from
                        some reliable source, the construction of the Road will have to be
                        abandoned:</p>
                    <p>THEREFORE, we, the subscribers, citizens of Augusta county, hereby promise
                        and bind ourselves, our heirs, &amp;c., to take the number of shares,
                        opposite our names of the stock of the Valley Railroad Company, at $100 per
                        share, and pay 30 <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> of the sum as soon as
                        called upon after the 1st of October, 1870, and the remainder in
                        installments of one and two years."</p>
                    <p>Many, who voted against the County subscription, are anxious to secure this
                        road, and have professed their willingness and determination to subscribe to
                        the stock. They can now have the opportunity. It behooves all such, as well
                        as those who have labored so earnestly in the past to secure this road, to
                        take the question of individual subscription in hand and push it
                        energetically.--What is to be done should be done at once. Hunt up the
                        subscription papers and subscribe as liberally as you can. If you can't take
                        twenty shares take ten. If ten is too much take five, three, two or one. At
                        all events take something. Every little will help to secure this great
                        enterprise. A few energetic men in each section of the county can readily
                        obtain the individual subscription necessary. We beg that a few such will
                        take hold of the subscription papers and work with a will for the next few
                        weeks.--The end to be secured will be of great and lasting advantage to all
                        of our people, and will amply compensate for the sacrifice and labor of
                        securing the subscriptions as well as advantage additionally those who
                        subscribe.</p>
                    <p>Put the ball in motion vigorously and let us secure the Valley Railroad, and
                        have it put under contract and commence deriving advantages therefrom this
                        Fall.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Tells Staunton residents that though the vote for subscription of the
                    Valley Railroad failed, there is still hope. Reports on the efforts taken by the
                    Railroad directors and private citizens to buy up the stock themselves instead
                    of having the County invest in it. Claims even those who voted against
                    subscription are eager to buy up shares themselves. Urges everyone to invest in
                    the venture to save the railroad.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn that among a number of those who opposed the County subscription of
                        the Valley Railroad it is proposed to have another vote in the County on a
                        subscription of $200,000. If this is so we shall be much pleased, but we do
                        not want Staunton to have anything to do with this vote. We were opposed to
                        her voting with the County before. She has done well by herself, and if the
                        County desires to subscribe and secure this road let her do it, but let us
                        keep hands off. It will be a good thing for the County, but as far as we are
                        concerned, she must take the initiatory steps and do her voting without any
                        inciting thereto by Stauntonians. Our columns, as heretofore, will be open
                        to any communication on either side.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Appears to do an about face by taking a stand against a new initiative for
                    the County to subscribe $200,000 of Valley Railroad stock, and says Staunton
                    should stay out of the vote.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>04</column>
                <head>Conservative Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Baldwin, county superintendent, announces a meeting of the
                    Conservatives of Augusta at the Court House on August 22nd. They will select
                    superintendents for the county and the various townships.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.08.19.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Announcement</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lynn</ln>
                        <fn>W. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>W. H. H. Lynn announces himself a candidate for the office of County
                    Treasurer.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Delinger</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McChesney</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bledsoe</ln>
                        <fn>M. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Delinger and Dr. McChesney take over the management of the American
                    Hotel in Staunton from M. P. Bledsoe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mason</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maury</ln>
                        <fn>M. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barronger</ln>
                        <fn>D. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clingman</ln>
                        <fn>T. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Caperton</ln>
                        <fn>Allen T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corcoran</ln>
                        <fn>W. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McRae</ln>
                        <fn>Duncan R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Meem</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Corse</ln>
                        <fn>M. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCausland</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Gen.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper praises the recent grand Masquerade and Fancy Dress Ball given at
                    the White Sulphur Springs for the benefit of the sufferers of a recent accident
                    at Jerry's Run. Many prominent persons attended.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Horrible Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Letitia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Letitia and Amanda Heizer, aged 18 and 15 respectively, died from burns
                    sustained after the explosion of a can of kerosene at the residence of their
                    father, Edward Heizer, near Churchville. The girls ran to the house of their
                    neighbor, A. B. Lightner, and received medical attention, but could not be
                    saved.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Our County Roads</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reminds surveyors of public roads that they still have a
                    responsibility to see that the roads are kept clear and in good repair. The new
                    Road Commissioners have been sworn in, but do not begin duty until the
                    legislature enacts the appropriate portion of the constitution.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Proceedings of the County Court--In Vacation</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>John S. Guy and Benj. O. Ferguson qualified as Justices of the Peace in
                        Pastures Township.</p>
                    <p>Stuart M. Crawford qualified as Clerk in Middle River Township.</p>
                    <p>John Waldrop qualified as Clerk in Pastures Township.</p>
                    <p>Thomas H. Cross qualified as Constable in pastures Township.</p>
                    <p>Jas. Henderson qualified as Com's of Roads in Beverly Manor Township.</p>
                    <p>The following appointments have been made by Judge Hendren to fill the
                        vacancies of officers, who failed to qualify in the time prescribed by law.</p>
                    <p>Saml. A. Kast, Supervisor, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> J. Givens Fulton.</p>
                    <p>Jno. W. Crist, Justice of Peace, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                            >vice</emph> Jas. T. Clarke.</p>
                    <p>Wm. H. Wooddell, Constable, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> Nelson Andrew.</p>
                    <p>Jno. T. Litten, Overseer of Poor, North River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                            >vice</emph> Jno. C. Rusmisel.</p>
                    <p>Wm. Crawford, Supervisor, Middle River Township, <emph rend="italic"
                        >vice</emph> J.D. Craig</p>
                    <p>David Myers, Overseer of Poor, Middle River Township, re-appointed.</p>
                    <p>Lucien M. Donaho, appointed by the State Auditor, Commissioner of Revenue,
                        1st District, <emph rend="italic">vice</emph> Jno. Tawberman, resigned,
                        qualified and entered upon the duties of his office.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Stuart M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waldrop</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cross</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henderson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>East</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. Givens</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clarke</ln>
                        <fn>James T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woddell</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Andrew</ln>
                        <fn>Nelson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Litten</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Donaho</ln>
                        <fn>M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reviews County Court business, mostly about filling county office vacancies
                    and the names of people assigned to the posts.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J. Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The funeral of J. Albert Hunter took place in Staunton's Episcopal Church.
                    "Though a young man, yet by his urbane manners, gentlemanly deportment and
                    social qualities he gathered around him a number of strong friends, who, with
                    his immediate family, sincerely deplore his demise. The C and O Railroad with
                    which he was connected for many a years, have lost a most trusty officer."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trout</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mayor Trout presided over a meeting at the Court House on August 11th aimed
                    at devising the best means to promote the Valley Railroad. It was decided to
                    allow the citizens of Staunton to vote on an additional $50,000 city
                    subscription to that road.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masters</ln>
                        <fn>Dewitt C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Susan Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fletcher</ln>
                        <fn>P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dewitt C. Masters and Susan Catharine Hanger, both of Augusta, were married
                    in Churchville on August 4th by the Rev. P. Fletcher.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>E. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Michie</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. E. W. Michie, wife of Thomas J. Michie, died at the residence of her
                    husband on August 15th. She was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Hettie A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Edward Smith, son of James H. and Hettie A. Smith, all of Staunton,
                    died on August 13th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn>J. Albert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Albert Hunter, formerly of Albemarle and lately of Staunton, died at
                    Salt Sulphur Springs, on August 13th. He was 28 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.08.19.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
