<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.02.18">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/01/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-02-18">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="02">Feburary</month>
            <day norm="">18</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.18.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.02.18.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The question of parties is exercising some of our <sic>cotemporaries</sic>.
                        While we are of the firm conviction that, in the course of a few years, the
                        principles which gave life and vigor to the Democratic party of the past
                        will loom up again, and that old party maintain its old ascendancy over the
                        Republican party, which was but a mushroom growth, nourished by that
                        powerful fertilizer fanaticism, yet we are not of the opinion that our
                        people, at present, need worry themselves over political questions, further
                        than those which tend to promote our prosperity. When we have attained the
                        pecuniary prosperity of the Eastern, Middle and Western States, and when it
                        ceases to be the necessity of every man in the South to provide for those
                        under his care by his incessant labor, we may have the time to devote, as of
                        yore, to politics. All the time we can spare at present must of necessity be
                        devoted to regaining the old time prosperity of our people.--With this we
                        will have enough to do for several years to come, and, whether we will or
                        not, must bide our time for the ascendancy of those principles which claimed
                        our hearty support in the past, and which made our system of government the
                        proud boast of nations and people, ere it descended into the farce which
                        characterizes it to-day. That time will come, but now our endeavors must be
                        directed in a different line. Let us not quibble about politics, but address
                        ourselves to completing and adding to our systems of communication,
                        developing the resources of our State and building up manufacturing
                        interests &amp;c. These accomplished, we can then afford to spend our
                        time in the <sic>dicussion</sic> of political questions but not until then,
                        for there is much to be done to make Virginia the equal of her sister States
                        and if we are wise we will not waste our time and efforts on less fruitful
                        objects. Let us not divide ourselves on the question of new parties, but
                        stand united, as one man, in the effort to secure the future welfare of our
                        beloved "Old Dominion."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges Virginians not to get mired down in politics and instead devote their
                    energies into rebuilding the state's prosperity.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bunch</ln>
                        <fn>G. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bruce</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ball</ln>
                        <fn>A. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coffman</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chrisman</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gray</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kurtz</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Logan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lightner</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Locke</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>A. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>B. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shelton</ln>
                        <fn>T. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seig</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheffey</ln>
                        <fn>H. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>A. H. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodward</ln>
                        <fn>P. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woodson</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingfield</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wartman</ln>
                        <fn>William McK.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper prints a list of Augusta citizens who had their political
                    disabilities removed by Congress.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>MR. EDITOR--<emph rend="italic">Sir:</emph>--Your correspondent "Staunton,"
                        whose communication, appeared in a recent number of your excellent paper,
                        takes the ground (in which I fully concur) that men of capital and
                        manufacturing experience will not invest their means in manufacturing
                        enterprises in a community, where money commands 2, 3 and even 5 per cent
                        per month as it does here, and in order to make our town a manufacturing
                        place a change in the management of our banks, or other Banking capital
                        secured, must take place.</p>
                    <p>Holding the views I do, that, in order to make us a thrifty, prosperous and
                        happy people, we must establish manufactures, and taking the views of
                        "Staunton" to be correct, we must have more Banking Capital, and at lower
                        rates of interest. If the present high rates of interest now demanded by our
                        Banks cannot be reduced, (and I must confess that the chances are slim under
                        their present management,) we must secure additional Banking facilities. Now
                        how is this to be done? Some suggest a savings institution. Well, if one can
                        be established with sufficient capital, and placed in the hands of men who
                        will manage its affairs in the interest of the legitimate business of the
                        town and county, and not be controlled by the "shylocks," who would take
                        "the pound of flesh" I say all right, but there is, I think, an institution
                        already established in our town, which, if properly fostered and patronized
                        by our business men, can be made to answer our purpose. I mean the Virginia
                        Insurance Company, which now has a capital of about $125,000--$50,000 of
                        which has been paid in, leaving a balance of about $75,000 unpaid, which is
                        secured by stock notes, the holders of which, in many cases, would sell
                        their stock to new stockholders, in order to convert the whole capital stock
                        into a cash fund of $125,000.</p>
                    <p>Suppose our merchants, mechanics and men of small means take the balance of
                        this stock, (which they can easily do as the shares are only $25 each,) or
                        so much of it as these share holders are willing to sell, which would make a
                        paid up capital of say $100,000, which would give the company a capital
                        stock equal to either of our present National Banks, and, if used for the
                        benefit of our business men, at rates they could pay, giving in all cases
                        the preference to policy holders and depositors, would in a short time
                        secure to the company a deposit line of at least $150,000, which, with the
                        paid up capital, would give us a Banking capital of $250,000. The profits
                        upon this if properly managed, at 6 per cent, would yield to the
                        stockholders an annual dividend of not less than 13 per cent on their
                        investment, to say nothing about the insurance department, which pays all
                        the expenses of the company, they being provided for in their charges on
                        life insurance. The depositor is perfectly safe, as the charter of the
                        Company provides that under no circumstances are the deposits liable for
                        losses incurred by the insurance department.</p>
                    <p>Taking for example the many prosperous life companies known to the public, it
                        is plain that a large business in life insurance can be done here. By an
                        actual calculation, based upon tables known to be reliable, the issue of 500
                        life policies per annum averaging $3000 each, (a low estimate as compared
                        with other good companies,) would add to the capital of the company, if
                        properly managed, in five years, not less than $500,000, a large proportion
                        of which would be drawn from distant communities and therefore an actual
                        increase to the capital of our town. That added to what would be made by the
                        Banking department would, in five years, make a cash capital on hand of at
                        least $700,000, including deposits, all of which would be
                        <sic>avilable</sic> for Banking purposes.</p>
                    <p>Taking the above statements to be true, (and I have carefully considered the
                        subject, and, with the information at hand, am convinced that I do not over
                        state the case,) is it not plain that it is to the interest of our business
                        men to examine into the subject before they undertake a new project.</p>
                    <p>Now I wish it to be distinctly understood that I have no personal interest in
                        this company, not owning one dollar of its stock, nor do I know that I ever
                        shall, as I have no means to invest in stocks of any kind, but I desire to
                        see our merchants, farmers, mechanics and manufacturers all prosper and
                        feeling and knowing that no legitimate business can prosper in a community
                        where money rates are as high as they are here, therefore let me urge our
                        business men to make some effort to build up their institution, and thereby
                        induce men of means and experience to invest their capital in manufacturing
                        enterprises in our town, which as I have endeavored, in two former
                        communication on this subject, to show is the sure road to material
                        prosperity and happiness.</p>
                    <p>A CITIZEN</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>An anonymous writer has some suggestions for making Staunton more
                    attractive to manufacturing investors. The biggest suggestion involves heavy
                    investment in the Virginia Insurance Company as a springboard for future capital
                    investment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.18.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports that a large number of African Americans left Staunton
                    for Mississippi on Monday morning.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Dr. Samson's lecture in the Baptist Church drew a large and appreciative
                    crowd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>J. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. F. Davis, Moscow auctioneer, is available to conduct sales in any part
                    of the county. "If a glib tongue and plenty of brass are essentials in a good
                    Auctioneer, then Franklin certainly has a right to be esteemed as such. Try
                    him."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Maupin</ln>
                        <fn>A. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. T. Maupin was arrested in Washington on charges of embezzling $2000 in
                    public funds. "These we presume were funds coming into his hands while
                    Postmaster at Staunton, as we learned, some time since, that notices had been
                    served upon his sureties, for a considerable deficiency."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Timberlake</ln>
                        <fn>J. L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Humphreys</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bagby</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. L. Timberlake and Miss Mary Ellen Humphreys, both of Staunton, were
                    married on February 15th at the residence of C. Bagby.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>Emily</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arnall</ln>
                        <fn>John T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClure</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Emily Arnall, daughter of the late John T. Arnall, died in Staunton at
                    the residence of A. W. McClure on February 12th of consumption.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine Virginia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kiracofe</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Virginia Kiracofe, wife of the Rev. J. W. Kiracofe of the
                    Virginia Annual Conference died in Maryland on January 11th. She was 23 years
                    old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>Turner Ashby</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wheeler</ln>
                        <fn>James D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Turner Ashby Wheeler, son of James D. Wheeler, died on February 2nd. He was
                    3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.ss.1870.02.18.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
