<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.09.30">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/20/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-09-30">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="09">September</month>
            <day norm="">30</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.30.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.30.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Republicans of this State held another Convention in Richmond last week
                        which is reported in our Richmond exchanges as very rich in disorder and
                        other characteristic features. It seems to have been called with the view of
                        perfecting their organization and agreeing upon a platform of principles. In
                        this connection they adopted and put forward a platform, in which they
                        re-affirm their old "principles," assert their support of President Grant;
                        claim the present Administration as a Republican success; declare for a
                        rigid enforcement of the Free School system, and assert that the present
                        General Assembly are not to be expected to carry out the constitution in
                        this particular, nor is it to be hoped that this body will secure to the
                        masses the "fruits" of the new Constitution; denounce the "Conservatives" as
                        a contrivance to evade the issue between the Republican and Democratic
                        parties, and that their ultimate tendency is to side with the latter; give
                        the True Republicans" a rub for their faithlessness to their promises made
                        to Grant and Congress and recommend the nomination of Republican candidates
                        for county offices--All of this will be readily seen as the merest claptrap,
                        which when squeezed contains not a germ of a political principle, unless it
                        be that one general principle--the desire for the loaves and fishes of
                        office.</p>
                    <p>The great card which they play is their request of Congress to enact laws to
                        secure to the people of the State the "full benefit of the Homestead clause
                        of the Constitution and "compensation to loyal men in the South for property
                        taken for the use of the Government during the war, and the payment of all
                        claims due citizens of the South for services rendered prior to the war,
                        under such guards and restrictions as may be necessary to protect the
                        Government from imposition."</p>
                    <p>They expect much from this plank.--They declare they will make great inroads
                        on the Conservatives and this is the "principle" they <sic>put put</sic>
                        forth to accomplish the purpose. The enactment of the law by Congress to
                        compensate "Loyal" men in the South, they think, and hope, will bring into
                        their ranks many who have lost property--in some cases their all--at the
                        hands of the Government. They quietly assert, "who wouldn't be loyal when
                        they are to be paid their losses!" They will fail in their object we think.
                        They know that when a Democratic Administration comes in such a step is sure
                        to be taken. They are only stealing Democratic Thunder, and, what is more,
                        Democrats and Conservatives understand it and will hold aloof from
                        Republican alliances. It was a strong card, boldly played, but only exposes
                        the weakness of the "hand" from which it was played.</p>
                    <p>A marked feature of this Convention was the selection of Maj. Jno. A. Harman,
                        "Stonewall Jackson's Quartermaster," as the presiding officer. To see this
                        man, who aided in the swift marches of Stonewall Jackson's troops, and to
                        some extent, in keeping up the efficiency of those troops, by which they
                        struck the deadly blows against the enemy which made the name of "Stonewall
                        Jackson" famous, and an old Democrat withal, in the mixed and disorderly
                        crowd that composed that Convention--a sort of ruling spirit among them--may
                        be a cause of wonder to many, and we even now find ourselves wondering at
                        this great change of front. At all events it is so. "Stonewall Jackson's
                        Quartermaster" not only presided over the Republican State Convention, but,
                        judging from the proceedings of that body, is to-day the leading man in that
                        party. It is this very fact we desire to call attention to, for another
                        purpose. A bait has been thrown to Conservatives and Democrats, as we have
                        mentioned above, and the fact of an old Confederate now occupying the most
                        prominent position in the Republican party may have its effect. We warn all
                        against this. Be not deceived by it. The Democrats, and Conservatives are
                        gaining ground every day, and it will not be long before they are again the
                        ruling power in this country. The Republicans know this and are, on all
                        sides, by moderating their proscriptions, endeavoring to secure a permanent
                        hold of power. Every argument and device will be used to secure this. Look
                        to it then and be not deceived by tempting baits or rallying cries but rest
                        assured that the opponents of Republicanism, will, in a few brief years,
                        control this country and make the government, (in strict subjection to the
                        Constitution) really the "best government the world ever saw."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Ridicules a Republican meeting held in Richmond, and claims they have no
                    real principles other than occupying office. Especially upset that a former
                    prominent Confederate is now at the head of the State Republican party, and
                    warns conservatives not to be taken in by this. Insists the Democrats and
                    Conservatives will soon retake control of the country.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The County Convention, held on Monday last, was composed of delegates from a
                        large majority of the Precincts. How these delegates were appointed, we do
                        not know, but there was ample time and notice given to have selected, as we
                        suppose they did, representative men at each precinct. At any rate, all the
                        candidates who submitted their claims to the convention expected to and of
                        course will support the nominees of the Convention, and, as a matter of
                        course, the friends of defeated candidates will do likewise.</p>
                    <p>The County Convention was a part and parcel of the Conservative organization
                        of the State. The County contest is but a skirmish preceding the great
                        battle to take place in the next election of State officers.--It therefore
                        behooves all Conservatives to give their cordial support to the
                            <sic>Consevative</sic> nominees for county offices, and thus perfect the
                        Conservative organization, in order to present an united front in opposition
                        to Republicanism in future elections.</p>
                    <p>Come up to the work Conservatives and let not one straggler from the ranks be
                        found.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Urges all Conservative voters to unite behind the Conservative nominees for
                    state office.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>For the Vindicator</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>"Observer" complains about the practice of forcing pupils of Staunton's
                    female schools to entrust their money to principals and teachers for purchase of
                    goods in town. This results in one or two businesses fielding all the purchase
                    requests from "two or three hundred young ladies." Allowing students to travel
                    to town to make their own purchases would increase competition and the
                    distribution of patronage. "Why not allow one or more of the teachers to
                    accompany their pupils to the several stores, and wherever their money can be
                    most judiciously expended, let it be done."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.30.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britt</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Britt, U.S. Surveyor of Distilleries for Augusta, reports that
                    there are 22 apple brandy stills in the county as compared to 3 last year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Board of Education, at its recent meeting in Richmond, appointed on the
                        nomination of Capt. Jed. Hotchkiss, the County Superintendent of Schools for
                        Augusta county, the following gentlemen as School Trustees in the several
                        Townships, &amp;c., of the county:</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For the City of Staunton</emph>.--Major H.M. Bell, Wm. J.
                        Nelson, and P. Byron Hoge.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Beverly Manor Township</emph>.--John Towberman, Col.
                        Asher W. Harman, and Leigh R. Waddell.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For the Pastures Township</emph>.--B.O. Ferguson, James
                        H. Heizer and John S. Guy.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Riverheads Township</emph>.--A.S. Turk, Capt. C.G.
                        Mezritt and Wm. Thompson.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For South River Township</emph>.--C.H. Withrow, Rev. C.
                        Beard and Dr. J.M. Watson.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For Middle River Township</emph>.--Wm. Wilson, Kasper B.
                        Koiner and B.J. Craig.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">For North River Township</emph>.--Dr. Wm H. Davies,
                        Samuel Forrer and Jacob H. Plecker.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hotchkiss</ln>
                        <fn>Jed</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nelson</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoge</ln>
                        <fn>P. Byron</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Asher W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Leigh R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ferguson</ln>
                        <fn>B. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heizer</ln>
                        <fn>James H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Guy</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Merritt</ln>
                        <fn>C. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Withrow</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Watson</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koiner</ln>
                        <fn>Kasper B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>B. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davies</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forrer</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plecker</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lists the names of men appointed as School Trustees for each township in
                    Augusta county. Nominations made by Jed. Hotchkiss, Superintendent of Schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The County Conservative Convention, to nominate County Officers and select
                        delegates to the Congressional Convention, to be held in Harrisonburg on
                        October 5th, in pursuance of published announcement, met in the Court House,
                        on Monday last. Delegations from a large majority of the Precincts were
                        present.</p>
                    <p>The Convention was called to order by Col. Jno. B. Baldwin, and Jas.
                        Bumgardner Jr., appointed temporary Secretary. On motion a committee of one
                        from each Township was appointed to nominate permanent officers and, after
                        retiring, reported as Chairman, Col. Wm. M. Tate and as Secretaries, the
                        Editors of the Staunton papers, which report was unanimously adopted.</p>
                    <p>On motion of Col. M.G. Harman, the selection of Delegates to the
                        Congressional Convention was first taken up, for the reason, as stated by
                        him, that the delegates from Staunton had the right to participate in that,
                        but, it being a doubtful question whether they had a right to vote for
                        County Officers, desired then to withdraw from the Convention and leave the
                        County Delegates to nominate the County Officers.</p>
                    <p>On motion, each Township and Ward delegation was requested to nominate the
                        Delegates to represent their Township or Ward in the Congressional
                        Convention.</p>
                    <p>The following Delegates were thereupon nominated and elected:</p>
                    <p>BEVERLEY MANOR TOWNSHIP.--A.W. Harman, Jacob Baylor, Wm. J. Shumate, John N.
                        Opie, T.P. Eskridge, Lewis Harman, David Doom.</p>
                    <p>MIDDLE RIVER TOWNSHIP.--S.C. Harper, T.J. Burke, C.S. Roller, J.D. Craig, Wm.
                        Crawford, C.S. Grattan, S.B. Finley, G. Barnhart.</p>
                    <p>PASTURES TOWNSHIP.--L. Sibert, J.G. Stover, E. Geeding, Wm. M. Tate, L.
                        Waddell, Jos. Trimble.</p>
                    <p>SOUTH RIVER TOWNSHIP.--J.W. Patrick, Wm. Chapman, A.G. Christian, J.D.
                        Brooks, D.S. Bell, P.T. Burkholder, J.M. Lewis, Clinton Hall.</p>
                    <p>NORTH RIVER TOWNSHIP.--J.G. Fulton, James A. Hamrick, T.S. Hogshead, Wm. H.
                        Gamble, D.N. Vanlear, John H. Ervin, James G. Turk.</p>
                    <p>RIVERHEADS TOWNSHIP.--A.S. Turk, T.M. Smiley, J.D. Lilley, A. Blauth, M.W.D.
                        Hogshead, A.A. Sproul, W.T. Rush, J.D. McCuffin.</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON WARD No. 1.--Wm. B. Kayser, Robt. Burke, W.G. Sterrett, R. Mauzy.</p>
                    <p>STAUNTON WARD No. 2.--Wm. A. Burke, M. H. Effinger, S. Travers Phillips, M.G.
                        Harman.</p>
                    <p>The selection of Delegates to the Congressional Convention being completed,
                        the Staunton Delegates withdrew and the County Delegates selected the
                        following gentlemen as the nominees for County Offices:</p>
                    <p>Treasurer--Charles T. Cochran.</p>
                    <p>County Clerk--Wm. A. Burnett.</p>
                    <p>Circuit Clerk--Joseph N. Ryan.</p>
                    <p>Commonwealth's Attorney--J.Bumgardner Jr.</p>
                    <p>Superintendent of the Poor--Geo. W. Fauber.</p>
                    <p>Sheriff--Wm. L. Mowry.</p>
                    <p>Surveyor--Col. J.D. Lilley.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>A. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Opie</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>T. P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Doom</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harper</ln>
                        <fn>S. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>T. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Roller</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Grattan</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Finley</ln>
                        <fn>S. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Barnhart</ln>
                        <fn>G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibert</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stover</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geeding</ln>
                        <fn>E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Tate</ln>
                        <fn>William M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patrick</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chapman</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Christian</ln>
                        <fn>A. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brooks</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>P. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lewis</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Clinton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fulton</ln>
                        <fn>J. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamrick</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>T. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vanlear</ln>
                        <fn>D. N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ervin</ln>
                        <fn>John H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>James G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Turk</ln>
                        <fn>A. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smiley</ln>
                        <fn>T. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blauth</ln>
                        <fn>A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hogshead</ln>
                        <fn>M. W. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sproul</ln>
                        <fn>A. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rush</ln>
                        <fn>W. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGuffin</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kayser</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sterrett</ln>
                        <fn>W. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mauzy</ln>
                        <fn>R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burke</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Effinger</ln>
                        <fn>M. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Phillips</ln>
                        <fn>S. Travers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>M. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Charles T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burnett</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ryan</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bumgardner</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fauber</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mowry</ln>
                        <fn>William L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lilley</ln>
                        <fn>J. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports on the Conservative County Convention minutes. Names the people
                    nominated from each township to serve as delegates to the Congressional
                    convention and those chosen as nominees for county offices.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Precinct Committees of the Augusta Memorial Association for the Confederate
                    Dead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Staunton--Ward No. 1--John S. Moorman, William L. Bumgardner, Mrs. Capt. D.
                        McCoy, Miss Avery Covell, Miss Eleanor Baylor.</p>
                    <p>Staunton--Ward No. 2--Capt. R. H. May, James Ker, Mrs. Josie Eyster, Miss
                        Fannie Skinner, Miss Florence Phillips.</p>
                    <p>Sandy Hollow--Capt. L. Harman, H. L. Opie, Mrs. William Donaghe, Mrs. J. N.
                        Opie, Miss Lorena Williams.</p>
                    <p>Bolivar--Jos. Merriken, George R. Bell, Miss Hattie McGuffin, Miss Nannie
                        Bell, Miss Kate Smith.</p>
                    <p>Peaco's Mill--E. M. Cushing, David Speck, Miss Sallie Kinney, Miss Sallie S.
                        Henderson, Miss Eliza Shuey.</p>
                    <p>Folly--Col. James C. Cochran, W. Harvey Marshall, Mrs. Mary Lewis, Miss
                        Sallie Gilkeson, Miss Bettie Eskridge.</p>
                    <p>Hebron--George H. Eidson, Alpheus Cook, Mrs. Rev. D. B. Ewing, Miss Emma V.
                        Taylor, Mrs. G. W. Swoope.</p>
                    <p>Greenville--Dr. William Gillum, John B. Smith, Miss Mary Smith, Miss Augusta
                        Bumgardner, Miss Lizzie Pilson.</p>
                    <p>Middlebrook--M. W. D. Hogshead, James W. McCorkle, Mrs. Sallie Kunkel, Mrs.
                        George Rusmisel, Miss Maggie McCutchen.</p>
                    <p>Newport--Dr. Charles Berry, Thomas M. Smiley, Miss Lorena McChesney, Miss
                        Lucy Turk, Miss Ellen Steele.</p>
                    <p>Midway--Nelson Bell, Jr., John H. Rush, Miss Betty Henry, Miss Willie
                        Pinkerton, Miss Florence McGuffin.</p>
                    <p>Waynesboro--Artemus Patterson, J. Phil Smith, Mrs. George A. Bruce, Miss E.
                        Withrow, Mrs. Sallie McGuire.</p>
                    <p>Fishersville--Capt. E. Bateman, John E. Hamilton, Mrs. Virginia Hamilton,
                        Miss Jennie Bell, Miss Bettie Caldwell.</p>
                    <p>Barterbrook--A. G. Christian, Dr. T. W. Shelton, Mrs. Martha Dold, Miss
                        Ophelia Wilson, Miss Emma Moffett.</p>
                    <p>Sherando--Clinton Hall, Daniel Heiserman, Mrs. J. M. Lewis, Mrs. David G.
                        Hyden, Miss Mary Coiner.</p>
                    <p>New Hope--Capt. Charles Grattan, Dr. B. F. Walker, Miss Lucy Stout, Miss Lucy
                        Waddell, Mrs. Lizzie Hinton.</p>
                    <p>Mt. Sidney--Capt. Thomas J. Burke, C. S. Roller, Miss Sadie Crawford, Miss
                        Jennie McCue, Mrs. Mary Wilson.</p>
                    <p>Verona--William B. Moorman, Ed Crawford, Miss Mollie Gilkeson, Miss Sallie
                        Crawford, Miss E. W. Edmondson.</p>
                    <p>Mt. Meridian--Capt. Tom McClung, J. D. Craig, Miss Cornelia Patterson, Miss
                        Mary Hanna Walker, Miss Laura Boone.</p>
                    <p>Red Mills--Sinclair Koiner, William Hanger, Miss Catharine Yount, Miss Betty
                        J. Barnhart, Miss Barbara Baylor.</p>
                    <p>Mt. Solon--Col. J. M. McCue, Capt. E. L. Curtis, Mrs. Maggie T. Lockridge,
                        Miss Bettie Forrer, Mrs. Robert Kyle.</p>
                    <p>Spring Hill--William H. Gamble, Dr. Van Lear, Miss Mary Plecker, Miss Lizzie
                        Herring, Miss Fanny Bell</p>
                    <p>Parnassus--Ad Cochran, Robert Byers, Miss Lizzie Kinnie, Miss Mary Hamrick,
                        Miss Lucy Blair.</p>
                    <p>Sangersville--J. W. Crist, N. L. Blakemore, Miss Mary S. Gregory, Mrs. Dr.
                        William Davis, Miss Ann L. Humbert.</p>
                    <p>Centreville--Clement Fulton, H. V. Bell, Mrs. Dr. J. M. Trevy, Miss Mody
                        Fulton, Miss Sallie Wheeler.</p>
                    <p>Churchville--Capt. Joseph A. Wilson, Lit Waddell, Mrs. William H. Bell, Miss
                        Rebecca Sterrett, Miss Jennie Stover.</p>
                    <p>Buffalo Gap--Dr. James F. Tate, Magnus S. Cease, Mrs. Samuel H. Bell, Miss
                        Ada Sibert, Miss Florence Lightner.</p>
                    <p>Craigsville--Dr. D. Bashaw, Robert S. Craig, Miss Josephine Hodge, Miss Mary
                        Thomas, Miss Amanda Woodward.</p>
                    <p>Deerfield--David V. Taylor, John S. Guy, Miss Agnes Montgomery, Miss Nannie
                        McCutchen, Miss Mary Montgomery.</p>
                    <p>Lebanon Springs--Thomas H. Gross, Frank E. Irvine, Miss Jennie Lange, Miss
                        Belle Pauly, Miss Susan Rhyan.</p>
                    <p>(Circulars will be sent to each Committee defining its duties.)</p>
                    <p>S. Travers Phillips, Secretary Ex. Com.<lb/> Bolivar Christian, Chairman Ex.
                        Com.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper prints a list of members, by precinct, of the Augusta Memorial
                    Association for the Confederate Dead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Augusta County Fair--A New Feature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper reports with excitement that a herd of thorough-bred cattle from
                    Hardy County will be brought to Augusta to be sold at the fair. "Growing
                    thorough-bred cattle, horses, sheep and hogs may be regarded as the agricultural
                    'fine arts,' and we hope the day is not far distant when our Valley, and
                    especially our county, will be celebrated for its success in this attractive
                    department of industry."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Terrible Freshet</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Teabo</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>May</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eskridge</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parker</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rice</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Echols</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Heavy rains caused Augusta's creeks and rivers to rise and overflow their
                    banks. Flooding from Lewis Creek caused an estimated $20,000 of damage in
                    Staunton. "Houses were swept away and even Masonry, compactly put up, and had
                    stood the test of many freshets, was swept away as though it were a wooden
                    structure." The bridges over Main Street, near the railroad bridge, and near the
                    American Hotel were destroyed or badly damaged. A party of men rescued James
                    Teabo from the flood. Several bridges of the C. and O. Railroad were destroyed,
                    including those near Waynesboro, Goose Creek, Christian's Creek, and Swoope's.
                    Two trains are stuck on the tracks. No train will run into Staunton for eight to
                    ten days, and all telegraphic communication is out.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gibbs</ln>
                        <fn>Laura</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Shafer and Miss Laura Gibbs, both of Staunton, were married on
                    September 21st at the residence of the bride's father by the Rev. Mr. Williams.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gladke</ln>
                        <fn>Charles A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Rosetta</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenbaum</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stempel</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Charles A. Gladke of Staunton and Miss Rosetta Rosenbaum, daughter of Henry
                    Rosenbaum of Washington D. C., were married on September 17th at the residence
                    of the bride's father by the Rev. Isaac Stempel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>David B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dillard</ln>
                        <fn>Mary C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dillard</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buckner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cowan</ln>
                        <fn>John F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David B. Wilson, formerly of Augusta, and Miss Mary C. Dillard, daughter of
                    the late Dr. F. Dillard of Missouri, were married on September 8th at "Prairie
                    Lee," the residence of John Buckner, by the Rev. John F. Cowan.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Alex</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Maria</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alex Hall and George Hall, sons of James and Maria Hall of Augusta, died on
                    July 23rd and August 18th. They were 3 years old and 18 months old respectively.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>03</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>Loretta Julie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gorman</ln>
                        <fn>J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Loretta Julie Gorman, daughter of W. H. and J. C. Gorman, died on September
                    15th. She was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.09.30.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
