<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.01.28">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>02/01/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-01-28">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.28.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.28.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The Bill for the admission of Virginia, passed by both Houses of Congress,
                        will be found elsewhere. When Virginia occupied an acknowledged place in the
                        Union, it was a Union of Sovereign States, with equal rights. To day she is
                        re-admitted to a place among the States of the Union, not the old Union
                        which she assisted to establish but a new concern. Her act of admission is
                        also a penal statute.</p>
                    <p>It contains conditions to which no other State in the Union is subjected;
                        that she will never do certain things which other States have the full power
                        to do. It prescribes an oath to be taken by her officers and Legislators,
                        which obtains in the case of no other State, and attaches a penalty of
                        imprisonment and fine for taking said oath improperly, and yet it is claimed
                        that the Union to which she is now admitted is a Union of "equal States,
                        with equal rights and privileges."</p>
                    <p>Well it may be, but we confess our inability to see it, and are more than
                        pleased that there has been no uproarious rejoicing over the re-admission of
                        Virginia on the terms and conditions required.</p>
                    <p>The only part that we are disposed to rejoice over, is the fact that Virginia
                        has not been required to give her assent to the terms of the Bill of
                        Admission, for God knows she has eaten dirt enough already to sicken a dozen
                        "Mothers of States and Statesmen."</p>
                    <p>There may be some who are disposed to exult at the mere restoration of
                        Virginia, to whom we commend the following summary of what she has been
                        required to do or bear, in order to secure the boon (?) of restoration:</p>
                    <p>1. The ratification of the 13th amendment to the Federal Constitution,
                        abolishing slavery.</p>
                    <p>2. The repeal of her ordinance of secession.</p>
                    <p>3. The repudiation of the Confederate debt.</p>
                    <p>4. The adoption of the Bayne-Underwood constitution, giving the ballot to all
                        male negroes twenty-one years old, and making them all eligible to office;
                        and giving them control in a large proportion of the counties of the State.</p>
                    <p>5. The election of a Republican delegation to Congress.</p>
                    <p>6. The election of a Republican State ticket.</p>
                    <p>7. The ratification of the 14th amendment to the Federal Constitution.</p>
                    <p>8. The ratification of the 15th amendment to the Federal Constitution.</p>
                    <p>9. An oath from every member of the State Legislature, and every executive
                        and judicial officer of the State, to the effect that he does not come
                        within the terms of the 3d clause of the 14th amendment.</p>
                    <p>10. That the constitution of the State shall never be amended so as to
                        prevent persons from voting who are paupers, or who may not have paid their
                        taxes, or who may not know how to read or write.</p>
                    <p>11. That the said constitution of the State shall never be altered so as to
                        deprive any one of the right to hold office on account of color.</p>
                    <p>12. That the said constitution shall never be changed so as to deprive the
                        colored people of equal rights and privileges in connection with the public
                        schools of the State.</p>
                    <p>After rolling this delightful morsel under their tongues, if they be still
                        disposed to rejoice, why let them do it. Halloo at the top of your voices,
                        gentlemen, and let the world hear how loud you can shout, and for how
                        little.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper discusses provisions of the bill readmitting Virginia to the
                    Union that the editors consider punitive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.28.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Plume</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Coleman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mr. Plume and Coleman opened a dancing academy in the Town Hall on
                    Wednesday. The paper recommends Mr. Plume as an "accomplished instructor."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper complains that the pavement along the wharf on Augusta Street is
                    in very bad condition. The editors call upon the street commissioners to make
                    repairs.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Sad Accident</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Erman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mahany</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>An "old gentleman" named George White fell from the railroad bridge while
                    attempting to cross it. Mr. Erman, an attendant at the Western Lunatic Asylum,
                    found him and carried him to the jail where several surgeons attempted to save
                    his life to no avail. A man named Mahany was arrested for throwing white from
                    the bridge and was released on $300 bail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Herron</ln>
                        <fn>T. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harman</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Friday night, $50 worth of leather was stolen from the tan-house of Mr.
                    T. D. Herron and a horse was stolen from the stable of William A. Hanger. The
                    South River Horse Thief Detective Club recovered the horse that was found loose
                    in the woods of John A. Harman. A man arrested an African American man who
                    attempted to sell leather resembling the stolen items. He was taken before the
                    Mayor but released for lack of evidence. Herron later identified the leather as
                    his.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Lavalette</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Towberman</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Joseph Carson and Miss Lavalette Swink, both of Augusta, were married in
                    Mint Spring on January 25th at the residence of John Towberman by Rev. Mr.
                    Murray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wright</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cox</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah Mildred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George W. Wright and Miss Sarah Mildred Cox, both of Augusta, were married
                    on January 20th by the Rev. William E. Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Magann</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blackwell</ln>
                        <fn>Mollie E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Beard</ln>
                        <fn>C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William H. Magann and Miss Mollie E. Blackwell, both of Augusta, were
                    married near Waynesboro at the residence of the bride's father on January 16th
                    by the Rev. C. Beard.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Nannie Robertson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>William S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hanger</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nannie Robertson Hanger, daughter of William S. and Margaret Hanger, died
                    in Churchville on December 31st. She was 21 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hays</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Margaret Hays died near Bethel Church, Augusta County, on December
                    29th. She was 96 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crist</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Miss Mary Crist died near Mint Spring at the residence of her brother on
                    December 26th after suffering a long illness.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Poage</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Nancy Poage, wife of James Poage, died on January 9th. She was 58
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Steele</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>Briscoe G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Martha Steele Baldwin, wife of the late Judge Briscoe G. Baldwin, died
                    at her Staunton residence on January 24th. She was 79 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.28.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
