<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.04.22">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/05/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-22">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">22</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.22.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.22.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>What we especially need in this locality is the development of our resources.
                        Everything tending to accelerate this should be fostered. In the first place
                        a progressive spirit--one which grasps great ideas and looks to the future
                        for advantages--not that spirit which only looks to the present to reap, but
                        rather that which plants and confidently waits till the harvest is ripened.
                        Then we need Railroads through our Valleys and Manufacturing establishments
                        at all available points, and near the raw material. This will rapidly
                            <sic>develope</sic> our resources, which would otherwise lie dormant, as
                        in the past. The progressive spirit we speak of is the power which is to put
                        all else in motion. It is that spirit which accomplishes every great work or
                        great good. In common parlance it is the "Venturer that makes the Merchant."</p>
                    <p>We were led to speak of this by an exhibition of this progressive spirit
                        before our Town Council at its last meeting, in the following resolution
                        offered by Councilman W.A. Burke.</p>
                    <p>Resolved--That all capital and property invested or employed in manufactures
                        in the town of Staunton within the next <emph rend="italic">three</emph>
                        years be exempt from (Corporation) taxation for <emph rend="italic"
                        >fifteen</emph> years.</p>
                    <p>This was followed by an accompanying resolution providing for the
                        promulgation of this resolution (should it pass the Council,) through the
                        necessary channels to reach the great Manufacturing interests of the
                        country.</p>
                    <p>Located as we are in the great iron centre of the country and soon to be in
                        easy access to the vast and unsurpassed coal mines of West Virginia, this
                        point and vicinity is destined to be the site of large manufacturing
                        establishments. But that we should have them here at the earliest day is
                        important. As an inducement to this end, the above resolution is of moment.
                        It is progressive in spirit and most assuredly a step in the right
                        direction. It exhibits a desire to have Manufacturers, come from where they
                        may, locate their establishments here, and a most liberal spirit in the
                        inducement it offers to them. Such inducements in less favored localities
                        have built up large Manufacturing interests, redounding ultimately to the
                        general good. This must follow as a consequence here.</p>
                    <p>We trust that the Council will consider the future interests of our citizens,
                        and pass the resolution, or a similar one, and accompany it with an
                        exposition of the many advantages of Staunton as a Manufacturing point. It
                        is only by such a spirit we can at the earliest possible period bring into
                        active use our undeveloped advantages, and secure early and increased
                        pecuniary prosperity to our people. As a matter, then, of material interest
                        to the people of both town and county it behooves our Council to fully
                        consider the resolution and take early action on it.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Comes out in full support of all measures designed to lure manufacturing
                    interests to the county. Praises a recent resolution offering corporations an
                    exemption from corporate taxes if they relocate to Staunton, and urges Staunton
                    residents to work for its passage.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have endeavored to enlist the active interest of the people of Staunton,
                        Augusta and adjoining counties in the effort to secure the work and repair
                        shops of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad Company, by calling attention to
                        some of the advantages, of the location here, to one and all of our people.
                        We have also endeavored to present some of the many advantages to the
                        company of the location of their shops at this place, in the hope that, even
                        before any particular steps are taken in that direction, the attention of
                        the directory might be called to it and the subject meet with a merited
                        consideration on their part. From the advantages already mentioned and
                        others which must suggest themselves to railroad-men, we believe that
                        Staunton will be one of the <emph rend="italic">few</emph> places, the
                        merits and demerits of which will be discussed when the subject of the
                        location of their shops comes properly before them. We also believe, that,
                        if our people will exhibit that interest which this matter seems to us to
                        demand at their hands, and make an united effort, both in exhibiting all the
                        advantages which this place offers, and in plainly offering inducements,
                        which our interests directly call upon us to offer, the directory will
                        unhesitatingly locate their shops here.</p>
                    <p>The repair shops of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad were located at Grafton,
                        when that place was nothing but a name, and the mere location of them there
                        has built up a population of from 4000 to 5000. That population is well
                        sustained and Grafton is now one of the thriving towns of West Virginia, and
                        all within a few years. May we not look for an equal addition to population
                        here from the location of the shops of a road which will, in a few years, be
                        the great through route from the Atlantic to the Pacific, and on which,
                        perhaps, three or four times as many trains must run daily as now run over
                        the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad? Will not such an increase of traffic
                        necessitate more repairs and a greater number of workmen here, than is
                        required at Grafton, and consequently a greater population than has been
                        brought to Grafton? With such prospective advantages to town and country,
                        does it not merit more interest than it receives at the hands of our people?
                        Ought we not to push this matter and leave not a stone unturned to secure
                        their location here, by donating the grounds, relieving from taxation
                        &amp;c, &amp;c? We believe that not one of the many readers of this
                        paper but will agree that it merits an effort. Consider this subject,
                        consult together, and let us take the necessary steps to secure this good to
                        our community. By merely wishing we may lose it, where an active effort may
                        secure it. We will have competitors for the location, therefore, let us put
                        the ball in motion and keep it moving till the end is secured.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Makes another effort to get people interested and active in getting the B
                    &amp; O Railroad to locate its repair shops in Staunton. Gives the example
                    of Grafton and its subsequent growth to display the economic benefits awaiting
                    Staunton if only its citizens would vigorously campaign for the repair shops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.22.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>A. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hendren</ln>
                        <fn>John N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper applauds the election of A. B. Cochran as City Judge and John N.
                    Hendren as County Judge.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scharf</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Prof.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Prof. Scharf will give a reading at the town hall on Tuesday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Grady's Circus will visit Staunton on April 28th. The Lynchburg news called
                    it the best to have visited that city in a long time.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stribling</ln>
                        <fn>F. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Western Lunatic Asylum issued its report for the years 1867-68 and
                    1868-69. Dr. F. T. Stribling has run the institution skillfully. The finances
                    were well-managed and are in good shape. Th Asylum had 338 inmates in September
                    1867, and admitted 204 since. Of those, 218 have left the institution, including
                    90 discharged, 2 eloped, 89 transferred, and 37 died. The percentage of deaths
                    fell from 13.38% in 1825 to 4.48% in 1869. The recovery rate stands at 42%.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Knisley</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Showalter</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forsythe</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jacob Knisly and Miss Amanda C. Showalter, both of Augusta, were married on
                    April 14th by the Rev. W. H. Forsythe.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clemmer</ln>
                        <fn>J. Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>S. Jennie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bushong</ln>
                        <fn>A. A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Henry Clemmer and Miss S. Jennie Snider, daughter of Adam Snider, both
                    of Augusta, were married on March 24th by the Rev. A. A. J. Bushong.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rivercomb</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blakemore</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Follansbee</ln>
                        <fn>James M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Rivercomb of California and formerly of Augusta, and Miss Mary Jane
                    Blakemore of Augusta, were married in Mt. Solon on April 7 by the Rev. James M.
                    Follansbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Deaths</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masincop</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Masincop</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John Masincop died near Churchville on April 3rd at the residence of his
                    son, Augustus Masincop. He was 94 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Henry T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheets</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Henry T. Sheets, son of Benjamin E. and Mary A. Sheets, died near Spring
                    Hill on March 11th. He was 2 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.22.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
