<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.12.09">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-12-09">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">9</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.09.01" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>06</column>
                <head>Sloppy Effusiveness</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper declares that "nothing is more annoying than that display of
                    affection which some husbands and wives show to each other in society." Although
                    some women consider that this "parade of love is the very essence of married
                    happiness," men "who have any manliness" do not "give in to this kind of thing."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.09.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The power of the country, due to the results of the war, until a short time
                        since, seemed to be irretrievably in the hands of the Republican party for
                        years to come, much to the regret of those who witnessed the extravagances,
                        persecutions and proscriptions of that party, and who longed for the return
                        to that economical management of public affairs, which marked the history of
                        public functionaries until the Republican party came in power, and that
                        liberty to the individual citizen which made the United States the proud
                        boast of all peoples and the asylum for the oppressed of all countries and
                        climes. This very belief in its long-lease of power has prevented the
                        Republican party from practicing that economy, so boasted by its military
                        leader, on his elevation to the Presidency, and has led it into the
                        extravagances and persecutions which have so markedly characterized it. It
                        has signally failed, therefore, to fulfill the mission of a party in power
                        in peaceful times, and its extravagances have disgusted Republicans,
                        themselves, who calmly considered the results in the future. Hence the
                        internal feuds of the party, which must result in its loss of power and
                        ultimate utter overthrow.</p>
                    <p>Will these feuds result in a new or third party? There is not the least
                        likelihood of it. We see that some of our exchanges speak of a National
                        Conservative party, similar to the Conservative party of Virginia, to
                        accomplish the overthrow of the National Republican party. This is simply a
                        repugnance to the name Democrat, and will amount to nothing. The Democratic
                        party has been nobly contending against the Republican party for years and
                        has never succumbed to any third party, even in its days of greatest
                        adversity, and now, upon the threshold of almost certain triumph, its giving
                        place to a third party to accomplish the end, almost already attained by it,
                        is not to be expected, and will not be by those who take a calm retrospect
                        of the long struggle between Democracy and Radicalism. Besides this, the
                        very principles contended for by the several reform feuds have been
                        advocated by the Democracy, and with the success that has attended the party
                        of late. In it then the reformers find their objects combined and it is not
                        likely they will attempt the formation of a third party, to do over the work
                        accomplished by the Democracy since the war. It is, therefore, utter folly
                        to advocate a third party and only argues a prejudiced enmity to the mere
                        name of Democracy. This film is clearly seen through, and those who really
                        desire the overthrow of Radicalism would do well to discard their prejudice
                        and unite with the Democracy.--Whether they do or not, the Democratic party
                        will, at no very distant day, win that success which it has so long
                        contended for. The Republican party will go down, but it will not be by the
                        aid of a new or third party. It will be before that party, which has won the
                        victory in the late elections.--It will be before the Democratic party,
                        which contains the principles necessary to unite the reformers in its fold,
                        and all the elements necessary to secure success, besides the prestige of
                        its recent victories.</p>
                    <p>Be ye prejudiced ones warned in time, and join the victorious column of
                        Democracy, and wait for your third party until Radicalism sinks into its
                        already deeply dug grave.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on all those who dislike the Republicans to join the Democrats, whom
                    the editor insists will certainly triumph in future elections. Dismisses
                    attempts to form conservative third parties, believes that will just delay the
                    inevitable rise to power of the Democratic party.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.09.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baldwin</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Baldwin delivered a temperance address in the M. E. Church South
                    on behalf of Staunton Council No. 47.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Yost</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Maj. S. M. Yost, former editor of the Vindicator, and editor at the
                    Rockingham Register, Lexington, Mo., Expositor, and St. Louis Daily Times,
                    recently purchased the Valley Virginian.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The paper reports that prior claims that John Wilson had committed suicide
                    are untrue. He died of natural causes.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Christmas Tree</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Simpson</ln>
                        <fn>A. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The officers, teachers, and friends of the Southern M. E. Sunday School are
                    holding a Christmas Tree celebration for the students. They also elected
                    officers for the upcoming year.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClung</ln>
                        <fn>James A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waddell</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. James A. McClung died at the Staunton residence of his
                    brother-in-law, Senator Joseph Waddell, after suffering a lingering illness of
                    several weeks. "Capt. McClung was connected with the Virginia Hotel, in this
                    place, for many years, as one of its Proprietors, and with the Exchange Hotel in
                    Richmond as manager, and for several years prior to his death had sole charge of
                    the celebrated Hot Springs of Virginia. He was famous as a Hotel manager, was a
                    genial and whole-souled gentleman, and perhaps the most widely known Hotel man
                    in the State. His kind, cordial and pleasant manners won him a host of friends,
                    by whom his loss is deeply felt."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Bronzed Bust of Lee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Donovan</ln>
                        <fn>W. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The citizens of New York plan to present a bust of Gen. Lee to Washington
                    and Lee University. W. R. O'Donovan, late resident of Staunton, will do the
                    work. He "served honorably in the Confederate army throughout the war and
                    afterwards, while engaged with Messrs. Marquis and Kelley of this place,
                    executed a life-like bust of his old commander, 'Stonewall Jackson.'" He now
                    lives in New York, and would be the perfect choice to do the Lee bust.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxell</ln>
                        <fn>John G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Price</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John G. Troxell and Miss Sarah J. Price, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Newport on November 16th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swisher</ln>
                        <fn>James F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Troxell</ln>
                        <fn>Mary J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James F. Swisher of Rockbridge and Miss Mary J. Troxell of Augusta were
                    married near Newport on November 17th by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ellinger</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wayman</ln>
                        <fn>B. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Ellinger and Miss Sarah M. Gordon, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Newport on December 1st by the Rev. B. C. Wayman.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Handy</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac W. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Edward Crawford and Miss Sadie Elizabeth Crawford, daughter of William
                    Crawford of Augusta, were married on November 30th at the house of the bride's
                    father by the Rev. Isaac W. K. Handy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shumate</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>Jennie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shafer</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pratt</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas Shumate of Staunton and Miss Jennie M. Shafer, daughter of the late
                    David Shafer of Rockbridge, were married on November 30th at the residence of
                    the bride's mother by the Rev. Mr. Pratt.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>Nimrod</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Swink</ln>
                        <fn>Nancy J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Nimrod Gordon and Miss Nancy J. Swink, both of Augusta, were married on
                    November 10th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>John M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lamb</ln>
                        <fn>Clara C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John M. Brown and Miss Clara C. Lamb, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 1st by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rohrer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel A. Dunlap and Miss Eliza D. Rohrer, both of Augusta, were married
                    near Churchville on December 1st by the Rev. J. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waid</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>John B. Waid died at Newport on November 27th of consumption. He was 27
                    years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Lieucetta H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Arehart</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lieucetta H. Arehart, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Arehart, died on
                    November 25th. She was 3 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. William Thompson died at the residence of her husband in Spring Hill
                    on December 3rd.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.09.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
