<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.01.07">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>01/31/06</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-01-07">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>7</day>
            <weekday id="FRI">Friday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.07.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.07.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The money question is that most talked of in these times. From every part of
                        the country, as well as this State, comes the cry of hard times, and
                        incidental thereto among business men the National Bank system and National
                        Banks come in for their share of discussion and criticism. As to the system,
                        we have nothing to say now, but in regard to the National Banks of the South
                        and their interest in and effect upon Southern communities we shall, as a
                        duty we owe to our people, have a word or two to say. Judging from the
                        National Banks in this locality, all in the South were started largely by
                        the capital of Baltimoreans and Northern men to aid in building up the
                        pecuniary interests of the people of the South. These foreign stockholders,
                        as many of them have repeatedly asserted, did not take the stock in Southern
                        Banks with the view of reaping a pecuniary profit directly therefrom, but,
                        as we have said, solely to aid in building up the pecuniary condition of the
                        South and increasing the field of their then contracted trade. Started on
                        this idea and for this purpose, some have loaned money at fair rates to
                        those asking their assistance, while others have loaned at most exorbitant
                        rates, or else refusing to discount on account of "scarcity of money," have
                        either bought the same paper at an enormous deduction with the same "scarce"
                        supply of money, or sent the individual to a third party, who was furnished
                        with a portion of this "scarce" supply, with which to buy up good paper at a
                        large discount.</p>
                    <p>This torturing the legitimate system of banking and converting the Banks into
                        mere <emph rend="italic">shaving</emph> shops, to play upon the necessities
                        of the people, has enabled many to pay large salaries to their officers and
                        set aside a handsome <emph rend="italic">per cent</emph> to their surplus
                        fund and declare very large dividends to their stockholders.</p>
                    <p>Now this is all wrong. The Banks were started in the South, as we again
                        re-iterate, for the purpose of aiding the Southern people and should have
                        that end strictly in view. Instead of shaving them to the utmost extent,
                        when needing assistance, to increase the dividends of stockholders, (which
                        in some instances has ranged from 20 to 30 <emph rend="italic">per
                        cent</emph> a very large portion of which is sent to foreign stockholders,
                        never to return, thereby impoverishing to that amount the very communities
                        they were established to aid,) they should so manage their affairs as to
                        render that aid to the people which was the object of their establishment.
                        Let them cut down expenses. Some cashiers receive large salaries, while
                        others doing twice the business get not over half so much. Clerks, Tellers,
                        &amp;c., may get but moderate amounts for the work they do, but we know
                        there are leaks somewhere. Then, we repeat, let them cut down expenses, loan
                        at a fair, living rate and though they may not declare large dividends, they
                        will have benefited community much more, and indirectly largely advanced the
                        interests of stockholders. As the meetings of Stockholders takes place
                        everywhere in a few days, we beg leave to call their attention to the much
                        talked of and crying evil of National Bank mismanagement and to take steps
                        to correct it. Elect directors who will look to the interest of community,
                        as indirectly effecting the interest and efficiency of the bank, and will
                        not agree to pay large salaries to officers simply to pile up large
                        dividends, drawn from the necessities of a people struggling with pecuniary
                        embarrassments, but giving fair salaries and content with fair rates of
                        interest, really aid the people of their respective localities.</p>
                    <p>If the stockholders do not attend to this and prevent their institutions from
                        being converted into mere shaving shops, they can only expect squalls. Some
                        individual, extorted upon, will with the U.S. Banking Law in his hand, not
                        only defy them, but recover from them double the amount of his <emph
                            rend="italic">shaven</emph> note. Attend to this ye stockholders, in
                        your approaching meetings, all over the South, and let "a word to the wise
                        suffice."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The paper discusses the relationship of banks to the current hard economic
                    times in the South. Though some banks operate only to benefit the southern
                    economy, others use the scarcity of money as an excuse to grow rich off of high
                    interest rates.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor of the Vindicator announces the beginning of the eighth new
                    volume of the paper published under his tenure. "In that time we all have passed
                    through trials to which few people in the world have been subjected, and even at
                    this late day are subjected to the conditions of those who were victorious alone
                    through might. In this trial the Vindicator has endeavored to vindicate the
                    cause of its readers and locality and has raised a warning voice against every
                    thing that militated against their just rights and their interest." The editor
                    calls attention to the growth of the paper from a half-sheet to "the largest in
                    size of any paper in the State."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.07.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Waynesboro Up to the Mark</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The people of Waynesboro raised and slaughtered 30,000 pounds of pork this
                    season.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Deaf, Dumb, and Blind Institution hosted a very successful tableaux and
                    concert.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>William McComb's home near Barterbrook burned on December 28th. The fire
                    was started when a young girl entered a clothes-closet with a lighted candle.
                    The home was insured by the Southern Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Richmond
                    whose agent came up the next day and presented Mr. McComb with a check to cover
                    the loss. "This speaks volumes for the promptness and responsibility of the
                    Southern Mutual Insurance Company. Its terms are most liberal and losses
                    promptly paid."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hall</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duckett</ln>
                        <fn>Sophia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Duckett</ln>
                        <fn>Benjamin M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dudley</ln>
                        <fn>T. U.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Alexander Hall, formerly of Staunton, and Miss Sophia Duckett, daughter of
                    the late Benjamin M. Duckett, of Prince George's County, Maryland, were married
                    in Baltimore at Christ Church on December 8th by the Rev. T. U. Dudley.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Zachary F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerby</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>C. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Zachary F. Crickenberger of Albemarle and Miss Elizabeth F. Kerby of
                    Augusta were married at the residence of the bride's parents on December 28th by
                    the Rev. C. F. Fry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kibler</ln>
                        <fn>Green M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburne</ln>
                        <fn>Elmira E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fishburne</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hammack</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Green M. Kibler and Miss Elmira E. Fishburne, daughter of Daniel Fishburne
                    of Augusta, were married near Spring Hill on December 24th by the Rev. C. B.
                    Hammack.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risque</ln>
                        <fn>J. Willie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Nella A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Langhorn</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J. Willie Risque, formerly of Staunton, and Miss Nella A. Jones of
                    Lynchburg were married in Lynchburg's Centenary Church on December 22nd by the
                    Rev. George Langhorn.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baylor</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoover</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George M. Baylor and Miss Elizabeth C. Hoover, both of Augusta, were
                    married on December 22nd by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wise</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cook</ln>
                        <fn>Harriet F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lewis A. Wise of Culpeper and Miss Harriet F. Cook of Augusta were married
                    on December 28th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>Fred L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn>Amanda</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fultz</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Baker</ln>
                        <fn>William E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Fred L. Fultz and Miss Amanda Fultz, daughter of Judge Fultz, were married
                    at the Presbyterian Church in Staunton on December 28th by the Rev. William E.
                    Baker.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Livick</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>Ginnie</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>J. I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A. J. Livick of Augusta and Miss Ginnie Robinson of Rockbridge were married
                    in Rockbridge on December 23rd by the Rev. J. I. Miller.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crosby</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Koontz</ln>
                        <fn>Liza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James Crosby and Miss Liza Koontz, both of Augusta, were married near
                    Churchville on December 30th by the Rev. J. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pool</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Huffer</ln>
                        <fn>Eliza</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hott</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Pool and Miss Eliza Huffer, both of Augusta, were married on
                    December 30th by the Rev. J. W. Hott.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Janet Taylor</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>H. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Maj.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bell</ln>
                        <fn>Ann</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Janet Taylor Bell, daughter of Major H. M. and Ann Bell of Staunton, died
                    on January 1st.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth S. Johnson, wife of Robert Johnson, died in Staunton on
                    December 22nd. She was 62 years old. She was a member of the Episcopal Church.
                    She was a "modest woman, affectionate daughter, devoted wife, and fond mother."
                    She bore her "painful affliction" with "christian resignation."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.01.07.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
