<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.04.08">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/02/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-04-08">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day norm="">8</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.08.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.08.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>"Treason to the Old Mother"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Such is the language which one of the Richmond papers applies to the
                        advocates of the Valley Railroad, declaring that they are guilty of "treason
                        to the old mother," Virginia. We think it full time to let those who utter
                        such sentiments in the interest of Eastern Virginia cities and of the Grand
                        Monarque of consolidation know that the people of this Valley, following the
                        lead and sustained by the approval of Robert E. Lee, and other eminent
                        citizens, are neither traitors to Virginia, nor inimical to her highest
                        welfare, when they declare, that "the longitudinal bisection of the Valley"
                        by a continuous line of railway is essential to their interests, and that
                        they intend to have it. In the opinion of our great Metropolitan Editors,
                        Norfolk, Petersburg and Richmond constitute the State. They utterly ignore
                        the great laboring and producing classes every where scattered throughout
                        the Commonwealth. They should remember, that under our benign constitution,
                        cities have ceased to be the fountains of supply to the treasury; and that
                        the great agricultural, manufacturing and mining interests, and the capital
                        invested in them constitute the broad basis of taxation and governmental
                        support. Taxation on licenses is almost done away with; the values of
                        property are to be chiefly looked to for revenue. It is these we wish to
                        increase and develop, not peculiarly for the sake of Richmond, or
                        Petersburg, or Norfolk, or Baltimore, but for our own sake and that of all
                        Virginia. Let Baltimore and Richmond strive against each other, as they may;
                        it is for our good the competition will be sustained. Every inducement
                        Richmond, and the railways leading to that city, offer for our trade, is so
                        much in diminution of the burden which would be upon it, had we only
                        Alexandria or Baltimore to look to; and, so, the bids of Alexandria and
                        Baltimore, and of the roads leading thitherward, tend to reduce the charges
                        on our produce sent forward, and on the goods brought back. And this is what
                        our people want; this is what Virginia's interests demand--free competition
                        among the <sic>marts</sic> of trade; and free transit over the avenues of
                        traffic. If our farmers want Smythe county plaster, we desire the same cars,
                        which receive it at the mines, to come, by the Virginia and Tennessee and
                        Valley Railroads, direct to Staunton. And so, when the great coal fields of
                        the West are opened and our manufacturing establishments are built up, we
                        wish free and unobstructed transit for our fabrics and products, West,
                        Southwest, East and Northeast; so that we may <emph rend="italic">buy</emph>
                        in the <emph rend="italic">cheapest</emph> and <emph rend="italic"
                        >ship</emph> to the <emph rend="italic">highest markets</emph>. We utterly
                        repudiate all tariffs for the great protection of cities at the expense of
                        the interests of the interior. Let the cities grow by means of their own
                        energies and enterprize, and by the prudent and profitable use of their own
                        capital. We protest against the metropolitan idea of building up great
                        cities by taxation of the farmers, miners and manufacturers of the interior.
                        And what does all this "war of the giants" mean, but this? Daily, we see in
                        the Richmond papers such heavily leaded headings as these: "Baltimore versus
                        Richmond," "Lady Baltimore's new domain," "Baltimore flanking Richmond,"
                        "Baltimore 200 miles in the rear of Richmond," and others of equally
                        startling import. All the while, the eager combatants forget that there are
                            <emph rend="italic">some</emph> interests outside of the city
                        precincts--that there are <emph rend="italic">some</emph> people, who don't
                        live in cities and who, in our Valleys and along our mountain slopes, desire
                        cheap transportation for their products and easy access to the best markets.
                        We ask what means this theory of consolidation--of compulsion to trade--of
                        damming up the natural outlets of traffic, and forcing it into artificial
                        channels towards selected localities? Why, it means taxation upon
                        production, to sustain cities, which cannot sustain themselves. It means,
                        that the farmers of Augusta, for example, shall pay twenty cents a barrel
                            <emph rend="italic">more</emph> to get their flour to market than they
                        would be required to pay, if <emph rend="italic">other</emph> channels were
                        opened. Say, the construction of the Valley Railroad will cheapen
                        transportation on all articles of traffic, in the proportion of ten cents on
                        a barrel of flour; and, what would be the result? Why, upon the whole trade
                        of the county the saving would be from thirty to forty thousand dollars a
                        year. This saving is actual increase of wealth; because the wealth of a
                        country consists in the <sic>nett</sic> results of its labor. And, on the
                        other hand, any system of policy, or of supposed policy, which prevents this
                        saving, is in effect, oppressive taxation upon labor, and tends to make a
                        poor people poorer.</p>
                    <p>Let the people of Augusta, then, look to their own interests. Let them see to
                        it, that they lose not the present opportunity to secure one more competing
                        line of road for their trade and travel. Let Richmond news papers call them
                        traitors to the old mother" if they choose; yet, conscious of a record of
                        loyal patriotism and devotion to Virginia, at least, as fair as their
                        traducers can produce, let them resolve to look to their own interests; to
                        build up their own interests; to build up their own enterprises; to add to
                        their own wealth and population; and, thus, will they prove themselves to be
                        loyal "to the old mother," the sneers of Richmond papers to the contrary,
                        notwithstanding.</p>
                    <p>In a word, let an overwhelming vote for the Valley Railroad subscription be
                        the response of Augusta to the unkindly and unjust assaults recently made
                        upon the people of this Valley&gt;.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Launches a verbal defense of the interests of the Valley against the
                    insults hurled by city newspapers. Asks why farmers should be taxed and endure
                    tariffs just to supply cities, when farmers have to look after their own
                    interests. Especially dislikes attacks on building Valley railroads, something
                    the editor feels is crucial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>In our last we called attention to the necessity of our people taking steps
                        to secure the location of the repair shops of the Chesapeake and Ohio
                        Railroad at this point which we are glad to see has aroused, to a
                        considerable extent, the interest of many here in this subject.</p>
                    <p>We propose now to speak of some <del/> the advantages to the company of the
                        location of their shops at this place.</p>
                    <p>In the first place, it is a central point on the road. This is of momentous
                        consequence in the successful running of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad
                        when completed, which we have no doubt will be duly appreciated by the
                        energetic men at the head of this company.</p>
                    <p>The location of their shops will bring a number of employees, whose wants as
                        consumers must be supplied to a great extent from the adjacent country.</p>
                    <p>At no point along the line can this be so readily and cheaply done as here.
                        Staunton is the regular market for a number of the adjacent counties, and is
                        accessible by good roads from others, and, besides, the production of
                        Augusta alone would furnish, from first hands, without cost of
                        transportation, nearly all that the employees and families would need, an
                        item of great interest to those employed by the company and of consequent
                        consideration to the Directors.</p>
                    <p>In this connection the advantages of churches and schools, of every
                        denomination, is also of consequence. The employees can, in this respect,
                        enjoy privileges not in their reach at any point on the line, certainly not
                        at any central point, and even Richmond does not surpass us in point of
                        schools. The laboring man will come more readily and remain more contentedly
                        with such advantages, than where he is secluded or deprived of them, and
                        this is also a matter of consequence to those interested in the great
                        Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad.</p>
                    <p>There must of necessity be a large consumption of materials--wood, iron,
                        steel &amp;c--in such repair shops, and we venture the assertion that
                        this, as a location, will not be excelled in the ability to supply all
                        demands in that line. The timber can readily be obtained from our extensive
                        forests, the supply of which is nearly or quite inexhaustible. The very
                        opening of this great road through the iron to the coal district will darken
                        the heavens along its route, especially in this locality, with the smoke of
                        Furnaces &amp;c. The necessary consequence of this will be the
                        establishment of Rolling Mills, Steel works, Nail factories &amp;c.,
                        near by. Their establishment also depends greatly upon the ability to supply
                        the necessary wants of those employed therein. In this respect the
                        advantages of Staunton and vicinity cannot be overlooked, and hence not only
                        the probability or possibility, but the almost positive certainty, in the
                        near future, of the erection of these and various other kinds of
                        manufacturing establishments here, near the great coal and iron beds of
                        Virginia and West Virginia.</p>
                    <p>This, as a means of supplying nearly all other materials, ready for
                        manipulation in the Repair Shops, without the expense of transportation, and
                        consequently at the cheapest possible cost, must be looked to by the company
                        and have a weighty consideration in the location of their shops at Staunton.</p>
                    <p>But as a people we must not content ourselves to stand by with our hands in
                        our pockets, and merely hope for their location here. We must show the
                        Directory the advantages at greater length then can be done in a newspaper
                        article. We must exhibit to them all the advantages and in all their
                        bearings and then, if needs be, make it their interest to locate here.</p>
                    <p>It is we think, decidedly to their interest to do so, and we know it is the
                        direct interest of our people, not only of town and county, but of adjacent
                        counties, that they should, and not a stone should be left unturned to
                        secure it. We ask on the part of our people that active interest which the
                        subject so imperatively demands.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Favors all measures designed to entice the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad to
                    locate their repair shops in Staunton. Lists all the benefits such a move would
                    bring to Staunton and the qualifications the town has for supporting repair
                    shops. Urges all residents to do what they can to make the venture succeed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.08.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunter</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Risk</ln>
                        <fn>H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. Hunter will replace H. Risk as guager.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuart</ln>
                        <fn>Martha</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>M. A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Stuart, an African American woman, was committed to jail by Mayor
                    Allan. She is charged with breaking into the house of Mr. M. A. Miller and
                    stealing clothing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harlan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Murray attempted to escape from jail on Sunday by removing the
                    window frame. Mr. Harlan, the jailor, heard the noises and prevented the escape.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Wholesale Arrest</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Parrent</ln>
                        <fn>J. T.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Othello</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Green</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>R. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allan</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mayor</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>J.T. Parrent, Chief of Police, arrested three persons calling themselves
                    Othello Clark, William Green, and R. M. Wilson. They had horses in their
                    possession matching the description of animals stolen from Brooke County, West
                    Virginia. Mayor Allan committed the men to jail.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>02</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Scherer</ln>
                        <fn>John B.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stafford</ln>
                        <fn>C. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crickard</ln>
                        <fn>James P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Toole</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>O'Brian</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gregory</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>B. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Waters</ln>
                        <fn>J. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>White</ln>
                        <fn>A. E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fifer</ln>
                        <fn>G. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Johnson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Augusta Fire Company elected the following officers: John B. Scherer,
                    Jr., Capt.; C. W. Stafford, Lt.; James P. Crickard, 1st Engineer; Patrick
                    O'Toole, 2nd Engineer; Michael Kennedy, 3rd Engineer; James O'Brian, 4th
                    Engineer; Charles Gregory, 1st Hose Director; James W. Smith, 2nd Hose Director;
                    B. F. Fifer, Secretary; J. H. Waters, Treasurer; A. E. White, Librarian; G. M.
                    Fifer, Assistant Librarian; James Johnson, engine keeper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>William B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William B. Dunlap and Miss Sarah C. Brown, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 20th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trainum</ln>
                        <fn>David C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Frances L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David C. Trainum and Miss Frances L. Smith, both of Augusta, were married
                    on March 24th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dunlap</ln>
                        <fn>James L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kerr</ln>
                        <fn>Mary A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ewing</ln>
                        <fn>D. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James L. Dunlap and Miss Mary A. Kerr, both of Augusta, were married on
                    March 27th by the Rev. D. B. Ewing.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKee</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Catharine McKee, wife of Samuel McKee, died near Middlebrook on March
                    18th after a painful illness of three weeks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>02</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilkeson</ln>
                        <fn>David W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>David W. Gilkeson died near Greenville of consumption on March 31st. He was
                    22 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.04.08.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
