<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hwp type="newspaper" id="rv1870/va.au.rv.1870.12.16">
    <header>
        <title>Staunton Vindicator</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andre Fleche</taggerName>
            <tagDate>12/28/05</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Staunton</city><county>Augusta</county><state>Virginia</state></address>
        <date n="1870-12-16">
            <year>1870</year>
            <month norm="12">December</month>
            <day norm="">16</day>
            <weekday id=""/>
        </date>
        <frequency>Weekly</frequency>
        <extent/>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.16.01" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.16.02" exists="no">
            <div type="e">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The whole aim of the Radical party, since the war, has been the retention of
                        power. Every act of legislation by Republican Congresses pointed to this
                        end. This has incited the passage of Amendments, Test-oath laws, Manhood
                        suffrage acts and Military enforcement bills.</p>
                    <p>The seeming necessity for enactment to bolster up their party has carried
                        Republicans to the excesses which have so marked their legislation since
                        1865.</p>
                    <p>With the fall of the Confederacy the keystone of the Republican arch,
                        Slavery, also dropped out, and the crumbling away of the whole arch was
                        anticipated. Then it was that New England furnished the limbs of her
                        celebrated "Blue Law" Tree, mentioned above as Amendments &amp;c., to
                        make a frame work to support it, and to give it greater strength added a
                        prop from the South, called "citizenship of African descent." The latter
                        gave great strength for a time, but was being sapped, like the rest of its
                        props, by the moist swamp air of the South and freezing winds of the West.
                        This prop itself needing a support, the military enforcement of suffrage was
                        brought to bear. Like all the rest it proved a slender stay. New York and
                        North Carolina, to whom it was applied as a panacea for their Democratic
                        ills, have proved its utter inutility. The presence of would-be overawing
                        bayonets but confirmed them in their Democracy, and the Congressional
                        Committee is now discussing the propriety of repealing this bill. Butler is,
                        however tinkering away at lumber for additional supports, which he calls
                        "War with England," and "Amnesty (?) Bill." This he thinks will give longer
                        lease of life and power to the Republican party. When other and heavier
                        lumber has failed, what can be expected of the slender rods shaven up by the
                        inevitable Ben! All such aims have thus far failed and will continue so to
                        do, despite the <sic>efierts</sic> of such partisan Mechanics as are engaged
                        in patching the Republican fabric.</p>
                    <p>In fact, the doom of any party, which forgets the interests of the whole
                        people and only looks to the retention of the spoils, is written before
                        hand. It is thus with the Republican party. The crash of its now tottering
                        arch will be heard ere long, and the wise and wary seeing it, are getting
                        from under.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Gives several reasons why the Republican party is doomed to die. Claims
                    they only passed legislation like black suffrage and test-oaths to keep
                    themselves in power while neglecting the people. Believes such measures will not
                    work anymore because the voters have seen through them.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.16.03" exists="no">
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Engle</ln>
                        <fn>J. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolfe</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The ladies of New Hope will hold a supper on December 27th to help raise
                    funds for the Round Hill Church. Rev. J. J. Engle will deliver a temperance
                    address, and the Rev. Mr. Wolfe will speak on Masonry.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>House and Barn Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Karicofe</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The home and barn of James Karicofe near Sangersville was destroyed in a
                    fire. His loss is estimated at $4000 to $5000. The widow Carson who was keeping
                    furniture in the house lost $150 to $200 in damages.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>01</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ketchum</ln>
                        <fn>Annie Chambers</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Vindicator thanks Mrs. Annie Chambers Ketchum, newly appointed chair of
                    Belles Lettres at the Virginia Female Institute, for a copy of her Christmas
                    Carol entitled "Benny." The story is "poetically told, and contains a happy
                    moral which will be appreciated by both old and young." She also submits a poem
                    to the paper.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rusmisel</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Mattie D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clayton</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blain</ln>
                        <fn>J. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>George Rusmisel and Miss Mattie D. Clayton, daughter of the late Thomas
                    Clayton, were married in Deerfield, Augusta County, on December 1st by the Rev.
                    J. S. Blain. "May their journey through life be as pleasant as was the bright
                    weather on the evening the merry bride was received at her new home in Moscow."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Campbell</ln>
                        <fn>Lawson P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rediford</ln>
                        <fn>Cynthia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schreckhise</ln>
                        <fn>J. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Lawson P. Campbell and Miss Cynthia Rediford, both of Augusta, were married
                    on November 20th by the Rev. J. M. Schreckhise.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>James W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>Ophelia</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>John P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Patterson</ln>
                        <fn>Brown</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murray</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>James W. Wallace and Ophelia Wilson, daughter of the late John P. Wilson,
                    were married near Barterbrook at the residence of Brown Patterson by the Rev.
                    James Murray.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snapp</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Elizabeth Snapp died on December 11th. She was 67 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamilton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>William Hamilton died at his residence near Christians Creek on November
                    14th. He was 71 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>01</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <transcript>
                    <p/>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fuller</ln>
                        <fn>Calvin I.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Calvin I. Fuller, formerly of Mt. Solon, died in Missouri on November 23rd.
                    He was 46 years old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="va.au.rv.1870.12.16.04" exists="no">
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
