<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.01.21">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/17/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-21">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>21</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.21.01">
            <pageNote>Reprint of address of New York Gov. Seymour to the New York State Assembly,
                plus classifieds and fiction</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.21.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>A Black Secessionist</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors quote an exchange between Thaddeus Stevens and another Senator,
                    in which Stevens admits that he does not believe the seceded states are members
                    of the Union. This serves as an endorsement of secession, the editors write, and
                    Stevens can be considered as bad as Jefferson Davis. The right of states to
                    remove themselves has been denied by "true friends of the Union," and Steven's
                    statement proves him an enemy of the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Election of a U.S. Senator--Hon. C. R. Buckalew</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Above all, we feel the deepest rejoicing at his success, as a pure-minded,
                    capable statesman, over the arts and debaucheries of corruption and corruptors.
                    . . . We look upon the dawning of a better day in the Commonwealth. The power of
                    a tempter's gold over the souls of honest men has lost its prestige, and we
                    hope, passed away for ever. Pennsylvania may well be proud of her redemption."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the election by the state legislature of Charles R.
                    Buckalew, a Democrat, to the U.S. Senate, by sixty-seven to sixty-five over
                    Cameron. Buckalew comes from Columbia County, where he was a prosecuting
                    attorney, state senator, and chairman of the state Democratic party. Buckalew
                    was also U.S. minister to Ecuador from 1858 to 1861. The editors praise the
                    absence of partisan acrimony during the election, as well as Buckalew's
                    integrity and opposition to the "fanatical, abolition party."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Correspondence from "the Army of the Potomac"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"None of us are "spilling for a fight"--that exclamation in an earnest tone
                    has had its day; but it does seem singular that there is not something done to
                    convince the country and the world that the Grand Army of the Potomac, the most
                    splendid military organization of modern times, is capable of doing its full
                    share in speedily ending the Rebellion."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Correspondence of the <emph rend="italic">Spirit and Times.</emph></p>
                    <p>In Camp Near Fredericksburg, Va. <lb/>January 6th, 1863.</p>
                    <p>There is nothing new to write about from the army at this time. The most
                        profound quietness prevails. As far as my observations extend, and my
                        information has been gleaned, we are again in good fighting trim and ready
                        to be led against the foe. Why it is that we are kept here so long,
                        inactive, I cannot conjecture. Everything has been auspicious for active
                        operations. Such splendid weather as we have had for this time in the
                        season, has no parallel in the memory of the oldest inhabitant. The roads
                        are in as good condition as they possibly can be and the organization and
                        condition of the army can scarcely be made better. None of us are "spilling
                        for a fight"--that exclamation in an earnest tone has had its day; but it
                        does seem singular that there is not something done to convince the country
                        and the world that the Grand Army of the Potomac, the most splendid military
                        organization of modern times, is capable of doing its full share in speedily
                        ending the Rebellion. I don't see any sign of a movement soon, and when we
                        do move our leaders, I think, will not be so fool-hardy as to risk another
                        attack on Fredericksburg. The question then is what route towards Richmond
                        will we take. It has been demonstrated over and over again, that the only
                        practicable rout, with any hope of success, is by the Peninsula. If,
                        therefore, we are at last to move in that direction now is the propitious
                        time to do it. We are favored by the weather, and while Jeff. Davis has
                        considerable on his hands in the West and Southwest. To wait until the
                        spring and summer months, would be to incur the risks of disease, high
                        waters and another concentration of the Rebel Army at Richmond. Let us have
                        McClellan in command again and proceed to the work at once, and while it is
                        being done, let the Washington authorities obey the demands of the army in
                        furnishing the necessary supplies and not in any way interfere with the
                        military programme of its commander. We may then have some show of success
                        and the grand Army of the Potomac will have at last accomplished the purpose
                        of its formation.</p>
                    <p>This is all I have to say this week.</p>
                    <p>Shenandoah.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Shenandoah</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>A short letter from a correspondent in the 126th Reg't Penn. Reserves,
                    reporting that all is quiet at their camp near Fredericksburg. The author
                    expresses his hope that nobody plans to attack the city again in the near
                    future.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Letter from the 107th</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The troops then took supper and we all laid down on the plain to rest for
                    the night, whilst the frost gently fell upon our unsheltered forms. Saturday
                    morning, the 13th, came and with it as it rose a beautiful sun. We eat our
                    breakfasts, knowing soon the great "ball," of which Burnside and Lee were the
                    floor managers, would open."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We are indebted to Dr. Reid, of this place, for the following letter from
                        Lieut. Carman of the 107th Reg't P.V. He has kindly consented to its
                        publication:</p>
                    <p>Headquarters 107th Reg't P.V. <lb/>In Camp Near Bell Plain Landing, Va.,
                        <lb/>December 25th, 1862.</p>
                    <p><emph rend="italic">Dear</emph> ____: Thinking you would like to hear from
                        the old One Hundred &amp; Seventh, since the late battle, as there is a
                        good number in it from Franklin county, being Christmas day and nothing
                        doing, I have concluded to give you a history of the regiment's doings; its
                        condition before going into battle; its conduct whilst being engaged; its
                        appearance and condition after coming out of the slaughter, for such I call
                        it.</p>
                    <p>On Tuesday, the 9th inst., we were ordered to break up camp at Brook's
                        Station and take up our line of march. On the 10th we encamped in the Pines,
                        about two miles from the Rappahannock river. At 9 o'clock at night we
                        received orders to have three day's cooked rations in haversacks, both
                        officers and men, and be ready to march at 3 o'clock next morning the 11th
                        inst., to cross the river at daybreak. We arrived at the river when the
                        bombardment of Fredericksburg commenced, which lasted until the Sun went
                        down behind the western hills. Our Brigade laid near the river on the north
                        side, all day on the 11th. On Friday, the 12th, the army crossed the river.
                        After we crossed, the left grand division maneuvred [sic] on the plain,
                        which is about five miles long and two wide. It was a magnificent sight to
                        see that army move in column by divisions, and in line of battle by
                        regiments, then by brigades. It was a beautiful day--the sight was an
                        imposing one.</p>
                    <p>The troops then took supper and we all laid down on the plain to rest for the
                        night, whilst the frost gently fell upon our unsheltered forms. Saturday
                        morning, the 13th, came and with it as it rose a beautiful sun. We eat our
                        breakfasts, knowing soon the great "ball," of which Burnside and Lee were
                        the floor managers, would open. Sure enough, in about half an hour, the
                        battle commenced. Our brigade, the first brigade in Gen. Gibbons' division,
                        was ordered into a corn-field to support a battery, where we remained
                        subjected to a heavy fire of shell and shot, which was aimed at the battery
                        for three hours.</p>
                    <p>About half-past one o'clock, p.m., the infantry was engaged, and finally one
                        brigade of our division was ordered forward, then another and so on, until
                        at last our brigade was ordered by Gen. Gibbons to charge on and through a
                        belt of wood that was in the rear of the railroad. The knapsacks were
                        unslung and at it we went. We relieved the brigade that was engaging the
                        enemy holding the railroad. We then gave them a volley and on a charge went
                        "double quick." The One Hundred and Seventh was the first that entered the
                        wood and charged half through it when it was ordered back on to the railroad
                        to hold it, until we could be supported; but not withstanding the order, the
                        boys would cheer and rush boldly on. The enemy advanced with fresh
                        reinforcements, and we were not supported. We were ordered to fall back out
                        of range and re-form, which we did in good order, but as our regiment was
                        the farthest in advance, we were the last in falling back, consequently we
                        received a heavy fire whilst we were doing so; it was then that the whole
                        brigade suffered most.</p>
                    <p>After we had re-formed we were ordered still farther back over a small hill,
                        where the Colonel commanding the brigade, (Colonel Root,) highly
                        complimented our Colonel (McCoy) upon the conduct of his regiment. Here we
                        laid down for the night.</p>
                    <p>The regiment went into the engagement with 171 men and 16 officers--53 killed
                        and wounded and one missing--and came out of the battle with 117 men and 16
                        officers. A remarkable incident here, is, that not an officer was killed and
                        only one, a Lieutenant, wounded. Since our loss in action the paroled
                        prisoners have returned, swelling the regiment to 175 effective men. You can
                        see from this statement that the 107th is nearly extinguished. It will soon
                        be numbered with other gallant regiments from Pennsylvania, which have
                        ceased to exist, "but only in men," their name, number and gallant deeds
                        will ever exist and will appear brighter on the pages of history as time
                        increases, and stimulate many a brave heart as they read over the noble
                        conduct of such men.</p>
                    <p>On Sunday morning, the 14th, at 2 o'clock, we were ordered up to march
                        immediately; we then changed our position about one and a half miles farther
                        on the left, fronting the enemy's right flank. Our brigade then took up
                        their line of battle in a new direction from what it was on the previous
                        day. After our line was formed we laid down on the frosty plain to rest
                        until daybreak--after daylight we all looked very venerable, as our locks
                        were "whitened," not with the frosts of many winters, but with the frost of
                        one night. Well, we laid, the 3d brigade, in the line of battle until about
                        10 o'clock on Sabbath, where we were annoyed by a rebel battery throwing
                        round shot on the plain and alighting close to us, one striking in the ranks
                        of the brigade on the right, hitting a knapsack of a man cutting it from his
                        back, and by the way the letter paper and envelopes flew in the air. I judge
                        his correspondence was damaged for a while. Our brigade then was ordered out
                        of range of the gun, which was soon afterwards silenced by two of our
                        batterys--here ended the particulars of that day (Sabbath). Where we were
                        ordered to on Sunday, we laid all day on Monday, the 15th, and had
                        inspection of arms in sight of the rebs, who were keeping up a smart fire on
                        our pickets, occasionally a minute ball flying over our heads. Thus ended
                        Monday. We laid down to sleep where we slept on Sunday night, but instead of
                        waking up in the same place, we woke up on this side of the river, somewhat
                        relieved, both in body and mind. As Gen. Burnside did not succeed in
                        storming the rebs' earth works, he played them a "Yankee Trick," at which
                        they were very much chagrined. On the next day we left the river and
                        encamped about two miles north of it. In the evening our regiment had dress
                        parade, at which time the Colonel commanding the brigade sent in his
                        compliments to the regiment which was read, saying in these words: "that he,
                        the commander of the 1st brigade in this division, had reason of being proud
                        of such a body of troops on account of their conduct in the late action, and
                        especially the 107th Pennsylvania regiment in which the officers and men
                        acted gallantly." Isaac Noel, son of John Noel, Esq., of Chambersburg, was
                        killed and Serg't Thomas Myers was wounded, both of company K, formerly
                        Capt. Brand's. They were both stricken down whilst gallantly charging on the
                        enemy. They were good and faithful soldiers such as your community have
                        reason to be proud of. My company (E) came out very safe; we had one
                        sergeant and one private wounded, both slightly. But while our company was
                        spared hundreds of the brave were made to bite the dust; but while I speak
                        of gallant men falling, at the same time the ground was strewn with dead and
                        wounded rebels. I have given you all the particulars of the action on the
                        left wing as they came under my observation when we crossed the river, until
                        we arrived again on the north side.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noel</ln>
                        <fn>Isaac</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Noel</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Myers</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reid</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brand</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A letter from Lieutenant Carman of the 107th Reg't Penn. Volunteers,
                    describing the regiment's participation in the battle at Fredericksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>A Soldier's Letter</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"We publish it as another evidence of that intense love and admiration
                    for General McClellan that still exists among the Army of the Potomac."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Soldier</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit reprints a letter from an unnamed soldier in the Army of the
                    Potomac who writes to express his displeasure with an editorial in the
                    Repository and Transcript that criticized General McClellan. That editor, says
                    the soldier, had better not come near the Army of the Potomac, lest his "length
                    and breadth would be found upon the ground."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Letter from Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Thus ended the greatest triumph of Democracy and the sorest disappointment
                    to office buyers that ever the Legislature of Pennsylvania brought forth."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Eye Witness</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports the election of Charles R. Buckalew over Simon Cameron to the U.S.
                    Senate. The Democrats in the state legislature voted as a party, and no Democrat
                    was bribed to vote for the other side as many had feared.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Continuation of Gov. Seymour's address</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.21.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Weather</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that the past several days have been the coldest of the
                    season, though they point out that cold weather allows "the ice dealer to lay up
                    a quantity of ice for the summer" and presents an opportunity for skating.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Small Pox</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that small pox has been appeared in both Hagerstown and
                    Harrisburg, though the number of cases (800 to 1,000) they believe to be greatly
                    exaggerated. They remind the readers that the vaccination is "an almost perfect
                    preventative of small pox."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Cheer the Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors encourage people to write to the soldiers to help keep their
                    spirits up.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Black and White</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is a marked difference between the black and white man. The immortal
                    Thomas Jefferson made seventeen points of difference. 'They differ in color, in
                    their hair, and in the shape of their bodies. The black man has more beard than
                    the white man. He prespires [sic] more profusely--a striking proof that his
                    condition is best adapted to a warm climate.'"</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is a marked difference between the black and white man. The immortal
                        Thomas Jefferson made seventeen points of difference. "They differ in color,
                        in their hair, and in the shape of their bodies. The black man has more
                        beard than the white man. He prespires [sic] more profusely--a striking
                        proof that his condition is best adapted to a warm climate. There is a sight
                        difference in the arrangement of the lungs, by which the black has more
                        exhaling than the white. The black requires less sleep--this will account
                        for their midnight revels to the music of the banjoe [sic], fiddle, bones,
                        triangle, &amp;c. His love is more ardent, but less imaginative than
                        that of the white man. His grief is more transient. He reflects less--hence
                        their constant whistling, humming and singing negro melodies. His reasoning
                        powers are decidedly inferior--which experience has demonstrated in
                        numberless instances. The black has less originality--a truth doubted by
                        none. He has no turn for the arts of painting and sculpture. He has as good
                        an ear for music as the white man, but no skill in composing. And lastly,
                        the black has no poetical tendencies.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors attempt to list the differences, both physiological and
                    psychological, between blacks and whites.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Panorama of Palestine</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDonnell</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors relay the announcement of the impending arrival of a panorama
                    of Palestine and the Holy Land, painted from photographs of a five-year resident
                    of that place. The exhibition will be worth the "patronage of an intelligent and
                    appreciating community."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Dangerous Counterfeit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors alert their readers to counterfeit five dollar notes on the
                    Bank of America in New York City. They "much resemble" the genuine bills, but
                    can be detected by the fact that the signatures and date of issuance on the
                    counterfeit notes are engraved, while on the originals they are handwritten.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Letter from a Judge on the Supreme Court</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary>"If Judge Miller is as sound a lawyer as he is a politician, we must
                    give the President credit for having made one good appointment."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors reprint a letter from Daniel Miller, a Lincoln appointee to the
                    Supreme Court. In it, Miller, a "Clay Whig" who had joined the Republican Party,
                    decries the abolitionist members of that party and declares his sympathies for
                    the Democratic Party's "mission" to save the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Carlisle Democrat</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We believe in the supremacy of the white race, and that this Government
                    was made by white men for white men; and we do not believe the people will ever
                    consent to the making of negro citizens equal with themselves."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Discusses a case in which the U.S. Attorney General argued that a free
                    black man was a citizen and thus allowed to commanded a ship registered in the
                    U.S. Such an opinion, writes the editor, only weakens the doctrine set forth in
                    Dred Scott, which declared that blacks were not citizens.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="c">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Chambersburg Female Seminary</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Notwithstanding the times and their adverse effect on all our literary
                    institutions, the efficiency of the corps of teachers has been increased rather
                    than diminished, with the belief that an appreciating public will sustain the
                    outlay, and encourage an institution promotive of good among them."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reeves</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf>A.M.</sf>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seibert</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilullan</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>DeForest</ln>
                        <fn>Z. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Curtis</ln>
                        <fn>S. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Miss</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Chambersburg Female Seminary will begin its Spring Session on February
                    9. The teachers are: Rev. Henry Reeves, A.M, Principal; Dr. George Seibert,
                    French and German; Miss Jane Gilullan, English branches and drawing; Miss Z. C.
                    DeForest, instrumental and vocal music; Miss S. H. Curtis, preparatory
                    department.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Market information and classified advertising fill out the page. Marriages and
                Deaths, usually printed on this page, do not appear in this issue.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.21.04">
            <div type="c">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Chambersburg Academy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shryock</ln>
                        <fn>J. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kinney</ln>
                        <fn>J. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Chambers</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wunderlich</ln>
                        <fn>D. K.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Messersmith</ln>
                        <fn>G. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heyser</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Sr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>T. B.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Bernard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McClellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reed</ln>
                        <fn>William G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The trustees of the Chambersburg Academy, in a long-running advertisement,
                    announce recent physical improvements and the supervision of the academy by J.
                    K. Shryock, Principal, teacher of classics, and J. R. Kinney, instructor in
                    natural sciences and higher mathematics.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
