<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.01.28">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/17/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-01-28">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="01">January</month>
            <day>28</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.28.01">
            <pageNote>Fiction, humor and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.28.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Fulton County Affair</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relay the facts in the shooting of Lieut. Ford by John Forney
                    in Fulton County. Forney, 46, had been listed as exempt from the draft since he
                    was older than 45. However, he had been put back on the draft list somehow, and
                    was subsequently put on a list to be arrested as a deserter. He was arrested by
                    the Provost Guard and, on Forney's writ of habeas corpus, was brought before a
                    judge who then dismissed the case. Lieut. Ford and two other men went to
                    Forney's house to re-arrest him after this, which is when Forney shot him.
                    Forney then turned himself in and was taken to Washington by military
                    authorities. The editors comment only that the military seems to be trying to
                    usurp civilian authority, and the removal of Forney from his home county is a
                    dangerous precedent--he should be tried by his peers where the crime was
                    committed.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Bribery and Corruption</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Simon was foiled, for once, in his attempt to corrupt the Legislature and
                    to secure his elevation to office through bribery, as we have every reason to
                    believe he succeeded in doing on several previous occasions."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors draw the reader's attention to an article on the same page
                    wherein T. Jefferson Boyer, member of the state legislature from Clearfield
                    County, claims he was offered $25,000 to vote for Simon Cameron for the U.S.
                    Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>A Contrast</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"The Jesuitical spirit that presides over that sheet, engaged as it has
                    been for the last two years, in stirring up the worst passion of the human
                    heart, is deserving only of the condemnation of a christian community and the
                    contempt of all honorable men."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors ask the reader to contrast the "fair and impartial" treatment
                    of the Forney affair in their paper with the "vile, false, and malicious
                    statement" of the Dispatch on the matter.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>A Good Suggestion</head>
                <origin>National Intelligencer</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the collection of stories from across the political
                    spectrum, all of which agree that morale in the Army of the Potomac is low,
                    though there is little agreement on why. It is clear to the editors that the
                    poor morale is due to the removal of General McClellan from command, and they
                    sarcastically suggest that he be brought in to address the men to try to make
                    them forget the incompetence and tragedy of Fredericksburg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Returning Justice</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"When only a few months ago Abolition fanaticism ruled supreme, Justice was
                    driven from this land. But she is coming back, after her brief exile."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors relay the news of the Wisconsin Supreme Court's sustaining of
                    the writ of habeas corpus for draft rioters, thus denying the right of the
                    President to sustain it in such cases.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Moccasin Tracks!--Attempts to Bribe a Member of the Legislature</head>
                <origin>Patriot and Union</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A letter from T. Jefferson Boyer, a Democratic member of the state
                    legislature, in which he alleges that representatives of Simon Cameron, and then
                    Cameron himself, offered him money to vote for Cameron for the U.S. Senate.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>The Army of the Potomac in Motion</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A pair of conflicting news reports as to whether or not the Army of the
                    Potomac had recrossed the Rappahannock river.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes Congressional report and miscellaneous war news</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.28.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Drafted Men Discharged</head>
                <origin>Fulton Republican and Fulton Democrat</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A pair of news articles describing the shooting of Lieutenant E. N. Ford of
                    the Provost Guard, who had been summoned from Chambersburg to Fulton County to
                    arrest John Forney. Ford and his two men entered Forney's house and searched the
                    lower level. As Ford approached the stairs, he saw Forney at the top; as Ford
                    turned to get his men, he was shot through the shoulder. His wound is severe and
                    it is not known if he will survive.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="j">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Besore</ln>
                        <fn>Adam C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darks</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglow</ln>
                        <fn>N.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Newton</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fillkell</ln>
                        <fn>Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Louisa</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Streets</ln>
                        <fn>Margaret</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stuckey</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Craig</ln>
                        <fn>Elias</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel J.</fn>
                        <sf>Jr.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Middour</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kuhn</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Slyder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Balsley</ln>
                        <fn>George J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Ignatius</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Harbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Sarah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McNulty</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gilds</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nill</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carson</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Associate Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Paxton</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Associate Judge</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A summary of the cases brought before the first week of Court (the editors
                    do not include "numerous petty cases ... of which we have not deemed of
                    sufficient importance"): Commonwealth vs. Adam C. Besore--having counterfeit
                    money; defendant pleaded guilty, sentenced to penitentiary for three years and
                    three months. Commonwealth vs. Susan Drake-- assault, on oath of N. Uglow;
                    verdict, guilty, sentenced to county jail for one month. Commonwealth vs. Joseph
                    Lane, et al. ("colored persons")--Riot, on oath of William Keith; a prosecution
                    against nine black people living in the vicinity of Mercersburg, verdict guilty,
                    sentence against James and Newton Stoner to the penitentiary for one year and
                    two months, Jane Fillkell, Louisa Lane and Margaret Streets, to pay costs of
                    prosecution, William Stuckey, Robert Stoner and Joseph Lane to the county jail
                    for one month. Commonwealth vs. Elias Craig--Larceny, verdict not guilty.
                    Commonwealth vs. Samuel J. Miller, Jr.--assault and battery, verdict guilty,
                    sentenced to county jail for one month; Commonwealth vs. Henry Middour--passing
                    counterfeit money, verdict guilty, sentence to the penitentiary for one year and
                    six months. Commonwealth vs. John Kuhn--passing counterfeit money, verdict
                    guilty, sentenced to penitentiary for one year and six months. Commonwealth vs.
                    Jacob Slyder, Henry Morgan and John Stoner--burglary and larceny, verdict guilty
                    as to Slyder and not guilty as to Morgan and Stoner, Slyder sentenced to four
                    years at the "house of refuge." COMMON PLEAS: George J. Balsley vs. Ignatius
                    Harbaugh and his wife Susan--assumsit, for good sold to Mrs. Harbaugh while a
                    minor; jury could not agree and was dismissed. David McNulty vs. Daniel
                    Gilds--action of deceit in horse trade, verdict in favor of plaintiff for
                    $60.00.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Returned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"They have our best wishes for their success in any new field of
                    operations, and we hope to see them return covered with glory."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>S. R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Capt. S. R. McKesson and the non-commissioned officers who were in
                    Chambersburg on recruiting business left on Monday to rejoin their regiment, the
                    77th Penn. Volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Funeral of Col. Housum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors describe the funeral of Col. Peter B. Housum, whose remains
                    arrived in Chambersburg on Wednesday and who was buried in Cedar Grove Cemetery
                    on Friday. A "vast concourse" of citizens attended, though many more were
                    prevented by the "miserable walking conditions." The Coronet Band provided the
                    music for the procession, followed by the order of Odd Fellows, citizens, and a
                    military escort which discharged three volleys over the grave.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rose</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pyfer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robinson</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wishert</ln>
                        <fn>Henry A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shroad</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Downey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Ass't Surgeon</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>A. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adjutant</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A resolution passed by a committee of the officers of the 77th Reg't Penn.
                    Volunteers, mourning the loss in action of Col. P. B. Housum and praising his
                    bravery and efficiency. It was signed by Thomas E. Rose, Captain commanding the
                    regiment; Fred. S. Pyfer, Capt. of Co. K, Joseph J. Lawson, Capt. of Co. C;
                    William A. Robinson, Capt. of Co. E; Alexander Philips, Capt. of Co. G.; Henry
                    B. Thompson, 1st Lieut. of Co. D; John C. Shroad, 1st Lieut. commanding Co. A;
                    Joseph B. Downey, Ass't Surgeon; S. J. Davis, Adjutant.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>List of casualties in the 77th Regiment Pa. Vols.</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>Peter B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>John E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Temnary</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Jackson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Canmon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reninger</ln>
                        <fn>Frederick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kreps</ln>
                        <fn>John W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratt</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Acker</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Darbey</ln>
                        <fn>David</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lawson</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Crawford</ln>
                        <fn>Scott R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keith</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Getty</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ganster</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kindline</ln>
                        <fn>Andrew</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kegerries</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Greenawalt</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McFarland</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mitchell</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thompson</ln>
                        <fn>Henry B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mace</ln>
                        <fn>Augustus</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cochran</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>2nd Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shirley</ln>
                        <fn>John C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blentzer</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Keenar</ln>
                        <fn>Joshua</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Robison</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hake</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buler</ln>
                        <fn>John A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hardy</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Murphy</ln>
                        <fn>Edward J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ray</ln>
                        <fn>Alfred</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eckle</ln>
                        <fn>Enoch</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rodgers</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bartholomew</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pyfer</ln>
                        <fn>Fred S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McMillen</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Prentiss</ln>
                        <fn>William J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buler</ln>
                        <fn>Lewis H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gamble</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Mackenaw</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>Alexander</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clark</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>John S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Short</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bivan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hearner</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cooper</ln>
                        <fn>George M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Horton</ln>
                        <fn>Milton M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Childers</ln>
                        <fn>Randal</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lippincott</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Philips</ln>
                        <fn>Alex.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foster</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gallagher</ln>
                        <fn>Patrick</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Morgan</ln>
                        <fn>Edwin</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brown</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Williams</ln>
                        <fn>Owen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jones</ln>
                        <fn>Edward</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forester</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Jordon</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Davis</ln>
                        <fn>S. J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adjutant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wetherbee</ln>
                        <fn>Woodsworth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>List of casualties from the 77th Reg't Penn. Volunteers from the battle of
                    Murfreesboro: Lieut. Col. P. B. Housum, commanding, mortally wounded and since
                    died. Co. A, 1st Lieut. John E. Walker commanding, fifty-five men taken into
                    action--Wounded, Lieut. Walker in knee, Private Henry Temnary in leg, Private
                    Jackson Smith in left leg; Missing, Corp. James Canmon, Private Frederick
                    Reninger. Co. B, Lieut. John W. Kreps commanding, thirty men taken into
                    action--Wounded, Private William Jones in hip, Private Edwin Bratt in leg;
                    Missing, Private Edward Acker, Private David Darby. Co. C, Joseph J. Lawson,
                    commanding, thirty-seven men taken into action--Wounded, Sgt. Scott R. Crawford
                    in both legs, left leg amputated, since died, Corp. William Keith in leg,
                    amputated, Corp. Samuel Getty in left leg, Private William Ganster in ankle,
                    Private Dixon in right eye, Private Andrew Kindline in right face, Private John
                    Kegerries left index finger off, Private Henry Greenawalt right arm; Missing,
                    Private Charles McFarland, Private Richard Mitchell. Co. D, 1st Lieut. Henry B.
                    Thompson commanding, twenty-four men taken into action--Killed, Private Augustus
                    Mace; Wounded, Private William Robison, breast; Missing, 2nd Lieut. Thomas G.
                    Cochran, Private John C. Shirley, Private Jacob Blentzer, Private Joshua Keenar.
                    Co. E, Capt. William A. Robison, commanding, twenty-six men taken into action-
                    -Killed, Private John A. Hake, Private John A. Buler; Wounded, Private Thomas
                    Hardy, not known where, Private Edward J. Murphy, not known where, Private
                    Alfred Ray, slightly in breast Private Enoch Eckle, slightly in hand; Missing,
                    Private James Rodgers, Private Jacob S. Bartholomew. Co. K, Capt. Fred S. Pyfer
                    commanding, thirty-five men taken into action--Killed, Alexander Brown; Wounded,
                    Corp. Robert McMillen in thigh, Private William J. Prentiss in breast and arm,
                    Private Lewis H. Buler in hip, Private John Gamble in shoulder; Missing, Private
                    Charles Mackenaw, Private Alexander Stewart, Private William Clark. Co. F, 1st
                    Lieut. John S. McDowell commanding, forty-two men taken into action; Wounded,
                    Private Michael Short in shoulder, Private William Bivan in hand, Private George
                    Hearner in knee; Missing, Corp. George M. Cooper, Corp. Milton M. Horton,
                    Private Randal Childers, Private James Lippincott. Co. G, Capt. Alex. Philips
                    commanding, eighty-nine men taken into action--Wounded, Corp. James Foster in
                    breast, Private Patrick Gallagher in face; Missing, Sgt. George Buchanan, Sgt.
                    Edwin Morgan, Corp. James Brown, Private William Davis, Private Owen Williams,
                    Private Edward Jones, Private James Forester, Private Jacob Jordan, Private
                    Woodsworth Wetherbee.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Killed and Wounded in Mueller's Battery</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>S. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn>P. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut. Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Cuddy</ln>
                        <fn>Edmund</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reine</ln>
                        <fn>Carl</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shartzer</ln>
                        <fn>E. F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Shaffer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Corp.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Louis</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Buchanan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fornes</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Firricks</ln>
                        <fn>Paul</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A list of soldiers from Mueller's Pennsylvania Battery killed at the battle
                    of Murfreesboro, passed on to the Transcript by Lieut. S. M. McDowell. The
                    battery had been principally recruited in Chambersburg by the late Lieut. Col.
                    P. B. Housum, was commanded by him, and was attached for a time to the 77th
                    Reg't. Penn. Volunteers. Killed were Private Edmund Cuddy of Franklin County and
                    Private Carl Reine; among the wounded were Sgt. E. F. Shartzer, Corp. George
                    Shaffer, Privates Louis Bitner (mortally), Daniel Stoner, William Miller,
                    William Buchanan, Joseph Fornes, of Franklin County, Private Paul Firricks.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Wanted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Now that it is a common thing for citizens to bury their deceased friends
                    in Cedar Grove Cemetery, we think it would be a move in the right direction to
                    have such pavements. . . ."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Housum</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Col.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors call for a few feet of pavement to be added at the corner of
                    King Street and the street leading to the cemetery. During the muddy season, it
                    is impossible for people to go to the cemetery without coming in contact with
                    the mud.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Fire and "Family Jars"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"In endeavoring to obtain some water from a cistern in the neighborhood,
                    the firemen met with an unpleasant reception from the inmates of a German
                    family, who proceeded to administer a severe castigation to the men about using
                    the water."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>Last Tuesday evening a small stable situated on the premises of Mr. Nicholas
                        Uglo, on Broad Lane, was entirely destroyed by fire. The fire companies,
                        together with the Hook and Ladder company were promptly on the ground, and
                        rendered efficient service. In endeavoring to obtain some water from a
                        cistern in the neighborhood, the firemen met with an unpleasant reception
                        from the inmates of a German family, who proceeded to administer a severe
                        castigation to the men about using the water. A squable [sic] ensued, which
                        was frightful in the extreme--our German friends, however, coming out of the
                        conflict "second best"--the firemen laying several of them almost as low as
                        a tumble bug after being passed over with a vehicle. We have often
                        questioned the propriety of firemen tearing down more fences than necessary,
                        or in case of fire in a dwelling house "to throw the looking glass out of
                        the window and carry the bed clothes down stairs," but of their perfect
                        liberty to relieve a cistern of its contents of water in cases of emergency,
                        or of absolute necessity, we have never entertained a doubt.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Uglo</ln>
                        <fn>Nicolas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A small stable belonging to Nicolas Uglo burned on Tuesday evening. Several
                    fire companies responded to the call, but when they tried to take water from a
                    nearby cistern, a local German family protested and a fight ensued between the
                    fireman and the family.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Counterfeiting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"At no previous time in our history has counterfeit money been so abundant.
                    The great scarcity of the currency, caused by the withdrawal of specie from
                    circulation, the great demand for change by soldiers and civilians, and the
                    utter recklessness of persons receiving notes without inspecting them, have all
                    combined to make the 'bogus' coin appear among us."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>At no previous time in our history has counterfeit money been so abundant.
                        The great scarcity of the currency, caused by the withdrawal of specie from
                        circulation, the great demand for change by soldiers and civilians, and the
                        utter recklessness of persons receiving notes without inspecting them, have
                        all combined to make the "bogus" coin appear among us. We have neither seen
                        nor heard of any of the Treasury notes imitated and put in circulation, but
                        one of our co[n]temporaries learns the astounding fact that a large order is
                        being executed in England for some rascals in the United States, but there
                        are plenty of counterfeits in the shape of paper money from five cent
                        postage currency upwards. There are always villians [sic] enough to take
                        advantage of the misfortunes of the country in various ways, and we hope it
                        is possible to check the infamous crime of issuing "bogus" money, or must it
                        progress at its present rate "until the "bogus" exceeds in amount the
                        genuine currency of the country."</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note the prevalence of counterfeit currency in circulation, due
                    to wartime conditions, and hope that steps will be taken to counter the issuance
                    of "bogus" money.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Another Citizen and Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He was upwards of fifty years of age, and therefore entered the army from
                    no other than the most patriotic motives."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pilkington</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas G. Pilkington, Postmaster of Waynesboro and a member of Company A,
                    126th Reg't Penn. Volunteers, died in the Washington Hospital of diarrhea last
                    Thursday. He was in the battle on the Rappahannock, and was wounded in both
                    hands and one leg.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Barn Burnt</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Weaver</ln>
                        <fn>P. D.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The barn of P. D. Weaver, who resides near Upton, was consumed by fire
                    about a week ago. Its content of hay and grain, plus two valuable horses, were
                    destroyed, a loss of $600 or $700. The fire was the work of an "incendiary."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCollum</ln>
                        <fn>B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sheller</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Nitterhouse</ln>
                        <fn>Helen M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Thomas R. Sheller of Washington City and Helen M. Nitterhouse of
                    Chambersburg were married on October 26, 1862, at the parsonage of Christ's
                    Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McHenry</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wingert</ln>
                        <fn>Abraham G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Heintzleman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Abraham G. Wingert of Green Township married Mary M. Heintzleman of
                    Fayetteville on January 22 at the Indian Queen Hotel.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hege</ln>
                        <fn>Michael</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rebecca W. Hege, daughter of Rebecca and Michael Hege, died near Marion on
                    January 14, of diphtheria, aged 3 years, 1 month and 22 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bolhard</ln>
                        <fn>Mary Belle</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Mrs.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGovern</ln>
                        <fn>E. G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Mrs. Mary Belle Bolhard, daughter of Dr. E. G. McGovern, formerly of
                    Chambersburg, died at Chilicothe on January 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Also includes market information and classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.01.28.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
