<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.03.11">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/19/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-11">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.11.01">
            <div type="l">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Letter from Hon. C. R. Buckalew</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Conservative men look for alliance and aid to the white race--our own
                    stock and kindred--and propose to secure their co-operation to restoring the
                    Union by a policy of conciliation, and by the example of a return by our own
                    government to a true constitutional rule . . . In their policy, the conservative
                    element along the border and in the South is to be encouraged and developed, not
                    repelled, spurned and insulted."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>C. R. Buckalew</trailer>
                <names/>
                <summary>C. R. Buckalew, the newly elected senator from Pennsylvania, writes in a
                    letter to the Central Democratic Club of Philadelphia on Washington's Birthday
                    that the role of the Democrats is to drive the Republicans from power and
                    reverse their policies of expanding the war aims into engaging the issues of
                    blacks. He decries what he sees as the arbitrary exercise of power by the
                    administration, and quotes Washington to the effect that the military must be
                    cautious about not becoming transgressors of the laws they seek to uphold.
                    Buckalew urges a policy of conciliation toward the conservative men in the
                    South.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes the text of the new conscription bill and two columns of classified
                advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.11.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Adjournment of Congress</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"[The historian] will compare them to the Roman Senate in its days of
                    degeneracy and corruption, or to the French Council, during the wildest days of
                    the revolution--and the comparison will be anything but complimentary to Rome
                    and France."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Spirit's editor notes the adjournment of the 37th Congress with relief.
                    While this Congress started out with a conservative, patriotic declaration of
                    war, it was quickly taken hold of by fanatical, radical leaders who twisted the
                    purposes of the war. The men who dared to defend the old Constitution were
                    "sneered and hooted in their seats." The editor hopes that the country will
                    never see the like of this Congress again.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Letter from Mr. Buckalew</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editor draws the reader's attention to the letter from C. R. Buckalew
                    printed on page one. He then goes on to discuss the impending changes in the
                    politics of the state. Pennsylvania will now be represented in the Senate by
                    Buckalew, a Democrat, and a conservative Republican "who votes with us on all
                    the vital questions of the day." In addition, the Congressional delegation has
                    fourteen Democrats and ten Republicans, and the whole state government is
                    "thoroughly Democratic." It is a pattern that can be found across the North, the
                    editor says, and soon the Democratic party will be restored to national power.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Seward on Emancipation</head>
                <origin>New York Tribune</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Quotes from a dispatch written by Secretary of State Seward, wherein he
                    speculates that radicals in both the North and South had conspired to instigate
                    a "servile war," one by rebelling against the Union and the other by promoting
                    emancipation. If this is indeed Seward's sentiment, the editor says, he should
                    have opposed the Emancipation Proclamation publicly and cleared himself of any
                    guilt by association.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head/>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary>"From personal observation and information and opinions given by
                    reliable men in different sections of the army, we are firmly convinced that the
                    army from the Middle and Western States is radically opposed to the measure."</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reprints a report that states that Union officers have been arrested for
                    mutinous conduct in connection with the arrival of black troops.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>The Radicals</head>
                <origin>New York Methodist</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>This writer sends a copy of an editorial from the New York Methodist,
                    reporting on a speech given by Wendell Phillips in Henry Ward Beecher's church.
                    In his talk, Phillips stated that he would not accept the reestablishment of the
                    Union without emancipation. This was the same line given by Beecher as well as
                    by Horace Greeley, says the editorialist, and they cannot escape the judgement
                    that they are as much for secession as Southern leaders.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Correspondence from "the Army of the Potomac"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Gen. Hooker, I hear, is in Washington arranging, I presume, a programme
                    for new operations. With the return of favorable weather the Army of the Potomac
                    will have work to do. One of these fine mornings the dogs of war will be let
                    loose, and if the "Rebs" don't be ousted from their boasted stronghold,
                    Fredericksburg, I am greatly mistaken."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">Correspondence of the Spirit and Times.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Camp of "Tyler's Brigade," 5th Corps, <lb/>Near Fredericksburg, Va.
                        <lb/>March 1st, 1863.</p>
                    <p>This is Sunday, but my devotions have not been so abstracted or business so
                        pressing but what I can give a few moments to writing my usual letter.</p>
                    <p>On Wednesday last, the "Rebs" made a fierce attack on our pickets.
                        Intelligence of the fact soon reached camp, causing no little excitement,
                        especially as the frightened messengers represented the matter as of a most
                        serious character. But a few moments elapsed before our Brigade was under
                        arms and marching to the lines. As night approached, however, our force,
                        with the exception of the 126th, returned to camp. This Regiment was left to
                        strengthen the lines and were thrown out a considerable distance. It
                        happened that they had started without their blankets, and a cold rain
                        prevailing that night, and fires being forbidden, they suffered no little.
                        The Rebs did not trouble them and they were called to camp on Friday. I
                        learn the attack occurred in the neighborhood of Stafford Court House. The
                        usual vigilance on the part of our officers in charge of our line was
                        forgotten, and with characteristic boldness the Rebs made a dash, capturing
                        about fifty of our men. an officer cannot hold a more responsible or
                        important position than to be in command on the picket lines, and any
                        relaxation or neglect of duty should be severely punished.</p>
                    <p>Gen. Hooker, I hear, is in Washington arranging, I presume, a programme for
                        new operations. With the return of favorable weather the Army of the Potomac
                        will have work to do. One of these fine mornings the dogs of war will be let
                        loose, and if the "Rebs" don't be ousted from their boasted stronghold,
                        Fredericksburg, I am greatly mistaken. The feeling seems to be universal
                        that we will have better luck in the next attack. The men are brave enough
                        and great enough in numbers. What is needed consists in good management,
                        hearty co-operation among commanders, and unrestructed powers in our Chief.
                        Then if we fail, I will admit that Fredericksburg is impregnable, and that
                        this army is an organization fated to misfortune and impotent as an
                        instrument of success.</p>
                    <p>The usual two month's muster for pay took place yesterday. This is the second
                        that has taken place since last pay day. Four month's pay is now due the
                        boys, but there will be hardly any funds forthcoming until next muster on
                        the 30th of April, or at the expiration of our term of service.</p>
                    <p>Several promotions have recently taken place in our Regiment. Capt. R.S.
                        Brownson has been commissioned Major, a good appointment and one very
                        acceptable to the Regiment. Lt. Court. Hullinger is now Captain of Co. "D,"
                        and Sergts. George Platt and Clay McCauley are his 1st and 2d Lieutenants.
                        First Lieut. James McCullough has been selected as Captain of Co. "C." In
                        nearly every company new promotions to non-commissioned officers have been
                        made.</p>
                    <p>Death carried off three of our men last week, among them James McKeason, Co.
                        "D" of your town. I regret to announce the severe illness of T.J.C. McGrath.
                        Co. "A," and clerk to Quartermaster Nill. He is having kind attention and I
                        trust he is not beyond recovery.</p>
                    <p>Among those now absent with leave is our very efficient Adjutant, John
                        Stewart, and Capt. George L. Miles, Co. "G." May they have a good time while
                        they can. Your correspondent will hardly be home until next May. Then he
                        expects to be discharged--cause: physical <emph rend="italic"
                        >ability</emph>, he being too strong for the service to hold him.</p>
                    <p>Shenandoah.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Shenandoah</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brownson</ln>
                        <fn>R. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hullinger</ln>
                        <fn>Court.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Platt</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCauley</ln>
                        <fn>Clay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Sgt.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCullough</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>1st Lieut.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adjutant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miles</ln>
                        <fn>George L.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A report from a correspondent with the 126th Reg't Penn. Reserves, encamped
                    near Fredericksburg, Virginia. He describes a Confederate raid on their lines,
                    reflects on the organization of the Army of the Potomac and its chances for
                    taking Fredericksburg, and relates a number of promotions and sicknesses.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Persons holding Eyster &amp; Brothers currency are requested to present
                    it for redemption at the store before April 1.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Democrats of Green Township are requested to meet in Scotland on
                    Saturday the 14th and in Fayetteville that same evening to nominate a ticket for
                    township elections in the spring.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>Visitors</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stewart</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Adjutant</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wampler</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Adjutant Stewart of the 126th Reg't Penn. Volunteers and Private George
                    Wampler of Company A of the same regiment were home last week on ten days
                    furlough. They returned to the regiment on Monday.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>A Companion in Arms</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A memorial written by a friend of T. J. C. McGrath, of Company A, 126th
                    Reg't Penn. Volunteers, who died of typhoid fever in a military hospital on
                    March 3.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Reilly</ln>
                        <fn>Wilson</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Hon.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Douglas</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eyster</ln>
                        <fn>C. S.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sharpe</ln>
                        <fn>J. McD.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Brewer</ln>
                        <fn>George W.</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Strickler</ln>
                        <fn>Snively</fn>
                        <sf>Esq.</sf>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A meeting of the Bar was held at the offices of Hon. Wilson Reilly for the
                    purposes of giving expression to their feelings in regard to the death of T. J.
                    C. McGrath, Esq. They adopted resolutions commemorating McGrath and moved to
                    publish them in the local papers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>I. O. O. F. Tribute of Respect</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Everett</ln>
                        <fn>W. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kennedy</ln>
                        <fn>W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Palmer</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A resolution prepared by a committee of the Chambersburg Lodge No. 175 I.
                    O. O. F. commemorating its member, T. J. C. McGrath, and noting that he was the
                    third member of "its little band of brothers" to have perished in the war.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Another Soldier Gone</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>Henry Clay</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Private</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bitner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Private Henry Clay Bitner, son of John Bitner, the miller who resides three
                    miles away from Chambersburg on the banks of the Conococheague, and a member of
                    Company E, 156th Reg't Penn. Militia, died on February 19 in Newbern, North
                    Carolina of congestive fever. His body has been forwarded home, and will arrive
                    this week.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>A Word to the Council</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"There is scarcely a week during which funerals do not pass along it to the
                    Cemetery, for want of a better route."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>There is scarcely a person who went, or attempted to go, to the Cemetery, on
                        last Sunday, who will not endorse us when we say it is the imperative duty
                        of the Town Council to take immediate measures for having a pavement laid,
                        on Franklin Street, from Market Street to the Cemetery, and having the
                        street itself macademized. It is now in a worse condition than any other
                        street in town; and in rainy weather is almost impassable, alike to foot
                        passengers and vehicles. There is scarcely a week during which funerals do
                        not pass along it to the Cemetery, for want of a better route; and, as a
                        general rule, it is more traveled than many other streets that are kept in a
                        much better condition. Let the Council start the improvement at once; it
                        will be acceptable to the entire community, and but few will be found to
                        object to it on the ground of a little additional tax.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors argue that Franklin Street, from Market Street to the Cemetery,
                    should be macadamized. It is in worse condition than almost any other road in
                    town, and many roads that are less traveled are kept in better condition. Since
                    there are so many funerals these days, the community will not object to paying a
                    little more tax to get the job done.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Page includes reviews of books and periodicals, as well as Congressional
            news.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.11.03">
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>Martha Scott</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Montgomery</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>M. D.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Martha Scott Montgomery, wife of James Montgomery, M.D., died on February
                    22, in Fannettsburg, at the age of 51.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Derringer</ln>
                        <fn>N. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>N. S. Derringer, formerly of Franklin County, died on December 25, 1862, at
                    a hospital near Falmouth, Virginia, of wounds received during the battle of
                    Fredericksburg. He was a member of the 24th Regiment New Jersey Volunteers.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes miscellaneous war and national news, and five columns of classified
                advertisements, including a list of taxes appraised on the merchants of Franklin
                County.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.11.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
