<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="vs1863/pa.fr.vs.1863.03.18">
    <header>
        <title type="uniform">Valley Spirit</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Andrew Morris, first pass; Colleen Doody, second pass 2/19/98</taggerName>
            <tagDate/>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1863-03-18">
            <year>1863</year>
            <month norm="03">March</month>
            <day>18</day>
            <weekday id="WED">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.18.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>(No Title)</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"We learn from the Boston papers, that the 'Americans of African descent'
                    in that vicinity are not satisfied with the proposition to form them into
                    separate military organizations under white officers."</excerpt>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We learn from the Boston papers, that the 'Americans of African descent' in
                        that vicinity are not satisfied with the proposition to form them into
                        separate military organizations under white officers. They claim that it
                        makes to[o] great a distinction in point of equality, which they will not
                        submit to. If equality is the point to be gained in this war, they demand
                        that it should be recognized in the army. In this, however, they seem to
                        forget that the white soldier might object to such an amalgamation. In this
                        neighborhood, there has, so far been no effort to procure negro recruits,
                        that we have heard of, and it is currently said that such an effort, if
                        made, will be useless. They will have to be drafted, if obtained at all.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Reports that black soldiers in Boston protested their segregation into
                    separate units. The editors state that no black troops have been raised yet in
                    their community and that it would take a draft to do it.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look>**</look>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes two columns of classified advertisements and miscellaneous fiction
                and non-fiction.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.18.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Party and Party Spirit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors object to the Transcript's invocation of Washington's farewell
                    address to criticize partisanship. It is true, the editors of the Spirit and
                    Times say, that Washington condemned partisanship. However, he rejected parties
                    based on sectional rivalries, much like the Republican party now in power. If
                    Washington was alive today, the editors claim, the Transcript would denounce him
                    as a copperhead.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Jackson Democracy</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"But Abraham Lincoln is not Andrew Jackson. That is what's the matter."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors point out that secessionism first arose under the Presidency of
                    Andrew Jackson, who, they argue, contained it within constitutional bounds.
                    Jackson warned that governmental powers must be strictly contained or they will
                    overwhelm and absorb the Constitution. If the Constitution was all that Jackson
                    needed, they argue, it should be all that Lincoln needs as well.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>The New Hampshire Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors note that, while none of the three candidates for governor in
                    New Hampshire gained a majority, the two Democratic candidates outpolled the
                    Republican. It also looks as if a Democratic Congressman will be elected. The
                    editors interpret this swing from a solid Republican state as good evidence that
                    the North is turning away from Republican radicalism.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Democratic Meeting in the South Ward</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Taylor</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The Democrats of the South Ward of Chambersburg are requested to meet at
                    the Public House of J. W. Taylor on Wednesday evening to nominate a ticket for
                    the spring election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Spring Election</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors request that their friends in the various townships send them
                    the results of the spring elections as soon as they take place, so that the
                    numbers may be published in the issue after the election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Preaching</head>
                <origin>Waynesboro Village Record</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dorsey</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev. Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Dr. Dorsey will preach in the Union Church in Waynesboro next Sunday.
                    He has accepted a call from the Lutheran congregations composing the Waynesboro
                    Charge, and he will be moving to town shortly.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Death of a Soldier</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McCloud</ln>
                        <fn>Harry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Eakles</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Harry McCloud, a soldier of Company I, 57th Reg't Penn. Volunteers, died at
                    the house of Christian Eakles in Chambersburg on Saturday and was buried in
                    Cedar Grove Cemetery, with military honors. He was a native of New York.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>At Home</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"He looks as if he is enjoying excellent health, and still stands up for
                    'Little Mac,' as the great body of the army and all other sensible men do."</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lane</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Samuel Lane, Surgeon of the 5th Penn. Reserves and a member of the
                    "Examining Board" is at home on a few days furlough.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>A New Counterfeit</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors warn of a new counterfeit note in circulation, drawn on the New
                    Castle County Bank in Delaware. A rural scene with a farmer, a dog in the front
                    and two houses in the background distinguishes the note.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>The "Amende Honorable"</head>
                <origin>Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors publish an apology from the editors of the Pilot, saying their
                    recent article regarding unsound money was not meant to slight the Bank of
                    Chambersburg. They agree that the Bank is solid, and since it pays out
                    greenbacks, it cannot be accused of the practice of paying out with notes from
                    suspect banks in the other parts of the state.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Handsome Drum</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stoner</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McKesson</ln>
                        <fn>C. B.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Capt.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A beautiful drum is on display at Shryock's book store, on which is
                    inscribed a dedication to John Stoner, Drum Major of the 77th Reg't Penn.
                    Volunteers, for his bravery displayed at Stone River, in January 1863. It was
                    originally purchased by Capt. C. B. McKesson for $30, and a subscription has
                    been started by members of the 77th to raise that amount.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGrath</ln>
                        <fn>T. J. C.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Spangler</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boyle</ln>
                        <fn>William H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A memorial resolution passed by the Olive Branch Encampment, No. 13, I. O.
                    O. F., on March 9, commemorating the death of T. J .C. McGrath, a member of the
                    encampment. It was signed by J. Spangler and recorded by William H. Boyle.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Town Lots in the Market</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schmidt</ln>
                        <fn>Hannes</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The editors applaud the Town Council for considering extending Catharine
                    Street from where it connects to second street, all the way through lots owned
                    by Dr. Schneck to the Franklin Railroad. This would open up 25 or 30 streetside
                    lots for development and would increase the tax base available to the community,
                    so needed after the heavy outlay for borough enlargement. Dr. Schneck is now
                    advertising the lots for sale, and the editors believe that, since people have
                    money and want a safe investment, this would be a good choice.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stouffer</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At a meeting of the Caledonia (Illinois) Encampment, No. 43, I. O. O. F.,
                    on February 20, a resolution was passed commemorating the death of Patriarch
                    William Stouffer, who died in Danville, Kentucky on January 21 while serving as
                    Captain of Company C, 92nd Illinois Volunteer Regiment. Stouffer was a member of
                    the Chambersburg Lodge and Caledonia encampment.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.18.03">
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welfley</ln>
                        <fn>J.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Metz</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Branthaver</ln>
                        <fn>Rebecca Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Daniel W. Metz of Lasalle County married Rebecca Branthaver of Franklin
                    County on March 2.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolf</ln>
                        <fn>M. M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lusend</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Vellus</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Jeremiah Lusend and Mary Vellus were married on March 6.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dyson</ln>
                        <fn>F.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Woods</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Geyer</ln>
                        <fn>Mary S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Richard Woods and Mary S. Geyer, both of Chambersburg, were married on
                    March 16.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Otenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel Hunter</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Samuel Hunter Otenberger died on March 6 near Loudon, aged 5 months and 17
                    days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hassell</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Dr.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Dr. Charles Hassell died on March 6 in Fairview, Southampton Township, aged
                    80 years, 5 months and 23 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Catharine</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Samuel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Henry</ln>
                        <fn>Rachael Jane</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Catharine Henry, youngest daughter of Samuel and Rachael Jane Henry, died
                    on March 4, aged 1 year, 1 month and 4 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Trimble</ln>
                        <fn>Robert</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Robert Trimble died on March 12 in Guilford Township, after an illness of
                    several years, aged 63 years, 2 months and 10 days.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote>Includes market information and five columns of classified
            advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.vs.1863.03.18.04">
            <pageNote>Classified advertisements</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
