<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.10.24">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>07/12</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-10-24">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="10"/>
            <day>24</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.24.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head>The Great Lesson!</head>
                <origin>New York Times</origin>
                <commentary>"The New York Times, the leading organ of President Johnson, thus calmly
                    and truthfully sums up the great verdict of the People in Pennsylvania, Ohio,
                    Indiana, and Iowa:"</commentary>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The New York <emph rend="italic">Times</emph>, the leading organ of President
                        Johnson, thus calmly and truthfully sums up the great verdict of the People
                        in Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana and Iowa:</p>
                    <p>Seldom, indeed, has a contest been conducted with so exclusive reference to a
                        single issue. True, the antecedents of candidates during the war have had
                        much to do with the question of individual eligibility. Clymer has been
                        consigned to private life because his sympathies and efforts were against
                        the war for the Union, while Geary's were heroically in its support. But,
                        after all, there have been few of the considerations which in ordinary times
                        have entered into party controversy. The tariff, internal improvements, the
                        currency, the foreign relations of the Government, have been discussed only
                        incidentally. Everywhere the conditions of national unity and peace have
                        formed the theme of debate, and the standard by which party nominations have
                        been weighed and judged. Minor questions, therefore, cannot be pleaded in
                        abatement of the account as it now stands. It is a settlement which can be
                        altered only to be made more stringent. <emph rend="italic">It is a
                            declaration of the popular determination to exact from the South
                            guarantees for the maintenance of the Union as the war has made it; a
                            Union assuring national citizenship to black and white, assuring
                            equality before the law, the just representation of the sections, and
                            the inviolability of the legal debt, and providing effectually against
                            the future assumption of the rebel debts or claims</emph>. This is the
                        sum and substance of Tuesday's verdict. Not negro suffrage--not
                        confiscation--not harsh or vindictive penalties; but the plan of restoration
                        dictated by Congress, and designed to be a final adjustment of our national
                        difficulties.</p>
                    <p>It is too late to say that the popular verdict hardly comes up to the rigid
                        constitutional standard. It would avail nothing now to argue that the
                        Amendment, equitable and moderate though it be, ought not to be a condition
                        of restoration. Equally useless were it to consider by what possible
                        combinations and compromises the view for which we have contended might have
                        acquired greater prominence and support. <emph rend="italic">The people have
                            been heard from, and from their decision our form of government provides
                            no appeal. The South, if wise, will hearken and comply. And the
                            President, if politic, will not refuse to listen to a verdict which
                            specially concerns himself and the plan to which he is committed</emph>.</p>
                    <p>At least one source of apprehension has been removed. Had these elections
                        ended adversely to Congress--had promises been held out of any considerable
                        change in the complexion of that body--the idea of a second House, with the
                        Southern representatives unconditionally admitted, might possibly have
                        assumed dangerous dimensions. <emph rend="italic">The proposition that a
                            second Congress should be organized, and that the President should
                            recognize the one favorable to his plan, might then have been more
                            plausible. Fortunately this beginning of revolution has been
                        obviated</emph>. Not the faintest pretext can now be found for impugning the
                        validity of the Congressional decision, or for mooting the legitimacy of any
                        other body. The people have taken care that this threatened peril shall not
                        be heard of more. They have decreed, not only that Congress as it now is,
                        faithfully represents their convictions and purposes, but that the Congress
                        which will come after shall sustain substantially the same policy. Neither
                        the South nor the President, then, has aught to expect from delay. The South
                        must choose between prolonged exclusion, with the probability of more
                        stringent terms, and the acceptance of the overture already submitted to
                        them. The President must be content to see Congress push forward its new
                        method of settlement, despite protestations and vetoes, or must frankly
                        accept the verdict pronounced by the people who elected him, and use his
                        opportunities to hasten restoration on the only basis that is practicable.
                            <emph rend="italic">He has stated his own case, and the people have
                            refused to accept it</emph>. The part of statesmanship surely is to
                        concede graciously and promptly to the popular requirements, and to exert
                        the influence of the Executive in support of the compromise now tendered the
                        Southern States.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>According to the article, one key issue--the debate over "national unity
                    and peace"--dominated the political discourse in the last campaign. Others
                    topics, such as the tariff, internal improvements, and foreign relations were
                    "discussed but only incidentally." Consequently, the results of the various
                    elections indicate that the general public in the North approves of the
                    Republicans' efforts to force the South to accept to proposed constitutional
                    amendments before being re-admitted to the Union.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.24.02">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Union County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Calls on local Republicans who "voted the ticket" to hold primaries to
                    select delegates for the Union County Convention on November 13th. The purpose
                    of the county meeting is to "express the preferences of the party for United
                    States Senator."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Informs readers that the Republicans will hold a majority of 9 in the state
                    senate and 24 in the house, therefore there is little doubt that the proposed
                    constitutional amendments will be ratified and a new U. S. Senator will be
                    selected.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gen. Geary will re-appoint William M. Meredith as
                    Attorney General. Meredith has held the office for the past five years, yet it
                    is unclear whether he will accept Geary's offer due to his "infirm health."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Senatorial County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>It will be seen in reference to the official call of the Union County
                        Committee, given in to-day's paper, that a regular Convention of Delegates
                        from the several districts of the county, is called to meet in Chambersburg
                        on Tuesday, the 13th of November, to express the preference of the
                        Republicans of this county for U. S. Senator in an authoritative manner. The
                        delegates are to be chosen on Saturday, the 10th of November, at the usual
                        places for holding primary meetings of the party.</p>
                    <p>The fact that a call for a meeting of the Committee to consider this
                        question, brought seventeen of the twenty-two members form every section of
                        the county; that three other members who could not attend advised action in
                        favor of positive instructions, and that of those in attendance but one
                        voted against officially directing the Republican party to declare its
                        choice for Senator, clearly demonstrates the earnestness prevailing among
                        the people on the subject. Betrayed by Cooper, again betrayed by Cowan, they
                        desire to say to their Senator and Representatives, and to their Republican
                        brethren throughout the State, who they deem most worthy of the many worthy
                        men named for the high and responsible position.</p>
                    <p>The Republicans of the "Green Spot" take this action now not because of any
                        new or unexpected occasion demanding it. They would have done it before the
                        election, but for the general desire to cast aside all questions but the one
                        great purpose to succeed until success should be attained. That time has now
                        come. The triumph has been gained, and they exercise but their confessed
                        right and supreme authority in directing who shall wear the richest garlands
                        of their well-earned victory. They propose no reflection upon any one. They
                        assume simply to discharge a plain duty, and when discharged in a manner
                        that will preclude cavil or dispute, as must be the case when a convention
                        elected on the single issue shall declare their wishes, we doubt not that
                        their voice will be cheerfully obeyed.</p>
                    <p>The Delegate Convention is the highest tribunal of the Republican party in
                        this county. To its decision all profess obedience. We struggle for the
                        success of cherished friends to secure its nominations for subordinate
                        offices, and when its mandate goes forth, expressed in integrity and
                        fairness, the friends of all who appealed to its favor, whether victors or
                        vanquished, rally to give victory to its banner. And so it will be in
                        nominating a Senator as the choice of this country. Whether the Republicans
                        shall declare for Gov. Curtin, Col. Forney, Mr. Stevens, Gen. Cameron or Mr.
                        Grow, it will be the unbiased, faithful reflex of the sentiment of the 4,200
                        Republican voters of the county, and as such will be respected by all.</p>
                    <p>We have no choice to urge upon the Republicans of Franklin county. Our
                        individual preference is known to all who have desired to learn it, and for
                        that choice we shall cast our vote at the delegate election. But in these
                        columns we seek neither to advance or retard the success of any gentleman
                        named. We only ask that there shall be a fair, full, unbiased expression of
                        the whole party, and then none can complain. We appeal to every Republican
                        to attend the primary elections and cast his vote for delegates in
                        accordance with his own convictions. In the late contest for Congress it
                        even overshadowed the Gubernatorial struggle. Earnestly as the Republicans
                        labored for the success of Gen. Geary, their chief aim was the success of a
                        faithful Congressman. How much more important is the election of a United
                        States Senator who will hold his position for four years longer than our
                        Congressman? It is the most important office within the gift of the party,
                        and its power will be felt not only during the remainder of Johnson's
                        administration, but during the whole of the succeeding administration. Let
                        the masses of the party fully appreciate the importance of the subject, and
                        the managers of delegate elections will have but little work to perform.</p>
                    <p>We trust that the steps taken in Franklin will be imitated throughout the
                        State. We hear from several quarters that the people are decided in <emph
                            rend="italic">their</emph> choice for U. S. Senator, but their
                        Representatives are <emph rend="italic">not</emph> so decided since the
                        election. It is just this criminal negligence that has cost our State so
                        much of her just power in the first legislative tribunal of the nation. Let
                        the people speak in an authoritative manner, and their voice will be obeyed.
                        If they prefer Gov. Curtin, let him be chosen; if Mr. Stevens, let him be
                        Senator; if Gen. Cameron, let him wear the honors fairly won; if Col.
                        Forney, he has the highest right to demand his success. But let not the
                        decided preferences of the people in their respective counties and districts
                        be smothered, while the legislators go to Harrisburg to barter their votes
                        for personal advancement or legislative success.</p>
                    <p>Let the People speak, and politicians who trust and obey them will best serve
                        themselves and their country!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Having been betrayed by the state's last two choices for the U. S. Senate,
                    Republican men of Franklin county do not intend to be duped again. Instead, the
                    article relates, they have scheduled a convention to meet so that they can tell
                    "their Senator and Representatives, and ... their Republican brethren throughout
                    the State, who they deem most worthy of the many worthy men named for the high
                    and responsible position."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Jefferson Davis</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The editors characterize President Johnson's actions with regard to
                    Jefferson Davis as disingenuous. Despite claims to the contrary, Davis has not
                    been tried because Johnson is unsure as to how to proceed since the current
                    charges against the former Confederate leader are for the assassination of
                    Lincoln. As such, if Davis were tried and convicted of those charges, he would
                    most likely be given the same punishment as Booth, Surratt, and the other
                    conspirators--death. Of course, such a ruling would undermine Johnson's ability
                    to appeal to white southerners for support, which is an integral component of
                    his political strategy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Swinging Around Again</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>We have seen various conjectures in the Washington correspondence of the
                        leading journals, as to the position the President will assume since the
                        crushing repudiation of "my policy" by the people. Some have insisted that
                        he would bow to the inexorable verdict, and advise the adoption of the
                        constitutional amendments by the rebel States, and thus facilitate the great
                        work of reconstruction, while others have insisted he is only the more
                        obstinate at his overthrow and will fight out his treasonable policy to the
                        bitter end.</p>
                    <p>We have no faith in Andrew Johnson. We would not accept any pledge he could
                        give as evidence that he meant to retrace his perfidious steps and
                        henceforth maintain a loyal policy. That he is chagrined, humiliated,
                        overwhelmed by the decisive verdict of the people against him, we are well
                        assured, and we are convinced that he will endeavor in some way to break the
                        force of the fall, but it will be utterly vain. We speak advisedly when we
                        say that he assured a leading Republican M. C. within the last ten days,
                        that he would be in harmony with Congress in a very short time; and he
                        excused his removals by saying that he had removed but few comparatively;
                        that he lost largely by it; that every appointment offended all who were
                        disappointed, while his appointees very often voted the Republican ticket to
                        save themselves in the Senate. We know, also, that in at least two instances
                        he has revoked appointments already made and continued the Republican
                        incumbents, and in one of the instances he proposed to do it if a Republican
                        Congressman desired it. These are facts within our knowledge, and we give
                        them to show that Andrew Johnson would, at least in some lucid intervals he
                        seems to enjoy, attempt to retrieve his fearful, fatal fall.</p>
                    <p>The people have saved this government in defiance of Andrew Johnson's
                        treachery, and in defiance of his shameless, corrupt use of his patronage,
                        and they will not now stop to inquire whether he is faithful or faithless.
                        If he shall assent to loyal reconstruction, it will be because he could
                            <emph rend="italic">not</emph> succeed, after an exhausting effort and
                        the most appalling prostitution of power, in giving success to treason in
                        the work of restoration, and it matters not whether he assents or
                        dissents--the grand commission will be attained because the people have so
                        decreed it. It matters not, therefore, either for himself or for the
                        country, whether he shall yield a passive obedience to the policy of
                        Congress, for he can do nothing less. He has no power to resist it. He has
                        no remedy against it, but in revolution, and that would end his official
                        term in a day. Having betrayed every party and every principle that he has
                        ever espoused but the Democracy, it would be singular indeed if he did not
                        complete the circle around which he has been swinging by cheating them,
                        particularly since they are not worth being faithful to. But whether he
                        shall be faithful or perfidious to them, his record will be all the same.
                        The people have repudiated him with profoundest scorn and consuming
                        retribution, and whatever may be his vagaries from right to wrong and from
                        wrong to right, they will maintain their terrible verdict until he passes
                        into the crucible of impartial history, to stand as a monument to all
                        mankind of the fate of a faithless ruler, who attempted to sacrifice the
                        liberties of a free people, and failed in utter dishonor. He has cast his
                        lot with the foes of the country and lavished his patronage upon them, and
                        there let him stay. The people rallied in their supreme might to save their
                        nationality from his treachery, and they have no terms to make on the
                        blotted altar of his perfidy.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of the resounding Republican victories in the recent elections,
                    and the rebuke of "My Policy," it is still uncertain whether President Johnson
                    will continue his intransigence or will acknowledge defeat and consent to the
                    Republicans' policies.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head>Congress Official</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article provides the district's official vote for Congress in 1862,
                    1864, and 1866. The results represent an "overwhelming verdict" that the people
                    expect "some measure of justice in the restoration of the rebellious States."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>4</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt>"Will traitors never learn that defiant treason cannot rule over loyal
                    people?"</excerpt>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that Gov. Swann and President Johnson have been consulting
                    about methods to remove the "loyal Police Commissioners of Baltimore so that the
                    rebels may be allowed to vote and regain their sway in Maryland."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head>Pennsylvania Legislature</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece contains a full list of the men elected to the Legislature. In
                    the next session, Republicans will hold the balance of power in both bodies. The
                    Senate remains as it was before, with a 21 to 12 majority for the Republicans;
                    in the House, the Democrats gained a total of four seats, but still trail the
                    Republicans by 24 seats, 38 to 62.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>5</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Thomas Williams, "one of the ablest lawyers in Pennsylvania," was
                    re-elected to Congress on the pledge that he would pursue charges of impeachment
                    against President Johnson.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a company of 175 Americans and 30 Mexicans under the
                    command of Gen. Ford tried unsuccessfully to capture Matamoras in Mexico on
                    Sept. 27th. A subsequent attempt was "equally unsuccessful."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Harrisburg</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Repository's correspondent relates that rumors continue to swirl in the
                    capital over who will be appointed to replace Senator Cowan. Currently, the
                    odds-on favorite is Gov. Curtin.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>7</column>
                <head>Greenvillage Slightly Ahead</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>
                        <emph rend="italic">To the Editors of the Franklin Repository:</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>We claim (I think justly) that we gave a larger majority for the Union ticket
                        than any other district in the county, in proportion to the number of our
                        whole vote, and we also claim that more old men voted in our box. Mr. Jacob
                        Immell, aged 91 years, walked to the election; Mr. Thos. Wallace, aged 86;
                        Mr. Christian Fry, aged 84 years, and Mr. Jacob Bittinger in his 80th year.
                        Mr. Bittinger and Mr. Wallace are both veteran soldiers of 1812. Long may
                        those glorious old men live to vote the Union ticket. We also claim that the
                        largest and heaviest man in the county voted with us, Mr. Daniel Lesher, who
                        weighs 365 pounds. Mr. L. is at the same time one of the best men that
                        Franklin County can produce. And lastly, we claim that the strongest man in
                        the county, or in the Congressional district, voted in our box, Mr. James
                        Bowers, our Supervisor, who has engaged in the good work this summer in
                        levelling the hills between this place and Scotland. Union districts let us
                        hear from you.<lb/> GREEN.</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer>Green</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Immell</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wallace</ln>
                        <fn>Thomas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fry</ln>
                        <fn>Christian</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bittinger</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Lesher</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bowers</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Green" brags about the high turnout in Greenvillage for the Republicans,
                    and suggests that the vote collected there included ballots from the county's
                    oldest and fattest residents.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>8</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that a "large portion" of the corn crop has failed as has
                    the cotton crop, which was "severely injured by drought and worm." "The people
                    in the inland and northern portion of the State are destitute, and unless there
                    be immediate assistance the suffering during the winter will be great."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.24.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Union County Committee</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>At its meeting last Monday, the Union County Committee voted and scheduled
                    a convention to meet on November 13th to discuss the best method of determining
                    the next Senator.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--"Kicked Out"</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Deal</ln>
                        <fn>J. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Matthew P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flinder</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Welsh</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>The article informs the newly appointed Postmaster, Matthew P. Welsh, that
                    his days are numbered since it is unlikely that the new Congress will approve
                    his nomination.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Union County Convention</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The piece indicates the number of delegates that each district will be
                    entitled to when the county convention meets on November 13th, as determined by
                    the resolution adopted by the late Union County Convention.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Robberies</head>
                <origin>Greencastle Pilot</origin>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hamiton</ln>
                        <fn>S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Reports that two robberies occurred in Greencastle last week. In the first
                    instance, a thief entered S. Hamilton's saloon and stole $15 from the "money
                    drawer." In the second, John Smith, a "hireling who had been discharged Joseph
                    Snively, stole Mr. Christian's pocket-book, containing $27. Smith was later
                    arrested and is in jail, awaiting trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The Franklin County Teachers' Institute will hold its next session in
                    Greencastle in the second week of November.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Call Accepted</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Kunkelman</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>Rev. Kunkelman, of Indianapolis, Indiana, (and formerly of Franklin county)
                    has accepted an offer to lead Chambersburg's Lutheran congregation.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sibbet</ln>
                        <fn>H. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Sadie S. V.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Forney</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 10th, H. S. Sibbet and Sadie J. V. Smith were married by Rev. C. H.
                    Frey.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hunsecker</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Sollenberger</ln>
                        <fn>Mary</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Schneck</ln>
                        <fn>B. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 18th, John Hunsecker and Mary Sollenberger were married by Rev. B.
                    S. Schneck.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Conrad</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dull</ln>
                        <fn>Susan</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McElroy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 18th, Jacob Conrad and Susan Dull were married by Rev. William
                    McElroy.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gutshall</ln>
                        <fn>Daniel</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hetrick</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 5th, Daniel Gutshall, of Cumberland county, and Elizabeth Hetrick
                    were married by W. H. Blair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Blair</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snively</ln>
                        <fn>Kate P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>W. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On Oct. 16th, Conrad K. Stumbaugh and Kate P. Snively were married by W. H.
                    Blair.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.10.24.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
