<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE hwp SYSTEM 'c:\xml_parser\dtd\news_kim.dtd'&amp;gt; -->
<hwp type="newspaper" id="fr1866/pa.fr.fr.1866.04.11">
    <header>
        <title>Franklin Repository</title>
        <tagger>
            <taggerName>Watson Jennison</taggerName>
            <tagDate>03/29</tagDate>
            <tagNote/>
        </tagger>
        <address><city>Chambersburg</city><county>Franklin</county><state>Pennsylvania</state></address>
        <date n="1866-04-11">
            <year>1866</year>
            <month norm="04">April</month>
            <day>11</day>
            <weekday id="Wed">Wednesday</weekday>
        </date>
        <frequency>weekly</frequency>
        <extent>04</extent>
        <editionNote/>
    </header>
    <paperBody>
        <page n="01" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.04.11.01">
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Stonewall Jackson</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The article gives a negative review of a new biography of Stonewall
                    Jackson, declaring the work to be astonishingly "partizan" in its glowing
                    portrayal of the fallen Confederate hero and his cause.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="02" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.04.11.02">
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>The Veto Vetoed!</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript>
                    <p>The United States Senate, on Friday last, passed the Civil Rights bill over
                        the veto of President Johnson by 33 yeas to 15 nays; three more than the
                        constitutional majority. It had passed the Senate originally on the 2d of
                        February by 33 to 12, and on the 13th of March it passed the House by 111 to
                        38; but the President, in accordance with his league with copperheads and
                        traitors to force rebels into our national legislature and protect treason
                        from all penalties for its bloody record of crime, vetoed the bill and
                        vainly hoped to corrupt or intimidate a sufficient number of Senators to
                        defeat its passage. Such was the history of the Freedmen's Bureau bill, but
                        Congress has at last resolved to discharge its duty regardless of the
                        treachery and power of the Executive, and the natural rights with which a
                        just Creator has endowed all mankind, will in the great Republic of the
                        world be conferred by statute in defiance of the objection of the President.
                        But once before in the history of this government has a law been enacted
                        over a veto, and that was an unimportant one passed notwithstanding the
                        objections of John Tyler, whose name has been measurably redeemed from
                        infamy by the perfidy of Andrew Johnson.</p>
                    <p>The following is the vote by which the bill was passed over the veto on
                        Friday:<lb/> YEAS.<lb/> Anthony,<lb/> Brown,<lb/> Chandler,<lb/> Clark,<lb/>
                        Conness,<lb/> Cragin,<lb/> Creswell,<lb/> Edmonds,<lb/> Fessenden,<lb/>
                        Foster,<lb/> Grimes,<lb/> Harris,<lb/> Henderson,<lb/> Howard,<lb/>
                        Howe,<lb/> Kirkwood,<lb/> Lane of Ind.,<lb/> Morgan,<lb/> Morrill,<lb/>
                        Nye,<lb/> Poland,<lb/> Pomeroy,<lb/> Ramsey,<lb/> Sherman,<lb/>
                        Sprague,<lb/> Stewart,<lb/> Sumner,<lb/> Trumbull,<lb/> Wade,<lb/>
                        Willey,<lb/> Williams,<lb/> Wilson,<lb/> Yates--33.</p>
                    <p>NAYS.<lb/> Buckalew,<lb/> Cowan,<lb/> Davis,<lb/> Doolittle,<lb/>
                        Guthrie,<lb/> Hendricks,<lb/> Johnson,<lb/> Lane of Kansas,<lb/>
                        M'Dougall,<lb/> Nesmith,<lb/> Norton,<lb/> Riddle,<lb/> Saulsbury,<lb/> Van
                        Winkle,<lb/> Wright--15.</p>
                    <p>The yeas are all Republicans, and the nays all Democrats but Doolittle, Lane,
                        Nesmith, Norton, and Van Winkle. We class Mr. Cowan with the Democrats--as
                        he has on all issues identified himself with that organization.</p>
                    <p>We congratulate the friends of Justice and Freedom in all sections of the
                        Republic on this triumph of right over deliberate, perfidious Wrong. It
                        proclaims that caste, condition and color shall work no distinction in the
                        enjoyments of the natural, inalienable rights of Man, and henceforth there
                        will be no foot of American soil whereon the humblest citizen cannot demand
                        and enforce in his own behalf and in behalf of his household, equal and
                        exact justice before the law. It confers no political or conventual rights.
                        These are wisely and properly left to the States; but it stamps all men, of
                        every condition and color, as citizens of the Republic they are compelled to
                        join in defending, and gives notice to the world with all the commanding
                        ceremony of law, that the humble and opulent are here equal in the enjoyment
                        of life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness. A faithless President may
                        interfere and aid the violent prejudices of treason to defeat its
                        enforcement in some degree for a time; but it is a step from which no nation
                        can recede, and the unwilling and discomfited President will see Right ever
                        strengthen as his treachery and much abused power draw daily toward the
                        close of their brief limitation.</p>
                    <p>At the time of this writing we have no word of the passage of the bill in the
                        House, but we hazard little in assuring that it will there have the
                        requisite two-thirds and probably twenty to spare. We feel warranted,
                        therefore, in assuring our readers that the Civil Right's bill will be the
                        law of the land before the close of the present week. Thus in the fullness
                        of time, does justice achieve its triumphs however clouded to gloom or beset
                        by treachery.</p>
                    <p>Since the above was in type a telegraphic dispatch gives us the cheering
                        intelligence that the House of Representatives took up the bill on Monday,
                        and passed it over the veto by 122 yeas to 41 nays--<emph rend="italic"
                            >forty</emph> more than the required number. The bill is therefore a
                        law, the objections of Andrew Johnson and copperheads and rebels generally
                        to the contrary notwithstanding. Freedom takes no step backward!</p>
                </transcript>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Overriding the President's veto, Congress passed the Civil Rights Bill, the
                    editors joyously note. The enactment of the legislation will guarantee that
                    "caste, condition and color" shall no longer affect an individual's ability to
                    enjoy the fruits of his labor or protection under the law. But it does not grant
                    suffrage to the freedmen, a decision supported by the editors who contend that
                    the qualifications for political rights are the province of the states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="e">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>A Gentle Admonition</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>In the wake of the Democrats' dreadful performance in the recent election
                    in Connecticut, some Democrats in Pennsylvania sense that their gubernatorial
                    nominee, Clyster Clymer, has little chance of defeating his opponent because his
                    record during the war was less than distinguished. As a consequence, there is a
                    movement afoot to replace Clymer with Senator Cowan, a more well-known political
                    entity. Regardless who the Democrats' select, the editors say, the Union party
                    will emerge triumphant in the next election.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>It is reported that the Supreme Court has ruled that "military commissions
                    cannot try citizens for offences in time of peace."</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>3</column>
                <head/>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>The failure of Culver, Penn, &amp; Co. has "crippled" several banks in
                    Pennsylvania, reports indicate. The Bank of Chambersburg is refusing to accept
                    notes from the Oil City Bank, Petroleum Bank, and Venango County Bank, all from
                    Venago county, as well as the Crawford County Bank, Lawrence County Bank, and
                    Tioga County Bank.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="l">
                <column>4</column>
                <head>County Superintendent</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer>Philomath</trailer>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gaff</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>"Philomath" nominates John R. Gaff as a candidate for County Superintendent
                    of Franklin county schools.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>6</column>
                <head>Proclamation by the President</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>A copy of the President's Proclamation affirming the official end of the
                    insurrection by the southern states.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="03" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.04.11.03">
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Court Proceedings</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Burkholder</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Clandy</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Miller</ln>
                        <fn>Jeremiah</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Goettman</ln>
                        <fn>George</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McGlaughlin</ln>
                        <fn>Dallas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wilson</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Bratton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flory</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Dixon</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Stumbaugh</ln>
                        <fn>C. H.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Carr</ln>
                        <fn>Richard</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Smith</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Thomas</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Wolff</ln>
                        <fn>Adam</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>During the court proceedings last Monday, the following cases were disposed
                    of: Com. vs. John Burkholder and William Clandy. Surety of the Peace. Nolle
                    prosequi entered. Com. vs. Jeremiah Miller, Dallas, McGlaughlin and others.
                    Assault and Battery. Nolle Prosequi entered. Com. vs. George Goettman. Assault
                    and Battery. Nolle Prosequi entered. Com. vs. James Wilson. Assault and Battery.
                    Nolle Prosequi entered. Com. vs. William Bratton. Assault and Battery. Nolle
                    Prosequi entered. Com. vs. William Flory. Assault and Battery. Nolle Prosequi
                    entered. Com. vs. James Dixon. Surety of the Peace. Nolle Prosequi entered. Com.
                    vs. Henry Stumbaugh. Assault and Battery. Nolle Prosequi. Com. vs. C. H.
                    Stumbaugh. Assault and Battery. Nolle Prosequi entered. Com. vs. C. H.
                    Stumbaugh, Henry Stumbaugh, and Richard Carr. Riot. Nolle Prosequi entered. Com.
                    vs. Charles Smith and James Thomas. Larceny. The defendants were charged with
                    stealing a quantity of jewelry from the house of Adam Wolff, of this place.
                    Defendants plead guilty and submit to the court. Sentenced to separate and
                    solitary confinement at labor in Eastern Penitentiary for the period of thirteen
                    calendar months.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Annual Meeting</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the annual meeting of the German Baptists, who are also
                    known as the "Dunkards," will be held at the residence of Jacob Price, near
                    Waynesboro, on May 19th. It is anticipated that the event will be large and will
                    continue for five or six days: organizers are preparing enough food to feed one
                    thousand people.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items--Another Stable Burned</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Skelly</ln>
                        <fn>Charles</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn/>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Officer</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A large stable, known as Radebaugh's barn, burned down in a fire last
                    Thursday night. The blaze destroyed all the contents of the barn except the two
                    horses, which were the only livestock it contained. Because of the fire's size
                    and extreme heat, residents feared it would spread to other buildings in the
                    neighborhood, particularly the Indian Queen Hotel's stable. It is believed that
                    the fire was started by Charles Skelly, who was seen by police officer Gelwicks
                    running away shortly before the alarm went off. Skelly was pursued and arrested
                    and is awaiting trial.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--Borough Appointments</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Seilhauer</ln>
                        <fn>G. O.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Fahnestock</ln>
                        <fn>D. S.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Snider</ln>
                        <fn>Nicholas</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Frey</ln>
                        <fn>Joseph</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Pearce</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gelwicks</ln>
                        <fn>John R.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Houser</ln>
                        <fn>M. W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Constable</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>At the last meeting of the Town Council, the following men were elected
                    officers: G. O. Seilhauer, Secretary; D. S. Fahnestock, Treasurer; Nicholas
                    Snider, Wood Inspector for North Ward; Joseph Frey, Wood Inspector for South
                    Ward. William Pearce and John R. Gelwicks were appointed night police, and
                    Constable M. W. Houser was made chief.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Local Items--House Burned Near Upton</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McLellan</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>A tenant house belonging to William McLellan burned to the ground last
                    Sunday night. No one was injured in the blaze, but a family was expected to move
                    into the dwelling on Monday. It is thought that the fire was the work of an
                    incendiary.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="a">
                <column>1</column>
                <head>Local Items</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names/>
                <summary>Announces that the 54th Anniversary of the Franklin County Bible School
                    will take place April 23rd in the Methodist E. Church.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Leedy</ln>
                        <fn>Jacob G.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Boosel</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>West</ln>
                        <fn>William A.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 29th, Jacob G. Leedy and Elizabeth M. Boosel were married by Rev.
                    William A. West.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Park</ln>
                        <fn>James</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Walker</ln>
                        <fn>Maggie M.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Gordon</ln>
                        <fn>J. Smith</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf>Rev.</pf>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 28th, James Park and Maggie M. Walker were married by Rev. J.
                    Smith Gordon.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>McDowell</ln>
                        <fn>William P.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Foreman</ln>
                        <fn>Mary E.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>William W.</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On March 16th, William P. McDowell and Mary E. Foreman were married by
                    William Britton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Rosenberry</ln>
                        <fn>Ashway</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Flengle</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 3rd, Ashway Rosenberry and Elizabeth Flengle were married by
                    William Britton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="s">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Married</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Allen</ln>
                        <fn>John</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Hoilingshead</ln>
                        <fn>Elizabeth</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Britton</ln>
                        <fn>William</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 5th, John Allen and Elizabeth Hoilingshead were married by William
                    Britton.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <div type="o">
                <column>2</column>
                <head>Died</head>
                <origin/>
                <commentary/>
                <excerpt/>
                <transcript/>
                <trailer/>
                <names>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Roney</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Henry</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                    <name>
                        <ln>Ward</ln>
                        <fn>Ellen</fn>
                        <sf/>
                        <pf/>
                    </name>
                </names>
                <summary>On April 4th, Roney, infant son of Henry and Ellen Ward, died in
                    Chambersburg. He was 4 months old.</summary>
                <note/>
                <look/>
            </div>
            <pageNote/>
        </page>
        <page n="04" image="pa.fr.fr.1866.04.11.04">
            <pageNote>This page contains advertisements.</pageNote>
        </page>
    </paperBody>
</hwp>
